<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>QQQ Investor</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/</link><description>Recent content on QQQ Investor</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jomonylw.github.io/en/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Personal Investment Bible: Investment Iron Law I</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1731056005960/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1731056005960/</guid><description>This article criticizes the traditional financial concept of “saving money in the bank”. It points out that under inflation, low bank deposit interest rates struggle to withstand erosion from inflation, effectively resulting in “the more you save, the less you have”. This viewpoint is supported by examples from biblical stories, savings rate data, and the Nobel Prize Foundation&amp;#39;s case, encouraging readers to invest their funds in long-term, high-return investment tools like stocks and real estate to achieve wealth appreciation.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[

<h2 class="relative group">Investment Iron Law I: Don&rsquo;t Keep Your Money in the Bank 
    <div id="investment-iron-law-i-dont-keep-your-money-in-the-bank" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#investment-iron-law-i-dont-keep-your-money-in-the-bank" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>The vast majority of people who fail at financial management don&rsquo;t do so because they don&rsquo;t earn enough,
but because they put their assets in the wrong place.
Have you ever heard of anyone getting rich from bank savings?</p>
</blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">Saving Equals Wasting Resources 
    <div id="saving-equals-wasting-resources" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#saving-equals-wasting-resources" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>There&rsquo;s a parable in the Bible about financial stewardship. A landowner entrusted his property to three servants. He gave the first servant five units of money, the second two, and the third one. He told them to cherish and manage their wealth wisely, and he would return in a year to see how they had fared.</p>
<p><strong>Wasting Time and Money</strong></p>
<p>The first servant invested his money; the second bought raw materials and produced goods to sell; the third, for safety, buried his money under a tree. A year later, the landowner returned.  The first two servants had doubled their wealth, pleasing the landowner.  Only the third servant&rsquo;s money remained unchanged. He explained, &ldquo;Fearing loss through mismanagement, I kept the money safe. Today, I return it untouched.&rdquo;</p>
<p>The landowner was furious.  &ldquo;You lazy servant!&rdquo; he scolded. &ldquo;You didn&rsquo;t even try to utilize your wealth!&rdquo;  Wealth not utilized is wasted money and wasted potential. The third servant was rebuked not for misusing the money, nor for losing it through failed investments, but for keeping it &ldquo;safe&rdquo; and unproductive.</p>
<p>Keeping money in the bank is the most common approach to personal finance today, and also the biggest mistake people make.  Therefore, the first and most important financial rule this book offers is: <em>Don&rsquo;t keep your money in the bank.</em>  &ldquo;Bank&rdquo; here refers to post offices, commercial banks, and any other financial institution where money can be deposited.</p>
<p>Many believe that earning interest in a bank, benefiting from compound interest, constitutes sound financial planning. In reality, with inflation, the real rate of return is close to zero, meaning no real financial gain. Therefore, leaving money in the bank is equivalent to no financial management at all.</p>
<p>It&rsquo;s impossible to predict how much wealth each person will accumulate through financial management. The only certainty is that getting rich solely through bank savings is incredibly difficult.  Ask yourself, &ldquo;Have you ever heard of anyone getting rich purely from bank deposits?&rdquo;  Those who keep all their savings in the bank often find themselves not only failing to become wealthy in their old age but also struggling to maintain financial independence. Such stories are common.  Those who choose bank deposits as their primary financial management method do so primarily for safety. However, readers must understand:  <strong>&ldquo;Money in the bank is safest in the short term, but the most dangerous form of financial management in the long term.&rdquo;</strong></p>
<p><strong>Blind Spots in Personal Finance</strong></p>
<p><em>Most people manage their finances by keeping their money in the bank, so most people are not wealthy.</em></p>
<p>If accumulating immense wealth were as easy as the examples suggest, then most people over 65 today would be millionaires. However, this is far from reality.  Millionaires over 65 are few and far between, with many senior citizens facing financial hardship, relying on continued work or support from their children to make ends meet.</p>
<p>Surveys on the elderly in Taiwan reveal increasingly serious financial challenges for senior citizens.  Among approximately 1.48 million people aged 65 and above, about 13% rely on financial assistance from family and friends or social welfare.  This demonstrates a serious problem with most people&rsquo;s financial concepts and investment methods. How else could they reach old age not only without wealth but without even basic financial independence?</p>
<p>Taiwan&rsquo;s savings rate has historically been above 30%, currently hovering between 20% and 30%, consistently ranking among the highest globally. This indicates excellent performance in saving and budgeting. Consequently, we can deduce that flawed financial management is the primary reason for the lack of financial independence among ordinary people. To understand where they go wrong, we must first observe how they handle their assets. In various lectures, I often ask the audience, &ldquo;How are your assets stored?&rdquo;  The majority answer: &ldquo;In the bank.&rdquo;</p>
<p><strong>Prioritizing Security over Investment</strong></p>
<p>Surveys on Taiwanese household investment preferences reveal that the top three investment choices are demand deposits (72%), rotating savings and credit associations (53%), and time deposits (36%). Clearly, most people lean towards traditional financial methods.  Furthermore, when asked, &ldquo;If you had 10 million Taiwan dollars in savings, how would you use it?&rdquo;, about 41% of surveyed households said they would deposit it in a financial institution to earn interest. This illustrates the widespread preference for bank savings.</p>
<p>Indeed, people have high savings rates and a strong preference for depositing money in financial institutions to earn interest.  In early 1996, total deposits in Taiwanese financial institutions reached 12.6 trillion Taiwan dollars.  With a population of 21 million, this translates to an average deposit of 600,000 Taiwan dollars per person, regardless of age.  For an average family of four, this amounts to 2.4 million Taiwan dollars.  This demonstrates a strong inclination towards bank savings. However, this traditional and conservative approach is the primary reason why most people fail to achieve wealth through investment.</p>
<p>This phenomenon reveals an over-reliance on traditional bank deposits for financial management. People prioritize safety and convenience over the rate of return. However, focusing solely on earning and saving money, then depositing it in a bank, is often the first step towards financial mismanagement.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Keeping money in the bank is like having no financial plan at all.</p>
</blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">Deposit Interest Rates Lack True Compound Interest Benefits 
    <div id="deposit-interest-rates-lack-true-compound-interest-benefits" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#deposit-interest-rates-lack-true-compound-interest-benefits" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>What&rsquo;s wrong with bank deposits? The problem lies in the low interest rates (return on investment), making them unsuitable for long-term investment tools.</p>
<p>How much interest can bank deposits earn?  The salaries of average office workers are usually directly deposited into demand deposit accounts (current interest rates around 2%-4%). A portion serves as temporary funds or covers daily expenses, while the remainder is transferred to time deposits (current interest rates around 5%-8%) for investment purposes. Thus, the average interest rate earned on bank deposits is about 5%.</p>
<p><strong>5% Interest is Hardly a Path to Wealth</strong></p>
<p>Most people have a basic understanding of compound interest, believing that interest earned on bank deposits, accumulating over time, can create substantial wealth. This misconception arises from a superficial understanding of compounding.  The vast differences in final returns resulting from different rates of return on the same principal over the same period often come as a surprise.</p>
<p>Let&rsquo;s illustrate with an example. Suppose someone saves 14,000 Taiwan dollars annually at the end of each year for 40 years, depositing everything into a bank account with an average interest rate of 5%. How much will they accumulate after 40 years? Before answering, recall the similar example from the previous section, but with the money in a bank instead of invested in stocks or real estate with an average annual return of 20%.</p>
<p>You might guess 25 million, 10 million, or even a conservative 5 million Taiwan dollars.  The correct answer, however, is only 1.69 million.  This can be calculated using the future value of an annuity formula:</p>
<p><math xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" display="block"><mtable displaystyle="true" columnalign="right center left" columnspacing="0 thickmathspace" rowspacing="3pt"><mtr><mtd><mn>14,000</mn><mo>×</mo><mfrac><mrow><msup><mrow><mo stretchy="false">(</mo><mn>1</mn><mo>+</mo><mn>0.05</mn><mo stretchy="false">)</mo></mrow><mrow><mn>40</mn></mrow></msup><mo>−</mo><mn>1</mn></mrow><mn>0.05</mn></mfrac></mtd><mtd><mi></mi><mo>=</mo></mtd><mtd><mn>1,690,000</mn></mtd></mtr><mtr><mtd><mn>14,000</mn><mo>×</mo><mfrac><mrow><msup><mrow><mo stretchy="false">(</mo><mn>1</mn><mo>+</mo><mn>0.20</mn><mo stretchy="false">)</mo></mrow><mrow><mn>40</mn></mrow></msup><mo>−</mo><mn>1</mn></mrow><mn>0.20</mn></mfrac></mtd><mtd><mi></mi><mo>=</mo></mtd><mtd><mn>102,810,000</mn></mtd></mtr></mtable></math></p>
<p>Let&rsquo;s compare this with the 20% return scenario.  The only difference between the two formulas is the rate of return (5% vs. 20%). A 20% return over 40 years yields 102.81 million Taiwan dollars, while a 5% return over the same period yields only 1.69 million, less than a fraction of the former. The difference is over 60 times! This illustrates the power of compound interest.  Many assume they benefit from compound interest in a bank, but at a 5% return, even with compounding over a long period, the wealth creation effect is very limited.</p>
<p>This example demonstrates that one of the keys to successful financial management is the rate of return. The key is not just whether your assets are invested, but <em>where</em> they are invested and what the rate of return is.</p>
<ul>
<li>
<ol>
<li>The key to financial management lies in how your assets are allocated. The rate of return has a decisive impact on your future wealth.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol start="2">
<li>While bank savings provide interest income and the benefit of compounding,  you&rsquo;ll find that as you age, bank deposits contribute little to overall wealth growth.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol start="3">
<li>The first step towards building wealth through investment is to allocate assets to investments with high long-term rates of return.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol start="4">
<li>&ldquo;Financial Management&rdquo; is a significant factor contributing to wealth disparity in society.</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>Inflation makes money worth less and less.</p>
</blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">The Invisible Killer of Currency Value: Inflation 
    <div id="the-invisible-killer-of-currency-value-inflation" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#the-invisible-killer-of-currency-value-inflation" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>Forty years ago, a millionaire was truly wealthy.  Today, a millionaire might struggle to afford a house. Why?  Inflation.  Every investor must consider the impact of inflation.</p>
<p><em>Inflation reduces the purchasing power of money and lowers the real rate of return, diminishing the effect of wealth accumulation.</em></p>
<p>Over the past 30 years, the average annual inflation rate in Taiwan has been around 5%. What about the future?  Inflation and economic growth are closely linked. As Taiwan&rsquo;s economy continues to grow, inflation is expected to remain around 5% annually.</p>
<p>Inflation means continuously rising prices, which translates to decreasing purchasing power.  If you keep your money in a demand deposit account earning 4% interest with a 5% inflation rate, what happens?  Your purchasing power decreases.  The longer your money sits in a savings account, the less it&rsquo;s worth.  What used to cost 10 Taiwan dollars for a newspaper now costs 15. Your 10 dollars can now only buy two-thirds of a newspaper. With inflation, money in the bank shrinks like wool submerged in water.</p>
<p><strong>Saving Alone Won&rsquo;t Make You Rich, Not Even in Two Lifetimes</strong></p>
<p>With 5% inflation and a nominal interest rate of around 5% on bank deposits, your real rate of return is zero. In this scenario, the effect of compound interest is nullified.  Wealth accumulation relies solely on painstaking saving. Imagine someone saves 500,000 Taiwan dollars a year. How long would it take to become a billionaire?  200 years!</p>
<p>Saving 500,000 Taiwan dollars a year is difficult; living for 200 years is even harder!  Therefore, even with diligent saving and budgeting, if all the money is kept in the bank, this person won&rsquo;t become wealthy in this lifetime, and worse, not even in the next! The average lifespan is around 75 years, meaning two lifetimes total only 150 years.  It would take a third lifetime for someone relying solely on bank savings to potentially reach billionaire status.  If a family maintains the financial strategy of &ldquo;frugality and bank savings,&rdquo; it would take at least 200 years, or about seven generations, for them to potentially become wealthy.  Conversely, with proper financial management, wealth can be achieved in 40 years (half a lifetime).</p>
<p><strong>Money in the Bank Should Be Spent Sooner Rather Than Later</strong></p>
<p>I remember 30 years ago, when I was in second or third grade, a popsicle cost 20 cents, and a red bean ice cream cost 50 cents.  My parents gave me 50 cents each day for allowance, which I invariably spent on red bean ice cream after school. My parents constantly encouraged me to save, so my father opened a bank account for me. If I had been obedient and developed good saving habits from a young age, saving those 50 cents daily and earning 8% interest, it would have grown tenfold over 30 years, to 5 Taiwan dollars.  However, a red bean ice cream now costs 15 Taiwan dollars. Those 5 dollars can only buy one-third of a red bean ice cream. More importantly, for a小学生 30 years ago, a red bean ice cream was precious.  Even a dozen red bean ice creams today couldn&rsquo;t compare to the value of one back then. Had I followed my parents&rsquo; financial advice and kept my money in the bank, I would regret it now.</p>
<p>Therefore, if you&rsquo;re going to keep money in the bank, my sincere advice is: &ldquo;Spend it sooner rather than later!&rdquo; This might sound shocking, but there&rsquo;s logic to it.  From an economic perspective, money has more value and higher utility when used sooner. We save money in the bank, delaying gratification for the sake of greater enjoyment in the future.  However, with inflation, money left in the bank often leads to <em>less</em> enjoyment.</p>
<p><strong>The Value of Money Decreases with Age</strong></p>
<p>My wife and her friends developed a financial philosophy: &ldquo;Money is most valuable when spent while young.&rdquo; This makes economic sense.  Their reasoning: &ldquo;When you&rsquo;re old, delicacies might harm your health, traveling becomes difficult, and most importantly, wearing beautiful clothes attracts unwanted attention and ridicule.&rdquo;</p>
<p>Thus, everyone managing their finances must be mindful of the dual pressures of inflation and the diminishing value of money with age. Bank deposit interest rates cannot compensate for these losses. In other words, <strong>money in the bank, while nominally increasing, actually decreases in value.</strong></p>
<p>Of course, I&rsquo;m not encouraging you to spend all your savings immediately.  Rather, I&rsquo;m highlighting that if you keep money in the bank, you must consider the declining purchasing power due to inflation and the reduced economic benefit as you age.  The fundamental solution is to withdraw your money from the bank and invest it in instruments with higher returns than bank deposit rates. <strong>Therefore, the best way to combat inflation is: Don&rsquo;t keep your money in the bank. Invest in long-term, high-return assets like stocks and real estate.</strong></p>
<p>Because inflation decreases real returns and hinders wealth accumulation, even saving 14,000 Taiwan dollars annually and investing in stocks or real estate for 40 years to become a billionaire won&rsquo;t carry the same weight as being a billionaire today.  Therefore, under inflation, consider using the <em>real</em> rate of return. If the return on investment is 20% and inflation is 5%, the real return is 15%.  So how much should you save annually, investing in stocks or real estate with a nominal return of around 20% (real return of 15%), to become a billionaire in 40 years?  The answer is 57,000 Taiwan dollars per year.</p>
<p><math xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" display="block"><mn>57,000</mn><mo>×</mo><mfrac><mrow><msup><mrow><mo stretchy="false">(</mo><mn>1</mn><mo>+</mo><mn>0.15</mn><mo stretchy="false">)</mo></mrow><mrow><mn>40</mn></mrow></msup><mo>−</mo><mn>1</mn></mrow><mn>0.15</mn></mfrac><mo>=</mo><mn>101,410,000</mn><mspace linebreak="newline"></mspace></math></p>
<blockquote>
<p>A small step today makes a world of difference tomorrow.</p>
</blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">The Path to Wealth of Chang Pin-san, Former Chairman of Chang Hwa Bank 
    <div id="the-path-to-wealth-of-chang-pin-san-former-chairman-of-chang-hwa-bank" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#the-path-to-wealth-of-chang-pin-san-former-chairman-of-chang-hwa-bank" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>Chang Po-hsin, the current standing director of Chang Hwa Bank, with assets exceeding tens of billions, inherited and expanded upon the fortune of his father, Chang Pin-san, the former chairman of Chang Hwa Bank, earning him a place among Taiwan&rsquo;s wealthiest individuals.</p>
<p><strong>Trading Bank Deposits for Stock Dividends</strong></p>
<p>Forty years ago, both Chang Pin-san and my father were from Nantun District, Taichung City.  They were not only fellow townsmen but also colleagues. Back then, Chang Pin-san was just a junior manager at Chang Hwa Bank, without much wealth.  However, he borrowed money to buy Chang Hwa Bank shares from colleagues who wanted to sell them. At the time, stock dividends were far lower than bank interest. Despite this, Chang Pin-san persisted in borrowing money to acquire shares, holding onto them for the long term.  Other colleagues deposited the proceeds from their stock sales into banks. Years later, Chang Pin-san, owning the most shares, became the largest shareholder and eventually the chairman of Chang Hwa Bank, laying the foundation for his immense wealth.</p>
<p>Chang Pin-san was also friends with Lien Chen-tung, father of Lien Chan, and encouraged him to buy Chang Hwa Bank shares. The Lien family&rsquo;s fortune also originated from those hundreds of Chang Hwa Bank shares.</p>
<p>It&rsquo;s hard to believe that the path to wealth could be so simple: borrow money to buy a few Chang Hwa Bank shares, invest in some real estate, hold them long-term, and essentially forget about them.  Decades later, great wealth is attained. Those who sold their shares and deposited the money in banks are still wondering how others became rich. Some might attribute this to luck, but financial management is not about luck.  It&rsquo;s about the method chosen and the investment tools selected.  Therefore, if you don&rsquo;t want to be poor, don&rsquo;t keep your money in the bank.</p>
<p><strong>Bank Savings Shouldn&rsquo;t Exceed Living Expenses</strong></p>
<p>Someone once jokingly asked me, &ldquo;You&rsquo;re telling us not to keep money in the bank.  Are we supposed to pay with stocks or real estate certificates at the supermarket or restaurant?&rdquo; Of course not!  Advising against keeping money in the bank doesn&rsquo;t mean you can&rsquo;t have any money in the bank at all. Bank deposits offer advantages: security and convenience. They are ideal for storing funds needed for daily expenses. However, you can&rsquo;t have your cake and eat it too.  Convenience comes at the cost of high returns.</p>
<p>The wise approach is to clearly divide funds into two categories: daily expenses and investments.  Keep enough for daily needs in the bank, enjoying the security and convenience it offers. Invest the rest in higher-return assets like stocks and real estate.</p>
<p>In my opinion, keeping the equivalent of two months&rsquo; living expenses in the bank is sufficient for an individual or family. Most individuals and families receive regular income, which is deposited into their bank accounts. Therefore, one month&rsquo;s expenses for immediate use and another month&rsquo;s worth as a safety net should be ample.  The remaining funds should be invested in higher-return assets like stocks and real estate.  In other words, if your monthly expenses average 50,000 Taiwan dollars, and your bank balance consistently exceeds 100,000, you are not managing your finances effectively.  Actively seek suitable investment opportunities to make your surplus funds work for you.</p>
<p><strong>The &ldquo;Two Big, One Small&rdquo; Approach to Flexible Fund Management</strong></p>
<p>Some believe in maintaining substantial emergency funds. However, even if unforeseen circumstances drain your bank savings, there&rsquo;s no need to panic. The high-return investments mentioned earlier—stocks and real estate—are not as illiquid as some might think.  Listed stocks in Taiwan&rsquo;s active stock market can be sold almost any day of the year (excluding holidays), providing quick access to cash within a few days.  Reluctant to sell? Stocks can also be used as collateral for loans.</p>
<p>Real estate is less liquid than stocks, but many Taiwanese banks now offer &ldquo;revolving mortgage loans,&rdquo; allowing property owners to convert fixed assets into liquid assets. These loans involve mortgaging a property to secure a credit line of up to 70%-75% of the property&rsquo;s value. Borrowers can draw and repay funds as needed, with interest accruing only on the outstanding balance. For example, a 10 million Taiwan dollar property could secure a 7.5 million credit line.  Borrowing 5 million leaves 2.5 million available without interest charges, with interest accruing only on the 5 million borrowed.  Any surplus funds can be used to repay the loan, reducing interest costs.</p>
<p>Many financial experts recommend a &ldquo;three-part&rdquo; approach, dividing assets equally among bank savings, real estate, and more speculative investments. I propose a &ldquo;two big, one small&rdquo; approach: allocate most of your assets to stocks and real estate, keeping a small portion in a bank for daily expenses.  This isn&rsquo;t my invention. In fact, this is the portfolio strategy employed by many who have achieved wealth through investments.</p>
<ul>
<li>
<ol>
<li>Keeping money in the bank is the riskiest form of financial management.  Inflation erodes returns, leaving real interest rates near zero.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol start="2">
<li>Banks offer convenience, not high returns.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol start="3">
<li>Keep only two months&rsquo; worth of living expenses in the bank.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol start="4">
<li>Trying to get rich with money in the bank is like trying to win a baseball game without swinging the bat.</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ul>
<p>If all this hasn&rsquo;t convinced you to reconsider keeping most of your money in a financial institution, perhaps the story of the Nobel Prize Foundation&rsquo;s success might change your mind.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Change your asset management perspective, change your financial destiny.</p>
</blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">Lessons from the Nobel Prize Foundation 
    <div id="lessons-from-the-nobel-prize-foundation" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#lessons-from-the-nobel-prize-foundation" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>Every October, the Nobel Committee announces the Nobel laureates. The Nobel Prize attracts global attention not only for representing the highest academic honor but also because each laureate receives a substantial prize of 1 million US dollars.</p>
<p><strong>The Folly of Depleting Capital</strong></p>
<p>The Nobel Foundation awards several prizes annually, disbursing millions of dollars. This raises the question: How large is the Nobel fund to sustain such substantial payouts? The Nobel Foundation&rsquo;s success, besides the substantial initial donation by Alfred Nobel over a century ago, is largely attributed to its shrewd financial management.</p>
<p>Established in 1896 with a 9.8 million US dollar donation from Nobel, the foundation&rsquo;s purpose is to fund the prizes.  Flawless fund management was paramount.  Initially, its charter stipulated that investments be restricted to safe, fixed-income instruments like bank deposits and government bonds, explicitly excluding stocks and real estate to avoid market risks.</p>
<p>This capital preservation approach, prioritizing safety over returns, seemed prudent, preventing losses. However, sacrificing returns had consequences.  After 50 years of prize payouts and operating expenses, low returns depleted two-thirds of the Nobel fund, leaving only a little over 3 million US dollars by 1953.</p>
<p><strong>From 3 Million to 270 Million: The Secret</strong></p>
<p>Facing depletion, the Nobel Foundation&rsquo;s board recognized the importance of investment returns. In 1953, they made a groundbreaking change, amending the charter to shift from bank deposits and bonds to primarily stocks and real estate.  This shift in investment philosophy transformed the foundation&rsquo;s fate. Over the next 40 years, despite continued prize payouts and operating costs, the foundation not only recovered all previous losses but also grew its assets to 270 million US dollars by 1993.</p>
<p><em>Nobel Prize Foundation Asset Growth and Decline</em></p>
<table>
  <thead>
      <tr>
          <th>Year</th>
          <th>Total Assets (Million USD)</th>
          <th>Remarks</th>
      </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
      <tr>
          <td>1896</td>
          <td>9.8</td>
          <td>Foundation Established</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>1953</td>
          <td>3.3</td>
          <td>Investment Charter Amended</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>1993</td>
          <td>270</td>
          <td></td>
      </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>
<p>Had the Nobel Foundation not changed its approach 40 years ago, clinging to bank savings, it would have vanished, unable to fund the prizes.  Perhaps other wealthy individuals would have established new foundations with larger prizes, replacing the Nobel Prize.</p>
<p>The Nobel Foundation&rsquo;s history underscores the importance of financial management.  Even a substantial initial fund, if mismanaged, can be depleted. Conversely, even with significant spending, skillful management can generate rapid growth.</p>
<p>I once heard of a Taiwanese hometown association that established a foundation with 100,000 Taiwan dollars 40 years ago to provide scholarships for children from their hometown.  Forty years later, the fund remains at 100,000 Taiwan dollars. While a significant sum back then, today it barely covers administrative costs, threatening the foundation&rsquo;s existence.  The problem? Neglecting financial management.</p>
<p>Learning from the Nobel Foundation, many US foundations, pension funds, university endowments, and even personal trusts have shifted from bank deposits and bonds to primarily stocks and real estate. In contrast, few Taiwanese foundations grasp this concept, and university endowments rarely address financial management seriously.  The fate of these foundations, if they don&rsquo;t adapt, is clear.</p>
<p>I often participate in corporate training programs, where I habitually ask companies about the size and investment strategy of their employee welfare funds.  The answers are usually similar: small funds, mostly in bank deposits, rarely exceeding a few hundred thousand or a million Taiwan dollars. However, in 1990, during my time at China Development Corporation, the employee welfare fund exceeded 200 million Taiwan dollars. Why?  Because it was primarily invested in China Development Corporation&rsquo;s own stock.</p>
<ul>
<li>
<ol>
<li>The Nobel Foundation&rsquo;s course correction 40 years ago secured its status today.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol start="2">
<li>Prioritizing security above all else leads to asset depletion.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol start="3">
<li>The growth and decline of wealth for individuals, families, businesses, or other entities depends on their investment strategy.</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ul>
<p>Will your hard-earned wealth shrink like the early Nobel fund, or grow like the later one? The key lies in <em>how</em> you invest. If, like many, you keep most of your money in the bank, it&rsquo;s not too late to change. The Nobel Foundation&rsquo;s story shows how a change in investment philosophy can transform everything.  Should you reconsider your financial habits and prioritize investments in stocks and real estate? Let the Nobel Foundation inspire your financial thinking. A single change in mindset can lead to immense wealth decades from now!</p>
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Personal Investment Bible: Preface</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1731056005958/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1731056005958/</guid><description>This book aims to help readers establish a correct view of wealth management, learn financial knowledge, master easy wealth management techniques, and ultimately achieve financial freedom, even becoming millionaires. Author Huang Peiyuan uses the story of the Lien Chan family&amp;#39;s wealth management as an example, explaining the importance of wealth management in a simple and profound way, and combining his rich experience and academic research, proposes the key elements of wealth accumulation: regular savings, pursuing high returns, and long-term waiting. In addition, this book also emphasizes the inadequacy of financial education and the importance of continuous learning and adaptation in a rapidly changing investment environment.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[
  



<div
  
    class="flex px-4 py-3 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900"
  >

  <span
    
      class="text-primary-400 ltr:pr-3 rtl:pl-3 flex items-center"
    >

    

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M256 0C114.6 0 0 114.6 0 256s114.6 256 256 256s256-114.6 256-256S397.4 0 256 0zM256 128c17.67 0 32 14.33 32 32c0 17.67-14.33 32-32 32S224 177.7 224 160C224 142.3 238.3 128 256 128zM296 384h-80C202.8 384 192 373.3 192 360s10.75-24 24-24h16v-64H224c-13.25 0-24-10.75-24-24S210.8 224 224 224h32c13.25 0 24 10.75 24 24v88h16c13.25 0 24 10.75 24 24S309.3 384 296 384z"/></svg>

  </span>


  </span>

  <span
    
      class="dark:text-neutral-300"
    ><strong>Synopsis</strong><br>
Written by Mr. Huang Peiyuan from Taiwan, this book&rsquo;s greatest strength lies in its departure from traditional thinking. It uses clear and easy-to-understand language to teach correct wealth management methods. The book outlines thirteen ironclad rules for effortless wealth management, guiding readers on how to establish a correct view of financial management. Many people strive to make money but don&rsquo;t know how.  Many possess the conditions for wealth but miss opportunities due to a lack of financial literacy. Even worse, some lose everything due to investment mistakes. The author draws on practical experience and extensive academic research, exploring these thirteen ironclad rules to help you &ldquo;enjoy wealth management, achieve wealth with ease,&rdquo; and confidently join the ranks of millionaires.
<br>
<br>
<strong>About the Author</strong><br>
<strong>Huang Peiyuan</strong>, Ph.D. in Business Administration from the University of California, Berkeley, General Manager of Sancai Construction and Real Estate Co., Ltd. Former Director of the Institute of Business Administration, Tunghai University, Deputy Director of the Project Business Department, China Development Trust Company, Vice President of East-West Securities, USA, Investment Manager at Merrill Lynch, USA, and financial advisor to numerous companies.</span>
</div>



<h2 class="relative group">Learning Wealth Management from the Lien Chan Family 
    <div id="learning-wealth-management-from-the-lien-chan-family" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#learning-wealth-management-from-the-lien-chan-family" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>The people of Taiwan are not only surprised by the enormous wealth of the Lien Chan family, the former chairman of the Kuomintang, but also harbor doubts. How could two generations of civil servants, with their meager salaries, accumulate wealth comparable to that of tycoon families?</p>
<p>This suspicion is deeply ingrained, but the Lien family is a prominent political family in Taiwan, and no one wants to antagonize them by probing too deeply.</p>
<p>As a journalist, the Lien family&rsquo;s wealth has always been a puzzle to me. I even made a determined effort to uncover the truth, but to no avail.  Six months ago, Professor Huang Peiyuan, then director of the Institute of Business Administration at Tunghai University, spoke about his desire to combine theory and practice and publish a &ldquo;Personal Investment Bible.&rdquo; After reading Professor Huang&rsquo;s manuscript, the mystery of the Lien family&rsquo;s wealth became clear to me.  The Lien family is a perfect example of the principles in this &ldquo;Personal Investment Bible.&rdquo; Perhaps Lien Ya-tang, in his early years, wrote not only the renowned &ldquo;General History of Taiwan,&rdquo; but also a &ldquo;Wealth Management Manual&rdquo; passed down only within the family.</p>
<p>According to Professor Huang&rsquo;s (his title at the time; now he is in business) &ldquo;Personal Investment Bible,&rdquo; the first rule is &ldquo;Don&rsquo;t keep your money in the bank.&rdquo; The second is that if you want to get rich, invest in stocks and real estate.  This gives you the opportunity, with the income of an average office worker, to become a multimillionaire after 40 years of wealth management.</p>
<p>By this standard, the Lien family is indeed the most faithful follower of the &ldquo;Personal Investment Bible.&rdquo; When they had little wealth, Lien&rsquo;s mother (Lien Chan&rsquo;s mother) invested solely in stocks and real estate.  Over the past few decades, the Lien family remained steadfast, waiting for the appreciation of their stocks and real estate, which naturally led to the vast wealth that now arouses public suspicion.</p>
<p>Several decades ago, there were many business people who possessed similar wealth to the Lien family.  These individuals also worked hard to manage their businesses and accumulate more wealth.  However, compared to the Lien family now, most of them lament their inferiority in terms of wealth. The Lien family&rsquo;s role as pure investors fully demonstrates that &ldquo;as long as the concepts and methods are correct, wealth will naturally follow.&rdquo;</p>
<p>In fact, the theories and methods in the &ldquo;Personal Investment Bible&rdquo; have been discussed by countless scholars and experts in mature Western societies, but not many have truly adhered to them and become millionaires as a result.  The reason lies not in the inadequacy of the theories and methods, but in the lack of confidence and patience of those who apply them, leading them to give up halfway.</p>
<p>Therefore, I advise all readers of this book to truly believe in the theories presented, have long-term patience, and adhere to them unwaveringly in order to succeed.</p>
<p>We wish all readers the ability to enjoy a happy retirement with sufficient financial resources, which is perhaps the greatest contribution of the &ldquo;Personal Investment Bible&rdquo; to the public! (This article is written by the president of Business Weekly Taiwan)</p>


<h2 class="relative group">The Joy of Wealth Management, Achieving Wealth with Ease 
    <div id="the-joy-of-wealth-management-achieving-wealth-with-ease" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#the-joy-of-wealth-management-achieving-wealth-with-ease" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>When I was young, I thought that money was the most important thing in life; now that I am old, I know that it is.</p>
<p>— Oscar Wilde, British playwright</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This book is written for those who are determined to become wealthy and strive for financial independence. If you have tried every possible way to get rich and your home is filled with investment books, but you still can&rsquo;t figure out how to achieve wealth in your lifetime, congratulations! You have found the book you need. The investment and financial management concepts and methods described in this book are absolutely understandable and achievable for everyone. As long as you put them into practice, becoming a millionaire is not difficult.</p>
<p>I see many people working tirelessly to make money, hoping to improve their own and their families&rsquo; financial situation, but they can&rsquo;t find the right way. Many people clearly have the conditions to become rich through financial management, but they don&rsquo;t know how to manage their finances, resulting in missed opportunities.  Others know that investment and financial management can lead to wealth, but the problem is that what they know is not true, leading them astray and suffering from financial mismanagement.  The author sees these phenomena and often feels sorry for them.</p>
<p>The biggest problem in Taiwan at present is the serious lack of financial education. The public lacks a correct concept of financial management. They either don&rsquo;t know how to manage their finances and neglect it, or they use the wrong methods. As a result, some people not only fail to achieve wealth through financial management, but even fail to achieve basic financial independence.  Insufficient or incorrect financial concepts are harmful not only to one&rsquo;s own financial situation, but also to the public. This is the main motivation for the author to write this book, and what this book offers readers is the correct basic concept of investment and financial management.</p>
<p>As a scholar and a practitioner of financial management, I feel obligated to share my years of investment research results and practical experience in financial management with everyone, helping the public to easily manage their finances and achieve wealth through investment. The message this book wants to convey is: Financial management is actually very simple. Not only can everyone do it easily, but almost all young people have the conditions to achieve wealth through financial management.</p>
<p>This book is based on 20 years of practical financial management experience in the United States and Taiwan, 6 years of investment research at Tunghai University, and 15 years of experience as a financial advisor.  In fact, the concepts and practices in this book were developed 3 years ago.  For the past 3 years, the author has given lectures on this topic in various places and received tremendous feedback.  Many listeners have continuously requested that I compile these concepts and action guidelines into a book.  I personally also feel that these financial management concepts and action guidelines are indeed beneficial to the public and there is indeed a need to publish a book.</p>
<p>However, putting these concepts into words is a difficult task for me, so I have procrastinated for 3 years. Recently, thanks to the repeated urging of Mr. He, President of Business Weekly Cultural Enterprise, and Ms. Sun Meiqing, and the examples and suggestions provided by Ms. Shen Wenci, and especially the efforts of Mr. Yang Weikai, who spent several months helping me revise and proofread, this book has finally been completed. I express my sincere gratitude here.</p>
<p>If this book can be read by the general public, and if they can accept the concepts and financial management methods described in the book, then all the author&rsquo;s efforts will have been truly worthwhile. Good ideas should be shared with everyone. I hope everyone can benefit from them and easily become millionaires through financial management.</p>
<p>Finally, I dedicate this book to my parents, Mr. Huang Minting and Ms. Huang Juzhi, who raised and nurtured me.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">Preface 
    <div id="preface" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#preface" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>In recent years, Taiwan&rsquo;s economy has grown rapidly.  While continuous economic growth is certainly gratifying, the problem of uneven wealth distribution has become increasingly serious. Some blame inappropriate government policies, while others believe it&rsquo;s due to speculation, which has caused stock and housing prices to rise, widening the gap between rich and poor. The author believes that these factors are not the main cause. The real reason for the widening wealth gap is the significant disparity in financial literacy among the public.</p>
<p>Starting in 1986, Taiwan officially entered an era of abundant capital and a focus on wealth management.  The New Taiwan dollar slowly appreciated from 40 to 27 against the US dollar, and during this period, a large amount of foreign exchange flowed into Taiwan, creating a situation where &ldquo;money overflowed in Taiwan.&rdquo;</p>
<p>Due to the excess capital, people began to shift their money towards investing in stocks and real estate. The huge influx of funds into the stock and housing markets caused stock and housing prices to soar. Between 1986 and 1989, housing prices increased by an average of two to four times, and the weighted stock market index rose from over 700 points in early 1986 to 12,680 points in February 1990, an increase of 18 times.  Investing in stocks and participating in the capital market is inherently meaningful, and rising stock prices are a natural consequence of economic growth. Unfortunately, most investors adopted the wrong approach, believing that to profit in the stock market, they must buy low and sell high, earning the difference.  In reality, short-term trading is not only time-consuming and laborious but also incurs huge transaction costs, resulting in most investors losing money. The stock market is almost equated with a casino.</p>
<p>The purpose of this book is to enlighten the public&rsquo;s financial mindset by providing new perspectives, concepts, and methods to cope with the important yet complex investment environment. The author sincerely hopes that after reading this book, readers will develop a new financial mentality and adopt correct financial management methods.</p>
<p>&ldquo;Getting rich&rdquo; is almost everyone&rsquo;s desire, and most people think that their monthly income is not much, and the amount they can save is even less. At this rate of wealth accumulation, it seems impossible to get rich. But in fact, with enough time and proper financial management, becoming a millionaire is not impossible.  Wealth accumulation through financial management requires only three basic conditions: regular savings, the pursuit of high returns, and long-term waiting.</p>
<p>The easiest way to achieve wealth through financial management is to learn from those who have done so. What are their methods? The secret of most successful wealth managers is not that they are smarter, harder working, or luckier than others, but that they have the habits and practices of wealth creation.</p>
<p>In the past, family financial management was rarely mentioned in school education.  Perhaps this is because investment and financial management involve money, and most people think that making money with money has a connotation of getting something for nothing.  In formal school education, teachers avoid mentioning it, believing that talking about money in education may corrupt people&rsquo;s minds, especially making money with money, which doesn&rsquo;t seem noble.  However, long-term avoidance of this issue has only exacerbated the problem.</p>
<p>The people of Taiwan, through years of joint efforts, have created an economic miracle and accumulated a large amount of wealth. However, most individuals and families only know how to make money but not how to manage it, let alone how to use it wisely.  After acquiring wealth, individuals, families, and even the entire society have suffered rather than benefited. For example, in recent years, money games have been prevalent.  Many people are busy speculating in stocks and real estate, and various forms of gambling such as the Mark Six lottery, futures, and foreign exchange margin trading are still popular and becoming increasingly rampant.  Many people are obsessed with money games, all for the purpose of making money and improving their family&rsquo;s financial situation.  However, if we calmly review the investment results of the past few years, it is not difficult to find that in the end, few have profited, many have lost, and even more have gone bankrupt.  Everyone has worked in vain, and the result is only a rapid redistribution of wealth and a prevalence of unhealthy speculation in society. The wealth of individuals and society as a whole does not increase. This is all due to the public&rsquo;s lack of clear understanding of financial management concepts.</p>
<p>The consequence of poor financial literacy is not only personal loss and family misfortune but also a waste of overall social resources.  Let&rsquo;s face this issue that is crucial to individuals, families, and the entire society: family financial management.</p>
<p>As the saying goes, &ldquo;When a couple is poor, everything is sad.&rdquo;  This shows that if a family&rsquo;s financial situation cannot meet the needs of family life, or if finances are not managed properly, happiness is hard to come by. Of course, there are many factors that contribute to a happy family, and wealth is only one of them, as many family problems cannot be solved with money. There is a saying: &ldquo;Money is not everything, but without money, you can do nothing.&rdquo; Although money is not the center of a family, in our real society, most good things require money. Wealthy families are not necessarily happy, but families without money are usually even less so. To make ourselves and our families happier, investment and financial management are indeed imperative. Investment and financial management can not only improve the financial situation of an individual or a family, but it is also a good way to accumulate wealth.  Using financial management to achieve wealth is achievable for everyone, and it is something everyone should do.</p>
<p>Future wealth depends on the future investment environment, and the biggest characteristic of the investment environment, in a word, is change.  The entire financial environment is ever-changing and unpredictable. This has been true in the past and will be even more so in the future. In the world of investment and financial management, there is constant change. It can be said that &ldquo;the only constant is change.&rdquo; It is foreseeable that the changes in the next 10 years will exceed those of the previous 50 years. Changes are not only becoming faster, but also more complex, diversified, and international. Whether we like it or not, we are already in a rapidly changing environment.</p>
<p>Facing change, you can remain calm, adapt, and adopt the appropriate mental attitude. However, if you know how change will affect you, you may not dare to take it lightly. Because the natural consequence of any change is redistribution, including wealth, power, markets, personnel&hellip; In terms of wealth, any change in the investment environment will naturally affect the flow of money at all levels.  Indeed, in financial markets, capital markets, commodity markets, spot or futures markets worldwide, billions of dollars are traded every day, and wealth is constantly being redistributed.  Your wealth may increase significantly during the redistribution process, or it may shrink rapidly.  After long-term redistribution, you may become a billionaire, or you may become penniless, depending on how you face and deal with the changes.</p>
<p>Any change and the resulting redistribution poses a &ldquo;crisis&rdquo; to your wealth to a greater or lesser extent. The Chinese characters for &ldquo;crisis&rdquo; are profound and often quoted in foreign books because they contain both danger and opportunity. &ldquo;Wei&rdquo; represents the threat to wealth, and &ldquo;Ji&rdquo; represents the opportunity for wealth creation.</p>
<p>We can wait for changes and redistribution to determine our future wealth level, or we can make good use of the opportunities brought about by change and try to reduce its destructive power.  In this era of accelerating change, cultivating the ability to manage and respond to change is essential to controlling our own future.</p>
<p>Looking ahead, changes in business, economy, finance, politics, society, and other aspects will accelerate. The overall financial environment will become more complex and unpredictable, and it is foreseeable that future wealth redistribution will inevitably accelerate. Therefore, for ourselves, our families, and society, everyone should play the role of a financial manager.</p>
<p>This is an era of rapid change and abundant wealth, and it is also an era that forces us to manage our finances.  Everyone desires to become rich and improve their living standards or achieve their life goals. There are many ways to get rich, but the concept the author wants to elaborate on in this book is: Investment and financial management is one of the effective methods to achieve wealth. As long as you have the correct financial management concepts and put them into practice, whether you are rich or poor now, over time, you may become a millionaire through investment and financial management.</p>
<p>In this critical era related to our future wealth, you can no longer remain indifferent to financial management or ignorant of investment.  You must adopt the correct financial concepts as early as possible, constantly acquire new knowledge, and avoid mistakes in order to win in the process of wealth redistribution.</p>
<p><strong>The Story of the Mailman Who Got Rich</strong></p>
<p>My brother-in-law has a friend in Taichung, a middle-aged man with a dark complexion and an occasional shy smile. My first impression of him wasn&rsquo;t memorable until he drove away in a new BMW. The second time we met, he arrived in a Mercedes-Benz, which made me admire him.  I realized that appearances can be deceiving and quickly asked him what kind of big business he was in. He said he wasn&rsquo;t a businessman, just an ordinary office worker.  I pressed him further, asking which big company he worked for. He said he worked at the post office. I thought he must be a senior executive to be so prestigious and own two luxury cars.  The answer, however, was surprising. He replied, &ldquo;I&rsquo;m a mailman. I deliver mail by motorcycle in the morning, with a monthly salary of NT$30,000-40,000.&rdquo; I secretly speculated that he must specialize in delivering registered mail and was pocketing some of the contents.  He then told me his story. His previous generation were poor farmers who left behind some land, which he had always regarded as ancestral property and kept without selling. No one expected that recent land consolidation would increase the value of his land by dozens of times. Now, just by renting out houses, he earns NT$500,000 in rent every month.  This 48-year-old mailman didn&rsquo;t rely on increasing income and reducing expenditure, but simply by putting his assets in the right place, he now has assets of more than NT$300 million. This is one of the examples of wealth accumulation through financial management in Taiwanese society.</p>
<p>Similar stories seem to happen frequently around us. Before I taught at the university, I worked for an investment company. Once, during the election of directors and supervisors at a shareholders&rsquo; meeting, I discovered that a major shareholder holding more than NT$200 million worth of shares was actually a clerk in the company&rsquo;s personnel department.  It turned out that 35 years ago, when she joined the company as an employee, her salary was very low and her life was insecure, so she saved her meager salary. When company employees had fractional shares to transfer, she would buy them. After many years, this woman in her 50s, although unremarkable and not looking like a rich woman, now has a net worth of more than NT$200 million, enough to enjoy her retirement. In fact, there are countless examples of such ordinary office workers who have become wealthy through investment and financial management. Many people say that office workers cannot become rich, but in reality, wealthy office workers mostly don&rsquo;t like to show off, so the way to get rich through investment and financial management is often overlooked.</p>
<p><strong>What Differentiates the Rich from the Poor?</strong></p>
<p>Many hardworking office workers who toil daily for money have had the common experience of watching rich people in expensive clothes, living in luxurious villas, and driving by in luxury cars, looking impressive and enviable. While admiring them, you may have wondered: &ldquo;What makes them rich, but not me?&rdquo;</p>
<p>Many people attribute the wealth of these rich people directly to their being born rich, their successful entrepreneurial ventures, their being smarter, harder working, or luckier than others. However, family background, entrepreneurship, intelligence, hard work, and luck cannot explain all the reasons for wealth accumulation. We have all encountered many rich people, such as &ldquo;nouveau riche&rdquo; or &ldquo;landowners.&rdquo; They were not born into wealthy families, nor are they businessmen. They are not necessarily very smart, haven&rsquo;t received much higher education, and are not more frugal than us. Some of them even idle around all day. The only thing they seem to be better at than you is that they are rich.</p>
<p>What special skills do these rich people possess that are lacking in those office workers who diligently save money and work hard every day? How can they accumulate such enormous wealth in their lifetime? This is the question the author has been eager to explore for many years.  I have tried to explain their wealth with factors such as family background, entrepreneurship, occupation, education, IQ, and effort, but all seem to have failed. After years of observation, induction, and academic research, I have discovered a very important factor that is often overlooked by most people: the ability to invest and manage finances. At the same time, I have also discovered the following three facts:</p>
<p><em>1. One of the important factors that distinguishes the rich from the poor is: the ability to invest and manage finances.</em></p>
<p><em>2. Everyone can achieve wealth through investment and financial management.</em></p>
<p><em>3. The first thing to do to improve your financial situation is: to understand the basic concepts of investment and financial management.</em>
content_copy
Use code with caution.</p>
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Personal Investment Bible: The Correct Concept of Financial Management</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1731056005959/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1731056005959/</guid><description>This article explores the correct concept of financial management, pointing out that investment is the key to wealth, rather than simply relying on increasing income and reducing expenditure. Using the wealth comparison between Koo Chen-fu and Koo Li-hsiung, the financial management methods of the Lien Chan family, and an example of becoming a billionaire by investing $1,200 monthly for 40 years, the article illustrates the importance of investment and emphasizes the power of compound interest. Furthermore, it analyzes the impact of financial habits on the wealth gap and how to educate the next generation to establish a correct concept of financial management, suggesting incorporating “Don&amp;#39;t keep money in the bank” into family precepts to cultivate investment awareness from an early age.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[

<h2 class="relative group">The Correct Concept of Financial Management 
    <div id="the-correct-concept-of-financial-management" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#the-correct-concept-of-financial-management" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>The key to winning the wealth race lies not in the starting point, but in choosing the right track.</p>
</blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">Investment Leads to Wealth 
    <div id="investment-leads-to-wealth" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#investment-leads-to-wealth" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>The Chinatrust Financial Holding Co., one of the top five conglomerates in Taiwan, was led by Koo Chen-fu, chairman of the Koo&rsquo;s Group, and Jeffrey Koo, chairman of Chinatrust Commercial Bank. The Koo&rsquo;s Group encompassed seven major business segments: finance, manufacturing, construction, hotels, media, services, and overseas operations, with over 50 affiliated companies and total assets exceeding NT$460 billion. Many wondered how this uncle-nephew duo achieved both political and business success, and who was wealthier.</p>
<p><strong>The Wealth Race Between Koo Chen-fu and Jeffrey Koo</strong></p>
<p>Wealth often correlates with personality. Koo Chen-fu was a slow and steady type, while Jeffrey Koo was more of a go-getter.  Due to their vastly different personalities, their investment approaches also differed significantly.  Koo Chen-fu&rsquo;s eldest son, Eugene Koo, the general manager of China Life Insurance in Taiwan, understood them well. He once said, &ldquo;Money put in Koo Chen-fu&rsquo;s pocket would never come out, but money put in Jeffrey Koo&rsquo;s pocket would disappear.&rdquo;  This was because Jeffrey Koo continuously reinvested his money, leading to greater wealth accumulation than his uncle. Jeffrey Koo&rsquo;s personal assets were spread across the US and Japan, invested in real estate, funds, hotels, golf courses, and banks.  Koo Chen-fu, in his 80s, was quite conservative. Regarding his financial management philosophy, he said, &ldquo;I neglect financial management and don&rsquo;t want to worry about money.&rdquo;  His personal income was deposited in the bank by his secretary, and aside from necessary expenses, the rest was converted into fixed-term deposits.</p>
<p>Over the years, Koo Chen-fu naturally had more cash on hand, as his money remained in the bank. However, in terms of wealth creation, Jeffrey Koo far surpassed him. Despite a 17-year age difference, with proper investment, one could still come out ahead.</p>
<p><strong>Investing $1,200 Monthly Can Make You a Billionaire in 40 Years</strong></p>
<p><em>It&rsquo;s not what you don&rsquo;t know that gets you into trouble. It&rsquo;s what you know for sure that just ain&rsquo;t so.</em></p>
<p>The first concept to understand about investment is: <strong>Investment not only improves financial situations but also allows anyone to achieve wealth.</strong></p>
<p>Let&rsquo;s illustrate with a simple example:</p>
<p>Suppose a young person with no savings starts saving NT$14,000 annually for 40 years.  If this money is invested in stocks or real estate with an average annual return of 20%, how much wealth will they accumulate after 40 years?</p>
<p>The author often asks this question in lectures. Most guesses range from NT$2 million to NT$8 million, with a maximum of NT$10 million. The correct answer, however, is a surprising NT$102.81 million!  For a 25-year-old, saving NT$14,000 annually (equivalent to $1,200 monthly) for 40 years, with a total investment of NT$560,000, could result in becoming a billionaire by age 65, assuming a 20% annual return in stocks or real estate.</p>
<p>This figure is calculated using the future value of an annuity formula in finance and investment. The calculation is as follows:</p>
<p><math xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" display="block"><mn>1.4</mn><mo>×</mo><mfrac><mrow><msup><mrow><mo stretchy="false">(</mo><mn>1</mn><mo>+</mo><mn>0.20</mn><mo stretchy="false">)</mo></mrow><mrow><mn>40</mn></mrow></msup><mo>−</mo><mn>1</mn></mrow><mn>0.20</mn></mfrac><mo>=</mo><mn>10281</mn><mspace linebreak="newline"></mspace></math>
(Units are in NT$10,000)</p>
<p>This formula illustrates how small amounts of money can grow significantly through investment.  Understanding the formula isn&rsquo;t crucial; most people who become billionaires through investment don&rsquo;t know it, and knowing it doesn&rsquo;t guarantee success.</p>
<p>Therefore, with youth, ambition, investment knowledge, and three key factors—saving NT$14,000 annually, investing in stocks or real estate, and patiently waiting for 40 years—anyone can achieve wealth through investment, regardless of their current economic situation.  These three factors are attainable for everyone:</p>
<ol>
<li>
<p>Saving NT$14,000 annually (NT$1,200 monthly) should be manageable for most. (If you can&rsquo;t save this much, focus on saving before investing. This book may not be as helpful yet, as you need some capital to start investing.)</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Historically, the long-term average return on stocks and real estate has been above 20%.  Consistently investing in these assets and holding them long-term can yield a 20% average return. These investment tools are accessible to everyone. (Data shows that the Taiwan stock market has averaged around 20% annual returns over the past 20 years; studies show similar returns for Taiwan real estate over the past 40 years.)</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>40 years seems long, but it&rsquo;s a timeframe most people have.  Starting work between 20 and 25 and retiring at 65 provides a 40-year investment window.  While some are born rich and others poor, most have a fair chance at accumulating wealth over 40 years.</p>
</li>
</ol>
<p>This example shows that investment not only improves finances but also provides a path to wealth.  With the right concepts and practices, anyone can achieve wealth through investment.</p>
<p><strong>Smart Investing Can Shorten the Journey by 10 Years</strong></p>
<p>While the initial example uses 40 years to demonstrate the power of investing, most readers are likely in a better position. They may already have savings and can save more than NT$14,000 annually, shortening their path to wealth.</p>
<p>The table below illustrates the wealth accumulation over 10-year intervals using the previous example (investing NT$14,000 annually with a 20% return):</p>
<p>If you have NT$360,000, congratulations! You&rsquo;ve saved 10 years of effort. By continuing to invest in stocks or real estate, you could become a billionaire in 30 years. With NT$2.61 million, you&rsquo;ve saved 20 years. With NT$16.55 million, you&rsquo;re even closer, needing only 10 more years.</p>
<table>
  <thead>
      <tr>
          <th>Investment Years</th>
          <th>Accumulated Amount (NT$10,000)</th>
          <th>Amount Accumulated in the Last Decade (NT$10,000)</th>
      </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
      <tr>
          <td>10</td>
          <td>36</td>
          <td>36</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>20</td>
          <td>261</td>
          <td>225</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>30</td>
          <td>1655</td>
          <td>1394</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>40</td>
          <td>10281</td>
          <td>8626</td>
      </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>
<p>Most readers likely have some savings, allowing them to achieve significant wealth in 20-30 years.</p>
<p><strong>Investing Doesn&rsquo;t Require Advanced Knowledge</strong></p>
<p><em>The trouble with the world is not that people know too little, but that they know so many things that just aren&rsquo;t so.</em></p>
<p>Many believe investing requires perfect timing and extensive financial knowledge.  This isn&rsquo;t entirely true.  After years of studying investment, and witnessing ordinary people achieve wealth through it, I can confidently say that investment success doesn&rsquo;t depend on academic qualifications, intelligence, technical skills, or predictive abilities.  It depends on doing the right things. Successful investors aren&rsquo;t necessarily highly educated or technically skilled; they can be ordinary people who understand fundamental principles.</p>
<p>By doing the right things, anyone can achieve wealth through investment, regardless of their background or effort. Investing doesn&rsquo;t require genius or specialized knowledge; common sense and consistent action are key. Investors don&rsquo;t need to rely on experts; with the right mindset, you can outperform them.</p>
<p>Investing isn&rsquo;t about complex techniques; it&rsquo;s about having the right mindset.  Successful investors simply cultivate habits that most people find uncomfortable or difficult to maintain. Do you understand that investing can create wealth? If so, are you actively pursuing it?</p>
<p>From another perspective, investing can be challenging. The difficulty lies not in needing advanced knowledge, but in going against ingrained habits. This is difficult for most people.</p>
<p>This book presents seemingly simple investment concepts, but wealth is built through consistent, correct habits. Start your investment journey by building the right habits!</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The amount of money you accumulate in your lifetime depends not on how much you earn, but on how you manage it.</p>
</blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">Saving Alone Is Not Enough 
    <div id="saving-alone-is-not-enough" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#saving-alone-is-not-enough" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>A Taiwanese proverb says, &ldquo;People have two legs, money has four.&rdquo; Money chases money faster than people chase money.</p>
<p>Traditional wisdom dictates that &ldquo;the path to wealth lies in diligence and frugality.&rdquo;  This held true in times of economic stagnation, but in today&rsquo;s rapidly changing economy, this mindset requires adjustment.</p>
<p>A century ago, before modern economics became widespread, during periods of economic stagnation and frequent wars, saving was indeed crucial for wealth accumulation. Today, however, with global economic growth and soaring stock and real estate prices, the focus should shift from saving to leveraging the power of compound interest for exponential growth.</p>
<p><strong>How Did Lien Chan Become Wealthy?</strong></p>
<p><em>With so many assets, it&rsquo;s impossible to monitor everything closely. During the period of entrusted management, the principle was to hold existing investments and not trade stocks or dispose of real estate.</em></p>
<p>Lien Chan, with an estimated net worth of nearly NT$6 billion, was one of Taiwan&rsquo;s wealthiest officials. His wealth wasn&rsquo;t accumulated through decades of frugal living on a government salary or through earning a doctoral degree.  It stemmed from his mother&rsquo;s shift in investment strategy over 40 years prior.</p>
<p>Around 1951, Chang Pin-san, former chairman of Chang Hwa Bank, advised Lien Chan&rsquo;s father, Lien Chen-tung, to invest in shares of the &ldquo;Big Three&rdquo; commercial banks.  Following this advice, Lien Chan&rsquo;s mother, Chao Lan-kun, invested her savings in hundreds of shares of Chang Hwa Bank, holding them long-term and letting their value appreciate naturally. This laid the foundation for the Lien family&rsquo;s fortune. Chao Lan-kun had a keen financial mind. Unlike other women who participated in rotating savings and credit associations or simply deposited money in banks, she actively invested.  She sold ancestral farmland in Miaoli and co-developed a property on Nanjing West Road with Huang Lie-huo, founder of Wei Chuan Foods Corporation, splitting the profits. This prime real estate became a significant source of wealth for the Lien family.</p>
<p>Stocks, real estate, and land were the Lien family&rsquo;s wealth-generating tools. Over the years, Lien Chan accumulated holdings in 19 different stocks, including Chang Hwa Bank, Taipei Business Bank, Hua Nan Bank, and Cathay Life Insurance.  His real estate holdings were located in prime areas like the Da&rsquo;an, Shilin, and Zhongshan districts, including 11 plots of land and 26 properties.</p>
<p>Lien Chan once described his family&rsquo;s investment approach as &ldquo;Wu Wei Er Zhi&rdquo; (doing nothing and achieving everything), meaning buying and holding long-term.  By investing in stocks and real estate 40 years ago and patiently holding them, with minimal trading and benefiting from annual returns exceeding 20%, they amassed a fortune nearing NT$10 billion.</p>
<p>You might argue that the Lien family was already wealthy 40 years ago. This might be true, but the point is that while they were prominent, many families in Taiwan were wealthier back then. Today, very few families surpass the Liens in wealth.  This is attributed to their early adoption of the correct investment strategy – focusing on stocks and real estate.</p>
<p><strong>The Key to Wealth Lies in Financial Management, Not Just Saving</strong></p>
<p><em>The ability to earn money is less important than having a mind for financial management, understanding how to make money work for you.</em></p>
<p>Chinese culture values diligence and frugality.  Older generations often teach younger ones that the path to wealth lies in these principles and careful budgeting.  The saying &ldquo;Great wealth comes from heaven, small wealth from frugality&rdquo; encourages thriftiness, as it&rsquo;s seen as the key to wealth.  This emphasis on saving is reflected in Taiwan&rsquo;s high savings rate.  However, I want to convey a crucial message: while saving is important, financial management is even more so.</p>
<p>In the previous example, how much of the NT$100+ million fortune came from diligence and frugality? The answer is NT$560,000, accumulated by saving NT$14,000 annually for 40 years.  This represents only 0.5% of the total.  The remaining 99.5% came from investment, specifically the power of compound interest at a 20% annual return over 40 years.  Which is more important, saving or investing? <strong>Therefore, lifetime wealth accumulation depends not on how much you earn, but on how you manage your money.</strong></p>
<p>If a worker realizes in old age that their wealth primarily comes from a lifetime of hard work and saving, it&rsquo;s almost certain they won&rsquo;t be very wealthy.  The key to wealth through investment isn&rsquo;t the ability to &ldquo;earn and save,&rdquo; but the ability to leverage the &ldquo;compounding power of money.&rdquo;  For most, improving their financial situation requires focusing on investment, not just saving.</p>
<p>Consider this: saving NT$1 million annually without investing would take 100 years to reach NT$100 million. In contrast, investing NT$14,000 annually could make you a billionaire in 40 years. If Chao Lan-kun had only focused on saving and not investing, would the Lien family be as wealthy as they are today?</p>
<p>I&rsquo;m not dismissing the importance of saving, but I want to emphasize that it shouldn&rsquo;t overshadow investment. Investment plays a crucial role in wealth accumulation.  For successful investors, wealth comes primarily from &ldquo;making money work for you,&rdquo; not from earning or saving. Therefore, in addition to being diligent and frugal, learn how to invest.</p>
<p>To improve your financial situation, remember: earning is important, but managing your money is more so. <strong>A correct investment mindset and wise investment choices have a greater impact on your future financial status than your current wealth or future income.</strong> For most, the first step towards improving their finances is not to increase saving, but to understand the correct investment concepts and take action.</p>
<p><em>1. For those who achieve wealth through investment, their fortune comes primarily from making money work for them, not from earning or saving.</em></p>
<p><em>2.  Less than 1% of a NT$100 million fortune comes directly from earned income.</em></p>
<p><em>3.  Investment is not a technique, but a mindset.</em></p>
<p><em>4. The key to financial management is having money to manage, not the amount of money.</em></p>
<blockquote>
<p>Those who learn to invest are like having a money-printing machine.</p>
</blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">How Investment Strategies Create the Wealth Gap 
    <div id="how-investment-strategies-create-the-wealth-gap" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#how-investment-strategies-create-the-wealth-gap" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>A study indicates that in recent years, the public has perceived a serious wealth gap in Taiwan, with a trend towards wealth polarization. Over 47% of respondents believe that &ldquo;speculation in stocks or real estate&rdquo; is the main cause of this widening gap, followed by &ldquo;personal work ability and effort&rdquo; (14%) and &ldquo;family background&rdquo; (11%).  This suggests a common belief that the wealth gap isn&rsquo;t solely due to individual effort, but also to systemic issues, luck, and unequal opportunities.</p>
<p>Indeed, &ldquo;stocks and real estate&rdquo; are major contributors to the wealth gap, while &ldquo;personal work ability and effort&rdquo; and &ldquo;family background&rdquo; have less impact. <strong>People often attribute their poverty to external factors like systemic issues, luck, or lack of opportunity, or use negative terms like &ldquo;speculation&rdquo; to explain their lack of action.</strong> Wealthy individuals often accumulate their wealth through real estate or stock investments, not primarily through &ldquo;speculation,&rdquo; but through &ldquo;holding appropriate investment assets.&rdquo;</p>
<p>Looking ahead, the wealth gap will likely continue to widen. Some will benefit, while others will suffer, depending on their ability to navigate the changing landscape. External factors alone don&rsquo;t determine our financial situation; our investment abilities play a crucial role.</p>
<p><em>1. Financial habits create the difference between the rich and the poor.</em></p>
<p><em>2. The prerequisite for building wealth through investment is allocating assets to high-return investments like stocks or real estate.</em></p>
<p><em>3. One way for the government to address the widening wealth gap is to educate the public about proper financial management.</em></p>
<p><strong>Greater Investment, Greater Returns</strong></p>
<p><em>&ldquo;Thoughts change actions, actions change habits, habits change character, and character changes destiny.&rdquo;</em></p>
<p>Imagine two classmates who join the same company after graduation, holding similar positions with the same salary.  Both are equally frugal, saving NT$14,000 annually for investment. The difference lies in their approach: one keeps their savings in the bank, while the other invests in stocks. Both largely leave their money untouched after depositing or investing it.</p>
<p>After 40 years, the stock investor becomes a billionaire, while the bank saver becomes a &ldquo;millionaire.&rdquo;  While a billion represents significant wealth, &ldquo;millionaire&rdquo; now evokes laughter, being synonymous with &ldquo;homeless&rdquo; in Taiwan&rsquo;s expensive housing market.</p>
<p>The &ldquo;millionaire&rdquo; classmate, seeing their former colleague with the same starting conditions become a billionaire, might assume foul play or lottery winnings. How could their wealth differ so drastically, with one rich and the other struggling?</p>
<p>Those with less wealth often attribute the success of the wealthy to luck or illicit activities. A more positive view might be that they worked harder or were more frugal.  However, they often overlook the critical factor: financial habits. The rich and poor manage their money differently: the rich hold assets like real estate and stocks, while the poor keep their money in the bank.</p>
<p>To become wealthy through investment, one must break free from conventional thinking. An adult who couldn&rsquo;t ride a bicycle saw a child doing so and complained, &ldquo;Only agile children can ride bikes.&rdquo; The child responded, &ldquo;Agility isn&rsquo;t necessary,&rdquo; and taught the adult to ride.  The adult quickly learned but, upon parting ways, instinctively pushed the bicycle home instead of riding it.  This illustrates the difficulty of breaking free from ingrained habits.</p>
<p>If financial management is the primary cause of the wealth gap, the solution lies in improving financial literacy and encouraging people to learn more about investing.</p>
<p><strong>Focusing Solely on Saving is Outdated</strong></p>
<p><em>If one adheres to the principles of investment, it&rsquo;s hard not to become wealthy. If one doesn&rsquo;t, it&rsquo;s hard to become wealthy.</em></p>
<p>I often wonder why, after over 200 years since their ancestors arrived in Taiwan with nothing, most Taiwanese families aren&rsquo;t significantly wealthy. Perhaps the problem lies in outdated family precepts that hinder wealth accumulation.</p>
<p>Family precepts are the guiding principles passed down through generations.  Most families emphasize diligence, frugality, and academic excellence, believing these are the keys to success and wealth.</p>
<p>Many families diligently follow these precepts, raising children who are both frugal and well-educated.  However, few families achieve significant wealth through these alone.  These precepts focus on earning money, not on managing it.  To build generational wealth, families need to update their guiding principles.  While &ldquo;diligence and frugality&rdquo; and &ldquo;academic excellence&rdquo; remain valuable, add another: &ldquo;Don&rsquo;t keep money in the bank.&rdquo;</p>
<p>Why retain &ldquo;diligence and frugality&rdquo;? While saving alone won&rsquo;t lead to great wealth, it&rsquo;s a virtue and a necessary foundation for investment.</p>
<p><strong>Educating the Next Generation Requires a Balanced Approach</strong></p>
<p>Why keep &ldquo;academic excellence&rdquo;?  Studies show a weak correlation between education and wealth.  Academic success doesn&rsquo;t guarantee financial success.  Based on this, I once stopped emphasizing academics with my children, resulting in declining grades.  Their teacher, puzzled, asked, &ldquo;You and your wife are both highly educated, why don&rsquo;t your children share this trait?&rdquo; I was ashamed.</p>
<p>I immediately reinstated the emphasis on academics. I realized it was partly for our own pride, but also because education can enhance social standing and job security. So, for both parents and children, academic pursuits remain important.</p>
<p>However, for future generations to prosper, add another precept: &ldquo;Don&rsquo;t keep money in the bank!&rdquo;  Encourage children to invest in assets like stocks and real estate, rather than leaving money in low-interest bank accounts.  Otherwise, building significant wealth might take generations.</p>
<p>Every Lunar New Year, I buy stocks for my children instead of giving cash. My second-grader is already learning the importance of investing over saving. This concept should be ingrained early as part of family values, fostering a healthy financial mindset from a young age.</p>
<p>In conclusion, most family precepts are outdated.  Building wealth for future generations requires new concepts and practices.  By updating family values and changing how we accumulate wealth, families can achieve lasting prosperity.</p>
<p><em>1. Diligence, frugality, and academic excellence alone are not enough for building lasting wealth.</em></p>
<p><em>2. Teach children not to keep money in the bank, cultivating a proper investment mindset from a young age.</em></p>
<p><em>3.  Leaving money to children might sustain them for a few years; teaching them how to manage it can provide for a lifetime and for generations to come.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>The Intelligent Investor：Book Notes</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1730598742194/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1730598742194/</guid><description>This book provides guidance on investment strategies for laymen, explores the difference between investing and speculation, different strategies for defensive and enterprising investors and the relationship between investors and investment advisors, highlighting the concept of &amp;#34;margin of safety&amp;#34; as the core of investment.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[

<h2 class="relative group">I. Summary 
    <div id="i-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>&ldquo;The Intelligent Investor&rdquo; is a seminal work in the field of investment, authored by Benjamin Graham, widely regarded as the &ldquo;father of value investing&rdquo;. The book aims to provide guidance on investment strategies for the layman, with the following core ideas:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Rational Investment:</strong> Investment decisions should be based on thorough analysis of a security&rsquo;s value, not on market sentiment or speculative behavior.</li>
<li><strong>Margin of Safety:</strong> The core of investing is the margin of safety, which means buying securities at a price significantly below their intrinsic value, thus reducing risk and enhancing potential returns.</li>
<li><strong>Defensive and Enterprising Investors:</strong> Based on risk tolerance and investment objectives, investors are classified as either defensive or enterprising, each employing different investment strategies.</li>
<li><strong>Investors and the Market:</strong> Investors should view market fluctuations rationally, seeing them as opportunities rather than sources of risk.</li>
<li><strong>Company Owner Mentality:</strong> Investors should adopt the mindset of a company owner, paying attention to corporate management and governance and safeguarding their own interests.</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">II. Chapter Summaries 
    <div id="ii-chapter-summaries" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii-chapter-summaries" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Chapter 1: What Intelligent Investors Get 
    <div id="chapter-1-what-intelligent-investors-get" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chapter-1-what-intelligent-investors-get" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>This chapter introduces fundamental concepts of investing, including:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Investing vs. Speculation:</strong>  Investing is an operation based on analysis, aiming for safety of principal and a satisfactory return; speculation is hoping for profit from market fluctuations and carries higher risk.</li>
<li><strong>Defensive Investors:</strong> Seeking safety and steady returns, they can adopt a simple portfolio strategy, allocating funds between high-grade bonds and a diversified selection of leading common stocks.</li>
<li><strong>Enterprising Investors:</strong>  Willing to take on more risk for greater returns, they can employ more aggressive strategies, such as selecting growth stocks and seeking undervalued securities.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chapter 2: The Investor and Market Fluctuations 
    <div id="chapter-2-the-investor-and-market-fluctuations" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chapter-2-the-investor-and-market-fluctuations" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>This chapter explores how investors should view market fluctuations:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Price Fluctuations as a Measure of Investment Success:</strong>  In the long run, investment success depends on the long-term returns of the portfolio, not short-term price movements.</li>
<li><strong>Market Fluctuations as a Guide for Investment Decisions:</strong> Investors can capitalize on market volatility to create opportunities for buying low and selling high, but should avoid excessive focus on short-term market trends.</li>
<li><strong>Market Fluctuations of Individual Stocks:</strong> Focusing on undervalued individual stocks is more meaningful than attempting to predict overall market movements.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chapter 3: A Review of the 1964 Market 
    <div id="chapter-3-a-review-of-the-1964-market" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chapter-3-a-review-of-the-1964-market" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>This chapter analyzes the stock market conditions at the time of writing (1964):</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Comparison with Previous Years:</strong>  The stock market was at a historical high, rendering traditional valuation methods no longer applicable.</li>
<li><strong>New Standards for a &ldquo;New Era&rdquo;:</strong> New valuation methods had not yet been tested by time, and the market was characterized by a high degree of uncertainty.</li>
<li><strong>Investment Strategy Recommendation:</strong>  Adopt a cautious investment strategy and avoid excessive risk-taking.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chapter 4: The Investor and His Advisers 
    <div id="chapter-4-the-investor-and-his-advisers" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chapter-4-the-investor-and-his-advisers" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>This chapter discusses the relationship between investors and their advisors:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sources of Investment Advice:</strong>  Investors can obtain investment guidance from various avenues, including family and friends, banks, brokerage firms, and professional investment advisors.</li>
<li><strong>Selecting Investment Advisors:</strong> Choosing the right advisor is crucial, requiring careful assessment of their expertise, experience, and ethical standards.</li>
<li><strong>Independent Thinking:</strong>  Even when seeking professional advice, investors should maintain their own independent judgment and be responsible for their investment decisions.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chapter 5: The Defensive Investor&rsquo;s Portfolio Policy 
    <div id="chapter-5-the-defensive-investors-portfolio-policy" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chapter-5-the-defensive-investors-portfolio-policy" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>This chapter details the strategies for defensive investors:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Bond and Stock Allocation:</strong> Allocate funds between high-grade bonds and a diversified selection of leading common stocks. The ratio can be adjusted based on market conditions, but generally maintain a 50:50 split.</li>
<li><strong>Bond Portfolio Composition:</strong>  Introduces characteristics of different types of bonds, such as US Savings Bonds, state and municipal bonds, and corporate bonds.</li>
<li><strong>Principles for Common Stock Selection:</strong> Choose large, prominent, and conservatively financed companies with a long history of dividend payments, and purchase them at reasonable price-earnings ratios.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chapter 6: Portfolio Policy for the Enterprising Investor: Negative Approach 
    <div id="chapter-6-portfolio-policy-for-the-enterprising-investor-negative-approach" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chapter-6-portfolio-policy-for-the-enterprising-investor-negative-approach" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>This chapter presents a &ldquo;negative list&rdquo; of what enterprising investors should avoid:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Second-Grade Bonds and Preferred Stocks:</strong> Avoid buying securities lacking sufficient safety merely for the allure of high yields.</li>
<li><strong>Foreign Government Bonds:</strong>  Higher risk and difficulty in enforcing claims in case of default.</li>
<li><strong>New Issues:</strong> Require careful evaluation and avoidance of excessive hype surrounding them.</li>
<li><strong>Convertible Issues:</strong> Their advantages often come at the expense of quality or income, and they present investors with decision-making dilemmas.</li>
<li><strong>New-Issue Mania</strong>: During bull markets, many smaller companies go public, and their stock pricing is often unattractive or even excessive. Investors should be wary of the hype surrounding new issues and avoid blindly following the crowd.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chapter 7: Portfolio Policy for the Enterprising Investor: The Positive Side 
    <div id="chapter-7-portfolio-policy-for-the-enterprising-investor-the-positive-side" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chapter-7-portfolio-policy-for-the-enterprising-investor-the-positive-side" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>This chapter discusses positive strategies enterprising investors can employ:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Market Timing Limitations:</strong>  While the strategy of buying low in depressed markets and selling high in booming markets could be profitable in the past, recent market dynamics have made this approach less viable.</li>
<li><strong>Considerations for Growth Stocks:</strong> Selecting growth stocks requires diligent assessment of future growth potential, avoiding overpaying for lofty expectations.</li>
<li><strong>Three Recommended Areas for Enterprising Investment</strong>:
<ol>
<li><strong>Investing in Large Companies during Unpopular Periods:</strong> When large companies are experiencing unpopular periods, their stock prices may be undervalued, presenting opportunities for investors.</li>
<li><strong>Bargain Issues:</strong> Seek securities whose intrinsic value is demonstrably understated and buy them at prices significantly below this value.</li>
<li><strong>Special Situations:</strong>  Focus on events like mergers, reorganizations, and liquidations where the price fluctuations can offer substantial profit opportunities.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li><strong>Broad Application of Investment Rules:</strong>  Enterprising investors should approach investing as a business endeavor, adhering to sound business principles, such as knowing their investment domain, choosing partners carefully, and managing risk.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chapter 8: Security Analysis for the Lay Investor: General Approach 
    <div id="chapter-8-security-analysis-for-the-lay-investor-general-approach" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chapter-8-security-analysis-for-the-lay-investor-general-approach" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>This chapter introduces basic methods of security analysis for non-professional investors:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Bond Analysis</strong>:
<ul>
<li>Focus on the ratio of earnings to interest expenses, ensuring it meets certain standards (4x for utilities, 5x for railroads, 7x for industrials).</li>
<li>Consider factors like company size, equity ratio, and asset value.</li>
<li>Understand the risk characteristics of different bond types, like the relatively higher risk of railroad bonds compared to the safer utility company bonds.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Common Stock Analysis</strong>:
<ul>
<li>Analyze company profitability, including projected future earnings, sales margins, and return on net worth.</li>
<li>Assess capitalization rates, considering factors like long-term prospects, management quality, financial condition, and dividend record.</li>
<li>Pay attention to the impact of non-recurring gains and losses, making adjustments to earnings data.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Industrial Stock Analysis:</strong> Focus on industry trends and individual companies&rsquo; competitive positions within their respective sectors.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chapter 9: Stock Selection for the Defensive Investor 
    <div id="chapter-9-stock-selection-for-the-defensive-investor" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chapter-9-stock-selection-for-the-defensive-investor" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>Using Dow Jones Industrial Average stocks as an example, this chapter explains how defensive investors can select securities:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Choose a Representative Sample:</strong>  For instance, buy equal amounts of all 30 Dow Jones industrial stocks.</li>
<li><strong>Exclude Stocks with Excessive Price-Earnings Ratios:</strong> Avoid overpaying for speculative growth.</li>
<li><strong>Select Relatively Unpopular Stocks with Reasonable Valuations:</strong>  Capitalize on the market&rsquo;s neglect of certain stocks, finding undervalued investment opportunities.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chapter 10: Stock Selection for the Enterprising Investor: General Approach 
    <div id="chapter-10-stock-selection-for-the-enterprising-investor-general-approach" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chapter-10-stock-selection-for-the-enterprising-investor-general-approach" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>This chapter introduces methods for enterprising investors to select securities:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>The Valuation Approach:</strong>  Estimate a company&rsquo;s future earnings and select a suitable multiplier to determine its intrinsic value.</li>
<li><strong>Factors Affecting Asset Value:</strong> Pay attention to net tangible asset value, especially net current asset value. Add half the excess of net current asset value over earnings power value to the earnings power value for a more comprehensive assessment.</li>
<li><strong>Growth Stock Valuation:</strong> Consider the expected growth rate, but be cautious in assessing its reasonableness. The author provides a simplified formula for growth stock valuation: Value = Current (normal) earnings x (8.5 + 2 x expected annual growth rate).</li>
<li><strong>First-Grade vs. Second-Grade Common Stocks:</strong> Enterprising investors can consider buying second-grade common stocks, but only at bargain prices, namely when their price is less than two-thirds of the indicated intrinsic value.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chapter 11: Security Analysis for the Lay Investor: Six Illustrative Cases 
    <div id="chapter-11-security-analysis-for-the-lay-investor-six-illustrative-cases" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chapter-11-security-analysis-for-the-lay-investor-six-illustrative-cases" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>This chapter uses six real-world cases to illustrate how to apply security analysis techniques to uncover undervalued investment opportunities:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Case 1:  Northern Pacific Railroad common stock (1947):</strong>  The company&rsquo;s stock price was undervalued due to a combination of a low dividend payout and the non-inclusion of certain earnings in its income statement.</li>
<li><strong>Case 2:  Standard Gas and Electric (SP&amp;L) $7 preferred (1947):</strong> Analyzed the complex capital structure of SP&amp;L, pointing out the undervaluation of its preferred stock.</li>
<li><strong>Case 3:  American-Hawaiian Steamship (AHS) (1947):</strong> The company held substantial cash assets that were not reflected in its market price.</li>
<li><strong>Case 4: Royal Dutch Petroleum (RDP) (1953):</strong>  Pointed out that the market value of RDP was undervalued relative to its earnings power.</li>
<li><strong>Case 5:  Hoover Company Class A (1957):</strong> The company&rsquo;s stock was undervalued because the net worth of its British subsidiary was not fully reflected.</li>
<li><strong>Case 6:  Chicago, Terre Haute &amp; Southeastern Railway (TH) bonds (1964):</strong> Analyzed the value of TH bonds, indicating their undervaluation compared to comparable bonds.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chapter 12: Stock Market Fluctuations: The Pattern of Behavior 
    <div id="chapter-12-stock-market-fluctuations-the-pattern-of-behavior" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chapter-12-stock-market-fluctuations-the-pattern-of-behavior" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>This chapter analyzes the patterns of earnings and price fluctuations for different types of stocks:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Pattern 1:  Relatively Stable Earnings, Wide Price Fluctuations:</strong> Using S.H. Kress as an example, the chapter demonstrates how even with stable earnings, market prices can fluctuate greatly, primarily driven by market sentiment.</li>
<li><strong>Pattern 2:  Earnings Fluctuate Moderately, Stock Prices Fluctuate Widely:</strong> Using General Motors as an example, it illustrates how stock price volatility often exceeds earnings volatility and advises investors to view such fluctuations rationally.</li>
<li><strong>Pattern 3:  Extreme Ups and Downs:</strong>  Taking examples like Brunswick Corporation and St. Louis Southwestern Railway, the chapter highlights the substantial uncertainties in company development and stock price movements. Investors should be wary of companies experiencing extreme volatility.</li>
<li><strong>Pattern 4:  Growth Stocks:</strong> Using examples like 3M and Philip Morris, the chapter shows that even growth stocks face risks, and investors should carefully evaluate their growth potential and avoid overpaying for lofty expectations.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chapter 13: A Comparison of Eight Pairs of Companies 
    <div id="chapter-13-a-comparison-of-eight-pairs-of-companies" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chapter-13-a-comparison-of-eight-pairs-of-companies" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>This chapter uses comparative analysis of various stock portfolios to further investigate factors impacting stock prices:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Four Groups of Randomly Selected Cases and the Dow Jones Industrial Average</strong>:  By contrasting the performance of stocks in different market standings and comparing their initial trading dates, the chapter suggests that choosing large, strong companies often yields more consistent results. New stocks of smaller companies carry higher risk.</li>
<li><strong>Secular Changes in the Quality of a Company Group</strong>:  Taking railroad stocks as an example, the chapter highlights how the standing and investment merit of companies within a group can shift significantly over time.</li>
<li><strong>The Results of a Policy of Quality Improvement:</strong>  Using the Dow Jones Industrial Average as an example, the chapter illustrates that merely replacing underperforming components with more popular ones does not necessarily lead to sustained investment gains. Stock selection should be based on a combination of company quality and price.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chapter 14: Stockholders and Management 
    <div id="chapter-14-stockholders-and-management" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chapter-14-stockholders-and-management" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>This chapter explores the relationship between stockholders and company management:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Management Efficiency:</strong>
<ul>
<li>How to assess Management efficiency: By comparing key indicators like profitability, sales margin, and return on net worth to  industry averages.</li>
<li>How to improve inefficient management: Stockholders can take actions like raising questions at shareholder meetings, hiring independent management consultants for assessment, and electing more independent board members.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>The Board of Directors:</strong>
<ul>
<li>Role in Corporate Governance: The board represents shareholder interests, oversees management, sets company strategy, and reviews and approves significant decisions.</li>
<li>Stockholder Oversight of the Board: Stockholders can exercise their influence by electing board members and voting on proposals at shareholder meetings.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Fair Treatment of the General Stockholder:</strong>
<ul>
<li>Management&rsquo;s responsibility to protect outside stockholder interests: Management should set a fair dividend policy, avoid repurchasing stock at excessively low prices, and prioritize shareholder interests.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Holding Companies:</strong>
<ul>
<li>Disadvantageous position of outside stockholders within holding companies: Holding companies often present conflicts between controlling shareholder interests and those of outside stockholders, leading to potential harm to the latter.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>The Securities and Exchange Commission and Investor Protection:</strong>
<ul>
<li>SEC&rsquo;s functions and limitations: The SEC oversees the securities market and protects investor interests. However, its powers and functions are limited and cannot fully guarantee investor rights.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chapter 15:  &ldquo;Margin of Safety&rdquo; as the Central Concept of Investment 
    <div id="chapter-15--margin-of-safety-as-the-central-concept-of-investment" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chapter-15--margin-of-safety-as-the-central-concept-of-investment" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>This chapter summarizes the core concept of the book - the Margin of Safety:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Definition of Margin of Safety:</strong>  Purchasing securities at a price significantly below their intrinsic value, thereby mitigating risk and enhancing potential returns.</li>
<li><strong>Application in Different Investment Types:</strong> Bonds, common stocks, growth stocks, bargain issues, and other asset classes.</li>
<li><strong>Margin of Safety and Diversification:</strong> Diversification can reduce the overall risk of a portfolio and therefore enhances the margin of safety.</li>
<li><strong>Distinguishing Investment from Speculation:</strong>  The margin of safety is a key criterion for differentiating investment operations from speculative ones. Investment operations should be based on a clear and demonstrably justifiable analysis of value, while speculative operations rely more heavily on subjective judgment and market sentiment.</li>
<li><strong>Generalization of the Investment Concept:</strong> The idea of margin of safety can be applied to broader investment domains, such as when purchasing real estate, art, or other assets.</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">III. Key Quotes 
    <div id="iii-key-quotes" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii-key-quotes" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;In Wall Street, if you&rsquo;re always doing what&rsquo;s obvious or what everyone else is doing, you&rsquo;re not going to make money.&rdquo;</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Analysis: This emphasizes that to achieve above-average returns, investors require independent thinking and must seek value that is overlooked by the market.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;For rational investment, mental attitude is more important than technique.&rdquo;</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Analysis:  Investment success necessitates not just skills and tools, but also the right investment philosophy and mindset, including rationality, patience, and discipline.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;Don&rsquo;t buy after a stock has surged and don&rsquo;t sell after it has plummeted.&rdquo;</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Analysis: Avoid chasing rising prices and panicking during market dips. Focus on rational valuation and don&rsquo;t be swayed by market emotions.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;Have the courage of your knowledge and experience. If you have formed a conclusion from the facts and if you know your judgment is sound, act on it—even though others may hesitate or differ.&rdquo;</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Analysis: Investment requires independent judgment. Investors need to be confident and courageous in their convictions, even when facing dissenting opinions. Stay true to your well-researched investment principles.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;Many that are first shall be last, and the last shall be first.&rdquo;</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Analysis:  The business landscape is dynamic. Company strength and investment merit can shift over time, requiring investors to maintain a dynamic outlook and avoid fixed biases.</p>
<blockquote>
<p><em>&ldquo;Margin of Safety&rdquo;</em></p>
</blockquote>
<p>Analysis:  This succinct phrase encapsulates the core of Graham&rsquo;s approach. Investing should be grounded in acquiring assets at a price that provides a buffer against uncertainty and potential errors in judgment.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">IV. Guiding Significance 
    <div id="iv-guiding-significance" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv-guiding-significance" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<ul>
<li><strong>Establish a Sound Investment Philosophy:</strong>  Investing should be based on value analysis, not on speculation.</li>
<li><strong>Emphasize Margin of Safety:</strong> Purchase securities at prices significantly below their intrinsic value to minimize risk and enhance potential returns.</li>
<li><strong>Choose a Suitable Investment Strategy:</strong> Opt for a strategy—defensive or enterprising—that aligns with your risk tolerance and investment objectives.</li>
<li><strong>View Market Fluctuations Rationally:</strong> Don&rsquo;t be swayed by emotional reactions to market volatility. Instead, view such fluctuations as potential opportunities.</li>
<li><strong>Continuously Learn and Improve Investment Knowledge:</strong> Investing requires ongoing study and practice.</li>
<li><strong>Maintain Patience and Discipline:</strong>  Investment success often requires a long-term perspective, avoiding impulsive reactions to market movements.</li>
</ul>
<hr>

<section class="space-y-10 w-full">
    
    
        
            






















  <a class="flex flex-wrap article " href="/en/posts/1728295490690-book-list/">
    
        
        <div class="w-full md:w-auto h-full thumbnail nozoom thumbnailshadow md:mr-7" style="background-image:url(/posts/1728295490690-book-list/featured_hu4424409690304057825.jpg);"></div>
        
      <div class=" mt-3 md:mt-0">
      <div class="items-center text-left text-xl font-semibold">
        
        <div class="font-bold text-xl text-neutral-800 decoration-primary-500 hover:underline hover:underline-offset-2 dark:text-neutral"
          href="/en/posts/1728295490690-book-list/">Recommended Reading List</div>
        
        
        
      </div>
      <div class="text-sm text-neutral-500 dark:text-neutral-400">
        











  









  



  









<div class="flex flex-row flex-wrap items-center">
  
  
  <time datetime="2024-10-01T00:00:00&#43;00:00">1 October 2024</time><span class="px-2 text-primary-500">&middot;</span><span>
  
  
    
    
      
      
        
        
      
        
        
      
      
    
  
  <span id="views_posts/1728295490690-book-list/index.md" class="animate-pulse inline-block text-transparent max-h-3 rounded-full mt-[-2px] align-middle bg-neutral-300 dark:bg-neutral-400" title="views">loading</span>
  <span class="inline-block align-text-bottom">

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 576 512">
<path fill="currentColor" d="M288 32c-80.8 0-145.5 36.8-192.6 80.6C48.6 156 17.3 208 2.5 243.7c-3.3 7.9-3.3 16.7 0 24.6C17.3 304 48.6 356 95.4 399.4C142.5 443.2 207.2 480 288 480s145.5-36.8 192.6-80.6c46.8-43.5 78.1-95.4 93-131.1c3.3-7.9 3.3-16.7 0-24.6c-14.9-35.7-46.2-87.7-93-131.1C433.5 68.8 368.8 32 288 32zM432 256c0 79.5-64.5 144-144 144s-144-64.5-144-144s64.5-144 144-144s144 64.5 144 144zM288 192c0 35.3-28.7 64-64 64c-11.5 0-22.3-3-31.6-8.4c-.2 2.8-.4 5.5-.4 8.4c0 53 43 96 96 96s96-43 96-96s-43-96-96-96c-2.8 0-5.6 .1-8.4 .4c5.3 9.3 8.4 20.1 8.4 31.6z"/></svg>
  </span>

</span>
</span><span class="px-2 text-primary-500">&middot;</span><span>
  
  
    
    
      
      
        
        
      
        
        
      
      
    
  
  <span id="likes_posts/1728295490690-book-list/index.md"
    class="animate-pulse inline-block text-transparent max-h-3 rounded-full mt-[-2px] align-middle bg-neutral-300 dark:bg-neutral-400"
    title="likes">loading</span>
  <span class="inline-block align-text-bottom">

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512">
<path fill="currentColor" d="M47.6 300.4L228.3 469.1c7.5 7 17.4 10.9 27.7 10.9s20.2-3.9 27.7-10.9L464.4 300.4c30.4-28.3 47.6-68 47.6-109.5v-5.8c0-69.9-50.5-129.5-119.4-141C347 36.5 300.6 51.4 268 84L256 96 244 84c-32.6-32.6-79-47.5-124.6-39.9C50.5 55.6 0 115.2 0 185.1v5.8c0 41.5 17.2 81.2 47.6 109.5z"/></svg>
  </span>

</span>
</span>
  

  
  
</div>





<div class="flex flex-row flex-wrap items-center">
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  <span style="margin-top:0.5rem" class="mr-2" onclick="window.open(&#34;/en/tags/recommended/&#34;,'_self');">
    <span class="flex" style="cursor: pointer;">
  <span class="rounded-md border border-primary-400 px-1 py-[1px] text-xs font-normal text-primary-700 dark:border-primary-600 dark:text-primary-400">
    Recommended
  </span>
</span>
  </span>
  
  <span style="margin-top:0.5rem" class="mr-2" onclick="window.open(&#34;/en/tags/book/&#34;,'_self');">
    <span class="flex" style="cursor: pointer;">
  <span class="rounded-md border border-primary-400 px-1 py-[1px] text-xs font-normal text-primary-700 dark:border-primary-600 dark:text-primary-400">
    Book
  </span>
</span>
  </span>
  
  
  
  
</div>




      </div>
      
    </div>
  </a>

        
    
</section>
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>00490 Workers are just picking up trash; Mortgages are a risk for retirees; Buying a house won't make you rich.</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1730597712367/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1730597712367/</guid><description>This session focuses on investment philosophy, asset allocation, lifestyle, and how to cope with market fluctuations. It emphasizes the importance of staying optimistic, continuous learning, and answers questions from the audience on Bitcoin, real estate, retirement planning, leveraged funds, and education funds.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<lite-youtube videoid="Ad9u7a-z6Ro" playlabel="Ad9u7a-z6Ro" params=""></lite-youtube>



<h2 class="relative group">I. Main Topic 
    <div id="i-main-topic" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-main-topic" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This session revolves around investment and life planning. The core ideas are: be optimistic about investment and keep learning, ignoring short-term market fluctuations; young people should focus on asset appreciation, with Nasdaq 100 index funds being the top choice; utilize leverage and allocate assets reasonably; retirees should plan carefully and avoid excessive debt; and one should stay optimistic and confident, avoid material comparisons, and pursue true freedom.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">II. Presentation Content 
    <div id="ii-presentation-content" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii-presentation-content" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Investment Philosophy and Market Analysis 
    <div id="investment-philosophy-and-market-analysis" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#investment-philosophy-and-market-analysis" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Market Fluctuations and Investment Mentality:</strong> The market is always fluctuating. Don&rsquo;t let short-term fluctuations affect your investment decisions. Stay optimistic.</li>
<li><strong>Currency Devaluation and Asset Appreciation:</strong> Money depreciates; only assets like stocks can preserve and increase in value. Currency devaluation is more severe in emerging countries, so it is advised to convert currency into assets. Taiwan&rsquo;s low wages and currency devaluation are related to the government&rsquo;s subsidy policies.</li>
<li><strong>Worker Mindset vs. Capitalist Mindset:</strong> Workers exchange labor for depreciating currency, while capitalists exchange currency for appreciating assets. Learn to invest and become a capitalist, exchanging &ldquo;trash&rdquo; (depreciating currency) for assets.</li>
<li><strong>Global Market Linkage:</strong> Global markets are highly interconnected, and diversifying investments into other regions has limited effectiveness. Focusing on the US stock market is recommended.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Asset Allocation Strategies 
    <div id="asset-allocation-strategies" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#asset-allocation-strategies" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Nasdaq 100 Index Funds:</strong> The preferred choice for young people. Long-term investment can yield substantial returns.  Global codes for purchasing Nasdaq 100 index funds were provided, and investing based on market conditions is recommended.</li>
<li><strong>The Importance of Cash:</strong> Cash reserves are crucial. 00864B and money market funds (like SWVXX, VOXX) are safeguards and should not be replaced with high-dividend products like SPHD, as principal safety is paramount.</li>
<li><strong>Smart Rebalancing:</strong> Suitable for those who use leveraged funds, are not retired, and have income.</li>
<li><strong>Risks of Real Estate Investment:</strong> Housing prices in the Bay Area are high, putting great pressure on young people to buy houses, which can easily lead to financial difficulties. Renting is recommended to maintain flexibility.</li>
<li><strong>Borrowing and Investment:</strong> Loans, mortgages, and car loans should be repaid with stable cash flow, not relying on stock market returns.</li>
<li><strong>Retirement Planning:</strong> Retirees should be cautious about borrowing and make plans based on the size of their retirement funds.  If retirement funds are 50 times the annual expenses, two options are available: 1. Keep the mortgage and car loan, using 2% of the retirement fund annually to cover all expenses; 2. Pay off the mortgage and car loan, invest 80% of the remaining funds in 00662, 20% in 00864B, and use 2% of the total funds annually for living expenses.</li>
<li><strong>Asset Allocation Case Study:</strong> A case study with 45 million Taiwan dollars illustrated asset allocation strategies when withdrawals are not needed. An 80/20 allocation or a combination of leveraged funds (60% 00662, 20% 00670L, 20% 00864B) is recommended.  For those with stable income and no need to withdraw from investments, 100% investment in QQQ can be considered.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Other Matters 
    <div id="other-matters" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#other-matters" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Class Suspension Notice:</strong> Class is suspended on November 9th and resumes on November 16th. After daylight saving time ends, the class time will be changed to 6:00 AM Pacific Time and 10:00 PM Taiwan time.</li>
<li><strong>Stay Optimistic:</strong> Maintain an optimistic mindset; the market will reward you. Like, subscribe, and leave comments on various platforms to benefit more people.</li>
<li><strong>Contact Information:</strong> Two email addresses were provided for contact.</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">III. Q&amp;A Session 
    <div id="iii-qa-session" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii-qa-session" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Brian: 
    <div id="brian" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#brian" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing 1: Read &ldquo;Investing is Asset Allocation, What You Don&rsquo;t Know,&rdquo; agreeing with the importance of accumulating the first pot of gold early; learning investment allows for more focus on work and personal improvement, spending time each day learning new skills and increasing self-worth.  Investment enables people to be more motivated to improve their professional skills rather than &ldquo;lying flat.&rdquo;</li>
<li>Sharing 2: Individuals can improve their earning potential through learning, even if their investment assets are reduced to zero, they can still rely on professional skills to make a comeback.</li>
<li>Question 1: What should I do if the Beta value is very low when the asset value plummets in the Excel sheet?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: The sheet is designed for acceleration during market rises and deceleration during falls. A low Beta value is normal and a reflection of risk control; no adjustment is needed.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2: Even knowing that investment should be mindless, I still worry when the Beta value drops. How should I cope?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: Deceleration during declines is the purpose of the investment strategy. Don&rsquo;t worry, stick to the plan, just like autopilot.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">LU: 
    <div id="lu" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#lu" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question 1: What is the impact of Trump&rsquo;s potential return to office on Bitcoin?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: The US has abandoned the gold standard and will not adopt a Bitcoin standard. Bitcoin is similar to gold and has an anti-inflationary function, but its future development is limited.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2: Can QQQ break through its previous high?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: It definitely can. The current market is bullish; there&rsquo;s no need to worry.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Wendy: 
    <div id="wendy" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#wendy" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing 1: Learned James&rsquo;s investment philosophy and successfully recouped the income lost during unemployment. Started reading recommended books such as &ldquo;The Richest Man in Babylon&rdquo; and &ldquo;The Most Important Thing.&rdquo;</li>
<li>No Questions</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Peter: 
    <div id="peter" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#peter" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing 1: Agrees with James&rsquo;s philosophy and has increased the investment proportion of QQQ, but some individual stocks have not been completely sold due to tax reasons.</li>
<li>Question 1: Advantages and disadvantages of converting 401K to Roth 401K?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: Just put new contributions into Roth 401K; don&rsquo;t convert existing funds. Convert at retirement.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2:  How to use HSA and 529 accounts?  Is there any problem with using a credit card to pay medical bills from an HSA?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply:  HSA, 529, and college fund accounts are not recommended because they lead to a loss of control over the funds. Using your own funds or loans is recommended.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 3: Are there any suggestions for increasing income and saving money besides a full-time job?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: Excessive saving is not recommended. Plan for retirement funds first, and the remaining money can be freely used and enjoyed.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Yi Jie (First Sister): 
    <div id="yi-jie-first-sister" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#yi-jie-first-sister" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing 1: Previously followed the advice of online influencers and invested in US stocks and treasury bonds, currently converting to QQQ.  Has a modest salary and one child.</li>
<li>Question 1: Can the 20% cash in the 80/20 allocation be replaced with Fubon 50 2X leverage?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply:  QQQ 2X leverage (00670L) is recommended. He explained the use of leveraged funds.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2: Is it feasible to regularly invest equal amounts in QQQ and 2X leverage?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: Feasible, but pay attention to cash reserves. A Beta of 1.1 or 1.2 allocation is recommended, adjusting according to market conditions.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 3: Can a child&rsquo;s Lunar New Year money be all-in on 2X leverage?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: If you can guarantee continuous regular investment for more than 30 years, it&rsquo;s worth considering, but be aware of the risks and be able to withstand significant asset shrinkage.  In the long run, the returns can be substantial, but psychological barriers must be overcome.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 4: Are the views of online influencers recommending treasury bonds correct? Are treasury bonds more valuable during a market crash?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: Incorrect. During market downturns, bond declines can be even greater.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">IAM: 
    <div id="iam" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iam" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing 1: Reflecting on the value of money, learning gratitude, and paying attention to community articles, realizing that spending money is spending one&rsquo;s life energy.</li>
<li>Sharing 2: Made 100 pages of notes and calculated the return on an 80,000 loan invested for 40 years; the result was shocking.</li>
<li>Question 1: Why are people not accustomed to borrowing for investment?  Confused about the phenomenon of young people being afraid to borrow for investment but willing to use installment plans for consumption.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: This is due to cultural influences.  Change your mindset and recognize that good debt can help accumulate wealth. Shared personal experiences and spending philosophy, emphasizing the freedom of spending after becoming wealthy.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">YJ Yuanlin: 
    <div id="yj-yuanlin" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#yj-yuanlin" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing 1: Investing boosts confidence, enabling focus on work and hobbies.</li>
<li>Question 1: In a down year, can TQQ replace QLD in smart rebalancing?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: Both are possible, but pay attention to risk control and avoid excessive pursuit of high risk. TQQ has greater volatility and requires a stronger psychological capacity.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">T: 
    <div id="t" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#t" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question 1: What are your thoughts on Elon Musk supporting Trump?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: Politicians&rsquo; decisions are the result of weighing pros and cons. Elon Musk&rsquo;s support for Trump stems from personal interests and positions, such as opposing certain liberal policies.  Entrepreneurs also have to choose between different political forces.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Yi Ni: 
    <div id="yi-ni" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#yi-ni" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question 1: How to invest and use Canadian education fund accounts?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: It&rsquo;s recommended to thoroughly research the specific rules of the account and consider methods like pledged loans to avoid locking up funds. Inquired about whether it&rsquo;s possible to withdraw all funds and the limitations, suggesting consulting with professionals.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Meng: 
    <div id="meng" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#meng" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing 1: In the high-tech era, privacy and freedom are difficult to have both.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Peter: 
    <div id="peter-1" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#peter-1" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing 1: It can be difficult for beginners to invest in QQQ, etc. It&rsquo;s suggested to start by buying one share and gradually build confidence.  James&rsquo;s explanations are very patient and benefit everyone.</li>
<li>Question 1: How to strengthen mental and psychological well-being?  James&rsquo;s experience sharing on meditation and hypnosis.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: Recommended Rachel&rsquo;s hypnosis channel and shared personal methods of using hypnosis and positive psychological suggestions. Suggested listening to hypnotic audios every night before sleep.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">IV. Key Takeaways 
    <div id="iv-key-takeaways" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv-key-takeaways" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>Rise faster, fall slower.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This is one of James&rsquo;s core investment philosophies. Through smart rebalancing strategies, increase investment during market rises to accelerate profits, and reduce investment during market downturns to mitigate losses.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Money is the least valuable thing when it has no value.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This reflects James&rsquo;s unique view on wealth. When wealth accumulates to a certain extent, the value of money itself is no longer important; what matters more is pursuing freedom and happiness.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>If you want freedom, and you want privacy, you will not have freedom. In the future world, if you want privacy, you will not have freedom.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This shows James&rsquo;s insight into future social trends. In the high-tech era, one needs to make trade-offs between privacy and freedom.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The more daring one is to borrow money, the broader their perspective.
&ndash; YJ Yuanlin</p>
</blockquote>
<p>YJ Yuanlin&rsquo;s sharing led to James&rsquo;s views on borrowing: good debt can help wealth growth.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>If you want freedom, you cannot care.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Echoing the topic of Elon Musk supporting Trump and the entrepreneurial spirit, true freedom is not caring about external opinions and focusing on one&rsquo;s goals.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>If you don&rsquo;t use ChatGPT now, you are outdated and will be eliminated.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>James advocates for new technologies and maintains an open attitude towards learning new things.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">V. Summary 
    <div id="v-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#v-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This session covered various aspects of investment philosophy, asset allocation, lifestyle, and how to cope with market fluctuations.  James answered the audience&rsquo;s questions with easy-to-understand language and rich examples, sharing his life experiences and insights, and encouraging everyone to stay optimistic, continue learning, and pursue true freedom and happiness.</p>

  



<div
  
    class="flex px-4 py-3 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900"
  >

  <span
    
      class="text-primary-400 ltr:pr-3 rtl:pl-3 flex items-center"
    >

    

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M506.3 417l-213.3-364c-16.33-28-57.54-28-73.98 0l-213.2 364C-10.59 444.9 9.849 480 42.74 480h426.6C502.1 480 522.6 445 506.3 417zM232 168c0-13.25 10.75-24 24-24S280 154.8 280 168v128c0 13.25-10.75 24-23.1 24S232 309.3 232 296V168zM256 416c-17.36 0-31.44-14.08-31.44-31.44c0-17.36 14.07-31.44 31.44-31.44s31.44 14.08 31.44 31.44C287.4 401.9 273.4 416 256 416z"/></svg>

  </span>


  </span>

  <span
    
      class="dark:text-neutral-300"
    ><strong>Disclaimer:</strong> This article is for personal learning notes only and does not constitute any investment advice.</span>
</div>

]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>00489 US Dollar Hegemony and the Sorrow of Trade Surplus Countries; Investing in QQQ Outperforms SPY</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1730069768515/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1730069768515/</guid><description>In this session, James begins by analyzing the current investment market, pointing out that it&amp;#39;s poised to hit new highs. He advises listeners to solidify their investment confidence and enter the market sooner rather than later. James then delves into a research paper discussing asset portfolios comprising leveraged funds, cash, QQQ, and SPY. He analyzes the risks and returns associated with various investment portfolios, emphasizing the critical role of cash allocation. He addresses questions from participants regarding asset allocation, stock pledges, retirement planning, investment strategies, and the US dollar&amp;#39;s global dominance. He also shares his personal views on marriage and having children.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<lite-youtube videoid="eOh-hu1X0jo" playlabel="eOh-hu1X0jo" params=""></lite-youtube>



<h2 class="relative group">I. Topic of the Day 
    <div id="i-topic-of-the-day" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-topic-of-the-day" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>The session focuses on the impending new highs anticipated in the investment market. James encourages everyone to bolster their investment confidence and enter the market early. He elaborates on various asset allocation strategies, particularly the use of leveraged funds and the significance of cash reserves. Additionally, James dives into the nature of US dollar hegemony and its implications for the global economy. He also shares his thoughts on marriage and childbearing.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">II. Briefing Content 
    <div id="ii-briefing-content" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii-briefing-content" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<ol>
<li>
<p><strong>The Market is About to Hit New Highs:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>The market is on the verge of reaching new highs. Entering early is more advantageous than waiting for the new highs to materialize.</li>
<li>Earnings reports from AI and high-tech sectors are projected to surpass expectations. Market funds and corporate profits are also expected to exceed projections.</li>
<li>The market consistently trends upward. Investment requires patience; wealth is worth the wait.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Interpreting the Asset Portfolio Research Paper:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Long-term bonds carry higher risks than stocks while yielding lower returns. Investment in them is not recommended.</strong></li>
<li><strong>QQQ offers superior returns and risk resistance compared to SPY.</strong></li>
<li><strong>Leveraged funds (e.g., QQQ2D) are characterized by high volatility, substantial downside risk, but also significant upside potential.</strong></li>
<li><strong>Intelligent asset allocation can achieve returns equivalent to a 100% QQQ portfolio while providing greater cash security.</strong></li>
<li><strong>Retirees or individuals without income are advised against using leveraged funds. An 80/20 asset allocation strategy is recommended.</strong></li>
<li><strong>Cash is the cornerstone ensuring investors can continue investing.</strong></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Additional Investment Advice and Experience Sharing:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Retirees should claim their social security benefits as early as possible and utilize them for investments.</li>
<li>Real estate is a liability; selling property for investment purposes is recommended. Avoiding mortgage loans against real estate is advised.</li>
<li>Young individuals can leverage credit loans for investments, accelerating wealth accumulation.</li>
<li>Exercise prudence in investments. Avoid excessive diversification or venturing into unfamiliar domains such as real estate or REITs.</li>
<li><strong>Investing in individual stocks is not advised. Opt for market capitalization-based index funds like QQQ.</strong></li>
<li>Experiencing substantial losses is a prerequisite to appreciating the allure of high returns. The market always presents risks, and one must learn to navigate them.</li>
<li>Short-term safe assets (e.g., treasury bills) are essential components of an investment portfolio, aiding investors in weathering market fluctuations.</li>
<li><strong>The higher the proportion of cash or cash-equivalent assets, the greater the risk tolerance of the investment portfolio.</strong></li>
<li><strong>Refrain from self-managing stock portfolios. The returns from most stocks fall short of those from treasury bills.</strong></li>
<li><strong>Stock index funds constantly face future risks. Embrace risk tolerance; only by weathering the storms can one see the sunshine.</strong></li>
<li><strong>Don&rsquo;t put faith in market predictions. During market downturns, &ldquo;stock gurus&rdquo; often emerge, but their predictions are frequently inaccurate.</strong></li>
<li><strong>Adhere to long-term investment principles. Avoid being swayed by short-term market fluctuations.</strong></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Marriage and Childbearing:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Marriage serves the purpose of creating life to carry on the universe&rsquo;s legacy. Loving one&rsquo;s partner as one would love their own child is paramount to a successful marriage.</li>
<li>Childbearing lies at the heart of life&rsquo;s meaning. Young individuals should marry and have children early, unburdened by financial pressures.</li>
<li>Even without marriage, childbearing should be considered. A life spent single and childless will ultimately lead to profound loneliness.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ol>


<h2 class="relative group">III. Q&amp;A Session 
    <div id="iii-qa-session" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii-qa-session" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p><strong>Mike:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing:</strong>
<ul>
<li>Mentions the Chinese government&rsquo;s strong push for policies akin to MMT (Modern Monetary Theory).</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question 1:</strong> Taiwan Semiconductor Manufacturing Company (TSMC) is not included in the Nasdaq 100 index, and the NYSE has extended its trading hours to 22 hours, while Nasdaq hasn&rsquo;t followed suit. Why?
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response:</strong> Nasdaq&rsquo;s trading hours are already standard. Extending trading hours only affects after-hours trading, holding little significance for ordinary investors. TSMC&rsquo;s exclusion from the Nasdaq 100 index is linked to factors such as trading costs.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question 2:</strong> How can MMT be explained to someone without financial expertise?
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response:</strong> James uses simple language to elucidate the relationship between government deficits and currency issuance. He asserts that governments can cover deficits by printing money without facing national bankruptcy. Using early American history and ancient barter systems as examples, he illustrates how governments utilize currency issuance to purchase goods and services, and how taxation maintains currency value. James emphasizes the essence of US dollar hegemony, highlighting that the US leverages its control over vital resource trading, like oil, to sustain the dollar&rsquo;s global dominance, citing Russia&rsquo;s forced use of dollars for oil purchases as an example. He also points out that the core nature of fiat currency is a representation of national sovereignty, enabling governments to mandate its use through legal means.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>IAM:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing:</strong>
<ul>
<li>Questions whether investing in QQQ also implies supporting &ldquo;rogue&rdquo; entities.</li>
<li>After comparing returns from QQQ and its top ten constituent stocks, IAM observed higher returns from the latter, leading to confusion about the role of the remaining 90 companies.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question 1:</strong> Does investing in QQQ equate to supporting &ldquo;rogue&rdquo; entities?
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response:</strong> We, as investors, are contributors. Through our investment in QQQ, we allocate capital to the 100 companies making the most significant contributions to humanity, propelling societal progress.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question 2:</strong> The top ten constituent stocks of QQQ generate higher returns; what is the purpose of the other 90 companies?
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response:</strong> The composition of QQQ&rsquo;s top ten holdings changes annually. Examining solely the past decade&rsquo;s data is insufficient. Companies previously ranked lower have the potential to enter the top ten, underscoring the vital role played by the remaining 90 companies.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question 3:</strong> Are companies ranked lower in QQQ&rsquo;s constituents at risk of being removed due to a decrease in their market capitalization percentage?
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response:</strong> Typically not, but QQQ mandates that the percentage of any individual constituent stock cannot exceed a specific threshold. Adjustments are made if this limit is surpassed.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question 4:</strong> How can one view the complete list of QQQ&rsquo;s constituent companies?
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response:</strong> This information can be accessed on websites like Yahoo Finance, which displays QQQ&rsquo;s holdings, or on QQQ&rsquo;s official website.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Chunxia:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing:</strong>
<ul>
<li>Shares a friend&rsquo;s investment story. This friend works at Apple and previously held steadfast belief in real estate and cash investments. However, recent issues like property taxes have awakened them to the importance of QQQ. Concerns about Apple stock&rsquo;s risk have led them to hesitate about stock pledges.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question:</strong> This friend holds a large quantity of Apple stock. How can they convert it into QQQ, and how should they approach a stock pledge?
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response:</strong>
<ul>
<li>The maximum long-term capital gains tax is 20%, regardless of income. James recommends that this friend sell a portion of their Apple stock sooner rather than later, converting it into QQQ to mitigate individual stock risk and reduce future tax burdens.</li>
<li>A gradual sale of Apple stock is advised, such as selling 10% or 20% each year or only selling the appreciated portion to minimize tax liability.</li>
<li>A stock pledge can be utilized for tax payments, for instance, borrowing 20% for tax obligations while reinvesting the remaining funds to enhance investment efficiency.</li>
<li>James suggests experimenting with a stock pledge, such as borrowing 2% for personal use, to gain firsthand experience with the convenience of borrowing.</li>
<li>He emphasizes the critical role of cash. A higher proportion of cash or cash-equivalent assets translates to greater risk tolerance for the investment portfolio.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Jenny:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing:</strong>
<ul>
<li>Owns multiple properties but has refrained from selling due to tax deductions and rising rental income.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question 1:</strong> Should she sell her properties?
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response:</strong> Real estate investments lack the return and liquidity offered by QQQ and potentially face substantial inheritance taxes in the future. Selling the properties is advised. Property taxes, maintenance costs, insurance fees, and more erode the returns from real estate investments. Moreover, real estate is illiquid, requiring time for liquidation. Properties, as inheritance, subject heirs to hefty inheritance taxes, potentially creating an insurmountable financial burden.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question 2:</strong> How can she convert to a Roth IRA?
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response:</strong> A Backdoor Roth IRA conversion is an option, involving initially depositing funds into a Traditional IRA and subsequently converting them to a Roth IRA.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question 3:</strong> Can property tax deductions and rising rental income offset the costs associated with real estate investment?
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response:</strong> The deductible amount for property taxes is limited. Moreover, income from rent increases is subject to income tax and cannot fully offset the costs tied to real estate investment.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question 4:</strong> Concerns about mortgages and trusts.
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response:</strong> If a mortgage is obtained under an individual&rsquo;s name, even placing the property within a trust cannot circumvent inheritance taxes. Using an LLC (Limited Liability Company) for property purchase from the outset is recommended, or transferring the property into an irrevocable trust before death to avoid inheritance tax liabilities.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Professor Zhou:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing:</strong>
<ul>
<li>Shares personal and sibling investment experiences. His sister, after experiencing investment losses, is hesitant to redeem her insurance policy. Jenny, due to returns from real estate investment, is reluctant to sell her properties. This illustrates how investors often fall prey to sunk cost and opportunity cost fallacies.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question:</strong> How can we enlighten ourselves and those around us to avoid such investment pitfalls?
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response:</strong> Understanding the concepts of sunk cost and opportunity cost is essential. Losses from investments should be cut promptly, avoiding attachment to past investments. Seek superior investment opportunities. While Jenny&rsquo;s real estate investment generates cash flow, its return is low, and it may face high inheritance taxes in the future. Therefore, she should consider selling the property and investing in higher-yielding assets like QQQ.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Bart:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Question:</strong> Issues connecting to the room.
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response:</strong> Recommends force-quitting the app and re-entering the room before raising a hand.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Daisy253:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing:</strong>
<ul>
<li>New to financial management, past investments were haphazard, primarily focused on real estate and insurance.</li>
<li>45 years old, with an 18-year-old daughter and a 14-year-old son, can invest NT$80,000 monthly. NT$10,000 is allocated to children&rsquo;s savings, with the remaining NT$70,000 for personal investment, aiming for rapid asset accumulation to reach NT$10 million.</li>
<li>Owns a rental property generating NT$30,000-40,000 in net monthly income, with principal invested ranging from NT$2 to 3 million, and the property valued at NT$3 to 4 million.</li>
<li>Children lean towards a &ldquo;non-marriage&rdquo; ideology, expressing no desire for offspring.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question:</strong> How should assets be allocated, and how can children be guided towards sound financial management principles?
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response:</strong>
<ul>
<li>Suggests referencing the article James provided, titled &ldquo;Individuals Still Some Time Away from Retirement,&rdquo; and adopting a BETA 1.2 asset allocation strategy.</li>
<li>Advises against giving children excessive funds at present. Instead, encourage them to save independently once they have a stable income, guiding them to establish proper financial management habits.</li>
<li>Proposes incentivizing children to marry and have children by offering NT$1 million annually in the future.</li>
<li>Emphasizes that 00864B cannot be replaced by 0056. Cash is cash and should not be substituted with stocks.</li>
<li>Underscores the significance of marriage and childbearing, advising early marriage and parenthood, urging them not to be bound by financial anxieties.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Xie Weiya:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing:</strong>
<ul>
<li>Recounts the story of a friend working at Apple. This friend steadfastly believed in real estate and cash as investments but recently recognized the importance of QQQ due to concerns like property taxes. However, they remain apprehensive about the risks associated with Apple stock and hesitate to engage in stock pledges.</li>
<li>This friend maintains a high spending level but undoubtedly possesses the financial capacity for retirement. They simply derive great enjoyment from work.</li>
<li>The friend has already contacted Lisa and is preparing for a stock pledge.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question:</strong>  This friend holds a substantial amount of Apple stock. How can they convert it into QQQ, and how should they approach a stock pledge?
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response:</strong>
<ul>
<li>The maximum long-term capital gains tax is 20%, independent of income. James recommends selling a portion of their Apple stock as soon as possible, converting it to QQQ to mitigate individual stock risk and reduce future tax burdens.</li>
<li>A gradual sale of Apple stock is advised, such as 10% or 20% each year, or selling only the appreciated portion to minimize tax liability.</li>
<li>Utilizing a stock pledge for tax payments is suggested, such as borrowing 20% for tax obligations while reinvesting the remaining funds to enhance investment efficiency.</li>
<li>James encourages them to experiment with a stock pledge, perhaps borrowing 2% for personal use, to experience the convenience of borrowing firsthand.</li>
<li>He highlights the vital role of cash. A higher proportion of cash or cash-equivalent assets translates to greater risk tolerance for the investment portfolio.</li>
<li>James advises this friend to learn from investment approaches employed by individuals like Warren Buffett and Wei Ying-ch’ung, leveraging credit for investment purposes.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Sunny:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Question:</strong> How should labor pension funds be withdrawn?
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response:</strong> If proficient in investment, withdrawing the entire labor pension fund at once and investing it in high-yielding assets like QQQ is recommended.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Wu Liyun:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Question:</strong> Is NT$5 million in stocks and cash sufficient for retirement?
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response:</strong>  NT$5 million in assets is insufficient to support a comfortable retirement. Withdrawing a labor pension monthly to supplement retirement income is recommended.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Nana:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Question:</strong> Concerns regarding genetic screening.
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response:</strong> Genetic screening is recommended to identify any potential genetic defects.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>College Student:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Question:</strong> Concerns about Backdoor Roth IRA.
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response:</strong> College students, lacking income, do not require a Backdoor Roth IRA. Directly depositing funds into a Roth IRA is suitable.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Jessie:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing:</strong> Has 1099 income.</li>
<li><strong>Question:</strong> Can 1099 income be deposited into a Traditional IRA?
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response:</strong>  Yes, 1099 income is eligible for deposit into a Traditional IRA. Additionally, a Backdoor Roth IRA can be executed using a spouse&rsquo;s W2 income.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">IV. Key Takeaways 
    <div id="iv-key-takeaways" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv-key-takeaways" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p><strong>Young individuals should be bold in using borrowed funds for investment to accelerate wealth accumulation.</strong>
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Young people are in their prime earning years, with steadily increasing income. They can utilize tools like credit loans to access low-cost capital for investing in high-return assets like QQQ, thereby speeding up their wealth-building journey.</p>
<blockquote>
<p><strong>Cash is the cornerstone ensuring investors can continue investing.</strong>
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Market volatility is a constant. Maintaining sufficient cash or cash-equivalent assets helps investors navigate market fluctuations with ease, preventing panic-driven asset sales, ultimately achieving long-term investment objectives.</p>
<blockquote>
<p><strong>Exercise prudence in investments. Avoid excessive diversification or venturing into unfamiliar domains.</strong>
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Focus investments within familiar areas. Refrain from blindly pursuing diversification or investing in unfamiliar domains, such as real estate or REITs.</p>
<blockquote>
<p><strong>The essence of US dollar hegemony lies in the US leveraging its control over vital resource trading, like oil, to sustain the dollar&rsquo;s global dominance.</strong>
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>By mandating US dollar settlements for global oil transactions, the US compels other nations to hold dollar reserves, solidifying its global currency dominance.</p>
<blockquote>
<p><strong>Marriage serves the purpose of creating life to carry on the universe&rsquo;s legacy. Loving one&rsquo;s partner as one would love their own child is paramount to a successful marriage.</strong>
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>The significance of marriage lies in procreation and the continuation of life. Loving one&rsquo;s partner deeply, treating them as one would treat their own child, is crucial for a lasting and fulfilling marriage.</p>
<blockquote>
<p><strong>Childbearing lies at the heart of life&rsquo;s meaning. Young individuals should marry and have children early, unburdened by financial pressures.</strong>
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Childbearing is inherent to human nature and the perpetuation of life. Young people should courageously embrace the responsibility of parenthood, refusing to be deterred by financial concerns.</p>
<blockquote>
<p><strong>Investors often fall prey to sunk cost and opportunity cost fallacies.</strong>
&ndash; Professor Zhou</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Sunk costs refer to incurred expenses that are irretrievable, such as purchased stocks or real estate. Opportunity cost represents the potential gains foregone by choosing one investment over other available options. During decision-making, investors should not be swayed by sunk costs; instead, they should prioritize opportunity cost, selecting investments offering higher returns.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">V. Conclusion 
    <div id="v-conclusion" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#v-conclusion" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This session revolves around the anticipated new highs in the investment market. James encourages listeners to solidify their investment confidence and enter the market promptly. He meticulously explains various asset allocation strategies, emphasizing the use of leveraged funds and the paramount importance of cash reserves. He also delves into the nature of US dollar hegemony and its global economic implications, sharing his personal views on marriage and childbearing. The Q&amp;A segment addresses questions encompassing asset allocation, stock pledges, retirement planning, investment strategies, and more, making it a content-rich and insightful session.</p>

  



<div
  
    class="flex px-4 py-3 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900"
  >

  <span
    
      class="text-primary-400 ltr:pr-3 rtl:pl-3 flex items-center"
    >

    

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M506.3 417l-213.3-364c-16.33-28-57.54-28-73.98 0l-213.2 364C-10.59 444.9 9.849 480 42.74 480h426.6C502.1 480 522.6 445 506.3 417zM232 168c0-13.25 10.75-24 24-24S280 154.8 280 168v128c0 13.25-10.75 24-23.1 24S232 309.3 232 296V168zM256 416c-17.36 0-31.44-14.08-31.44-31.44c0-17.36 14.07-31.44 31.44-31.44s31.44 14.08 31.44 31.44C287.4 401.9 273.4 416 256 416z"/></svg>

  </span>


  </span>

  <span
    
      class="dark:text-neutral-300"
    ><strong>Disclaimer:</strong> This article is for personal learning purposes only and does not constitute any investment advice.</span>
</div>

]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>00488 AI Demand and Market Future：Insights from TSMC and Investment Trends; Ever-Growing Assets and Smart Spending without Repaying Principal</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1729384159255/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1729384159255/</guid><description>This session focuses on strategies for long-term investment in Nasdaq 100 index funds amidst market volatility and changing international landscapes. It also covers leveraging investments, smart spending habits, and navigating the job market in the age of AI. Additionally, the discussion touches upon comparing different types of economic crises, estate planning, the synergy between real estate and stock investments, the feasibility of long-term investing in Taiwanese and US stock markets, and government policies regarding economic stimulus and social welfare. Specific advice for Chinese investors accessing US markets and related tax implications are also addressed.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<lite-youtube videoid="y6smxG48k4M" playlabel="y6smxG48k4M" params=""></lite-youtube>



<h2 class="relative group">I. Main Topic 
    <div id="i-main-topic" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-main-topic" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>Trust in the power of technology and maintain a long-term investment strategy focused on Nasdaq 100 index funds, learning how to utilize stock pledging and spend wisely, especially during market fluctuations and shifts in the international situation.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">II. Presentation Content 
    <div id="ii-presentation-content" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii-presentation-content" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<ol>
<li><strong>Market Trends and Investment Philosophy:</strong>
<ul>
<li><strong>AI Drives the Future:</strong> AI demand is not a bubble, but a genuine driving force behind technological advancement, promising a bull market spanning two decades.  We are currently in the early stages of this growth.  Morris Chang (TSMC Chairman)&rsquo;s perspective and TSMC&rsquo;s investments in AI corroborate this judgment. The long bull market has begun, seize the opportunity to join the wealth train.</li>
<li><strong>Market Volatility and Long-Term Investment:</strong> Market fluctuations are inherent to investing.  Downswings are followed by even greater upswings. Using historical data from the Taiwan Weighted Index, Nikkei Index, and the US stock market as examples, the session illustrates the long-term market development pattern: an initial period of rapid growth followed by a period of stagnation (e.g., 32 years in Taiwan, 35 years in Japan, 24 years in the US), before entering a phase of stable growth.  Therefore, overcoming panic caused by market volatility and adhering to a long-term investment strategy is crucial for ultimate success.</li>
<li><strong>Capitalism and Investment:</strong>  The side effects of capitalism are wealth disparity and the exploitation of labor. Learn to operate like a capitalist and profit from investment.  Hard work and saving money to buy government bonds will ultimately result in wealth erosion due to inflation.</li>
<li><strong>Benefits of Quantitative Easing:</strong> Quantitative easing is beneficial for investors, fostering a low-interest-rate environment and driving asset price appreciation.  Those who fail to understand quantitative easing and complain about government money printing are often victims of capitalism, missing out on the benefits of asset appreciation.</li>
<li><strong>Characteristics of a Mature Market:</strong> Mature markets are characterized by fair, just, and transparent regulatory mechanisms, companies focused on their core businesses, and a high proportion of long-term investors and institutional holdings. The Taiwanese market is gradually maturing.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Investment Strategies and Recommendations:</strong>
<ul>
<li><strong>Invest in Nasdaq 100:</strong>  The session recommends investing in Nasdaq 100 index funds (QQQ), with the option to allocate to S&amp;P 500 or high-dividend ETFs based on individual circumstances.  References to Nasdaq 100 index funds globally are provided for the convenience of investors worldwide.</li>
<li><strong>Avoid Penny Stocks:</strong>  Refrain from investing in penny stocks, as they generally offer low long-term returns.  Real investment opportunities lie in companies that demonstrate sustained growth and lead technological advancements.</li>
<li><strong>Advantages of Stock Pledging:</strong> Stock pledging offers advantages over real estate mortgages, as stocks, unlike real estate, do not depreciate and can be held long-term, potentially allowing for &ldquo;borrowing without repayment or interest&rdquo; (specific instructions are available in related videos).</li>
<li><strong>Avoid Flawed Rebalancing Strategies:</strong> Avoid a 50% principal + 50% leveraged ETF rebalancing strategy, as it carries high risk and can easily deplete cash reserves during market downturns.</li>
<li><strong>Estate Planning and Stock Pledging:</strong> When engaging in stock pledging, it is advisable to diversify assets across multiple brokerage firms, pledging a portion and keeping the rest as cash to facilitate estate handling for inheritors.  Cat supplemented this with a detailed explanation of the stock pledging inheritance process, emphasizing the importance of advance planning.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Other Important Matters:</strong>
<ul>
<li><strong>Risk Warning and Disclaimer:</strong>  The content is for informational purposes only and does not constitute investment advice.  Do not remit funds to unknown accounts.</li>
<li><strong>Program Format Adjustment:</strong>  The presentation content will be expanded to include material previously covered in short videos.</li>
<li><strong>QQQ Stock Selection Mechanism:</strong>  Addresses audience questions regarding the QQQ stock selection mechanism, explaining the advantages of the Nasdaq exchange and why technology companies prefer listing on Nasdaq.</li>
<li><strong>Stock Pledging for Non-US Residents:</strong> Explains the regulations for non-US residents engaging in stock pledging with US brokers.</li>
<li><strong>Learning to Spend:</strong> Shares the philosophy of spending after achieving investment success, emphasizing the importance of focusing on future wealth growth and utilizing financial leverage for consumption.  Don&rsquo;t let wealth sit idle; learn how to use it.  This point is illustrated with the example of a listener who has $4 million but doesn&rsquo;t know how to spend it, calculating their potential wealth growth over 40 years and a reasonable spending level.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ol>


<h2 class="relative group">III. Q&amp;A Session 
    <div id="iii-qa-session" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii-qa-session" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p><strong>IAM:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Shared:</strong>  Expressed confusion about different types of economic crises and how the 2020-2023 pandemic period compares to previous bubbles after reading a book about economic crises.</li>
<li><strong>Question 1:</strong>  Which historical economic crisis is most similar to the economic downturn during the 2020-2023 pandemic?</li>
<li><strong>Answer:</strong> The 2020-2023 pandemic was an economic shock caused by an external event, distinct from previous bubble economies. The 2000 dot-com bubble was an industry bubble with limited impact; the 2008 financial crisis resembled the 1929 Great Depression, both being asset bubble bursts, but the 2008 crisis recovered faster due to quantitative easing. The 2022 market decline was not a bubble burst, but a revaluation caused by central bank interest rate hikes.</li>
<li><strong>Question 2:</strong> What did the US do to stimulate the economy that other countries couldn&rsquo;t replicate?</li>
<li><strong>Answer:</strong> The US is less constrained by fiscal discipline and is willing to borrow and issue debt, allocating funds to social welfare programs for the elderly, children, and healthcare, while guiding domestic capital towards overseas investment to mitigate inflation.  Taiwan&rsquo;s government was advised to learn from the US&rsquo;s fiscal spending approach and guide capital towards investment, while also focusing on efficient capital utilization and building a social safety net.</li>
<li><strong>Question 3:</strong> Why are Chinese people so keen on buying houses?</li>
<li><strong>Answer:</strong> This is a vestige of the agrarian &ldquo;land is wealth&rdquo; mentality, which is no longer applicable today.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Eason (Doctor):</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Shared:</strong>  Points to consider for Chinese investors buying Nasdaq ETFs:
<ul>
<li>Different brokerage firms have different fee policies and financing rates; careful comparison is necessary.</li>
<li>Domestic Nasdaq ETFs have premiums; buying during periods of low or negative premiums is recommended.  There are no limits for buying ETFs on the exchange, but there are limits for off-exchange subscriptions.</li>
<li>Recommends allocating a portion of assets to USD-denominated investments like QQQ, which can be purchased by opening brokerage accounts in Singapore or Hong Kong.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Added:</strong>  Chinese residents have a $50,000 annual foreign exchange quota for overseas investments.  Hong Kong and mainland China identities have different withholding tax rates on US stock investments.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Dave:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Question 1:</strong> Will the Nasdaq 100 index become stagnant like the Dow Jones index?</li>
<li><strong>Answer:</strong> Currently, the Nasdaq 100 is the most competitive; excessive worry about the future is unnecessary.</li>
<li><strong>Question 2:</strong> Is it feasible to only buy the top 10 companies in the Nasdaq 100 index?</li>
<li><strong>Answer:</strong> The top ten companies change frequently; individual stock selection and portfolio adjustments are too cumbersome, and returns may not be higher.  Investing directly in index funds is more efficient.</li>
<li><strong>Question 3:</strong> How do VGT and XLK compare to QQQ?</li>
<li><strong>Answer:</strong> VGT and XLK track different indices than QQQ, with different constituent stocks and concentration. QQQ is more robust and has broader coverage.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Jiawen:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Question:</strong> Can an 80% leveraged ETF + 10% cash + 10% bond portfolio be directly pledged? How is this done?</li>
<li><strong>Answer:</strong> Yes, but a small-scale trial is recommended, for instance, borrowing $200,000 against $5 million in principal, or borrowing within $1 million against $10 million. Long-term borrowing strategies should be adjusted according to circumstances. It&rsquo;s possible to pledge only a portion of the stocks, leaving the remainder for additional purchases or other uses.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Peter:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Shared:</strong>  Personal investment journey, transitioning from real estate to stocks, learning about stock pledging and asset allocation.</li>
<li><strong>Question:</strong> Is there synergy between real estate and stock investment? How can real estate cash flow be used for stock investment?</li>
<li><strong>Answer:</strong>  Buying a house is not recommended for young people. Real estate investment returns are lower than stocks and come with various risks (e.g., natural disasters, property taxes).  Even with positive cash flow, opportunity costs should be considered; investing that capital in stocks might yield higher returns.  Used Texas real estate as an example to illustrate the drawbacks of real estate investment.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Qiu Xiao:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Question 1:</strong>  What are the Canadian equivalents of US retirement accounts like IRA, Roth IRA, and 401k? Which account should cash be held in?</li>
<li><strong>Answer:</strong> Roth IRA corresponds to Canada&rsquo;s TFSA, Traditional IRA to RRSP, and 401k to DCPP. The choice of retirement account for cash depends on the individual&rsquo;s balance between taxable and tax-free accounts and their asset allocation strategy.  One should choose to place cash in either a tax-free or taxable account based on their specific circumstances for tax optimization.</li>
<li><strong>Question 2 (Related to Eason&rsquo;s question):</strong> How can one invest in Nasdaq ETFs in China, and how can quota limitations be addressed?</li>
<li><strong>Answer:</strong> Off-exchange subscriptions have quota limits, while on-exchange ETF purchases do not, but premiums should be considered.  Opening multiple brokerage accounts or opening an account in Hong Kong for US stock investment can be considered.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Haoqing:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Shared:</strong>  Used the example of SpaceX launching rockets with a small team to highlight concerns about AI replacing human labor and the difficulties young people face in finding employment.</li>
<li><strong>Question:</strong> How can we address the challenge of youth unemployment in the AI era?</li>
<li><strong>Answer:</strong>  Young people need to acquire AI skills to adapt to the future job market.  Recommends that schools incorporate AI courses into their core curriculum, cultivating AI talent from a young age. Philosophy is an important foundational subject but should not be a primary career focus.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Jimmy:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Shared:</strong>  Discussed the changing times and the need for young people to adapt, sharing observations about the youthful demographics of Xiamen. Mentioned the importance of aligning investments with the times and shared some common misunderstandings about investing he had encountered.</li>
<li><strong>Question:</strong> What are your views on index fund investing? Is the long-term return of 0050 sufficient? What are your thoughts on individual stock investing (e.g., TSMC)?</li>
<li><strong>Answer:</strong> Index fund investing is a method accessible to the general public, but many don&rsquo;t understand it and require time and experience to appreciate it. In the long run, QQQ and SPY offer higher returns and are more suitable for long-term investment. Individual stock picking demands specialized knowledge and skills and carries higher risks; it is difficult for average investors to select and hold high-quality stocks like TSMC for the long term.  The key to investing is finding investment targets that can be held long-term and sticking with them.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Other Q&amp;A:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>TQQQ Pledging:</strong>  Learn about stock pledging and how to achieve interest-free borrowing through the recommended videos.</li>
<li><strong>Top 10 QQQ Holdings:</strong>  Frequent trading is discouraged; holding the index fund long-term is sufficient.</li>
<li><strong>BOX vs. SWVXX:</strong>  BOX is recommended for brokerage accounts to avoid dividend taxes.</li>
<li><strong>Conservative Investing:</strong>  Conservative investing can involve holding cash or holding index funds long-term.</li>
<li><strong>How to Spend Money:</strong>  Focus on future wealth growth and utilize financial leverage for consumption.</li>
<li><strong>Investing in US Stocks from within China:</strong>  Coming to the US to invest or remitting funds to the US for investment is recommended.  Consider opening an account in Hong Kong or using other compliant channels for investment.</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">IV. Key Takeaways 
    <div id="iv-key-takeaways" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv-key-takeaways" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>AI demand is not a bubble; technological advancements will drive a bull market lasting 20 years.  We are just at the beginning.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>James emphasizes his belief that AI is a long-term trend and encourages investors to recognize the current market as the starting point of a significant bull run.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>High returns are meaningless if the probability of success is low.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>James reiterates that a successful investment strategy prioritizes long-term holding and consistency over chasing high returns with low success rates.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Young people need to learn AI skills to adapt to the future job market. AI courses should be core curriculum in all departments.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>James stresses the importance of acquiring AI skills for future employment and advocates for integrating AI education into all academic disciplines.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Earning money is easy; spending it wisely is difficult.  Don&rsquo;t let your wealth sit idle; learn how to use it.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>James offers a unique perspective on wealth management, urging listeners to become skilled spenders and maximize their wealth&rsquo;s potential.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Governments should invest in the elderly and children, building a strong social safety net.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>James underscores the importance of social welfare, suggesting that nations prioritize investing in the well-being of their youngest and oldest citizens.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">V. Summary 
    <div id="v-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#v-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This session centers on long-term investment in the Nasdaq 100 index fund, covering market trends, investment strategies, the use of financial leverage, and personal development in the AI era.  James not only shares professional investment concepts and techniques but also encourages listeners to shift their mindsets, embrace the opportunities presented by technological advancements, and learn how to better manage and utilize their wealth. He also emphasizes the government&rsquo;s responsibility in social welfare development, advocating for a more robust social safety net to protect the well-being of the elderly and children.  Furthermore, the session addresses the needs of Chinese investors by answering questions about accessing US markets from China and related tax implications.</p>

  



<div
  
    class="flex px-4 py-3 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900"
  >

  <span
    
      class="text-primary-400 ltr:pr-3 rtl:pl-3 flex items-center"
    >

    

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M506.3 417l-213.3-364c-16.33-28-57.54-28-73.98 0l-213.2 364C-10.59 444.9 9.849 480 42.74 480h426.6C502.1 480 522.6 445 506.3 417zM232 168c0-13.25 10.75-24 24-24S280 154.8 280 168v128c0 13.25-10.75 24-23.1 24S232 309.3 232 296V168zM256 416c-17.36 0-31.44-14.08-31.44-31.44c0-17.36 14.07-31.44 31.44-31.44s31.44 14.08 31.44 31.44C287.4 401.9 273.4 416 256 416z"/></svg>

  </span>


  </span>

  <span
    
      class="dark:text-neutral-300"
    ><strong>Disclaimer:</strong> This article is for personal learning notes only and does not constitute any investment advice.</span>
</div>

]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>The Most Important Thing：Book Notes</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1729341470274/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1729341470274/</guid><description>This book, by renowned investor Howard Marks, summarizes his investment experience, explaining his investment philosophy and analyzing key factors such as market environment, investor psychology, and risk control, aiming to help investors achieve above-market investment performance.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[

<h2 class="relative group">I. Summary 
    <div id="i-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>The core idea of this book is how to achieve investment returns that surpass the market average. The author argues that achieving this goal requires &ldquo;second-level thinking,&rdquo; which is deeper and more comprehensive than the thinking of ordinary investors. He emphasizes contrarian investing, being greedy when others are fearful, and fearful when others are greedy. The book elaborates on important concepts such as market efficiency, value assessment, risk identification and control, cyclical and pendulum awareness, investor psychology, and diversified investment. It also provides a wealth of practical experience and case studies, aiming to help investors establish a sound thinking framework and control the impact of emotions on investment decisions.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">II. Chapter Summaries 
    <div id="ii-chapter-summaries" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii-chapter-summaries" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<ol>
<li>
<p><strong>Second-Level Thinking:</strong> To outperform the market, one must engage in second-level thinking, which requires investors to think more deeply and comprehensively, not being satisfied with simple conclusions, but considering various possibilities, probabilities, market consensus, and their own cognitive biases. For example, first-level thinking might conclude, &ldquo;This is a good company, so I should buy it,&rdquo; while second-level thinking would consider, &ldquo;While it&rsquo;s a good company, has the market already overreacted, pushing the price too high?&rdquo;</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Understanding Market Efficiency and Its Limitations:</strong> Markets are not perfectly efficient; there are opportunities for mispricing. However, due to the large number of investors competing, beating the market remains very difficult. Markets are efficient at incorporating information, but they don&rsquo;t always interpret that information correctly. Investors should focus on relatively inefficient markets, such as those that are less followed, have opaque information, or are controversial.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Value Assessment:</strong> The foundation of value investing is accurate estimation of intrinsic value, which requires considering factors such as a company&rsquo;s financial position, management capabilities, profitability, competitive advantages, and future growth prospects. The author emphasizes that value investing focuses more on present value, while growth investing emphasizes future value, but both require considering the future.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>The Relationship Between Price and Value:</strong> Successful investing is not about &ldquo;buying good things,&rdquo; but about &ldquo;buying things well,&rdquo; which means buying at a price below intrinsic value. Price is influenced by value, psychology, and technical factors. Investors need to understand the relationship between these three to make sound investment decisions. Buying a good company at a high price can still lead to losses, while buying a lower-quality asset at a low price can yield high returns.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Understanding Risk:</strong> Risk is not volatility, but the possibility of permanent loss of capital. It&rsquo;s crucial to understand the various forms of risk, such as failing to meet objectives, underperformance, career risk, and liquidity risk. Risk is subjective and difficult to quantify, depending on the investor&rsquo;s specific circumstances and goals.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Recognizing Risk:</strong> Risk often increases when market optimism is high and prices are inflated. Be wary of the &ldquo;no risk&rdquo; narrative and recognize signs of an overheated market, such as high P/E ratios, narrow credit spreads, and loose credit conditions.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Controlling Risk:</strong> Risk control is more important than taking risks. Control risk through diversification, limiting risk exposure, adhering to a margin of safety, and avoiding excessive leverage. The results of risk control are often invisible because they manifest in losses avoided.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Focusing on Cycles:</strong> Everything is cyclical. Recognize the inevitability of cyclical fluctuations and look for opportunities at cyclical extremes. The author uses the credit cycle as an example to illustrate how cycles are self-correcting and how investors can find opportunities within them.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Pendulum Awareness:</strong> Investor psychology swings like a pendulum between optimism and pessimism, greed and fear. Recognize the patterns of this swing and act contrarianly at extremes. Market extremes often represent turning points and opportunities.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Resisting Negative Influences:</strong> Resist the influence of negative emotions such as greed, fear, herd mentality, envy, and ego on investment decisions. Recognizing the existence of these psychological factors and striving to overcome them is crucial for making rational investment decisions.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Contrarian Investing:</strong> Be greedy when others are fearful, and fearful when others are greedy. Contrarian investing is not simply doing the opposite of the crowd; it requires independent thinking and judgment, as well as a deep understanding of value. Contrarian investing can be lonely and unsettling but is key to achieving superior returns.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Finding Bargains:</strong> Bargains often appear in unpopular and unfavored assets, such as those with apparent flaws, misunderstood by the market, or overlooked.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Waiting Patiently for Opportunities:</strong> Don&rsquo;t chase opportunities; wait patiently for them to come to you. Investors should be like baseball hitters, waiting for the perfect pitch instead of swinging blindly.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Recognizing the Limitations of Forecasting:</strong> Predicting the future is very difficult. Recognize the limitations of forecasting and focus on knowable factors, such as company fundamentals and industry trends.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Understanding Your Position in the Cycle:</strong> Understand your position within the market cycle and adjust your investment strategy accordingly. Investors can assess market conditions by observing investor behavior, the credit environment, and valuation levels.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Appreciating the Role of Luck:</strong> Investment outcomes are influenced by luck. Distinguish between skill and luck, and avoid being blinded by short-term success. Investors should focus on long-term performance and analyze the sources of returns, rather than just focusing on short-term gains.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Diversification:</strong> Diversification is an important risk management tool, but understand correlations and avoid ineffective diversification. True diversification means holding assets that behave differently under different market conditions.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Avoiding Mistakes:</strong> Avoiding major mistakes is more important than pursuing great success. Identify and avoid various types of errors, such as analytical errors, psychological errors, and failure to recognize cycles and market sentiment.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>The Significance of Value Creation:</strong> Value creation requires superior investment skill. Understand alpha and beta, and strive for asymmetric investment performance, meaning achieving higher returns when the market rises and suffering fewer losses when the market falls.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Reasonable Expectations:</strong> Set reasonable return expectations and avoid being misled by unrealistic expectations. Excessively high return expectations are often accompanied by excessive risk. Understand how returns are generated and the conditions required to achieve objectives.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>The Most Important Thing:</strong> Summarizes the core ideas of the book, emphasizing the importance of value assessment, risk control, contrarian investing, and psychological factors. Successful investing requires comprehensive consideration of these factors and the development of a complete investment framework.</p>
</li>
</ol>


<h2 class="relative group">III. Key Takeaways 
    <div id="iii-key-takeaways" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii-key-takeaways" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;There&rsquo;s a certain irony in the investing world: What&rsquo;s obvious to everyone else is likely to be wrong.&rdquo;</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Insight:  Consensus views often lead to average results, at best.  Superior returns require non-consensus views that prove to be correct.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;Remember, your goal in investing isn&rsquo;t to earn average returns; you want to do better than average.&rdquo;</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Insight:  Complacency is the enemy of superior performance.  Strive to exceed benchmarks, not simply match them.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;The widespread belief that there&rsquo;s no risk is the biggest risk of all.&rdquo;</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Insight:  When markets are universally optimistic, risk is often at its highest because prices don&rsquo;t reflect potential problems.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;Only when the tide goes out do you discover who&rsquo;s been swimming naked.&rdquo;</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Insight: Adverse market conditions reveal the weaknesses in portfolios and investment strategies that were hidden during favorable periods.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;It takes greatest courage, but provides the greatest profit, to buy when others are despondently selling and to sell when others are greedily buying.&rdquo;</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Insight: Contrarian investing is difficult because it requires going against the crowd, but it offers the potential for the highest rewards.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;One of the great things about investing is that you don&rsquo;t have to make a lot of good decisions to do well. What&rsquo;s essential is avoiding bad decisions.&rdquo;</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Insight:  Preserving capital is paramount.  Avoiding significant losses has a greater impact on long-term returns than occasional big wins.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;An investor needs do very few things right as long as he avoids big mistakes.&rdquo;</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Insight:  Risk management and capital preservation are the cornerstones of successful investing.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">IV. Practical Application 
    <div id="iv-practical-application" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv-practical-application" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This book provides a comprehensive investment framework to help investors:</p>
<ol>
<li><strong>Establish a sound investment philosophy:</strong> Emphasizes the importance of value investing, contrarian investing, and risk control.</li>
<li><strong>Improve investment skills:</strong> Learn how to assess value, identify risks, control emotions, and construct portfolios.</li>
<li><strong>Cultivate a healthy investment mindset:</strong> Remain rational, objective, patient, and think independently, avoiding being swayed by market sentiment.</li>
<li><strong>Achieve better investment performance:</strong> By applying the methods and techniques discussed in the book, improve the quality of investment decisions and ultimately achieve above-market returns.</li>
</ol>

  



<div
  
    class="flex px-4 py-3 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900"
  >

  <span
    
      class="text-primary-400 ltr:pr-3 rtl:pl-3 flex items-center"
    >

    

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 640 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M172.5 131.1C228.1 75.51 320.5 75.51 376.1 131.1C426.1 181.1 433.5 260.8 392.4 318.3L391.3 319.9C381 334.2 361 337.6 346.7 327.3C332.3 317 328.9 297 339.2 282.7L340.3 281.1C363.2 249 359.6 205.1 331.7 177.2C300.3 145.8 249.2 145.8 217.7 177.2L105.5 289.5C73.99 320.1 73.99 372 105.5 403.5C133.3 431.4 177.3 435 209.3 412.1L210.9 410.1C225.3 400.7 245.3 404 255.5 418.4C265.8 432.8 262.5 452.8 248.1 463.1L246.5 464.2C188.1 505.3 110.2 498.7 60.21 448.8C3.741 392.3 3.741 300.7 60.21 244.3L172.5 131.1zM467.5 380C411 436.5 319.5 436.5 263 380C213 330 206.5 251.2 247.6 193.7L248.7 192.1C258.1 177.8 278.1 174.4 293.3 184.7C307.7 194.1 311.1 214.1 300.8 229.3L299.7 230.9C276.8 262.1 280.4 306.9 308.3 334.8C339.7 366.2 390.8 366.2 422.3 334.8L534.5 222.5C566 191 566 139.1 534.5 108.5C506.7 80.63 462.7 76.99 430.7 99.9L429.1 101C414.7 111.3 394.7 107.1 384.5 93.58C374.2 79.2 377.5 59.21 391.9 48.94L393.5 47.82C451 6.731 529.8 13.25 579.8 63.24C636.3 119.7 636.3 211.3 579.8 267.7L467.5 380z"/></svg>

  </span>


  </span>

  <span
    
      class="dark:text-neutral-300"
    ><strong>Related Reading:</strong>  Howard Marks&rsquo; investment memos: <a href="https://www.oaktreecapital.com/insights/memos" target="_blank"><strong>Archived Memos</strong></a></span>
</div>

<hr>

<section class="space-y-10 w-full">
    
    
</section>
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>The Millionaire Next Door：Book Notes</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1728996298300/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1728996298300/</guid><description>This book reveals the true portrait of American millionaires through a survey, debunking myths about them and showcasing their common characteristics：frugality, diligence, self-discipline, and skillful investment. It also explores the definition of wealth, how to accumulate it, how to educate children, and how to distribute inheritance, providing a life textbook for readers.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[

<h2 class="relative group">I. Summary 
    <div id="i-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This book unveils the real lives of American millionaires through a comprehensive survey, shattering the mystique surrounding them. The authors discovered that most American millionaires were not born with a silver spoon but built their wealth from scratch through frugality, hard work, self-discipline, and smart investing. The book also explores the definition of wealth, how to accumulate it, how to raise children, and how to distribute inheritance, offering a practical guide for those who aspire to build wealth.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">II. Chapter Summaries 
    <div id="ii-chapter-summaries" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii-chapter-summaries" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Chapter 1: Meet the Millionaire Next Door 
    <div id="chapter-1-meet-the-millionaire-next-door" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chapter-1-meet-the-millionaire-next-door" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>This chapter introduces the authors&rsquo; motivation and methodology for surveying millionaires and paints a typical picture of an American millionaire: they are mostly self-made entrepreneurs who live frugally and focus on investment rather than conspicuous consumption.</li>
<li>Through analyzing affluent individuals from diverse racial backgrounds and professions, the authors reveal the relationship between wealth accumulation and factors like racial origin and career choices, emphasizing the crucial role of &ldquo;frugality&rdquo; in wealth building.</li>
<li>The authors introduce the concept of &ldquo;Big Hat, No Cattle,&rdquo; referring to the phenomenon that many who appear to be millionaires are not truly wealthy, while many genuine millionaires live modest, frugal lives.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chapter 2: Frugality: The Cornerstone of Wealth Building 
    <div id="chapter-2-frugality-the-cornerstone-of-wealth-building" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chapter-2-frugality-the-cornerstone-of-wealth-building" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>This chapter delves into the theme of &ldquo;frugality,&rdquo; highlighting it as the foundation of wealth accumulation.</li>
<li>By comparing the lifestyles and consumption habits of &ldquo;Prodigious Accumulators of Wealth (PAWs)&rdquo; and &ldquo;Under Accumulators of Wealth (UAWs),&rdquo; the authors demonstrate the decisive impact of frugality on wealth accumulation. For instance, the contrasting cases of Mr. Ford, a lawyer with high spending habits, and Mr. Richards, a mobile home dealer who lived frugally, ultimately show that Mr. Richards accumulated almost five times the wealth of Mr. Ford.</li>
<li>This chapter points out that most American millionaires are first-generation affluent individuals who practice a lifestyle of saving more than they spend, refraining from splurging on luxury items like expensive clothing, watches, and cars. They accumulate wealth but maintain a moderately frugal lifestyle.</li>
<li>This chapter also introduces a crucial wealth formula: <em>Age multiplied by realized pretax annual household income, divided by 10, minus inherited wealth, equals your expected net worth.</em> Using this formula, readers can calculate their expected net worth and assess whether they are PAWs, UAWs, or &ldquo;Average Accumulators of Wealth (AAWs).&rdquo;</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chapter 3: Time, Energy, and Money 
    <div id="chapter-3-time-energy-and-money" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chapter-3-time-energy-and-money" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>This chapter explores the importance of efficiently allocating &ldquo;time, energy, and money&rdquo; for wealth accumulation.</li>
<li>By comparing how PAWs and UAWs allocate these three resources, the chapter illustrates that PAWs prioritize long-term planning, investment strategies, and risk management, while UAWs tend towards instant gratification, impulsive spending, and a lack of financial planning.</li>
<li>This chapter emphasizes the importance of household budgeting, stating that even high earners need to meticulously plan and control expenses to accumulate wealth.</li>
<li>The authors point out that PAWs spend significantly more time on financial planning than UAWs, and PAWs prefer to invest in appreciating assets like stocks and real estate, while UAWs tend to spend their money on consumer goods.</li>
<li>The authors advise readers to manage their household finances like a business, creating a budget, controlling expenses, and regularly reviewing investment plans.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chapter 4: You Aren&rsquo;t What You Drive 
    <div id="chapter-4-you-arent-what-you-drive" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chapter-4-you-arent-what-you-drive" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>This chapter uses the car-buying habits of millionaires as an example to further illustrate the principle that &ldquo;being financially independent is more important than displaying high social status.&rdquo;</li>
<li>The authors categorize millionaire car buyers into four types: &ldquo;New-Car Dealers&rsquo; Conservatives,&rdquo; &ldquo;New-Car Shoppers,&rdquo; &ldquo;Used-Car Dealers&rsquo; Conservatives,&rdquo; and &ldquo;Used-Car Shoppers.&rdquo;</li>
<li>By analyzing the purchasing behaviors of these four types, the authors find that &ldquo;Used-Car Shoppers&rdquo; are the most frugal, highly price-sensitive, and adept at leveraging various channels to find the best deals. This group is also the most likely to become PAWs.</li>
<li>This chapter also notes that most millionaires buy American-made cars, and many buy used cars. They believe that cars are depreciating assets and there&rsquo;s no need to spend excessively on new ones.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chapter 5: Economic Outpatient Care 
    <div id="chapter-5-economic-outpatient-care" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chapter-5-economic-outpatient-care" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>This chapter explores the phenomenon of &ldquo;Economic Outpatient Care,&rdquo; where parents provide substantial financial assistance to their adult children, often leading to the children&rsquo;s lack of financial independence and drive, ultimately hindering their ability to accumulate wealth.</li>
<li>By comparing the wealth accumulation of children who receive &ldquo;Economic Outpatient Care&rdquo; with those who don&rsquo;t, the authors illustrate the negative impact of this practice. For example, the case of Rama and Mary, a couple who received long-term financial support from Mary&rsquo;s parents, ultimately developed high spending habits and failed to accumulate wealth.</li>
<li>This chapter analyzes the causes of &ldquo;Economic Outpatient Care&rdquo; and offers suggestions to help affluent parents avoid the tragedy of &ldquo;shirtsleeves to shirtsleeves in three generations.&rdquo; For instance, parents should teach their children frugality and financial management instead of solely providing financial aid.</li>
<li>This chapter points out that adult children who receive gifts from their parents generally perform worse in wealth accumulation compared to those who don&rsquo;t. This is because receiving gifts can foster dependence and a tendency to spend the money on consumption rather than investment.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chapter 6: Rules of Thumb 
    <div id="chapter-6-rules-of-thumb" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chapter-6-rules-of-thumb" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>This chapter discusses how affluent parents distribute wealth to their adult children and how they choose heirs.</li>
<li>The authors note that affluent parents often distribute wealth based on their children&rsquo;s professions, gender, and contributions to the family, tending to leave more to children who need financial assistance. For instance, homemakers often receive more inheritance than working children.</li>
<li>This chapter also emphasizes the importance of choosing executors and suggests that affluent parents select an experienced professional as a co-executor to prevent inheritance disputes among children.</li>
<li>This chapter offers advice to help affluent parents avoid family conflicts when distributing inheritance. For example, affluent parents should establish estate plans early and communicate with their children to ensure their wishes are understood.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chapter 7: Affirmative Action, Family Style 
    <div id="chapter-7-affirmative-action-family-style" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chapter-7-affirmative-action-family-style" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>This chapter explores the business opportunities in providing products and services to the wealthy, noting that these opportunities will continue to grow with the increasing affluent population.</li>
<li>The authors list several businesses and professions that can benefit from serving the wealthy, including specialized lawyers, healthcare and dental specialists, estate liquidators, educational institutions and professionals, and real estate experts.</li>
<li>The authors also analyze the spending habits of the wealthy and point out that they are willing to spend on certain aspects, such as investment consulting, healthcare, and education, which provides significant business opportunities for many industries.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chapter 8: The Perfect Investment 
    <div id="chapter-8-the-perfect-investment" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chapter-8-the-perfect-investment" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>This chapter discusses the relationship between career choice and wealth accumulation, pointing out that self-employed business owners and professionals are more likely to build wealth.</li>
<li>By comparing the profitability and risks of different professions, the authors illustrate why self-employed business owners and professionals are more likely to accumulate wealth. For example, the average profit margin of a doctor&rsquo;s office is higher than that of a coal mining operation.</li>
<li>This chapter also analyzes why affluent parents often discourage their children from taking over family businesses and instead recommend pursuing careers as self-employed professionals. This is because self-employed professionals can leverage their knowledge and skills to generate sustainable income, and their careers tend to be more stable and less risky.</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">III. Key Quotes 
    <div id="iii-key-quotes" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii-key-quotes" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;Wealth is not the same as income. If you make a good income each year and spend it all, you are not getting wealthier. You are just living high. Wealth is what you accumulate, not what you spend.&rdquo;</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Analysis: This quote highlights the book&rsquo;s core message: wealth accumulation is not solely based on high income but also relies on frugal habits and smart investment skills. High income doesn&rsquo;t equate to wealth; only by converting income into assets can one achieve true financial freedom.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;Frugality is the cornerstone of wealth building.&rdquo;</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Analysis: This quote emphasizes the crucial role of frugality in wealth accumulation. Only by controlling consumption can one free up more funds for investment, leading to wealth growth. Frugality doesn&rsquo;t mean living an austere life but rather being a rational consumer and avoiding unnecessary waste.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;To build wealth, minimize your realized (taxable) income and maximize your unrealized income (wealth that is not taxed until it is converted to cash).&rdquo;</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Analysis: This quote reveals a vital strategy for wealthy individuals to accumulate wealth, namely, achieving wealth growth through investment rather than solely relying on salary income. One must skillfully utilize tax policies to convert income into tax-advantaged assets like stocks and real estate.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;If you&rsquo;re not yet wealthy but want to be someday, never purchase a home that requires a mortgage that is more than twice your household&rsquo;s total annual realized income.&rdquo;</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Analysis: This quote offers practical advice for those in the early stages of wealth accumulation: avoid excessive mortgage burdens and allocate more funds towards investment. When funds are limited, prioritize investment over consumption.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;Those who are financially independent are considerably happier than those in the same income/age cohort who are not financially secure.&rdquo;</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Analysis: This quote illustrates the importance of financial security for personal happiness. Possessing sufficient wealth allows individuals to face life&rsquo;s challenges with greater confidence. Economic independence is the foundation of personal freedom and a crucial guarantee of happiness.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;Never tell children that their parents are wealthy.&rdquo;</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Analysis: This quote provides valuable educational advice for affluent parents: avoid letting children know about the family&rsquo;s wealth too early to prevent them from developing dependence and a lack of initiative. Children need to understand that wealth is created through their own efforts.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;No matter how wealthy you are, teach your children to be self-sufficient and frugal.&rdquo;</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Analysis: This quote emphasizes the importance of frugality and self-discipline. Even children from affluent families should develop good habits to better adapt to future challenges. Children need to understand that frugality is a virtue and a prerequisite for success.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">IV. Significance 
    <div id="iv-significance" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv-significance" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<ol>
<li><strong>Importance of Frugality and Financial Management:</strong> This book highlights the importance of frugality and investment, helping readers establish a correct perspective on wealth and offering practical financial advice. There are no shortcuts to wealth creation; only through diligent saving and rational investment can one steadily accumulate wealth.</li>
<li><strong>Wisdom in Raising Children:</strong> This book explores how to raise children to be financially responsible individuals, providing insights into the educational experiences and methods of affluent parents and inspiring readers to reflect on their own parenting styles. Affluent parents should focus on cultivating their children&rsquo;s independence, responsibility, and financial management skills instead of solely providing financial assistance.</li>
<li><strong>Career Choices and Wealth Accumulation:</strong> This book analyzes the profitability and risks of different professions, helping readers better understand the relationship between career choices and wealth accumulation and providing guidance for individual career planning. Choosing a career with development potential that aligns with one&rsquo;s interests and abilities is a crucial prerequisite for achieving wealth accumulation.</li>
<li><strong>Business Opportunities in Serving the Wealthy:</strong> This book reveals the vast business opportunities in providing products and services to the wealthy, offering insights and inspiration for aspiring entrepreneurs. To succeed in this market, one must be adept at identifying the needs of the wealthy and providing high-quality products and services.</li>
<li><strong>Debunking Stereotypes about the Wealthy:</strong> This book debunks the myths surrounding millionaires through its survey of American affluent individuals, presenting a realistic portrait of their lives and prompting readers to contemplate the true meaning of wealth. True wealth encompasses more than just money; it also includes health, happiness, family, and a sense of accomplishment.</li>
</ol>
<p>In conclusion, &ldquo;The Millionaire Next Door&rdquo; is a timeless classic worth revisiting. It not only unveils the secrets to the success of the wealthy but also provides valuable insights and methods for ordinary readers to accumulate wealth, raise children, and plan their lives.</p>
<hr>

<section class="space-y-10 w-full">
    
    
        
            






















  <a class="flex flex-wrap article " href="/en/posts/1728295490690-book-list/">
    
        
        <div class="w-full md:w-auto h-full thumbnail nozoom thumbnailshadow md:mr-7" style="background-image:url(/posts/1728295490690-book-list/featured_hu4424409690304057825.jpg);"></div>
        
      <div class=" mt-3 md:mt-0">
      <div class="items-center text-left text-xl font-semibold">
        
        <div class="font-bold text-xl text-neutral-800 decoration-primary-500 hover:underline hover:underline-offset-2 dark:text-neutral"
          href="/en/posts/1728295490690-book-list/">Recommended Reading List</div>
        
        
        
      </div>
      <div class="text-sm text-neutral-500 dark:text-neutral-400">
        











  









  



  









<div class="flex flex-row flex-wrap items-center">
  
  
  <time datetime="2024-10-01T00:00:00&#43;00:00">1 October 2024</time><span class="px-2 text-primary-500">&middot;</span><span>
  
  
    
    
      
      
        
        
      
        
        
      
      
    
  
  <span id="views_posts/1728295490690-book-list/index.md" class="animate-pulse inline-block text-transparent max-h-3 rounded-full mt-[-2px] align-middle bg-neutral-300 dark:bg-neutral-400" title="views">loading</span>
  <span class="inline-block align-text-bottom">

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 576 512">
<path fill="currentColor" d="M288 32c-80.8 0-145.5 36.8-192.6 80.6C48.6 156 17.3 208 2.5 243.7c-3.3 7.9-3.3 16.7 0 24.6C17.3 304 48.6 356 95.4 399.4C142.5 443.2 207.2 480 288 480s145.5-36.8 192.6-80.6c46.8-43.5 78.1-95.4 93-131.1c3.3-7.9 3.3-16.7 0-24.6c-14.9-35.7-46.2-87.7-93-131.1C433.5 68.8 368.8 32 288 32zM432 256c0 79.5-64.5 144-144 144s-144-64.5-144-144s64.5-144 144-144s144 64.5 144 144zM288 192c0 35.3-28.7 64-64 64c-11.5 0-22.3-3-31.6-8.4c-.2 2.8-.4 5.5-.4 8.4c0 53 43 96 96 96s96-43 96-96s-43-96-96-96c-2.8 0-5.6 .1-8.4 .4c5.3 9.3 8.4 20.1 8.4 31.6z"/></svg>
  </span>

</span>
</span><span class="px-2 text-primary-500">&middot;</span><span>
  
  
    
    
      
      
        
        
      
        
        
      
      
    
  
  <span id="likes_posts/1728295490690-book-list/index.md"
    class="animate-pulse inline-block text-transparent max-h-3 rounded-full mt-[-2px] align-middle bg-neutral-300 dark:bg-neutral-400"
    title="likes">loading</span>
  <span class="inline-block align-text-bottom">

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512">
<path fill="currentColor" d="M47.6 300.4L228.3 469.1c7.5 7 17.4 10.9 27.7 10.9s20.2-3.9 27.7-10.9L464.4 300.4c30.4-28.3 47.6-68 47.6-109.5v-5.8c0-69.9-50.5-129.5-119.4-141C347 36.5 300.6 51.4 268 84L256 96 244 84c-32.6-32.6-79-47.5-124.6-39.9C50.5 55.6 0 115.2 0 185.1v5.8c0 41.5 17.2 81.2 47.6 109.5z"/></svg>
  </span>

</span>
</span>
  

  
  
</div>





<div class="flex flex-row flex-wrap items-center">
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  <span style="margin-top:0.5rem" class="mr-2" onclick="window.open(&#34;/en/tags/recommended/&#34;,'_self');">
    <span class="flex" style="cursor: pointer;">
  <span class="rounded-md border border-primary-400 px-1 py-[1px] text-xs font-normal text-primary-700 dark:border-primary-600 dark:text-primary-400">
    Recommended
  </span>
</span>
  </span>
  
  <span style="margin-top:0.5rem" class="mr-2" onclick="window.open(&#34;/en/tags/book/&#34;,'_self');">
    <span class="flex" style="cursor: pointer;">
  <span class="rounded-md border border-primary-400 px-1 py-[1px] text-xs font-normal text-primary-700 dark:border-primary-600 dark:text-primary-400">
    Book
  </span>
</span>
  </span>
  
  
  
  
</div>




      </div>
      
    </div>
  </a>

        
    
</section>
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Just Keep Buying：Book Notes</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1728914740948/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1728914740948/</guid><description>This book answers the most common questions in the field of personal finance and investing. From saving to investing, it provides practical tips to teach you how to increase your income, invest in income-producing assets, manage your finances more wisely, and live a richer life.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[

<h2 class="relative group">I. Content Summary 
    <div id="i-content-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-content-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This book is divided into two parts: saving and investing. The <strong>saving</strong> section covers all aspects of saving money, including how much to save, how to save more, and how to spend money without guilt. The <strong>investing</strong> section covers many aspects of making money with money, including why you should invest, what you should invest in, and how often you should invest. The author answers the most common questions in the field of personal finance and investing, with each chapter exploring a topic in depth and providing practical tips.  Using a large amount of data and empirical research as evidence, the author arrives at reliable ways to save money and build wealth.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">II. Chapter Summary 
    <div id="ii-chapter-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii-chapter-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Chapter 1. Where Should You Start? 
    <div id="chapter-1-where-should-you-start" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chapter-1-where-should-you-start" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>The poor should focus on saving, and the rich should focus on investing.</p>
<ul>
<li>Recent graduates should focus on increasing their income and savings rate, rather than obsessing over investment decisions, because the growth rate of savings far exceeds the growth rate of investment.</li>
<li>People who have accumulated a certain amount of wealth should spend more time thinking about the details of their investment plan.</li>
<li>The author proposes a &ldquo;Save-Invest continuum&rdquo; concept to help you determine your current financial focus: calculate your expected savings and expected investment growth. Focus on whichever is greater.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chapter 2. How Much Should You Save? 
    <div id="chapter-2-how-much-should-you-save" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chapter-2-how-much-should-you-save" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>You probably need to save less than you think.</p>
<ul>
<li>Many saving recommendations are based on false assumptions: that people&rsquo;s incomes are stable and that everyone has the ability to achieve the same savings rate.</li>
<li>In fact, incomes become more unstable over time, and the biggest determinant of an individual&rsquo;s savings rate is their income level.</li>
<li>The best saving advice is: <strong>save what you can save.</strong></li>
<li>A large body of evidence suggests that retirees generally don&rsquo;t spend enough, with many even increasing their financial assets after retirement.</li>
<li>Today&rsquo;s younger generation is not creating wealth any slower than previous generations, so there is no need to worry too much about running out of money after retirement.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chapter 3. How to Save More Money? 
    <div id="chapter-3-how-to-save-more-money" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chapter-3-how-to-save-more-money" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>The biggest lie in personal finance: you can get rich just by saving.</p>
<ul>
<li>The effectiveness of reducing spending is limited. For low-income people, spending is already at its lowest level, making it difficult to reduce further. The author uses data from the U.S. Bureau of Labor Statistics Consumer Expenditure Survey to support this point.</li>
<li>Increasing income is more effective than reducing spending because as income increases, spending does not necessarily increase proportionately (diminishing marginal utility). The author calls this the &ldquo;law of the stomach.&rdquo;</li>
<li>Five ways to increase your income:
<ul>
<li>Sell your time/expertise: easy to do, but not scalable.</li>
<li>Sell a skill/service: higher income, but takes time to develop skills.</li>
<li>Teach: easy to scale, but highly competitive.</li>
<li>Sell a product: scalable, but requires a lot of upfront investment and ongoing marketing efforts.</li>
<li>Climb the career ladder: traditional but effective, can gain skills, experience and stable income growth.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>The most reliable way to get rich is: <strong>Increase your income and invest in income-producing assets.</strong></li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chapter 4. How to Spend Money Without Guilt? 
    <div id="chapter-4-how-to-spend-money-without-guilt" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chapter-4-how-to-spend-money-without-guilt" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Most financial advice uses guilt to make you question your spending decisions, causing you to be overly nervous about spending money.</li>
<li>Two tips to help you make financial decisions without worry and spend money without guilt:
<ul>
<li>The 2x rule: When you splurge, invest the same amount of money in income-producing assets or donate it to charity. For example, if you want to buy a pair of $400 shoes, buy $400 worth of stock at the same time.</li>
<li>Focus on maximizing satisfaction: Think about whether your purchase can bring autonomy, mastery, and purpose, thereby increasing your long-term satisfaction. For example, a daily latte might allow you to do your job better.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>The only right way to spend money is: <strong>the way that works for you</strong>. Think about what you want to get out of life, and make spending decisions accordingly. Research from the University of Cambridge shows that the more your spending patterns match your psychological state, the higher your life satisfaction, and this effect is greater than the happiness brought by your total income.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chapter 5. How Much Lifestyle Inflation Is Harmless? 
    <div id="chapter-5-how-much-lifestyle-inflation-is-harmless" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chapter-5-how-much-lifestyle-inflation-is-harmless" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Lifestyle inflation refers to the increase in spending that follows an increase in one&rsquo;s income.</li>
<li>Some lifestyle inflation is enjoyable, but too much lifestyle inflation will lead to having to delay retirement.</li>
<li>The author simulates the retirement plans of two investors with different savings rates after salary increases to arrive at these conclusions:
<ul>
<li>The lower your current savings rate, the higher your lifestyle inflation can be without affecting your original retirement plan.</li>
<li>The author recommends saving at least 50% of your future raises, a rule that is simple, practical, and suitable for most people.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chapter 6. Should You Go Into Debt? 
    <div id="chapter-6-should-you-go-into-debt" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chapter-6-should-you-go-into-debt" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>Debt is not necessarily good or bad, it depends on how you use it.</p>
<ul>
<li>Debt as a form of risk mitigation: Some people, even with savings, keep credit card debt as a strategy to reduce the risk of future funding shortages.</li>
<li>Debt as a behavioral pillar of forced savings: Some people use debt as a behavioral pillar to force themselves to save.</li>
<li>The two most useful types of debt:
<ul>
<li>To reduce risk: for example, keeping cash on hand for emergencies or fixing housing costs.</li>
<li>To earn a return higher than the cost of borrowing: for example, by taking out education loans, business loans, or mortgages to generate higher returns. The author uses data to demonstrate that getting a college degree is often worthwhile.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Debt can also have non-financial costs, such as psychological stress and health problems, so non-mortgage financial debt should be avoided as much as possible.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chapter 7. Should You Rent or Buy? 
    <div id="chapter-7-should-you-rent-or-buy" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chapter-7-should-you-rent-or-buy" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>The point of buying a home is not whether to buy it, but when to buy it.</p>
<ul>
<li>In addition to the mortgage, there are a number of one-time and ongoing costs associated with buying a home, such as down payment, closing costs, taxes, maintenance, and insurance. The author details these costs, concluding that buying a home is only cost-effective if the buyer intends to live in it for the long term.</li>
<li>In the short term, buying a home is riskier than renting, but in the long term, renters face greater long-term risks such as rent fluctuations, housing instability, and moving costs.</li>
<li>In the United States, the long-term return on  homeownership as an investment is not ideal, far lower than the stock market. The author uses the example of his grandparents buying a home to illustrate this point.</li>
<li>The right time to buy a home is when you:
<ul>
<li>plan to stay in that location for at least ten years;</li>
<li>have a stable personal and professional life;</li>
<li>can afford a 20% down payment and keep your debt-to-income ratio below 43%. The author recommends, if possible, to make a 20% down payment and buy a larger home in one step, because the transaction costs are lower in the long run.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chapter 8. How to Save For a Down Payment (and Other Big Purchases)? 
    <div id="chapter-8-how-to-save-for-a-down-payment-and-other-big-purchases" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chapter-8-how-to-save-for-a-down-payment-and-other-big-purchases" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>Why the length of time you save matters?</p>
<ul>
<li>Short-term saving for less than two years: Holding <strong>cash</strong> is the best option, as it has the lowest risk.</li>
<li>Long-term saving for more than two years: Investing in <strong>bonds</strong> is preferable to holding cash because bond returns can offset the effects of inflation. The author compares cash and bonds using two examples: &ldquo;Save $1,000 per month with a goal of $24,000&rdquo; and &ldquo;Save $1,000 per month with a goal of $60,000&rdquo;.</li>
<li>Longer-term saving for more than three years: You can choose to invest in <strong>stocks</strong>, but the risk is higher and you need to choose an appropriate portfolio based on your own risk tolerance. The author uses data to show that stocks have much higher long-term returns than bonds, but also greater volatility.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chapter 9. When Can You Retire? 
    <div id="chapter-9-when-can-you-retire" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chapter-9-when-can-you-retire" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>There&rsquo;s more to consider than just money when it comes to retirement.</p>
<ul>
<li>The 4% rule: When your retirement savings reach 25 times your expected annual expenses, you can retire.
<ul>
<li>You can withdraw 4% of your investment assets (half bonds and half stocks) in the first year of retirement, and increase the amount withdrawn by 3% each year to keep up with inflation.</li>
<li>If you have a pension or other guaranteed income, you only need to save 25 times your &ldquo;annual excess spending&rdquo; (expected annual expenses less future guaranteed income).</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>The crossover point rule: The point at which your monthly investment income is greater than your monthly expenses, you have reached the &ldquo;crossover point&rdquo; and achieved financial freedom.
<ul>
<li>&ldquo;Crossover Assets&rdquo; = Monthly Expenses / Monthly Investment Return.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Retirement is much more than just a financial decision, it&rsquo;s a lifestyle decision. You need to think about what you want to do and how you want to live after retirement. The author uses the examples of several celebrities to illustrate the confusion and emptiness that can exist after early retirement.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chapter 10. Why You Should Invest? 
    <div id="chapter-10-why-you-should-invest" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chapter-10-why-you-should-invest" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>Three reasons to make your money grow.</p>
<ul>
<li>Save for your future self: Investing allows you to have a pool of resources to draw from as you age. Human lifespans are increasing, and the concept of &ldquo;retirement&rdquo; has emerged accordingly. To ensure quality of life after retirement, it is necessary to invest in advance.</li>
<li>Fight inflation and maintain the purchasing power of your wealth: Investing can offset the impact of inflation and maintain or increase your purchasing power. The author uses data to show that investing can effectively combat the effects of inflation.</li>
<li>Replace your human capital with financial capital: Investing can turn your diminishing human capital into financial capital that can continue to generate returns. The author illustrates this with the example of professional athletes.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chapter 11. What Should You Invest In? 
    <div id="chapter-11-what-should-you-invest-in" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chapter-11-what-should-you-invest-in" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>There is no single right way to get rich.</p>
<ul>
<li>The author lists a variety of income-producing assets, including:
<ul>
<li>Stocks: One of the most reliable ways to build wealth over the long term, easy to own and trade, with low maintenance costs, but highly volatile and valuations easily influenced by market sentiment.</li>
<li>Bonds: Low volatility, safe principal, and helpful in rebalancing portfolios, but returns are generally lower than stocks, especially in a low interest rate environment.</li>
<li>Investment real estate: Returns are higher than stocks or bonds, especially when using leverage, but require more effort to manage and are difficult to diversify.</li>
<li>Real Estate Investment Trusts (REITs): Provide access to real estate investment income without needing to manage it yourself, but are more volatile and highly correlated with stocks and other risky assets during stock market crashes.</li>
<li>Farmland: Low correlation with stocks and bonds, low volatility, inflation-resistant, but low liquidity, higher fees, and requires &ldquo;accredited investor&rdquo; status to participate.</li>
<li>Small businesses/franchises/angel investing: Potential for high returns and the more effort you put in, the greater the return, but requires a significant time commitment and has a high failure rate.</li>
<li>Royalties: Can generate stable income that is uncorrelated with traditional financial assets, but sellers incur high fees and public taste changes are unpredictable.</li>
<li>Your own products: 100% ownership, personal satisfaction and achievement, can create a valuable brand, but very labor-intensive and no guarantee of return.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>The author also contrasts the characteristics of income-producing and non-income-producing assets (e.g., gold, cryptocurrency, art, etc.) and their respective advantages and disadvantages.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chapter 12. Why You Shouldn&rsquo;t Buy Individual Stocks? 
    <div id="chapter-12-why-you-shouldnt-buy-individual-stocks" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chapter-12-why-you-shouldnt-buy-individual-stocks" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>Why underperforming the market is the least of your worries?</p>
<ul>
<li>Most people (even professionals) can&rsquo;t beat the market. Data from the SPIVA report shows that active funds tend to underperform index funds over the long term.</li>
<li>Only a very small percentage of individual stocks outperform in the long run. Bessembinder&rsquo;s research indicates that since 1926, only 4% of stocks have generated returns that exceed U.S. Treasury bonds.</li>
<li>Even stocks that outperform are not always winners. West&rsquo;s statistical analysis suggests that many companies will disappear within a decade.</li>
<li>Choosing individual stocks is emotionally draining and stressful. The author uses the example of his friend Darren investing in GameStop stock to detail the emotional rollercoaster of stock trading.</li>
<li>It&rsquo;s hard to tell if you&rsquo;re really good at picking stocks. The link between stock picking decisions and outcomes is not significant, making it difficult to assess your stock picking skills. Even if you have performed well in the past, there is no guarantee that you will continue to do so in the future.</li>
<li>The risk of holding a concentrated position in a single stock is that the return is lower than the market. The author uses data on U.S. stock performance since 1963 to show that the median return of individual stocks is lower than that of index funds.</li>
<li>The author suggests buying index funds or ETFs to earn market average returns, which can lead to higher returns and less stress during the investment process.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chapter 13. How Early Should You Start Investing? 
    <div id="chapter-13-how-early-should-you-start-investing" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chapter-13-how-early-should-you-start-investing" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>Why buying early is better than buying late?</p>
<ul>
<li>Most markets tend to go up most of the time, so investing early allows for a longer period of compounding growth.</li>
<li>The author compares two investment strategies:
<ul>
<li>Buy now: Put all the money you can invest in immediately.</li>
<li>Average in: Invest the money you can invest in batches.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Conclusion: The <strong>buy now</strong> strategy is generally better than the average-in strategy. The author uses U.S. stock market data from 1997 to 2020, as well as U.S. stock market data from 1920 to 2020, to respectively prove this conclusion. The same results hold when testing other types of assets.</li>
<li>For risk-averse investors, you can choose to invest in a lower risk portfolio. For example, change an 80% stock / 20% bond portfolio to a 60% stock / 40% bond portfolio.</li>
<li>Even if market valuations are high, the buy now strategy is still better than the average in strategy. The author compares the two strategies using CAPE percentile categories, and the results show that the buy now strategy is still superior even during periods of high valuations.</li>
<li>For investors concerned about the risk of a lump sum investment, you can take a longer time to gradually adjust to your target asset allocation.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chapter 14. Why You Shouldn&rsquo;t Wait to Buy the Dip? 
    <div id="chapter-14-why-you-shouldnt-wait-to-buy-the-dip" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chapter-14-why-you-shouldnt-wait-to-buy-the-dip" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>Even God can&rsquo;t beat dollar-cost averaging.</p>
<ul>
<li>The buy the dip strategy only works if the market is about to have a big drop and you can accurately predict when it will happen.</li>
<li>Big market drops don&rsquo;t happen that often, so the buy the dip strategy has a small chance of beating dollar-cost averaging. The author simulates the two strategies using U.S. stock market data from between 1920 and 1980. The results show that in all forty-year investment periods, the buy-the-dip strategy underperformed dollar-cost averaging more than 70% of the time.</li>
<li>Even with perfect information, the buy the dip strategy often loses to dollar-cost averaging because the market may continue to rise while you miss out on compounding growth. The author simulates the two strategies using U.S. stock market data from 1975 onward, again proving this conclusion.</li>
<li>Even if the predicted time of the market bottom is off by only two months, the long-term investment performance of the buy-the-dip strategy still loses to dollar-cost averaging.</li>
<li>Conclusion: <strong>you should invest as early as possible and as often as possible</strong>.</li>
<li>Investment returns are heavily influenced by time, and the power of strategy is far less than the power of market change.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chapter 15. Why Does Investing Involve Luck? 
    <div id="chapter-15-why-does-investing-involve-luck" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chapter-15-why-does-investing-involve-luck" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>And why you shouldn&rsquo;t care.</p>
<ul>
<li>The year you were born influences your investment returns because markets fluctuate unpredictably. The author illustrates this with data on 10-, 20-, and 30-year investment returns in the U.S. stock market since 1910.</li>
<li>The sequence of investment returns also affects your final return because you invest more money in the later stages of your investment, so later returns are more important. The author illustrates the impact of return sequence with two cases of 20-year investment horizons with the same annualized return but in reverse order.</li>
<li>How to mitigate bad luck:
<ul>
<li>Hold low-risk assets (such as bonds) for the long term to diversify risk.</li>
<li>Withdraw less money during market downturns.</li>
<li>Consider getting a part-time job to supplement your income.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chapter 16. Why You Shouldn&rsquo;t Fear Market Volatility? 
    <div id="chapter-16-why-you-shouldnt-fear-market-volatility" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chapter-16-why-you-shouldnt-fear-market-volatility" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>The price of admission for successful investing.</p>
<ul>
<li>Avoiding too many market declines can limit your upside.</li>
<li>Using the analogy of a &ldquo;market genie&rdquo; that tells you the maximum intra-year drawdown for the coming year, the author simulates different risk aversion strategies. The conclusion is that if you want to maximize long-term wealth, you should accept some degree of intra-year market decline (0% to 15%) and avoid large intra-year market declines (greater than 15%).</li>
<li>Buying a diversified portfolio of income-producing assets over the long term is one of the best ways to combat market volatility as it rears its ugly head.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chapter 17. How to Buy During a Crisis? 
    <div id="chapter-17-how-to-buy-during-a-crisis" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chapter-17-how-to-buy-during-a-crisis" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>Why you should keep your cool when the market panics?</p>
<ul>
<li>Market crashes are opportunities to buy because every dollar you invest at this point will earn a higher return after the market recovers. The author uses the 1929 U.S. stock market crash as an example to illustrate the excess returns of investing at the bottom of the market.</li>
<li>The more the market falls, the higher the return you need to make up for the loss. The author illustrates this with a simple mathematical formula and chart.</li>
<li>Even if the market takes a long time to recover, buying during a crisis is still a good decision because you can earn a decent annualized return while you wait. The author proves this conclusion using examples of the U.S. stock market falling 30% and 50% between 1920 and 2020.</li>
<li>Most stock markets trend upwards most of the time, and even if a prolonged downturn occurs, the likelihood of losing money is significantly reduced if you make regular investments as most investors do, rather than a single lump sum investment. The author illustrates this with the example of the Japanese stock market.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chapter 18. When Should You Sell? 
    <div id="chapter-18-when-should-you-sell" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chapter-18-when-should-you-sell" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>About rebalancing, concentrated positions, and the purpose of investing.</p>
<ul>
<li>Three situations where you should consider selling an investment asset:
<ul>
<li>Rebalancing your portfolio.</li>
<li>Getting rid of a concentrated (or consistently losing) investment position.</li>
<li>Meeting your financial needs.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>You should have a plan in place before you consider selling investment assets to avoid emotional decisions.</li>
<li>Selling gradually (or selling later) is generally better than selling immediately, because in the long run, the market tends to go up.</li>
<li>Regularly rebalancing your portfolio can reduce risk, but it generally reduces returns. The author simulates two strategies, annual rebalancing and never rebalancing, using a portfolio of 60% stocks/40% bonds, and compares the returns and maximum drawdowns after 30 years.</li>
<li>Accumulative rebalancing is a better way to rebalance by buying asset classes that are underweight over time to avoid incurring tax liabilities. The author uses the same portfolio to simulate a strategy of adding investments each month, demonstrating that this strategy can effectively reduce the maximum drawdown.</li>
<li>For investors holding large concentrated positions, it is advisable to sell some of the assets to reduce risk and meet their own living needs. Selling strategies can range from selling a portion on a regular basis to selling based on price levels, as long as it is decided in advance.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chapter 19. Where Should Your Investments Be Held? 
    <div id="chapter-19-where-should-your-investments-be-held" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chapter-19-where-should-your-investments-be-held" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>On taxes, traditional 401(k) vs. Roth 401(k), and why you might not want to maximize your 401(k).</p>
<ul>
<li>Tax policy in the United States is constantly changing, and financial management should also be adjusted according to tax policy. The author reviews the history of income tax in the United States to illustrate this point.</li>
<li>When choosing between a traditional 401(k) and a Roth 401(k), the most important factor is whether your effective income tax rate is higher now (during your working years) or later (in retirement).</li>
<li>The author favors traditional 401(k)s because they offer more flexibility and allow you to convert funds to a Roth IRA when tax rates are lower, such as when you are in business school or on maternity leave.</li>
<li>Roth 401(k)s may be a better option for high savers because they can enjoy greater total tax deferral benefits. The author illustrates this with the example of Sally and Sam.</li>
<li>Using a retirement savings account to invest can avoid capital gains taxes, which can lead to significant long-term gains. The author uses simulated data to compare the returns of three approaches: tax-free accounts, accounts taxed once on capital gains, and accounts taxed annually on capital gains. The author also explains the impact of compounding on investment returns.</li>
<li>Maximizing your 401(k) may not be the best option because 401(k) plan fees may offset the tax benefits. The author suggests that you should at least increase your personal contributions to the point where you can receive the maximum employer match. For any contributions beyond that, you need to take into account the 401(k)&rsquo;s expense ratio and your own need for liquidity.</li>
<li>When allocating assets, it is advisable to place high-growth assets (e.g. stocks) in tax-advantaged accounts and low-growth assets (e.g. bonds) in taxable accounts.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chapter 20. Why Will You Never Feel Rich? 
    <div id="chapter-20-why-will-you-never-feel-rich" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chapter-20-why-will-you-never-feel-rich" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>You might already be rich, so why not?</p>
<ul>
<li>People can always find someone richer than themselves, so it&rsquo;s hard to feel content. The author illustrates people&rsquo;s sense of relative wealth by telling the story of Powerball lottery winner Jack Whittaker, and the story of his friend John.</li>
<li>If you compare yourself to people around the world, you may find that you are much richer than you think. For example, if your net worth is over $4,210, you are wealthier than half the world; if your net worth is over $93,170, you are in the top 10% of the world&rsquo;s wealth.</li>
<li>Don&rsquo;t let feelings of relative wealth affect your happiness and appreciate the wealth you have.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chapter 21. The Most Important Asset 
    <div id="chapter-21-the-most-important-asset" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chapter-21-the-most-important-asset" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>Why you can never get more of this asset.</p>
<ul>
<li>Time is your most important asset, and how you use your time will have a huge impact on your future life. The author tells the story of Dashrath Manjhi, an Indian villager who carved a road through a mountain, to illustrate the power of time.</li>
<li>In your younger years, you should prioritize career development because that&rsquo;s when your income grows the fastest. The author uses his own experience to illustrate the importance of making the right career choices early on.</li>
<li>Don&rsquo;t sacrifice your time in pursuit of money, because you can never buy more time with money.</li>
<li>People&rsquo;s happiness tends to follow a U-shaped curve as they age, overestimating their future happiness in their youth, being more pessimistic in middle age, and feeling pleasantly surprised in old age.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Conclusion. The Just Keep Buying Rules 
    <div id="conclusion-the-just-keep-buying-rules" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#conclusion-the-just-keep-buying-rules" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>How to win the time traveler&rsquo;s game?</p>
<ul>
<li>The author summarizes 21 financial guidelines to help you succeed on your financial journey, these guidelines are called the &ldquo;Just Keep Buying Rules&rdquo;:
<ol>
<li>The poor should focus on saving, and the rich should focus on investing.</li>
<li>Save what you can save.</li>
<li>Focus on income, not expenses.</li>
<li>Use the &ldquo;2x rule&rdquo; to eliminate spending guilt.</li>
<li>Save at least 50% of your future raises and bonuses.</li>
<li>Debt is not necessarily a good thing or a bad thing, it depends on how you use it.</li>
<li>Only buy a house when the timing is right.</li>
<li>Use cash when saving for large purchases.</li>
<li>There&rsquo;s more to retirement than just money.</li>
<li>Invest to accumulate financial capital to replace your diminishing human capital.</li>
<li>Think like an owner and buy income-producing assets.</li>
<li>Don&rsquo;t buy individual stocks.</li>
<li>Buy fast, sell slow.</li>
<li>Invest as early and as often as possible.</li>
<li>Investing is not just about the cards you have, it&rsquo;s also about how you play them.</li>
<li>Don&rsquo;t be afraid when volatility inevitably comes.</li>
<li>Market crashes are usually opportunities to buy.</li>
<li>Use your money for the life you need before risking it for the life you want.</li>
<li>Think twice before maximizing your 401(k).</li>
<li>You&rsquo;ll never feel rich, and that&rsquo;s okay.</li>
<li>Time is your most important asset.</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">III. Quotes 
    <div id="iii-quotes" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii-quotes" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>The surest way to get rich is to increase your income and invest in income-producing assets.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Analysis: Instead of blindly pursuing saving, it is better to focus your energy on increasing your income and investing in assets that can generate income; this is a more reliable path to financial freedom.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The only right way to spend money is the way that works for you.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Analysis: Everyone&rsquo;s values, life goals, and preferences are different, so their financial management style should also be personalized. Don&rsquo;t blindly follow the crowd; find a spending pattern that suits you in order to achieve true happiness.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Time is your most important asset.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Analysis: Time is a non-renewable resource. We should cherish time and spend it on the most valuable things. Investing early is not only about accumulating wealth, but also about buying back more time and freedom.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">IV. Guiding Significance 
    <div id="iv-guiding-significance" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv-guiding-significance" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<ul>
<li><strong>Establishing the right financial mindset:</strong> This book helps us understand the essence of personal finance and how to develop a sound savings and investment plan, avoiding common financial pitfalls.</li>
<li><strong>Enhancing personal competitiveness:</strong> The book emphasizes the importance of increasing income and encourages us to continuously learn and improve our personal skills to gain greater career development space.</li>
<li><strong>Balancing life and wealth:</strong> The author reminds us that wealth is not the only goal in life. We should focus on the quality of life and the realization of personal values while pursuing wealth.</li>
<li><strong>Viewing investment rationally:</strong> This book emphasizes the importance of long-term investing and warns investors not to blindly chase short-term gains or be intimidated by market volatility. Only rationality and patience can ultimately lead to success.</li>
</ul>

  



<div
  
    class="flex px-4 py-3 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900"
  >

  <span
    
      class="text-primary-400 ltr:pr-3 rtl:pl-3 flex items-center"
    >

    

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 640 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M172.5 131.1C228.1 75.51 320.5 75.51 376.1 131.1C426.1 181.1 433.5 260.8 392.4 318.3L391.3 319.9C381 334.2 361 337.6 346.7 327.3C332.3 317 328.9 297 339.2 282.7L340.3 281.1C363.2 249 359.6 205.1 331.7 177.2C300.3 145.8 249.2 145.8 217.7 177.2L105.5 289.5C73.99 320.1 73.99 372 105.5 403.5C133.3 431.4 177.3 435 209.3 412.1L210.9 410.1C225.3 400.7 245.3 404 255.5 418.4C265.8 432.8 262.5 452.8 248.1 463.1L246.5 464.2C188.1 505.3 110.2 498.7 60.21 448.8C3.741 392.3 3.741 300.7 60.21 244.3L172.5 131.1zM467.5 380C411 436.5 319.5 436.5 263 380C213 330 206.5 251.2 247.6 193.7L248.7 192.1C258.1 177.8 278.1 174.4 293.3 184.7C307.7 194.1 311.1 214.1 300.8 229.3L299.7 230.9C276.8 262.1 280.4 306.9 308.3 334.8C339.7 366.2 390.8 366.2 422.3 334.8L534.5 222.5C566 191 566 139.1 534.5 108.5C506.7 80.63 462.7 76.99 430.7 99.9L429.1 101C414.7 111.3 394.7 107.1 384.5 93.58C374.2 79.2 377.5 59.21 391.9 48.94L393.5 47.82C451 6.731 529.8 13.25 579.8 63.24C636.3 119.7 636.3 211.3 579.8 267.7L467.5 380z"/></svg>

  </span>


  </span>

  <span
    
      class="dark:text-neutral-300"
    ><strong>Further Reading</strong>: Check out the author, <strong>Nick Maggiulli</strong>&rsquo;s blog: <a href="https://ofdollarsanddata.com/" target="_blank"><strong>Of Dollars And Data</strong></a></span>
</div>

<hr>

<section class="space-y-10 w-full">
    
    
        
            






















  <a class="flex flex-wrap article " href="/en/posts/1728295490690-book-list/">
    
        
        <div class="w-full md:w-auto h-full thumbnail nozoom thumbnailshadow md:mr-7" style="background-image:url(/posts/1728295490690-book-list/featured_hu4424409690304057825.jpg);"></div>
        
      <div class=" mt-3 md:mt-0">
      <div class="items-center text-left text-xl font-semibold">
        
        <div class="font-bold text-xl text-neutral-800 decoration-primary-500 hover:underline hover:underline-offset-2 dark:text-neutral"
          href="/en/posts/1728295490690-book-list/">Recommended Reading List</div>
        
        
        
      </div>
      <div class="text-sm text-neutral-500 dark:text-neutral-400">
        











  









  



  









<div class="flex flex-row flex-wrap items-center">
  
  
  <time datetime="2024-10-01T00:00:00&#43;00:00">1 October 2024</time><span class="px-2 text-primary-500">&middot;</span><span>
  
  
    
    
      
      
        
        
      
        
        
      
      
    
  
  <span id="views_posts/1728295490690-book-list/index.md" class="animate-pulse inline-block text-transparent max-h-3 rounded-full mt-[-2px] align-middle bg-neutral-300 dark:bg-neutral-400" title="views">loading</span>
  <span class="inline-block align-text-bottom">

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 576 512">
<path fill="currentColor" d="M288 32c-80.8 0-145.5 36.8-192.6 80.6C48.6 156 17.3 208 2.5 243.7c-3.3 7.9-3.3 16.7 0 24.6C17.3 304 48.6 356 95.4 399.4C142.5 443.2 207.2 480 288 480s145.5-36.8 192.6-80.6c46.8-43.5 78.1-95.4 93-131.1c3.3-7.9 3.3-16.7 0-24.6c-14.9-35.7-46.2-87.7-93-131.1C433.5 68.8 368.8 32 288 32zM432 256c0 79.5-64.5 144-144 144s-144-64.5-144-144s64.5-144 144-144s144 64.5 144 144zM288 192c0 35.3-28.7 64-64 64c-11.5 0-22.3-3-31.6-8.4c-.2 2.8-.4 5.5-.4 8.4c0 53 43 96 96 96s96-43 96-96s-43-96-96-96c-2.8 0-5.6 .1-8.4 .4c5.3 9.3 8.4 20.1 8.4 31.6z"/></svg>
  </span>

</span>
</span><span class="px-2 text-primary-500">&middot;</span><span>
  
  
    
    
      
      
        
        
      
        
        
      
      
    
  
  <span id="likes_posts/1728295490690-book-list/index.md"
    class="animate-pulse inline-block text-transparent max-h-3 rounded-full mt-[-2px] align-middle bg-neutral-300 dark:bg-neutral-400"
    title="likes">loading</span>
  <span class="inline-block align-text-bottom">

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512">
<path fill="currentColor" d="M47.6 300.4L228.3 469.1c7.5 7 17.4 10.9 27.7 10.9s20.2-3.9 27.7-10.9L464.4 300.4c30.4-28.3 47.6-68 47.6-109.5v-5.8c0-69.9-50.5-129.5-119.4-141C347 36.5 300.6 51.4 268 84L256 96 244 84c-32.6-32.6-79-47.5-124.6-39.9C50.5 55.6 0 115.2 0 185.1v5.8c0 41.5 17.2 81.2 47.6 109.5z"/></svg>
  </span>

</span>
</span>
  

  
  
</div>





<div class="flex flex-row flex-wrap items-center">
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  <span style="margin-top:0.5rem" class="mr-2" onclick="window.open(&#34;/en/tags/recommended/&#34;,'_self');">
    <span class="flex" style="cursor: pointer;">
  <span class="rounded-md border border-primary-400 px-1 py-[1px] text-xs font-normal text-primary-700 dark:border-primary-600 dark:text-primary-400">
    Recommended
  </span>
</span>
  </span>
  
  <span style="margin-top:0.5rem" class="mr-2" onclick="window.open(&#34;/en/tags/book/&#34;,'_self');">
    <span class="flex" style="cursor: pointer;">
  <span class="rounded-md border border-primary-400 px-1 py-[1px] text-xs font-normal text-primary-700 dark:border-primary-600 dark:text-primary-400">
    Book
  </span>
</span>
  </span>
  
  
  
  
</div>




      </div>
      
    </div>
  </a>

        
    
</section>
]]></content:encoded></item></channel></rss>