<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>QQQ Investor</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/</link><description>Recent content on QQQ Investor</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jomonylw.github.io/en/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Millionaire Teacher：Book Notes</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1728295541698/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1728295541698/</guid><description>Andrew Hallam, the author of this book, started investing at the age of 19 and achieved millionaire status within 17 years on a teacher&amp;#39;s salary. He shares nine financial principles that anyone can learn, yet few are taught in school. Through real-life stories and personal experiences, he guides readers on how to avoid common investment pitfalls and achieve financial freedom using the simplest, safest, and most effective methods.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[

<h2 class="relative group">I. Summary 
    <div id="i-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This book reveals a financial secret that everyone can learn but is rarely taught in school: <strong>You don&rsquo;t have to be a finance expert or a high-income earner to achieve financial freedom; prudent spending and rational investing are all it takes, even on a modest income.</strong></p>
<p>The author, Andrew Hallam, is a high school English teacher who started investing at age 19 and became a millionaire by age 38. He distilled his years of investment experience and wisdom he garnered from numerous financial wizards into nine simple and actionable principles. Supported by factual cases and personal anecdotes, he guides readers step-by-step towards financial freedom.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">II. Chapter Summaries 
    <div id="ii-chapter-summaries" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii-chapter-summaries" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Lesson One: Spend Like You Want to Grow Rich 
    <div id="lesson-one-spend-like-you-want-to-grow-rich" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#lesson-one-spend-like-you-want-to-grow-rich" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Distinguish between &ldquo;wants&rdquo; and &ldquo;needs&rdquo;</strong>: Spend rationally, control unnecessary expenses, and avoid over-reliance on credit cards. Invest the money you save.
<ul>
<li>Example: In his youth, the author lived an extremely frugal life to pay off his student loans as quickly as possible, succeeding within a year and subsequently investing all his income.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>How to buy a car for less</strong>: Opt for low-mileage, easy-to-resell used cars instead of blindly pursuing luxury vehicles.
<ul>
<li>Example: The author purchased low-mileage used Japanese cars in his youth and sold them for the same or even higher price after a few years, turning a small profit.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Buying a house: It&rsquo;s not about the down payment, but the interest rate</strong>:  Consider whether you can still afford the mortgage if the interest rate doubles to prevent financial strain due to rising rates.</li>
<li><strong>Start strong, don&rsquo;t rely on a &ldquo;rich dad&rdquo;</strong>:  Excessive financial support from parents can hinder a child&rsquo;s ability to create wealth independently. Teach them financial knowledge and skills, letting them learn how to earn, save, and invest on their own.
<ul>
<li>Example: Studies show that accountants who received financial assistance from their parents had 43% less average wealth than their self-made counterparts.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>You don&rsquo;t have to live like a pauper, but spend like a millionaire</strong>: Frugality does not equate to a lower quality of life. It&rsquo;s about investing the money you save, allowing it to work for you instead of the other way around.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Lesson Two: Use the Greatest Investment Ally You Have 
    <div id="lesson-two-use-the-greatest-investment-ally-you-have" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#lesson-two-use-the-greatest-investment-ally-you-have" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Leverage compound interest to accelerate wealth accumulation</strong>: The earlier you start investing, the longer the time horizon for compound interest to work its magic, leading to faster wealth growth.
<ul>
<li>Example: Investing $45 per month for 40 years yields significantly higher returns than investing $800 per month for only 25 years.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Buffett&rsquo;s &ldquo;Noah&rsquo;s Ark Principle&rdquo;</strong>: Invest early, just like Noah built the ark, don&rsquo;t wait for the &ldquo;flood&rdquo; to arrive before taking action.</li>
<li><strong>What to do when you get paid</strong>:  Keep track of your monthly expenses, calculate the amount available for investment, and transfer that money to your investment account on payday to avoid running out of funds at the end of the month.
<ul>
<li>Example: A couple the author knew, both teachers, realized their wasteful spending habits after tracking their expenses for three months. They subsequently allocated more money to investment, tripling their investment amount within two years.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>The stock market doesn&rsquo;t believe in tears, but it believes in time</strong>:  In the long run, the stock market rises with corporate earnings growth. Therefore, be patient and don&rsquo;t be intimidated by short-term market fluctuations. The author&rsquo;s stock market investments from 1990 had increased tenfold by 2016.
<ul>
<li>Example: Using Willy Wonka&rsquo;s chocolate factory as an analogy, the author explains the fundamentals of stocks, share prices, dividends, and the stock market in a simple and engaging way, highlighting the substantial returns from long-term investment.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Lesson Three: Small Fees Pack Big Punches 
    <div id="lesson-three-small-fees-pack-big-punches" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#lesson-three-small-fees-pack-big-punches" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Index funds: the secret to effortless wealth generation</strong>: Index funds track a specific market index, holding all or most of the stocks in that index to achieve the same return as the market. Their advantages lie in low costs, risk diversification, and stable returns.</li>
<li><strong>&ldquo;The Oracle of Omaha&rdquo; buys index funds</strong>:  Investment gurus like Warren Buffett, Paul Samuelson, and Daniel Kahneman all recommend index funds because they provide market-average returns at the lowest cost, outperforming the vast majority of actively managed funds over the long term.
<ul>
<li>Example: Buffett suggests putting 90% of one&rsquo;s funds into an ultra-low-cost S&amp;P 500 index fund.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>78% of active fund returns go to the advisors&rsquo; pockets</strong>:  The high fees (management fees, transaction costs, commissions, etc.) of actively managed funds will eat up most of the investors&rsquo; gains. Generally, their returns underperform index funds over the long run.
<ul>
<li>Example: The author&rsquo;s wife could have earned an extra $20,000 if she had invested in index funds instead of actively managed funds, as recommended by her financial advisor, over the past five years.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Don&rsquo;t bother picking &ldquo;top actively managed funds&rdquo;</strong>: There is no reliable method to consistently pick actively managed funds that will outperform index funds. Even if a fund has a history of exceptional performance, it doesn&rsquo;t guarantee future success. Their returns tend to revert to the average or lower in the long run.
<ul>
<li>Example: Investors in Morningstar&rsquo;s five-star-rated funds often experience lower long-term returns compared to index fund investors.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>&ldquo;International citizens&rdquo; should opt for index funds</strong>:  Actively managed funds are significantly more expensive outside of the US. Therefore, &ldquo;international citizens&rdquo; should choose index funds to lower their investment costs.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Lesson Four: Conquer the Enemy in the Mirror 
    <div id="lesson-four-conquer-the-enemy-in-the-mirror" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#lesson-four-conquer-the-enemy-in-the-mirror" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Stay rational, earn 10% returns even in a bear market</strong>: Don&rsquo;t let fear and greed dictate your investment decisions. Don&rsquo;t panic sell in a falling market or chase rising prices in a bull market. Stick to regular investment and buy more cheap stocks in a bear market to achieve higher returns in the long run.
<ul>
<li>Example: During the 2008-2009 financial crisis, investors who steadily invested in index funds at the lows ultimately reaped higher returns.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Don&rsquo;t try to time the market</strong>:  No one can accurately predict short-term market trends; don&rsquo;t try to beat the market by timing it. Market timing often causes you to miss the best investment opportunities, leading to lower investment returns.</li>
<li><strong>Earning 150%? Be wary of tech stocks</strong>:  Don&rsquo;t be fooled by high-growth, high-valuation stocks. Stock prices eventually revert to the level justified by corporate earnings. Blindly chasing hot stocks can easily lead to losing your entire investment.
<ul>
<li>Example: The dot-com bubble burst in 1999, causing countless investors to suffer heavy losses. The author himself lost nearly half of his money due to investing in Nortel Networks stock.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Falling stocks: a buying opportunity</strong>:  A bear market is the best time to invest. Seize the opportunity to buy more cheap stocks when prices are low. In the long run, stocks rise with corporate earnings growth.</li>
<li><strong>Young people should be excited when stocks rebound</strong>: Young investors have more time to allow compound interest to work its magic. They should actually hope for market declines to buy more low-priced stocks. Over the long term, stocks bought at a discount offer higher returns.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Lesson Five: Build Mountains of Money with a Responsible Portfolio 
    <div id="lesson-five-build-mountains-of-money-with-a-responsible-portfolio" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#lesson-five-build-mountains-of-money-with-a-responsible-portfolio" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Buy bonds as insurance for your stocks</strong>:  Bonds offer lower returns than stocks but have lower volatility, reducing the overall risk of your portfolio. They act as a buffer when the stock market falls.
<ul>
<li><strong>Short-term bonds: a safe haven for your money</strong>:  Short-term bonds are less sensitive to interest rate fluctuations and are more suitable as a &ldquo;safety cushion&rdquo; for your portfolio.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Adjusting your portfolio to profit from market crashes</strong>:  Determine the appropriate mix of stocks and bonds based on your age and risk tolerance. Rebalance your portfolio regularly (e.g., review it annually), selling bonds to buy stocks in a down market and selling stocks to buy bonds in a bull market.
<ul>
<li>Example: Before the 2008 financial crisis, the author created a portfolio with a 35% bond allocation. During the downturn, he consistently increased his stock holdings. Consequently, he achieved higher returns when the market rebounded.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>&ldquo;Globalize&rdquo; your investment</strong>: Don&rsquo;t limit yourself to the domestic market. Diversify your investments across the globe to further reduce risk and access a wider range of opportunities.</li>
<li><strong>&ldquo;Lazy portfolio&rdquo;: adjust once a year for annual returns</strong>:  Allocate your portfolio equally between stocks and bonds, rebalance once a year. This simple strategy delivers impressive long-term returns without demanding excessive time or effort.
<ul>
<li>Example: Following the &ldquo;Lazy Portfolio&rdquo; strategy allowed investors to achieve positive returns even during the 2008 financial crisis.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Lesson Six: Sample a &ldquo;Round-the-World&rdquo; Ticket to Indexing 
    <div id="lesson-six-sample-a-round-the-world-ticket-to-indexing" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#lesson-six-sample-a-round-the-world-ticket-to-indexing" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>ETFs: Access Global Markets with One Account</strong>:  Exchange-traded funds (ETFs) offer a convenient way to invest in index funds. They are traded on stock exchanges like individual stocks and cover a wide array of global markets.
<ul>
<li><strong>How to buy ETFs?:</strong> The author details the steps involved in buying ETFs: opening a brokerage account, finding the ETF ticker symbol, determining the price per share, and setting the investment amount, etc.</li>
<li><strong>Limit orders vs. market orders:</strong> The author explains these two common ETF order types and recommends using limit orders to avoid losses due to price fluctuations.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>US Indexes: Strategic Allocation for Optimal Returns</strong>:  For US investors, a portfolio split equally between a US stock market index, a global stock market index, and a US bond market index, with annual rebalancing, is recommended for stable long-term returns.
<ul>
<li>Example: The author&rsquo;s friend, Chris, following this approach, grew his portfolio by 73.09% in 10 years despite experiencing the 2008-2009 financial crisis.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Canadian Indexes: Minimize Costs for Maximum Returns</strong>:  Canadians can build a low-cost, diversified global portfolio using TD Bank&rsquo;s &ldquo;e-Series&rdquo; index funds or ETFs.
<ul>
<li>The author uses personal anecdotes to illustrate that Canadian financial advisors are more inclined to recommend actively managed funds while overlooking low-cost index funds.</li>
<li>He uses the example of Air Force Technician, Felix, to demonstrate how investors can build a low-cost, diversified portfolio through TD&rsquo;s &ldquo;e-Series&rdquo; index funds.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>UK Indexes: Avoid High Fees, Optimize your Portfolio</strong>:  UK investors should be wary of high-fee index funds. Building a diversified portfolio using low-cost index funds or ETFs provided by Vanguard or iShares is recommended.
<ul>
<li>The author cites Virgin Money as an example to demonstrate how high fees and tracking errors can significantly affect index fund returns.</li>
<li>He then uses the case of software engineer, Paul, to illustrate how investors can utilize iShares and Vanguard ETFs to build a low-cost, diversified portfolio.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Australian Indexes: Multi-Asset Portfolios, Lower Fees with Higher Investments</strong>:  Australians can opt for Vanguard&rsquo;s multi-asset LifeStrategy funds or utilize platforms like Stockspot and Ignition Wealth to build ETF portfolios.
<ul>
<li>The author shares the story of Andy, a software developer, who uses the Nabtrade brokerage platform to buy ETFs and create a diversified index fund portfolio.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Singapore indexes: Low cost, smart allocation</strong>:  Singaporean investors should also be cautious of high-fee index funds. Building a diversified portfolio using low-cost ETFs offered by Vanguard is recommended, but it&rsquo;s important to avoid ETFs traded on US exchanges to avert US estate taxes.
<ul>
<li>The author utilizes the example of &ldquo;Fundsupermart&rsquo;s&rdquo; &ldquo;S&amp;P 500 index&rdquo; fund to illustrate how high fees significantly impact long-term investment returns.</li>
<li>He further uses the case of a professor couple to show how investors can construct a diversified portfolio using ETFs traded on Singaporean and Canadian exchanges, thus avoiding US estate taxes.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Lesson Seven: No, You Don&rsquo;t Have to Invest on Your Own 
    <div id="lesson-seven-no-you-dont-have-to-invest-on-your-own" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#lesson-seven-no-you-dont-have-to-invest-on-your-own" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Why do index investors lag behind the index?:</strong> Many investors fall prey to their emotions, making irrational decisions during market fluctuations, or are swayed by investment predictions, ultimately hindering their returns.
<ul>
<li>Example: Some investors panic sell during market downturns and chase rising prices in a bull market, resulting in returns far lower than the index itself.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>US Robo-Advisors: Let the Smart Investors &ldquo;Win&rdquo; Effortlessly</strong>: Robo-advisor platforms can help investors create and manage low-cost index fund portfolios, rebalancing them regularly, and preventing investors from damaging their accounts.
<ul>
<li>Example: Vanguard&rsquo;s Target Retirement Funds offer a one-stop solution at a very low cost, suitable for those who prefer a hands-off approach to investment.
<ul>
<li>The author uses his wife as an example to highlight the advantages of Vanguard Target Retirement Funds: achieving positive returns even without investment knowledge.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Vanguard&rsquo;s Comprehensive Financial Advisory Services:</strong> Vanguard provides comprehensive financial planning services at a low cost, making it a good option for investors seeking professional advice.</li>
<li><strong>Investment Guidance Training Services:</strong> Mark Zoril of PlanVision offers training services that guide investors to open low-cost brokerage accounts and build their own index fund portfolios.</li>
<li><strong>Investment Enhancement Services:</strong> Scott Burns of AssetBuilder provides investment enhancement services, using Dimensional Fund Advisors (DFA) index funds to help investors build a &ldquo;Lazy Portfolio&rdquo;.
<ul>
<li>The author elaborates on DFA&rsquo;s investment philosophy: pursuing excess returns through small-cap and value stocks.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Betterment, Rebalance IRA, SigFig, and Wealthfront:</strong> These companies also offer robo-advisory services, building and managing portfolios consisting of index funds or ETFs for investors.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Canadian Robo-Advisors: Lower Cost and More Targeted:</strong> Robo-advisor platforms in Canada, such as WealthBar and Wealthsimple, offer lower-cost, personalized services, tailoring portfolios to suit client risk tolerance and investment goals.
<ul>
<li>The author uses personal experiences to demonstrate that Canadian bank advisors still favor actively managed funds over low-cost index funds.</li>
<li><strong>Tangerine:</strong> Tangerine bank provides Canadian investors with a financial product that encompasses a diversified index fund portfolio. Low cost makes it suitable for those who prefer to invest small sums regularly.
<ul>
<li>The author uses 19-year-old Katie as an example to show how young people can leverage Tangerine&rsquo;s investment products for regular investing.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>WealthBar:</strong> WealthBar offers Canadian investors five portfolio management solutions and provides comprehensive financial planning based on their risk tolerance.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>UK Robo-Advisors: Diversified Index Fund Baskets</strong>: UK robo-advisor platforms, like Nutmeg, construct diverse index fund portfolios for investors, rebalancing regularly, although their fees are comparatively higher.</li>
<li><strong>Australian Robo-Advisors: Increasing Competition and Falling Fees</strong>: The Australian robo-advisor market is highly competitive with decreasing fees. Platforms like Stockspot and Ignition Wealth offer low-cost, personalized ETF portfolio management services.</li>
<li><strong>Singapore Robo-Advisors: Avoid &ldquo;Suicidal&rdquo; Asset Allocation:</strong>  Singapore&rsquo;s robo-advisory market is nascent. Investors should opt for companies that don&rsquo;t utilize ETFs traded on US exchanges to avoid US estate tax liabilities.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Lesson Eight: Peek Inside A Pilferer’s Playbook 
    <div id="lesson-eight-peek-inside-a-pilferers-playbook" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#lesson-eight-peek-inside-a-pilferers-playbook" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Identifying Financial Advisors&rsquo; Tricks:</strong> Financial advisors use various tactics to persuade investors to buy actively managed funds, such as claiming that &ldquo;index funds are more dangerous during downturns&rdquo; or that &ldquo;index funds can only achieve average returns,&rdquo; both of which are misleading.
<ul>
<li>Examples:  When the author and his friend sought advice from financial advisors, they were aggressively steered towards actively managed funds without mention of their high fees or lower returns. One advisor even claimed index funds were riskier and that actively managed funds were better suited for navigating bear markets.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Index Fund Returns Outshine &ldquo;Financial Elites&rdquo;</strong>: Even seasoned investment professionals like pension fund managers struggle to beat index fund returns. Many pension funds have started shifting towards indexed investments, allocating a significant portion of their funds to index funds.
<ul>
<li>Example: A study by US consulting firm FutureMetrics revealed that less than 30% of large corporate pension funds outperformed a diversified portfolio holding 60% S&amp;P 500 index and 40% corporate bond index.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Don&rsquo;t Accidentally Become a &ldquo;Second-Rate Investor&rdquo;</strong>:  Don&rsquo;t be fooled by financial advisors&rsquo; sales pitches. Trust the data and facts - index funds are the most reliable way to profit in the stock market. Advisors&rsquo; interests are often at odds with those of their clients; they prioritize commission income over investor returns.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Lesson Nine: Avoid Seduction 
    <div id="lesson-nine-avoid-seduction" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#lesson-nine-avoid-seduction" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Stock Picking Scams: Do their stock recommendations really work?:</strong>  Investment newsletter predictions are often inaccurate, and their recommended stocks are likely to lead to financial ruin. Their primary goal is to attract subscribers, not to help investors make money.
<ul>
<li>Example: The author invested in stocks recommended by &ldquo;The Gilder Technology Report&rdquo; and suffered significant losses.  The author of that report continues to publish similar reports, using the lure of high past returns to attract investors.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Investing in Emerging Markets: Don&rsquo;t be fooled by GDP</strong>: High economic growth does not necessarily translate into high stock market returns. Be cautious when investing in emerging markets. They are more volatile and risky, and their long-term returns may not surpass developed markets.
<ul>
<li>Example: While China&rsquo;s GDP grew rapidly from 2008 to 2016, its stock market performance was lackluster, with investors in a large-cap Chinese stock ETF experiencing a 30% loss.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>&ldquo;Gold speculation&rdquo;: It&rsquo;s not investing</strong>: Gold has a low long-term return rate with high price volatility, making it unsuitable for long-term investment. &ldquo;Gold speculators&rdquo; attempt to profit from price differences by buying low and selling high, a risky strategy that cannot guarantee stable long-term returns.
<ul>
<li>Example: $1 worth of gold purchased in 1801 would only be worth $73 in 2016, whereas a $1 investment in the US stock market during the same period would turn into $16.24 million.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Investment Magazines: The Untold Truth</strong>:  Investment magazines rely heavily on advertising revenue, leading them to cater to their advertisers rather than prioritize investors&rsquo; needs. They often recommend high-fee actively managed funds while neglecting low-cost index funds.
<ul>
<li>Example: In April 2009, &ldquo;SmartMoney&rdquo; magazine recommended bond funds and gold, ignoring the investment opportunity presented by low-priced stocks amidst the financial crisis.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Hedge Funds: Picking the Pockets of the Rich</strong>: Hedge funds charge exorbitant fees and carry significant risks, with long-term returns that are often no better, and sometimes even worse, than index funds. Their reported performance is often skewed by &ldquo;survivorship bias&rdquo; and &ldquo;backfill bias.&rdquo;
<ul>
<li>Example: Hedge funds struggle to achieve an average annual compounded return of even 1%.  Only one out of the top 20 largest hedge funds has outperformed the S&amp;P 500 index.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Don&rsquo;t buy currency-hedged ETFs</strong>: Currency-hedged ETFs  aim to eliminate the impact of exchange rate fluctuations on investment returns. However, the hedging mechanism itself incurs costs, decreasing a portfolio&rsquo;s returns.
<ul>
<li>Example: Research indicates that non-currency-hedged ETFs generally outperform their currency-hedged counterparts over the long term.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Don&rsquo;t fall for smart beta funds</strong>: These hybrid funds fall somewhere between active and index funds, attempting to achieve excess returns with specific strategies. Their effectiveness is debated, and their fees are generally higher.
<ul>
<li>Example:  Studies show that the market capitalization growth of smart beta funds has been primarily due to valuation increases, not corporate earnings growth, suggesting potential decreases in future returns.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Don&rsquo;t blindly buy into small-cap stocks</strong>:  Small-cap stocks, those of smaller companies, offer high growth potential, but also carry higher risk. Investing in them requires careful consideration and risk tolerance; avoid chasing high returns blindly.</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">III. Key Quotes 
    <div id="iii-key-quotes" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii-key-quotes" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>You don&rsquo;t have to be a financial expert; even with a moderate income, you can achieve financial freedom through prudent spending and rational investing.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This encapsulates the core message of the book:  financial management and investment are not exclusive to the wealthy; ordinary people can also achieve financial freedom through learning and practical application.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Time is money.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This emphasizes that time is our most valuable asset. The earlier you start investing, the longer the time horizon for compound interest to work its magic, leading to faster wealth accumulation.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>A successful investor should follow two principles: the first is to never lose money and the second is to never forget the first principle.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This quote highlights the importance of risk management and capital preservation in investing.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The investor&rsquo;s task is to focus on the horse, not the jockey.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This means that investors should prioritize a company&rsquo;s intrinsic value over the fund manager&rsquo;s individual ability. Over the long run, a company&rsquo;s profitability is the most important factor determining its stock price.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>If you plan to live off hamburgers for the rest of your life, but you don&rsquo;t own any cattle, would you want beef prices to go up or down?</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Buffett used this analogy to illustrate that stocks represent ownership in a company. When share prices fall, long-term investors should view it as an opportunity to buy more shares.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The most insidious devil is the high cost associated with holding certain actively managed funds.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This quote emphasizes that investment costs are one of the most important factors affecting investment returns. Choosing low-cost index funds maximizes gains.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>How much you can accumulate in your lifetime depends not on how much you can earn, but on how you invest. Money finds people more effectively than people find money. Let your money work for you, not the other way around.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Buffett stresses the importance of investment and financial management, pointing out that wealth accumulation relies not only on income but also on how you manage and invest your money.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Too much money can harm investment returns.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This seemingly paradoxical statement highlights a critical principle: avoid over-diversification and the blind pursuit of high returns. Concentrating your investments in a few high-quality assets and holding them for the long term often yields better results.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>In stock investing, luck inevitably plays a role, but in the long run, good luck and bad luck offset each other. For sustained success, skills and sound principles are essential.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This emphasizes that the key to successful investing lies in mastering the correct investment philosophy and principles and adhering to them in the long term, rather than relying on luck.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Let time and money work for you; you just need to sit back and wait for the results.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This emphasizes the power of long-term investment and compound interest. By choosing the right investment method and being patient, significant returns will follow.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">IV. Practical Implications 
    <div id="iv-practical-implications" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv-practical-implications" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This book&rsquo;s key takeaways include:</p>
<ol>
<li><strong>Developing a sound financial mindset</strong>: Understand the importance of thrift, control unnecessary spending, and invest your savings.</li>
<li><strong>Mastering simple and effective investment methods</strong>: Learn to leverage compound interest, start investing early, choose low-cost index funds, and commit to long-term investments. Avoid being swayed by short-term market volatility.</li>
<li><strong>Avoiding common investment pitfalls</strong>:  Be wary of financial advisors&rsquo; sales tactics, don&rsquo;t blindly trust investment predictions or stock recommendations, and avoid being lured by the promise of high returns.</li>
<li><strong>Developing financial independence</strong>: Learn basic financial knowledge and skills, don&rsquo;t rely solely on financial advisors, and learn to make investment decisions independently.</li>
</ol>
<hr>

<section class="space-y-10 w-full">
    
    
        
            






















  <a class="flex flex-wrap article " href="/en/posts/1728295490690-book-list/">
    
        
        <div class="w-full md:w-auto h-full thumbnail nozoom thumbnailshadow md:mr-7" style="background-image:url(/posts/1728295490690-book-list/featured_hu4424409690304057825.jpg);"></div>
        
      <div class=" mt-3 md:mt-0">
      <div class="items-center text-left text-xl font-semibold">
        
        <div class="font-bold text-xl text-neutral-800 decoration-primary-500 hover:underline hover:underline-offset-2 dark:text-neutral"
          href="/en/posts/1728295490690-book-list/">Recommended Reading List</div>
        
        
        
      </div>
      <div class="text-sm text-neutral-500 dark:text-neutral-400">
        











  









  



  









<div class="flex flex-row flex-wrap items-center">
  
  
  <time datetime="2024-10-01T00:00:00&#43;00:00">1 October 2024</time><span class="px-2 text-primary-500">&middot;</span><span>
  
  
    
    
      
      
        
        
      
        
        
      
      
    
  
  <span id="views_posts/1728295490690-book-list/index.md" class="animate-pulse inline-block text-transparent max-h-3 rounded-full mt-[-2px] align-middle bg-neutral-300 dark:bg-neutral-400" title="views">loading</span>
  <span class="inline-block align-text-bottom">

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 576 512">
<path fill="currentColor" d="M288 32c-80.8 0-145.5 36.8-192.6 80.6C48.6 156 17.3 208 2.5 243.7c-3.3 7.9-3.3 16.7 0 24.6C17.3 304 48.6 356 95.4 399.4C142.5 443.2 207.2 480 288 480s145.5-36.8 192.6-80.6c46.8-43.5 78.1-95.4 93-131.1c3.3-7.9 3.3-16.7 0-24.6c-14.9-35.7-46.2-87.7-93-131.1C433.5 68.8 368.8 32 288 32zM432 256c0 79.5-64.5 144-144 144s-144-64.5-144-144s64.5-144 144-144s144 64.5 144 144zM288 192c0 35.3-28.7 64-64 64c-11.5 0-22.3-3-31.6-8.4c-.2 2.8-.4 5.5-.4 8.4c0 53 43 96 96 96s96-43 96-96s-43-96-96-96c-2.8 0-5.6 .1-8.4 .4c5.3 9.3 8.4 20.1 8.4 31.6z"/></svg>
  </span>

</span>
</span><span class="px-2 text-primary-500">&middot;</span><span>
  
  
    
    
      
      
        
        
      
        
        
      
      
    
  
  <span id="likes_posts/1728295490690-book-list/index.md"
    class="animate-pulse inline-block text-transparent max-h-3 rounded-full mt-[-2px] align-middle bg-neutral-300 dark:bg-neutral-400"
    title="likes">loading</span>
  <span class="inline-block align-text-bottom">

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512">
<path fill="currentColor" d="M47.6 300.4L228.3 469.1c7.5 7 17.4 10.9 27.7 10.9s20.2-3.9 27.7-10.9L464.4 300.4c30.4-28.3 47.6-68 47.6-109.5v-5.8c0-69.9-50.5-129.5-119.4-141C347 36.5 300.6 51.4 268 84L256 96 244 84c-32.6-32.6-79-47.5-124.6-39.9C50.5 55.6 0 115.2 0 185.1v5.8c0 41.5 17.2 81.2 47.6 109.5z"/></svg>
  </span>

</span>
</span>
  

  
  
</div>





<div class="flex flex-row flex-wrap items-center">
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  <span style="margin-top:0.5rem" class="mr-2" onclick="window.open(&#34;/en/tags/recommended/&#34;,'_self');">
    <span class="flex" style="cursor: pointer;">
  <span class="rounded-md border border-primary-400 px-1 py-[1px] text-xs font-normal text-primary-700 dark:border-primary-600 dark:text-primary-400">
    Recommended
  </span>
</span>
  </span>
  
  <span style="margin-top:0.5rem" class="mr-2" onclick="window.open(&#34;/en/tags/book/&#34;,'_self');">
    <span class="flex" style="cursor: pointer;">
  <span class="rounded-md border border-primary-400 px-1 py-[1px] text-xs font-normal text-primary-700 dark:border-primary-600 dark:text-primary-400">
    Book
  </span>
</span>
  </span>
  
  
  
  
</div>




      </div>
      
    </div>
  </a>

        
    
</section>
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>00486 Market Trends and Future Investment Strategies:Navigating the New Economic Era</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1728231523948/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1728231523948/</guid><description>In this session, James shares his analysis of the current market situation and investment advice. He also answers questions from the audience on topics like asset allocation, retirement planning, children&amp;#39;s education, handling stock options, leverage, and tax planning.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<lite-youtube videoid="mwchPrvkFMA" playlabel="mwchPrvkFMA" params=""></lite-youtube>



<h2 class="relative group">I. Main Topic 
    <div id="i-main-topic" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-main-topic" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>The theme of this session is <strong>Embrace the New Bull Market and Invest Long-Term.</strong> James believes that the global monetary easing policy and the rapid development of AI technology herald the arrival of a new bull market. He advises everyone to invest in the Nasdaq 100 index fund (QQQ or 00662) and view market fluctuations with a long-term perspective.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">II.  Content Summary 
    <div id="ii--content-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii--content-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<ul>
<li><strong>A new bull market is coming:</strong>  The world has entered an era of loose monetary policy with the start of a rate cut cycle, which will drive the stock market up. This bull market may be a slow one but will continuously rise.</li>
<li><strong>Invest confidently in the Nasdaq 100 index fund:</strong> QQQ could increase by 50 times in the next 20 years, with an annualized return of over 20%, making it the best investment target.</li>
<li><strong>Individual stocks are unreliable:</strong> Individual stock investment is risky, and in the long run, almost all of them will disappear. They are very difficult to outperform the market in the long term. It is recommended not to waste time and energy on stock selection.</li>
<li><strong>Do not invest in the Chinese stock market:</strong> The Chinese stock market is not mature enough; consider investing in it after 30 years.</li>
<li><strong>Comparison of household asset allocation in the US and Taiwan:</strong>  American families invest most of their assets in securities to create social value, while Taiwanese families prefer cash, insurance, and real estate, locking up funds in non-appreciating areas.</li>
<li><strong>Leveraging through stock pledges:</strong> Using stock pledges to borrow increases liquidity and allows for continued investment to enjoy the benefits of compound growth. With an understanding of asset allocation, the interest cost of borrowing can be almost negligible.</li>
<li><strong>Plan for retirement early:</strong> Young people are advised to invest in 00662, and retirees can choose 00646 (SPY) or 0056 according to their fund size.</li>
<li><strong>Emphasize family education:</strong> Parents should cultivate their children&rsquo;s financial management concepts from an early age, guide them to make long-term investments, stay away from bad habits such as short-term speculation and gambling, and lead by example.</li>
<li><strong>Don&rsquo;t blindly trust high-yield investment products:</strong> Any investment product promising high returns may be a scam. It is important to understand its operating mechanism and learn to discern between true and false.</li>
<li><strong>The dangers of short-term trading:</strong> Short-term trading will miss the best investment opportunities. Long-term investment in index funds will yield more stable returns.</li>
<li><strong>The purpose of cash allocation:</strong> It is not for profit, but for dealing with emergencies like unemployment or a market crash. It is advisable to keep more than 10% of your assets in cash.</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">III. Q&amp;A Session 
    <div id="iii-qa-session" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii-qa-session" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<ul>
<li>
<p><strong>Retired Doctor Poch:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: After learning about James&rsquo; investment philosophy, he found a more relaxing and suitable investment method.</li>
<li>Question: How to obtain a stable cash flow after retirement? Is it necessary to adjust the investment strategy of 00662?
<ul>
<li>Answer:  The investment target can be adjusted according to the size of the retirement fund. Choose 00646 (SPY) or 0056 with lower volatility to guarantee cash flow.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>IM:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: He tried to guide his child to invest by matching contributions and increased his vigilance against high-yield traps.</li>
<li>Question 1: How to guide a child to invest and prevent them from spending investment income?
<ul>
<li>Answer: Emphasize that investment is a long-term behavior. Income cannot be withdrawn for consumption. Funds should grow continuously through compound interest.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2: How to choose a safe and reliable trust company? How to avoid the traps of high-yield trust products?
<ul>
<li>Answer: Any trust company that promises high returns may be a scam. You should take control of your own investment and financial management rights, clearly stipulate investment in index funds in the trust clause, and set up a regulatory unit to ensure fund security.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Rose:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: She frankly talked about her past investment failures and the process of gradually establishing the correct investment concept under the guidance of James.</li>
<li>Question 1: What are the differences and pros and cons of Margin Loan and Pledge Loan?  The interest rate of Margin Loan from IB is relatively low. Is it necessary to transfer to Charles Schwab for Pledge Loan?
<ul>
<li>Answer:  Margin Loan is riskier, and Pledge Loan is relatively safe. If the interest rate of IB&rsquo;s Margin Loan is low, you can continue to use it, but pay attention to controlling the borrowing ratio, preferably no more than 20%.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2: The return on cash allocation will decrease in the interest rate cut cycle. Is it still necessary to allocate cash?
<ul>
<li>Answer: The purpose of cash allocation is not for profit but to deal with contingencies, such as unemployment or a market crash. It is advisable to keep more than 10% of your assets in cash.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 3: How to manage children&rsquo;s investment accounts? Under whose name should it be, yours or the child&rsquo;s?
<ul>
<li>Answer: It is recommended to open an account in the child&rsquo;s name to cultivate their financial management concept, but control the amount and provide proper investment guidance. Estate planning can be done after the child becomes an adult.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Phoenix:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: He shared his confusion about handling company stock options and finally adopted James&rsquo; suggestion.</li>
<li>Question 1: How to deal with the stock options of unlisted companies?
<ul>
<li>Answer: If the company has a high possibility of going public, it is recommended to sell it to an investment company before the listing to get cash and invest in QQQ.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2: What do you think of Bitcoin? Can I invest in it?
<ul>
<li>Answer: If you already hold a small amount of Bitcoin, you can continue to hold it, but do not invest any more capital. It is recommended to focus on investing in QQQ.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Allen:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: He shared his questions about 401k and stock investment and eventually made adjustments under James&rsquo; advice.</li>
<li>Question 1: What should I do if I have too much money in my 401k account?
<ul>
<li>Answer:  It is recommended to stop making further contributions to 401k and transfer some funds to the Roth IRA account through the Backdoor Roth IRA.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2: How to switch from holding Nvidia stock to QQQ?
<ul>
<li>Answer: Sell Nvidia stock as soon as possible, transfer funds to QQQ, and pledge stocks to borrow money to pay taxes.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Haoqing:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: He demonstrated the difficulty of stock selection through data analysis and illustrated the advantages of long-term investment in QQQ with practical examples.</li>
<li>Question: Can stock picking beat QQQ?
<ul>
<li>Answer: Stock selection is difficult to outperform QQQ in the long run. Even if it beats the market in the short term, transaction costs and taxes need to be considered.  Invest in index funds for the long term.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Xiang:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: He shared his confusion about saving for children&rsquo;s education and inheritance and finally found a solution under James&rsquo; advice.</li>
<li>Question 1: Is it better to use a 529 Education Fund or invest in QQQ for children&rsquo;s education savings?
<ul>
<li>Answer:  Investing in QQQ is recommended because it has higher long-term returns and is more flexible.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2: How to do estate planning?
<ul>
<li>Answer:  For larger estates, it is recommended to set up an irrevocable trust and consult an estate lawyer for planning.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Kevin:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Frankly admitted his past investment failures and regained confidence under the guidance of James, starting to embark on the road of steady investment.</li>
<li>Question: How many listeners are losing money on investments?
<ul>
<li>Answer: Past investment experience is not important. What is important is to establish the correct investment concept and believe in the value of long-term investment in index funds.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Julia:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Shared her lessons learned from investing in Chinese concept stocks and second-tier growth stocks, and how to guide children to make long-term investments.</li>
<li>Question 1: How to deal with losses caused by investment in Chinese concept stocks and second-tier growth stocks?
- Answer: It is advisable to &ldquo;cut your losses&rdquo; and switch funds to QQQ in a timely manner.</li>
<li>Question 2: How to guide children to make long-term investments?
- Answer: You can use an investment calculator to show children the power of compound interest and guide them with your own investment experience.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Peter:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Shared his experience working at Apple and confirmed that many high-income earners also choose to invest in index funds.</li>
<li>Question: How to balance family expenses and investment?
- Answer: It is recommended to use stock pledges to borrow money to meet living expenses and continue investing in QQQ, so that assets can continue to grow through compound interest.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Jason:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: He shared his confusion about company tax declaration and finally found a suitable solution under James&rsquo; advice.</li>
<li>Question: How to choose the tax filing method?
<ul>
<li>Answer: If your income is low, you can choose to file a 1099; if your income is high, you are advised to establish an S Corporation.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Cindy:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Shared her experience of guiding her child to invest in Roth IRA and keep away from gambling.</li>
<li>Question: How to guide children to invest in Roth IRA? How to guide children to stay away from gambling?
<ul>
<li>Answer: Open a Roth IRA account for the child and make matching contributions. Lead by example and educate your child with the experiences and stories of people around you.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">IV.  Highlights 
    <div id="iv--highlights" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv--highlights" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>Lending is more powerful than the atomic bomb; it&rsquo;s ten times the atomic bomb!
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>When encouraging people to use stock pledges for borrowing and investment, James used this analogy to vividly illustrate the power of leverage.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Investing should be easy and fun.
&ndash;  Hola</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This is what a listener said when she shared her investment experience. She also tried short-term trading, but finally found that long-term investment suited her better.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Each person has a different destiny when it comes to money.
&ndash; Peter</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Peter said this thought-provoking sentence when he shared his experience of persuading his father to invest in QQQ. This also reflects that investment and financial management should be combined with one&rsquo;s own situation to find a suitable way.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>All the money in the world is mine; you just need to take it and use it.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>James used humorous words to express his confidence in the market when encouraging everyone to invest, which also reflects his optimistic and positive attitude towards life.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">V. Conclusion 
    <div id="v-conclusion" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#v-conclusion" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>In this live broadcast, James once again emphasized the concept of long-term investment in index funds. He also provided specific investment advice for the audience based on the current market situation, covering asset allocation, retirement planning, children&rsquo;s education, stock options handling, leverage, and tax planning. The sharing from the students provided other listeners with valuable reference experience, showing their growth and earnings during the process of learning about investment and financial management.</p>

  



<div
  
    class="flex px-4 py-3 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900"
  >

  <span
    
      class="text-primary-400 ltr:pr-3 rtl:pl-3 flex items-center"
    >

    

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M506.3 417l-213.3-364c-16.33-28-57.54-28-73.98 0l-213.2 364C-10.59 444.9 9.849 480 42.74 480h426.6C502.1 480 522.6 445 506.3 417zM232 168c0-13.25 10.75-24 24-24S280 154.8 280 168v128c0 13.25-10.75 24-23.1 24S232 309.3 232 296V168zM256 416c-17.36 0-31.44-14.08-31.44-31.44c0-17.36 14.07-31.44 31.44-31.44s31.44 14.08 31.44 31.44C287.4 401.9 273.4 416 256 416z"/></svg>

  </span>


  </span>

  <span
    
      class="dark:text-neutral-300"
    ><strong>Disclaimer:</strong> This article is only for personal learning notes and does not constitute any investment advice.</span>
</div>

]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Recommended Reading List</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1728295490690-book-list/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1728295490690-book-list/</guid><description>a description</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[

<h2 class="relative group">Millionaire Teacher 
    <div id="millionaire-teacher" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#millionaire-teacher" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>Andrew Hallam, the author of this book, started investing at the age of 19 and achieved millionaire status within 17 years on a teacher&rsquo;s salary. He shares nine financial principles that anyone can learn, yet few are taught in school. Through real-life stories and personal experiences, he guides readers on how to avoid common investment pitfalls and achieve financial freedom using the simplest, safest, and most effective methods.

<section class="space-y-10 w-full">
    
    
        
            






















  <a class="flex flex-wrap article " href="/en/posts/1728295541698/">
    
        
        <div class="w-full md:w-auto h-full thumbnail nozoom thumbnailshadow md:mr-7" style="background-image:url(/posts/1728295541698/featured_hu5541998357026236747.jpg);"></div>
        
      <div class=" mt-3 md:mt-0">
      <div class="items-center text-left text-xl font-semibold">
        
        <div class="font-bold text-xl text-neutral-800 decoration-primary-500 hover:underline hover:underline-offset-2 dark:text-neutral"
          href="/en/posts/1728295541698/">Millionaire Teacher：Book Notes</div>
        
        
        
      </div>
      <div class="text-sm text-neutral-500 dark:text-neutral-400">
        











  









  



  









<div class="flex flex-row flex-wrap items-center">
  
  
  <time datetime="2024-10-07T00:00:00&#43;00:00">7 October 2024</time><span class="px-2 text-primary-500">&middot;</span><span>
  
  
    
    
      
      
        
        
      
        
        
      
      
    
  
  <span id="views_posts/1728295541698/index.md" class="animate-pulse inline-block text-transparent max-h-3 rounded-full mt-[-2px] align-middle bg-neutral-300 dark:bg-neutral-400" title="views">loading</span>
  <span class="inline-block align-text-bottom">

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 576 512">
<path fill="currentColor" d="M288 32c-80.8 0-145.5 36.8-192.6 80.6C48.6 156 17.3 208 2.5 243.7c-3.3 7.9-3.3 16.7 0 24.6C17.3 304 48.6 356 95.4 399.4C142.5 443.2 207.2 480 288 480s145.5-36.8 192.6-80.6c46.8-43.5 78.1-95.4 93-131.1c3.3-7.9 3.3-16.7 0-24.6c-14.9-35.7-46.2-87.7-93-131.1C433.5 68.8 368.8 32 288 32zM432 256c0 79.5-64.5 144-144 144s-144-64.5-144-144s64.5-144 144-144s144 64.5 144 144zM288 192c0 35.3-28.7 64-64 64c-11.5 0-22.3-3-31.6-8.4c-.2 2.8-.4 5.5-.4 8.4c0 53 43 96 96 96s96-43 96-96s-43-96-96-96c-2.8 0-5.6 .1-8.4 .4c5.3 9.3 8.4 20.1 8.4 31.6z"/></svg>
  </span>

</span>
</span><span class="px-2 text-primary-500">&middot;</span><span>
  
  
    
    
      
      
        
        
      
        
        
      
      
    
  
  <span id="likes_posts/1728295541698/index.md"
    class="animate-pulse inline-block text-transparent max-h-3 rounded-full mt-[-2px] align-middle bg-neutral-300 dark:bg-neutral-400"
    title="likes">loading</span>
  <span class="inline-block align-text-bottom">

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512">
<path fill="currentColor" d="M47.6 300.4L228.3 469.1c7.5 7 17.4 10.9 27.7 10.9s20.2-3.9 27.7-10.9L464.4 300.4c30.4-28.3 47.6-68 47.6-109.5v-5.8c0-69.9-50.5-129.5-119.4-141C347 36.5 300.6 51.4 268 84L256 96 244 84c-32.6-32.6-79-47.5-124.6-39.9C50.5 55.6 0 115.2 0 185.1v5.8c0 41.5 17.2 81.2 47.6 109.5z"/></svg>
  </span>

</span>
</span>
  

  
  
</div>





<div class="flex flex-row flex-wrap items-center">
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  <span style="margin-top:0.5rem" class="mr-2" onclick="window.open(&#34;/en/tags/finance/&#34;,'_self');">
    <span class="flex" style="cursor: pointer;">
  <span class="rounded-md border border-primary-400 px-1 py-[1px] text-xs font-normal text-primary-700 dark:border-primary-600 dark:text-primary-400">
    Finance
  </span>
</span>
  </span>
  
  <span style="margin-top:0.5rem" class="mr-2" onclick="window.open(&#34;/en/tags/investment/&#34;,'_self');">
    <span class="flex" style="cursor: pointer;">
  <span class="rounded-md border border-primary-400 px-1 py-[1px] text-xs font-normal text-primary-700 dark:border-primary-600 dark:text-primary-400">
    Investment
  </span>
</span>
  </span>
  
  <span style="margin-top:0.5rem" class="mr-2" onclick="window.open(&#34;/en/tags/financial-freedom/&#34;,'_self');">
    <span class="flex" style="cursor: pointer;">
  <span class="rounded-md border border-primary-400 px-1 py-[1px] text-xs font-normal text-primary-700 dark:border-primary-600 dark:text-primary-400">
    Financial Freedom
  </span>
</span>
  </span>
  
  <span style="margin-top:0.5rem" class="mr-2" onclick="window.open(&#34;/en/tags/index-funds/&#34;,'_self');">
    <span class="flex" style="cursor: pointer;">
  <span class="rounded-md border border-primary-400 px-1 py-[1px] text-xs font-normal text-primary-700 dark:border-primary-600 dark:text-primary-400">
    Index Funds
  </span>
</span>
  </span>
  
  <span style="margin-top:0.5rem" class="mr-2" onclick="window.open(&#34;/en/tags/compound-interest/&#34;,'_self');">
    <span class="flex" style="cursor: pointer;">
  <span class="rounded-md border border-primary-400 px-1 py-[1px] text-xs font-normal text-primary-700 dark:border-primary-600 dark:text-primary-400">
    Compound Interest
  </span>
</span>
  </span>
  
  
  
  
</div>




      </div>
      
    </div>
  </a>

        
    
</section></p>
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>00485 Buying a house will only make you poor. Investing makes you rich. Borrowing money to keep your assets growing is the way to become wealthy</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1728259977859/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1728259977859/</guid><description>This episode focuses on investment philosophy, strategies to avoid scams, and the impact of China&amp;#39;s newest economic policies on the global market. James reiterates the importance of long-term investment in index funds, specifically QQQ, and advises investors to control their emotions and resist market volatility. He uses real-life examples and data to illustrate the concept of &amp;#34;borrowing for consumption, investing for asset growth&amp;#34;, and analyzes China&amp;#39;s recent economic stimulus policies, viewing them as a positive sign for global economic recovery.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<lite-youtube videoid="zJdXwFaec2c" playlabel="zJdXwFaec2c" params=""></lite-youtube>



<h2 class="relative group">I. Main Topic 
    <div id="i-main-topic" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-main-topic" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This episode primarily discusses proper investment philosophy, ways to avoid investment traps, and the implications of China&rsquo;s latest economic policies for the global market. James emphasizes the importance of long-term investment in index funds, particularly QQQ, and reminds investors to maintain emotional control and not be swayed by market fluctuations. He uses specific examples and data to illustrate the concept of &ldquo;borrow for consumption, invest for asset growth,&rdquo; while also analyzing China&rsquo;s recently introduced series of economic stimulus policies, believing them to be a positive signal for a global economic recovery.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">II. Briefing Content 
    <div id="ii-briefing-content" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii-briefing-content" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<ul>
<li><strong>Investment Philosophy:</strong>
<ul>
<li>Emotions are the biggest enemy in investing. You need to avoid being influenced by news and information, stay rational, and refrain from chasing rising or falling markets.</li>
<li>Investing requires a long-term perspective, aiming for a timeframe of 40 years or more. Warren Buffett acquired 99% of his wealth after the age of 50, demonstrating that patience is key to wealth creation.</li>
<li>Choose investment targets that are consistently stable and provide high returns. Index funds are the best option, especially QQQ, which boasts a long-term annualized return of 14%.</li>
<li>Adhere to the &ldquo;never sell&rdquo; strategy to allow assets to continue appreciating. Avoid selling stocks unless absolutely necessary.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Scam Avoidance Guide:</strong>
<ul>
<li>Be wary of various investment traps. Do not trust any projects that guarantee high returns, especially those that require you to sell existing assets for new investments.</li>
<li>Do not readily believe any investment or financial management information received via phone, text messages, or online platforms. Any information involving bank accounts or government departments must be verified through official channels.</li>
<li>Be cautious of aggressive sales tactics from financial institutions. Stick to your investment plan and avoid being lured by various fancy financial products.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Regarding Real Estate Investment:</strong>
<ul>
<li>James advises against homeownership for average working individuals, believing it turns them into &ldquo;mortgage slaves&rdquo; burdened with heavy loan pressure, hindering wealth accumulation.</li>
<li>He advocates for a &ldquo;rent instead of buy&rdquo; approach, suggesting using a stock pledge loan to rent high-quality housing at lower interest rates, then investing the saved funds for higher returns.</li>
<li>Consider purchasing real estate only when your assets reach a certain scale and you can comfortably afford the payment.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>New Trends in China&rsquo;s Economy:</strong>
<ul>
<li>The People&rsquo;s Bank of China recently introduced a series of potent fiscal policies, including reserve requirement ratio and interest rate cuts, injecting funds into banks, and encouraging stock purchases, to stimulate economic growth.</li>
<li>These policies will contribute positively to stabilizing China&rsquo;s real estate market, boosting consumer confidence, and promoting global economic recovery.</li>
<li>Investors should pay attention to developments in the Chinese market and seize new investment opportunities.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">III. Q&amp;A Session 
    <div id="iii-qa-session" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii-qa-session" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p><strong>IM:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Through conversations with individuals of different age groups, IM discovered that most people have insufficient awareness of long-term savings and are often constrained by mortgages and other factors. By comparing the returns of index funds in different countries and regions with those of fixed deposits and pensions, IM illustrated the advantages of long-term investment in index funds.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>INGYNYING:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: INGYNYING&rsquo;s mother wanted to sell all her assets to purchase a house but, after persuasion, realized that this would lead to losing opportunities for asset appreciation. Many of INGYNYING&rsquo;s friends are afraid of change, preferring to endure the hardships of their current situation rather than attempt new investment methods.</li>
<li>Question: How to convince family members to accept new investment concepts?</li>
<li>James&rsquo; answer: Utilize data and case studies for illustration, such as comparing the long-term returns of fixed deposits and index funds, and sharing success stories of investors. It&rsquo;s also important to respect family members&rsquo; choices and refrain from forcing them to accept new ideas.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Allen:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Questions:  Should someone with assets worth 50 times their annual living expenses use their salary to pay for a car? How can a couple combine their stock accounts for collateral purposes?</li>
<li>James&rsquo; answer: It is recommended to utilize Tesla&rsquo;s official website loan to purchase a vehicle, then use funds from a stock pledge loan to repay the car loan. Dedicate your salary entirely to investment. Couples can combine their accounts through a joint account for collateral, sharing the limit, while their accounts remain individually managed.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Eric:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Question: Eric&rsquo;s mother is visiting the US and is concerned about medical expenses. How should this be  handled?</li>
<li>James&rsquo; answer:  Purchasing travel insurance is advised, but excessive worry is unnecessary. Most non-emergency situations can be treated back home. If encountering extremely high medical costs, attempting negotiation with the hospital or seeking alternative solutions is possible. Due to the specific circumstances of foreign nationality and lack of income, the hospital may choose not to pursue the medical expenses.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Dean:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Dean purchased a new car using Tesla&rsquo;s website loan and a stock pledge loan, conserving a significant amount of capital. Learning about investing boosted Dean&rsquo;s confidence to decline a high-paying job and choose to stay home with their child.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Michael:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Questions: How to secure a loan from Tesla&rsquo;s official website for a car purchase? Can funds from 401k or IRA accounts be used for collateral? What are the options if QQQ is not available in their company&rsquo;s 401k plan?</li>
<li>James&rsquo; answer: To apply for a car loan through Tesla&rsquo;s website, choose the desired model and configuration, click &ldquo;Order Now&rdquo;, and select &ldquo;Finance&rdquo;. Funds in retirement accounts cannot be used as collateral; it is recommended to transfer part of those funds to a brokerage account for collateral purposes.  Alternative options include choosing an S&amp;P 500 index fund or inquiring with the company about the possibility of Blockage Link to invest in QQQ.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>EVA:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Question: As a single, middle-aged woman with limited savings, how to balance work and investment? Should selling the house be considered for investment purposes?</li>
<li>James&rsquo; answer: Continue working diligently while consistently making monthly investments. Even small amounts will accumulate over 8-9 years, reaching the threshold for collateral, allowing you to leverage and accelerate wealth growth. Selling a house for investment is an option but requires careful consideration based on personal circumstances.  If renting is more cost-effective, choose to rent and allocate the funds to investments yielding higher returns.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Jenny:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Questions:  Any knowledge regarding the latest Roth SEP IRA policy?</li>
<li>James&rsquo; answer: The policy information is quite recent, and the accuracy of the $69,000 limit requires verification. Consulting with professionals like a financial advisor at Chase or Lisa is recommended. As it is a new product, not all institutions may offer it.</li>
<li>Sharing: Jenny shared a personal experience of being scammed, reminding everyone to exercise caution and avoid trusting any investment information, particularly those spread through unofficial channels.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Haoqing:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Haoqing relayed the experiences of close friends falling victim to scams, lamenting that scam tactics are constantly evolving and are hard to guard against, even for highly educated individuals.</li>
<li>Question: How can investment concepts be better conveyed to people around us to prevent them from being deceived? Is there a need to explain professional investment knowledge?</li>
<li>James&rsquo; answer: Avoid explaining intricate investment knowledge; simply emphasize the core principle of long-term investment in index funds. Excessive professional details may confuse them, making them more susceptible to being misled by other investment information and ultimately falling prey to scams.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Jason:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Recounted an NFT scam incident encountered on Clubhouse, warning everyone to be wary of risks in the cryptocurrency world. Expressed gratitude toward James&rsquo; investment philosophy for helping them avoid such traps.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Amy:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Amy shared personal encounters with scams, including impersonations of government departments and courier companies. She emphasized the importance of relying only on written communication and ignoring any investment information delivered through phone calls or text messages. Amy suggested that, when in doubt, contact official channels for clarification.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Becky:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Suggestion: Avoid answering calls from unfamiliar numbers, set up spam filters, and use a less important email address when necessary to share personal information to minimize the risk of scams.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Mike:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Question: What are your thoughts on China&rsquo;s most recent economic policies? Are they sustainable?</li>
<li>James&rsquo; answer: The People&rsquo;s Bank of China has introduced powerful policies that are having a positive impact on economic confidence. Investors should keep an eye on these developments. Although the policies appear to be heading in a positive direction, their sustainability remains to be seen.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Julia:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Question:  Any updates on the Roth SEP IRA policy? Are there any financial institutions already offering related products?</li>
<li>James&rsquo; answer: The policy information is fairly new, and the $69,000 limit&rsquo;s accuracy is debatable. Consulting with a professional is advised. Being a new product, not all institutions might offer it yet.</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">IV. Noteworthy Points 
    <div id="iv-noteworthy-points" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv-noteworthy-points" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>“You have enough money when you have enough.&quot;
&ndash; Many people</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Many individuals believe that having just enough to get by is sufficient. This is a mistaken notion, as money is never truly enough. True financial freedom lies in possessing the power of choice – going wherever you want, doing whatever you desire – instead of being constrained by finances.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;Never borrow money for investments.&rdquo;
&ndash; Many people</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Many believe that borrowing for investment is unwise; however, this viewpoint is overly cautious. True investors, like Warren Buffett, skillfully leverage debt. Following the principle of &ldquo;borrow for consumption, invest for asset growth&rdquo;, the correct approach is to use borrowed money for expenses and personal money for investment. This enables rapid wealth accumulation.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“All investment information received through phone calls, text messages, or online platforms is not trustworthy.”
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Nowadays, numerous scams operate through these channels. It&rsquo;s crucial to exercise caution and avoid blindly believing any financial advice or information. Anything involving bank accounts or government departments must be verified through official sources. Additionally, seeking guidance from qualified professionals is essential.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“Investment must be consistently stable over the long term, which is why index funds are the only viable option.&quot;
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Within the complex investment landscape, index funds stand out as a few reliable options capable of offering consistent stability and high returns. Index funds are like living organisms; they will never die, whereas all individual stocks will eventually disappear within a century.  If you&rsquo;re looking for generational wealth, index funds are the way to go.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">V. Summary 
    <div id="v-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#v-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This episode is packed with valuable information and insights. It not only reiterates the importance of long-term index fund investment but also offers practical tips on scam prevention and provides an in-depth analysis of China&rsquo;s newest economic policies.  It is recommended to apply this knowledge to your investment practices and strive for financial freedom.</p>

  



<div
  
    class="flex px-4 py-3 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900"
  >

  <span
    
      class="text-primary-400 ltr:pr-3 rtl:pl-3 flex items-center"
    >

    

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M506.3 417l-213.3-364c-16.33-28-57.54-28-73.98 0l-213.2 364C-10.59 444.9 9.849 480 42.74 480h426.6C502.1 480 522.6 445 506.3 417zM232 168c0-13.25 10.75-24 24-24S280 154.8 280 168v128c0 13.25-10.75 24-23.1 24S232 309.3 232 296V168zM256 416c-17.36 0-31.44-14.08-31.44-31.44c0-17.36 14.07-31.44 31.44-31.44s31.44 14.08 31.44 31.44C287.4 401.9 273.4 416 256 416z"/></svg>

  </span>


  </span>

  <span
    
      class="dark:text-neutral-300"
    ><strong>Disclaimer:</strong> This article serves solely as personal study notes and does not constitute any investment advice.</span>
</div>

]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>00484 Buying at the market price immediately when you have money is the best investment strategy:a market with an unbreakable asset allocation doesn't exist</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1728261371758/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1728261371758/</guid><description>This live session focused on long-term investment strategies, delving into investment philosophy, risk management, and values. James shared personal experiences and insights, offering valuable guidance on understanding the nature of investing and its inherent risks, emphasizing the importance of being rational, patient, and vigilant.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<lite-youtube videoid="UGUV4GIqKVg" playlabel="UGUV4GIqKVg" params=""></lite-youtube>



<h2 class="relative group">I. Topic of the Session 
    <div id="i-topic-of-the-session" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-topic-of-the-session" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>The session centered on the core principle of long-term investment strategies. James reiterated his investment philosophy: &ldquo;Buy QQQ whenever you have money and hold it for the long term.&rdquo; The discussion expanded to cover aspects like investment philosophy, risk management, and values, incorporating current events and questions from attendees. James also shared insights from legendary investors like Warren Buffett, encouraging attendees to cultivate a sound investment mindset.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">II. Briefing Highlights 
    <div id="ii-briefing-highlights" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii-briefing-highlights" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<ol>
<li><strong>Buying at the Dip vs. Buying When You Have Money:</strong> James cited research from ChatGPT, indicating that even with the ability to accurately predict and buy at market dips, the long-term returns differed minimally compared to simply buying when one has available funds. Over a 20-year period, the difference was merely 8%, translating to a difference in annualized returns of less than 0.2%. Hence, rather than expending time and effort predicting market bottoms, it&rsquo;s more effective to seize opportunities and buy QQQ when you have the money.</li>
<li><strong>Risks of Leveraged Funds:</strong>  Using the 2000 tech bubble as an example, James explained how leveraged funds can accelerate losses in bear markets, potentially leading to devastating financial setbacks, even bankruptcy. He simulated a scenario where an investor repeatedly buys more leveraged funds as the market declines, culminating in financial ruin. This served as a cautionary tale against the &ldquo;buy the dip&rdquo; strategy with leveraged funds, emphasizing the importance of risk management.</li>
<li><strong>Keys to Investment Success:</strong> James emphasized that the key to successful investment lies in overcoming human weaknesses. Maintaining a detached and &ldquo;unfeeling&rdquo; attitude towards invested capital and short-term market fluctuations is crucial for adhering to a long-term investment approach.</li>
<li><strong>Market Cycles:</strong> James stated he wouldn&rsquo;t teach attendees about predicting market cycles or any trading techniques. He considers these unimportant and prone to misinterpretation and misapplication, potentially leading to increased risks. He advocated for a long-term investment strategy, likening it to riding a cable car, a smooth and steady ascent to the summit of financial success.</li>
<li><strong>Money and Values:</strong> Acknowledging that individuals have different values regarding money, James advised understanding and respecting diverse values, discouraging attempts to impose one&rsquo;s own values upon others. He used the example shared by an attendee about a mother preferring a financial subsidy over a family trip to illustrate the diverse ways people assign value to things.</li>
</ol>


<h2 class="relative group">III. Q&amp;A Session 
    <div id="iii-qa-session" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii-qa-session" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p><strong>IIM:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Shared:</strong> A story about a deceased friend, leading to reflections on money and values, and expressing confusion about balancing personal values with those of others.</li>
<li><strong>Question 1:</strong>  How to understand some people&rsquo;s &ldquo;frugality&rdquo; with money while being &ldquo;generous&rdquo; towards their pets.
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response:</strong> People manage their finances differently based on what they consider important and valuable. What might be significant to one person may hold little value for another.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question 2:</strong> How to understand a mother who prioritizes money over a family trip? How to better understand the needs of others?
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response:</strong>  This mother might have certain unmet needs, possibly requiring material security before pursuing leisurely experiences. Understanding true needs involves offering more choices (e.g., money plus a trip). Avoid trying to change others&rsquo; values; focus on understanding and respecting them.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Brian:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Shared:</strong> Encountering a friend who suggested leveraging to purchase Nvidia stock, leading to questions about investment advice.</li>
<li><strong>Question:</strong> How to evaluate investment advice received from others?
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response:</strong>   The validity of investment advice depends on individual judgment and risk tolerance. It&rsquo;s important to avoid blindly following the advice of others and to think independently.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Iny:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Shared:</strong>  Experiencing a sense of calm and reduced anxiety after adopting James&rsquo;s investment approach.  This newfound peace of mind allows for dedicating more time to important matters like family, and interestingly, focusing on work has led to increased income.</li>
<li><strong>Question:</strong>  How to understand the phenomenon of increased income resulting from a dedicated focus on work?
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response:</strong> This exemplifies the principle that altruism ultimately benefits oneself. By focusing on serving clients and enhancing product or service quality, one ultimately gains client recognition and rewards, leading to higher income and a sense of accomplishment.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Haoqing:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Shared 1:</strong>  An experience with check fraud, prompting concerns about bank security and the risks of using checks.
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response:</strong>  Banks do not verify the identity of check depositors. Checks present security vulnerabilities, making it advisable to use safer online banking and digital payment methods like Apple Pay.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Shared 2:</strong> Thoughts on the decline of US manufacturing and the rise of Asia, attributing this to factors like US regulations, labor laws, and unions.
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response:</strong> The decline of US manufacturing and the rise of Asia are multifaceted issues stemming from a complex interplay of factors, including national policies, labor laws, and unions. While Asian countries might resort to suppressing labor rights and environmental regulations to gain a competitive edge, the US places a higher value on worker well-being and environmental protection. This divergence in values contributes to different developmental paths.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Becky:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Shared:</strong> Based on personal experience working in a digital payment company, Becky recommended that everyone stop using checks due to inherent security risks. Digital payment methods offer greater security and convenience, with features such as spending alerts that enable prompt response and recovery in case of issues.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Mike:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Shared:</strong> As a long-time follower of James, Mike witnessed the evolution of his investment philosophy, from initially holding 30% SPY to converting to 100% QQQ, and eventually incorporating leveraged funds. He also shared personal investment experiences, like selling NIO and allocating a portion of his portfolio to private market investments.</li>
<li><strong>Question 1:</strong> Is investing in Intel after its acquisition worthwhile?
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response:</strong>  James advised against investing in large companies that are acquisitive. Acquisitions often lack efficiency, posing integration challenges and potentially hindering productivity. While acquiring smaller companies for technological advantages makes sense, acquiring large companies is akin to amassing a pile of scrap metal.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question 2:</strong>  How to view the supply chain security concerns stemming from the US outsourcing 3C product manufacturing, citing examples like the BBB Call explosion and walkie-talkie incidents?
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response:</strong> Espionage is ubiquitous, and supply chain security is just one facet of this broader issue. Governments might implant spy codes in chips and software for surveillance purposes. Explosions are a relatively rudimentary form of espionage; more sophisticated methods can be extremely difficult to detect and prevent.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question 3:</strong> Is it possible to offer advanced courses for more experienced attendees? He suggested using portfolio sharing as a means to differentiate attendees&rsquo; learning progress.
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response:</strong> James stated he wouldn&rsquo;t differentiate between attendees nor offer advanced courses. Assessing whether a student is genuinely learning is primarily based on their attitude, not investment returns or holding duration. Even portfolio sharing can&rsquo;t truly gauge learning progress. James mentioned his personal sensitivity to words and language, enabling him to discern learning attitudes from attendees&rsquo; emails and the way they pose questions.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">IV. Noteworthy Insights 
    <div id="iv-noteworthy-insights" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv-noteworthy-insights" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>The best time to buy is when you have money.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Many obsess over finding the perfect entry point, but research indicates that even if you could perfectly time market dips, the long-term returns barely differ from simply buying when funds are available. Instead of wasting time trying to predict the market, seize the opportunity and act promptly.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>To succeed in investing, you must be indifferent to the money you invest and the fluctuations in stock prices.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Overcoming the human tendency to fixate on money and fear short-term market swings is essential for maintaining a long-term investment strategy and achieving stable returns.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>To achieve effortless investing, you need to be numb to money.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>When investing becomes a habit, free from emotional impulses and external distractions, you can achieve optimal results.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The concept of a &ldquo;benefactor&rdquo; is relative.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>People perceive and absorb information differently. Who you consider a benefactor might not be perceived as such by others.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Don&rsquo;t try to change other people&rsquo;s values.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Everyone has their own values and ways of life. It&rsquo;s important to understand and respect diverse choices.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Espionage is everywhere.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Information security is a growing concern. Be vigilant and protect your personal data.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Acquisitions of large companies are generally inefficient, and leaders who are fond of acquisitions usually have inflated egos.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Integration complexities and high management costs associated with mergers often outweigh the benefits gained.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The US excels in areas such as finance and technology design, while Asian countries can only substitute and supplement in specific aspects.
&ndash; Haoqing</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Within the global division of labor, different countries have distinct strengths and weaknesses, leading to divergent paths of development.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The best judgments are validated by facts.
&ndash; Mike</p>
</blockquote>
<p>The success of an investment philosophy is ultimately determined by its long-term returns, not short-term fluctuations or gut feelings.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Your attitude determines my response.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>James adjusts his responses based on the learning attitude of the attendees. Attendees who are truly dedicated to learning will receive greater guidance.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Investing in individual stocks will ultimately lead to bankruptcy; holding onto individual stocks will also ultimately lead to bankruptcy.<br>
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Companies have lifecycles.  Holding onto a single stock long term significantly increases the risk of encountering bankruptcy. Diversification is key in investing.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">V. Summary 
    <div id="v-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#v-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This live session once again emphasized the importance of long-term investing while reminding attendees to stay rational, patient, and vigilant. James addressed attendees&rsquo; questions regarding investment strategies, risk management, and the relationship between money and values, sharing personal experiences and insights. Key takeaways include avoiding market timing, leveraged funds, and individual stock investments, and embracing an attitude of indifference towards money. Attendees actively shared their own investment experiences and reflections, prompting deeper contemplation on investment, money, life, and more. The session also delved into the philosophies of renowned investors like Warren Buffett and discussed various social phenomena, creating a rich and informative experience.</p>

  



<div
  
    class="flex px-4 py-3 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900"
  >

  <span
    
      class="text-primary-400 ltr:pr-3 rtl:pl-3 flex items-center"
    >

    

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M506.3 417l-213.3-364c-16.33-28-57.54-28-73.98 0l-213.2 364C-10.59 444.9 9.849 480 42.74 480h426.6C502.1 480 522.6 445 506.3 417zM232 168c0-13.25 10.75-24 24-24S280 154.8 280 168v128c0 13.25-10.75 24-23.1 24S232 309.3 232 296V168zM256 416c-17.36 0-31.44-14.08-31.44-31.44c0-17.36 14.07-31.44 31.44-31.44s31.44 14.08 31.44 31.44C287.4 401.9 273.4 416 256 416z"/></svg>

  </span>


  </span>

  <span
    
      class="dark:text-neutral-300"
    ><strong>Disclaimer:</strong> This transcript serves as personal learning notes only and does not constitute investment advice.</span>
</div>

]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>00483 Rock-solid asset allocation,Investment strategies based on asset allocation and risk management</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1728265687577/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1728265687577/</guid><description>This live stream focuses on the core concept of &amp;#34;wealth is a gift&amp;#34;. James explains the importance of investing and financial management, the advantages of index investing, the relationship between risk tolerance and investment returns, and how to allocate your assets reasonably. During the Q&amp;amp;A session, students raised questions about TQQQ investment, Beta calculation, asset allocation strategies, and the investment market in mainland China. James answered these questions in detail and shared numerous experiences and cases to help students overcome psychological barriers in investment and solidify their long-term investment philosophy.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<lite-youtube videoid="eSkubAhBlhE" playlabel="eSkubAhBlhE" params=""></lite-youtube>



<h2 class="relative group">I. Theme of the Episode 
    <div id="i-theme-of-the-episode" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-theme-of-the-episode" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>The theme of this episode is &ldquo;Investing and Financial Management, Wealth is a Gift.&rdquo; The core viewpoints  are: <strong>Wealth is innate, but one must be informed to realize it; investing and financial management is an important way to accumulate wealth; index investing is an effective method to achieve long-term stable growth; rational asset allocation and risk control are the keys to investment success; and overcoming psychological barriers in investment and solidifying the long-term investment philosophy are crucial to ultimately achieving financial freedom.</strong></p>


<h2 class="relative group">II. Summary of the Briefing 
    <div id="ii-summary-of-the-briefing" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii-summary-of-the-briefing" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<ul>
<li><strong>Wealth is a Gift:</strong> Wealth is innate, and being informed of this fact makes a huge difference. While successful entrepreneurs like Elon Musk are a minority, most people need to be told that &ldquo;wealth is a gift,&rdquo; and they need to learn how to invest and manage their finances to achieve wealth growth.</li>
<li><strong>The Power of Index Investing and Compound Interest:</strong> Index investing is an effective way to achieve long-term stable returns, and its compounding effect is astonishing. For example, investing $1,500 per month for 40 years with a 14% annualized return will yield $2.6 million. <strong>Even small amounts of money can accumulate considerable wealth through consistent long-term investment.</strong></li>
<li><strong>High Risk, High Return?</strong>: High risk doesn&rsquo;t necessarily lead to high returns. Whether you can bear the risk determines whether you can ultimately achieve high returns. Don&rsquo;t overestimate your risk tolerance. Your risk appetite should be determined by an asset allocation that you can withstand even if your investment goes to zero. <strong>For example, if you cannot afford the risk of TQQQ going to zero, you should not invest in TQQQ.</strong></li>
<li><strong>Choosing Investment Targets</strong>: It is recommended to invest in the global Nasdaq 100 index fund (QQQ). Those with insufficient funds or who are already retired can consider investing in SPY or high-dividend ETFs. Avoid investing in individual stocks because they tend to disappear over the long term, while index funds can continue to exist. <strong>The half-life of individual stocks is 10 years; out of 100 stocks, there may be less than three left after 50 years.</strong></li>
<li><strong>Investment Mindset</strong>: The market will eventually rise, and investment requires patience. Always stay optimistic, even if the investment goes to zero. Learning about investing and financial management requires continuous thinking, like peeling an onion, layer by layer, to elevate the energy of the spiritual level. <strong>Investing is like the Yellow Mountain, eternally unchanging, yet different every day; every learning experience will bring new insights.</strong></li>
<li><strong>Asset Allocation</strong>: Asset allocation is like building a house; it is a big project that requires comprehensive planning, not something simple. It is necessary to consider many factors, such as whether you are retired, your age, income, debt, and cash flow, to formulate a reasonable asset allocation plan. <strong>You need to carefully study the articles and videos on asset allocation provided by James to develop a plan that suits you.</strong></li>
<li><strong>Do Not  Blindly Trust External Information</strong>: Financial professionals often only consider their interests, so do not easily believe their advice. Think independently, study carefully, and do not be swayed by external information and noise. <strong>Most of the outside information is garbage; do not be affected by it, focus on learning James&rsquo; investment philosophy.</strong></li>
<li><strong>Balancing Risk and Reward</strong>: Do not excessively pursue high returns or completely risk-free investments; balance risk and reward. Avoid changing investment strategies easily to prevent additional costs due to frequent trading. <strong>James&rsquo; investment methods can guarantee asset appreciation and relative safety, avoiding extreme situations.</strong></li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">III. Q&amp;A Session 
    <div id="iii-qa-session" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii-qa-session" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p><strong>IM:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>Sharing: Learning about investment is like peeling an onion; at first, the amount of information is overwhelming, but as you learn more, you will gradually understand the core idea and ultimately reach the realm of &ldquo;the great Dao is simple.&rdquo;</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Question 1: What do you think about the idea that &ldquo;investing is simple&rdquo;?</p>
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo; Response: Such views often mistake ignorance for inaction and do not truly understand the complexity and risks of investment.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p>Question 2: How should we communicate with friends who don&rsquo;t understand index investing?</p>
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo; Response: You can start by briefly introducing the concept and advantages of index investing and suggest that they watch related videos to learn. Don&rsquo;t force them to accept it, everyone has their own choices. <strong>Just like preaching, we can only try our best to spread the message; whether it&rsquo;s ultimately accepted depends on the individual.</strong></li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>LAN:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>Question 1: How to calculate Beta? What is the actual Beta value of a leveraged ETF?</p>
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo; Response: You can refer to the link to the article on Beta calculation on the message board. The actual Beta value of a leveraged ETF may deviate from the theoretical value due to factors such as market volatility and friction costs. <strong>When market volatility is large, the wear and tear of leveraged ETFs will be more serious, resulting in an actual Beta value lower than the theoretical value.</strong></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p>Question 2: Why is there a huge difference in final return between scenario 3 and scenario 4.1 in the 005 topic?</p>
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo; Response: Scenario 4.1 is where no money is withdrawn from the investment, so the final return will be higher.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p>Question 3: How to adjust Beta in a rising market?</p>
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo; Response:  The adjustment of Beta should be determined by your own risk tolerance, not by the market trend. <strong>Do not try to predict the market, just keep a fixed Beta value.</strong></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p>Question 4:  For investments in Taiwan, should I choose Q2D or 00670L?</p>
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo; Response: 00670L is recommended because it includes New Taiwan dollar hedging, which can reduce the risk caused by exchange rate fluctuations. <strong>Don&rsquo;t change investment targets frequently, choose one that suits you and hold it for the long term.</strong></li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Nai Xin:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Wealth is a gift, just as self-confidence is a gift; everyone has potential, but it needs to be stimulated. The key to investing and financial management lies in learning. Once you have mastered the correct investment method, you can focus on your own career and life and let wealth grow naturally over time. <strong>Overcome fear, build confidence, and you can realize your potential, gain wealth, and achieve success.</strong></li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Jason:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Understanding &ldquo;buy whenever you have money,&rdquo; but still finding it difficult to overcome psychological fluctuations when the market rises or falls sharply.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo; Response:  Overcoming psychological fluctuations takes time and experience. You can try to make a small number of trades, experience the impact of market fluctuations, and gradually adapt to market changes.</li>
<li>IM Supplement: You can overcome psychological barriers by imagining starting to invest two years later and understanding that &ldquo;money arrives at different points in time.&rdquo;<strong>Don&rsquo;t worry about buying at the lowest point; as long as you stick to long-term investment, you can get good returns.</strong></li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Hai Rui Ji:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>Sharing:</p>
<ol>
<li>Thank you James for selflessly sharing your investment philosophy; students learn from each other and make progress together.</li>
<li>James&rsquo; investment philosophy requires continuous learning and understanding to grasp it fully. &ldquo;Never sell&rdquo; does not mean you cannot sell, but that you should develop a reasonable investment strategy based on your own situation. ** &ldquo;Never sell&rdquo; refers to mentally ignoring market fluctuations and adhering to a long-term investment philosophy.**</li>
<li>Investment philosophy needs to keep pace with the times and adjust investment strategies according to changes in the environment.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<p>Question: Already answered in the video.</p>
</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Li Zi:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: To overcome psychological barriers to investment, manage accounts separately, using one part for long-term investment and the other for tentative operations, such as selling covered calls. This satisfies the desire to trade and avoids losses due to frequent trading.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo; Response: You only know what is best after you have experienced it. Experience in trading can lead to a firmer commitment to a long-term investment strategy. <strong>Trying different trading strategies can help you understand the advantages of long-term investment and ultimately achieve the state of &ldquo;daily reduction for the Dao.&rdquo;</strong></li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>T:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>Question 1: Why has the capital market in mainland China performed poorly for a long time?</p>
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo; Response: Emerging markets take time to mature. The Chinese market is like the Taiwanese market 50 years ago. It has the potential to rise in the long term, but its return may be lower than that of the US market. <strong>Investment should focus on sustainable development markets. The US market has advantages in terms of systems and industries.</strong></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p>Question 2: Under foreign exchange control, how do I invest in US index funds? Are there any risks?</p>
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo; Response: You can invest by purchasing ETFs listed in China that track US index funds, such as 513100. Foreign exchange controls mainly restrict the physical flow of funds, and buying ETFs is not restricted. The current scale of such investment is small and will not trigger a quota limit. <strong>Even with foreign exchange control, it is still possible to allocate global assets through legal channels.</strong></li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">IV. Key Takeaways 
    <div id="iv-key-takeaways" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv-key-takeaways" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>Wealth is a Gift
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Everyone has the potential for wealth, but they must be informed to realize it and learn how to invest and manage their finances to achieve wealth growth.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Learning Increases Daily, the Dao Decreases Daily
&ndash; IM</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Learning about investing and financial management is a process of continuous improvement. At first, you will be exposed to a large amount of information, but as your understanding deepens, you will gradually simplify your investment strategy and eventually reach the state of &ldquo;the great Dao is simple.&rdquo;</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The Difficult to Return to After Seeing a Vast Ocean
&ndash; Li Zi &amp; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Only after experiencing something can you know what is best. In investing, only after actually operating and experiencing market fluctuations and the impact of different investment strategies can you more firmly choose the long-term investment strategy that suits you.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The More Money You Borrow, the More Money You Have
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Understand and control risk, not avoid it. Understanding how to use leverage can accelerate wealth growth, but only with proper risk management, such as building a solid asset allocation.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Cash is Air
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Cash is very important and you must keep enough cash to deal with market fluctuations and emergencies.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">V. Summary 
    <div id="v-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#v-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This live stream focused on the theme of &ldquo;Wealth is a gift.&rdquo; James explained the importance of investing and financial management, the advantages of index investing, the relationship between risk tolerance and investment returns, and how to conduct reasonable asset allocation in a simple and profound way. During the Q&amp;A session, students actively questioned their own issues and confusions. James patiently and meticulously answered them by combining practical cases and his own experience, helping the students better understand and master the knowledge and methods of investing and financial management. He also guided the students to overcome psychological barriers in investments, establish a firm long-term investment philosophy, and ultimately achieve financial freedom.</p>

  



<div
  
    class="flex px-4 py-3 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900"
  >

  <span
    
      class="text-primary-400 ltr:pr-3 rtl:pl-3 flex items-center"
    >

    

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M506.3 417l-213.3-364c-16.33-28-57.54-28-73.98 0l-213.2 364C-10.59 444.9 9.849 480 42.74 480h426.6C502.1 480 522.6 445 506.3 417zM232 168c0-13.25 10.75-24 24-24S280 154.8 280 168v128c0 13.25-10.75 24-23.1 24S232 309.3 232 296V168zM256 416c-17.36 0-31.44-14.08-31.44-31.44c0-17.36 14.07-31.44 31.44-31.44s31.44 14.08 31.44 31.44C287.4 401.9 273.4 416 256 416z"/></svg>

  </span>


  </span>

  <span
    
      class="dark:text-neutral-300"
    ><strong>Disclaimer:</strong> This article is a personal learning summary and does not constitute any investment advice.</span>
</div>

]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>00482 Investing in Humanity's Future：How to Harness the Power of Long-Term Investing, Grow Your Capital, and Make Time and Money Work for You?</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1728285089799/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1728285089799/</guid><description>This session explored the essence of capitalism, critiquing the current financial education system and delving into a brainless investment strategy. It emphasized the importance of asset allocation, achieving true financial freedom, and discussed topics like raising children with a sense of responsibility and finding one&amp;#39;s purpose in life.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<lite-youtube videoid="zQO1A-pLj6M" playlabel="zQO1A-pLj6M" params=""></lite-youtube>



<h2 class="relative group">I. Main Topic 
    <div id="i-main-topic" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-main-topic" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This session focused on the nature of capitalism and a brainless investment strategy. James criticized the current financial education system for &ldquo;enslaving&rdquo; the masses, arguing that it&rsquo;s designed to create workers, not capitalists. He stressed the importance of asset allocation and understanding the true meaning of wealth to achieve financial freedom in a capitalist society.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">II. Briefing Content 
    <div id="ii-briefing-content" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii-briefing-content" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<ul>
<li><strong>The Essence of Capitalism:</strong> James likened capitalism to a massive AI, with complex and opaque operating mechanisms that can easily lead to confusion. He argued that capitalism is not inherently evil but a tool, the key being the user&rsquo;s mindset and approach. Similar to the emergence of AI, capitalism also evolved from simple buy-and-sell relationships, its complexity making it difficult to predict and understand.</li>
<li><strong>Brainless Investing Strategy:</strong> &ldquo;Buy when you have money, and never sell.&rdquo;  He emphasized index fund investing, particularly the Nasdaq-100 index fund (QQQ), as the core investment vehicle. He opposed over-diversification, believing that focusing on the US market is more effective due to its fairness, justice, and openness.</li>
<li><strong>The Importance of Asset Allocation:</strong> Asset allocation is the core of investing, and it&rsquo;s crucial to develop a suitable strategy based on individual circumstances. James provided relevant links and video resources to help the audience learn more. A safe and sound asset allocation should be able to cope with market fluctuations, ensuring that even if the market drops to zero, one can still maintain their lifestyle for many years.  He highlighted the concept of &ldquo;being able to live comfortably for over a decade regardless of market fluctuations.&rdquo;</li>
<li><strong>The True Meaning of Financial Freedom:</strong> True financial freedom is not just about possessing wealth but also about &ldquo;knowing how to spend.&rdquo; This means understanding one&rsquo;s asset situation and knowing how much can be freely spent annually and monthly.  He emphasized the concept of &ldquo;knowing what to spend and spending it freely when desired.&rdquo;</li>
<li><strong>Parenting and Responsibility:</strong> He encouraged young people to have children and cultivate their sense of responsibility and financial awareness from a young age, enabling them to be self-reliant. He shared his experience of educating his daughter, emphasizing the importance of letting children bear the consequences of their actions, starting with small things.</li>
<li><strong>The Meaning of Learning:</strong> The purpose of learning is not just for monetary gain but for ultimate enlightenment. One should absorb knowledge like a sponge, cultivate thinking abilities, and ultimately reach the state of &ldquo;decreasing knowledge to gain wisdom.&rdquo; He used the example of martial arts manuals to illustrate that learning is a process from having something to having nothing.</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">III. Q&amp;A Session 
    <div id="iii-qa-session" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii-qa-session" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p><strong>YJ:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Sharing:  Discussed the lack of financial education in Asia, using the moon analogy to illustrate the differences between Eastern and Western education. Mentioned the inspirational Jewish financial education book, <em>Talmud</em>.</li>
<li>Question: How to educate children about finances from a young age.</li>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: Cultivate children&rsquo;s sense of responsibility from an early age, let them understand the meaning of wealth, and encourage them to start financial planning and investment early.  Avoid the negative views on money held by older generations.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Ying Nuo:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Sharing:  Shared the enlightenment gained after learning James&rsquo;s investment philosophy and how they implemented a simple asset allocation strategy, feeling secure and stable.</li>
<li>Question: Question about the pledging ratio.</li>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: Corrected the concept of the pledging ratio, emphasizing that retirees should pledge or borrow 2% of their total assets for living expenses, and young people should choose QQQ for better growth potential.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>IM:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Sharing:  Shared the simplicity and convenience of ETF investing, along with experiences sharing investment philosophies with friends and their views on having children.</li>
<li>Question:  Whether one should &ldquo;know too much&rdquo; in investing and life, and whether concerns about the future and AI would affect the willingness to have children.</li>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: Affirmed the importance of learning, but emphasized the need to learn to subtract, filtering out unimportant knowledge and information. &ldquo;Gaining knowledge daily, losing wisdom daily.&rdquo;  Encouraged young people not to be afraid of having children, sharing his understanding of the meaning of life - &ldquo;The meaning of life lies in creating the next generation of life in the universe.&rdquo;</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Chang An:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Sharing:  Shared news about a government department in China buying Nasdaq funds and becoming the largest shareholder.</li>
<li>Question: The implications of this action and its connection to US-China relations.</li>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: Affirmed the investment behavior of the government department, believing it to be the correct way to manage finances, and encouraged other government departments to learn from it.  He believed that governments should also engage in asset allocation.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Sam:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Shared entrepreneurial experiences and reflections on blind expansion, as well as personal confusion about retirement and future life.</li>
<li>Question: Preparing for retirement but feeling lost about the future state of life and unsure how to prepare.</li>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: Retirement is not the only option, listen to your inner voice, and find a lifestyle that makes you happy.  Don&rsquo;t over-plan the future; things will work out. He also suggested that Sam think about streamlining company processes, improving efficiency, and making employees happier at work.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Jason:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Sharing:  Examples of young people staying at home after graduating from university.</li>
<li>Question: How to help young people find meaning in life.</li>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: Cultivate children&rsquo;s sense of responsibility from an early age and let them learn to be self-reliant. Parents should not over-pamper their children, let them take responsibility, and encourage them to enter society and serve others.  He used his own daughter as an example to illustrate how to cultivate children&rsquo;s sense of responsibility from a young age.</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">IV. Key Takeaways 
    <div id="iv-key-takeaways" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv-key-takeaways" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>Spending money is moral.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Spending money should not be seen as negative; knowing how to spend and being willing to spend is the only way to truly enjoy the freedom that wealth brings. Also emphasized taking advantage of credit card benefits, points, etc.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The more we know, the greater the risks we don&rsquo;t know.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>As our knowledge increases, we need to be more cautious in identifying and assessing potential unknown risks. The real risk is the unknown risk.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The class of those who know and those who don&rsquo;t.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>There is a disparity in information and knowledge in capitalist society, leading to class differentiation between those who know and those who don&rsquo;t. Wealth and capital are concentrated in the hands of a few.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>I may not know where I&rsquo;m sailing, but I know there are some paths I can no longer take.
&ndash; Sam</p>
</blockquote>
<p>On the road of life, clarifying what you don&rsquo;t want is more important than knowing what you want.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">V. Conclusion 
    <div id="v-conclusion" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#v-conclusion" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This session covered investment philosophy, life philosophy, parenting experiences, and more. James, with his unique perspective and sharp language, criticized the shortcomings of the current financial education system, proposed a &ldquo;brainless investing&rdquo; strategy, and emphasized the importance of asset allocation and &ldquo;knowing how to spend.&rdquo;  He also discussed topics such as how to cultivate children&rsquo;s sense of responsibility and finding one&rsquo;s purpose in life, encouraging the audience to actively think about the meaning of life and contribute to society.</p>

  



<div
  
    class="flex px-4 py-3 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900"
  >

  <span
    
      class="text-primary-400 ltr:pr-3 rtl:pl-3 flex items-center"
    >

    

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M506.3 417l-213.3-364c-16.33-28-57.54-28-73.98 0l-213.2 364C-10.59 444.9 9.849 480 42.74 480h426.6C502.1 480 522.6 445 506.3 417zM232 168c0-13.25 10.75-24 24-24S280 154.8 280 168v128c0 13.25-10.75 24-23.1 24S232 309.3 232 296V168zM256 416c-17.36 0-31.44-14.08-31.44-31.44c0-17.36 14.07-31.44 31.44-31.44s31.44 14.08 31.44 31.44C287.4 401.9 273.4 416 256 416z"/></svg>

  </span>


  </span>

  <span
    
      class="dark:text-neutral-300"
    ><strong>Disclaimer:</strong> This article is only for personal learning notes and does not constitute any investment advice.</span>
</div>

]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>00481 Asset Allocation Strategies to Avoid Market Pitfalls; How to Achieve Steady Wealth through Proper Investment Strategies</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1728285792652/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1728285792652/</guid><description>In this session, James emphasizes the crucial role of mental strength in investment success. He discusses asset allocation, the use and rebalancing of leveraged ETFs, provides supplementary explanations of 401(k) and IRA accounts, and touches upon choosing the right brokerage. The Q&amp;amp;A session addresses audience questions concerning investing with mortgage loans, market crash risks, the risks associated with single brokerage accounts, and how to cope with the psychological pressure stemming from market fluctuations. Furthermore, the discussion includes insights on investment target selection, the purpose of holding cash, and life planning.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<lite-youtube videoid="ZvTM4--CaKw" playlabel="ZvTM4--CaKw" params=""></lite-youtube>



<h2 class="relative group">I. Main Theme 
    <div id="i-main-theme" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-main-theme" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This session centers around the importance of psychological resilience in investing. James&rsquo;s core message is that mental strength is the key to investment success, while other skills and calculations are secondary. Investors need to maintain a highly optimistic mindset, viewing market fluctuations as opportunities rather than crises in the long run. Long-term investing, rational analysis, and maintaining a healthy mindset are more crucial than striving for precise calculations.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">II. Briefing Content 
    <div id="ii-briefing-content" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii-briefing-content" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<ul>
<li><strong>Correction on 401(k) and IRA:</strong> James corrects a statement from the previous session regarding 401(k) and IRA contribution limits, clarifying that the limits for each are independent, but that IRAs have income restrictions. He provides further explanations about the Backdoor Roth IRA conversion, advising listeners to manage pre-tax and after-tax funds carefully to avoid account confusion and complications during tax filing.</li>
<li><strong>Asset Allocation Strategy:</strong> He emphasizes the significance of asset allocation and suggests listeners refer to existing articles and Excel spreadsheets for simulations, discouraging impulsive decision-making. He offers various asset allocation plans catering to different risk tolerances and retirement stages, stressing the concept of &ldquo;fuzzy accuracy&rdquo; – that it is not necessary to pursue overly precise ratios, but ensuring sufficient cash reserves is crucial. Example: A listener proposes an allocation of 60% QQQ and 40% cash, which James believes carries a risk of bankruptcy and advises them to consult the provided asset allocation plans.</li>
<li><strong>Leveraged ETFs and Rebalancing:</strong> Using QQQ&rsquo;s beta value of 1.0 as a benchmark, he simplifies beta calculations for leveraged ETFs, for instance, QLD is considered 2.0. He recommends a gradual approach when adjusting beta during rebalancing, advising against drastic changes. For investors with earned income, the frequency and ratio of rebalancing can be more flexible. Example: He suggests that young investors can rotate investments among QQQ, QLD, and TQQQ every six months, then rebalance at the end of the year.</li>
<li><strong>Long-Term Investing and Market Volatility:</strong> James reiterates the importance of long-term investing, using the dot-com bubble of 2000 as an example to demonstrate that long-term investors ultimately profit, even after enduring prolonged market downturns. Market dips are opportunities, and investors should remain optimistic, buying whenever they have funds available. He refutes the notion that &ldquo;investments in 2000 took 15 years to break even,&rdquo; emphasizing that the market always recovers in the long run. Example: An investment of $5 million at the peak of the market in 2000, despite experiencing the burst of the internet bubble, would still have grown to $32.375 million by 2024.</li>
<li><strong>Brokerage Selection:</strong> He advises choosing brokerages with physical branch offices and understanding how stocks and cash are held in custody to ensure asset security. Example: He explains the risks of nominee accounts and recommends selecting brokerages that allow for direct ownership of stocks, encouraging listeners to inquire about the brokerage&rsquo;s custodian banks for stocks and cash.</li>
<li><strong>Purpose of Holding Cash:</strong> He underlines that cash holdings are meant for emergencies and to seize buying opportunities during market downturns, not for pursuing interest income. Example: He suggests maintaining a 20% cash position, a portion of which can be utilized for adding to leveraged ETFs during dips.</li>
<li><strong>Investment Target Selection:</strong> He recommends selecting suitable investment targets based on individual circumstances. For instance, retirees or individuals with limited funds may consider high-dividend ETFs, while younger individuals or those with ample funds should focus on growth-oriented ETFs like QQQ. Example: Addressing a listener holding SCH, James advises them to assess whether high-dividend ETFs are appropriate based on their asset level and annual expenses.</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">III. Q&amp;A Session 
    <div id="iii-qa-session" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii-qa-session" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p><strong>Danny:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Shares: He has been following James&rsquo;s investment strategy for three years and achieved a return of approximately 35%.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Chang&rsquo;an:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Question: Brokerage security and recommendations in Hong Kong.</li>
<li>James&rsquo;s Response: Choose brokerages with physical branch offices in the region, understand the custodian banks for stocks and cash, and avoid easily dissolved online brokerages.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Eric:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Shares: He began investing during the pandemic, experienced the hardships of short-term trading, and eventually recognized the importance of long-term investing and psychological control. He uses the example of Jesse Livermore to illustrate the risks of trading.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Jessie:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Shares: Both she and her husband are nearing 60 years old, and a portion of their investment funds comes from a mortgage loan. She expresses concerns about a potential market crash and the risk of USD devaluation.</li>
<li>Questions:</li>
</ul>
<ol>
<li>How to cope with a possible future market crash, especially with a mortgage due before retirement?</li>
<li>What about USD devaluation?</li>
<li>Are there risks associated with concentrating large sums of money in a single brokerage account?</li>
<li>Is it feasible to refinance the mortgage in five years or repay it early with funds from the investment account?</li>
</ol>
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Response:</li>
</ul>
<ol>
<li>The market is unlikely to experience losses within a 15-year timeframe. Ensure you can comfortably handle mortgage payments for the next 13 years; the most secure approach is to sell the house and repay the loan.</li>
<li>He declines to answer hypothetical questions.</li>
<li>Stocks are registered under the investor&rsquo;s name, hence the risk of brokerage failure is manageable.</li>
<li>Refinancing or early repayment is not recommended. Excessive focus on short-term interest gains is akin to &ldquo;penny wise, pound foolish,&rdquo; and ultimately increases risk.</li>
</ol>
<p><strong>Sam:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Shares: He went all-in on QQQ, but after some short-term trading, realized it wasn&rsquo;t suitable for him and experienced psychological pressure due to large position fluctuations.</li>
<li>Question: How to overcome the psychological pressure brought about by fluctuations in a large portfolio?</li>
<li>James&rsquo;s Response:</li>
</ul>
<ol>
<li>Focus on realized gains rather than unrealized gains.</li>
<li>Maintain 20% cash and 20% leveraged ETFs to stabilize your mindset.</li>
<li>Exercise caution with short-term trading, as it may not be sustainable in the long run.</li>
</ol>
<p><strong>Haoqing:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Shares: He uses examples of friends gambling and raising children to illustrate the importance of moderate expectations and nurturing interests. He compares and contrasts education philosophies and Nobel Prize achievements between China and the US, emphasizing the significance of financial freedom for the next generation.</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">IV. Highlights 
    <div id="iv-highlights" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv-highlights" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>Mental fortitude is the equipment for investing, it determines whether you will succeed.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Investment skills and calculations are undoubtedly important, but psychological resilience is the ultimate factor that decides investment success. Even for simple index fund investing, a sound mental state is needed to navigate market volatility.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>A market downturn is not a disaster, it&rsquo;s an opportunity.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>From a long-term investment perspective, market downturns provide excellent opportunities to acquire high-quality assets.  Maintain a long-term outlook and don&rsquo;t be intimidated by short-term fluctuations.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>There should be a limit to human pessimism.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Excessive pessimism and worry are detrimental to investments. One should rationally analyze risks and develop sensible coping strategies. Do not let extreme scenarios or low-probability events unduly influence investment decisions.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Parents sometimes have these expectations for their children, don&rsquo;t impose your unfulfilled aspirations on them.
&ndash; Haoqing</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Parents should respect their children&rsquo;s individuality and interests and refrain from forcing their own unaccomplished goals onto them. Allowing children to have a joyful childhood and the autonomy to choose their own paths in life is more important than chasing conventional success.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">V. Summary 
    <div id="v-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#v-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>In this session, James reiterates the importance of mental fortitude in investing and the effectiveness of long-term investment and asset allocation strategies. By addressing listeners&rsquo; practical concerns, such as retirement planning, market volatility, and capital security, he helps them better understand and apply these investment principles. James also provides advice on choosing appropriate investment targets and the purpose of holding cash, aiding listeners in constructing more comprehensive investment strategies. Haoqing&rsquo;s sharing sparked reflection on educational philosophies and life values, advocating for a focus on children&rsquo;s overall development and mental well-being.</p>

  



<div
  
    class="flex px-4 py-3 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900"
  >

  <span
    
      class="text-primary-400 ltr:pr-3 rtl:pl-3 flex items-center"
    >

    

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M506.3 417l-213.3-364c-16.33-28-57.54-28-73.98 0l-213.2 364C-10.59 444.9 9.849 480 42.74 480h426.6C502.1 480 522.6 445 506.3 417zM232 168c0-13.25 10.75-24 24-24S280 154.8 280 168v128c0 13.25-10.75 24-23.1 24S232 309.3 232 296V168zM256 416c-17.36 0-31.44-14.08-31.44-31.44c0-17.36 14.07-31.44 31.44-31.44s31.44 14.08 31.44 31.44C287.4 401.9 273.4 416 256 416z"/></svg>

  </span>


  </span>

  <span
    
      class="dark:text-neutral-300"
    ><strong>Disclaimer:</strong> This document is only for personal learning and note-taking purposes and does not constitute any investment advice.</span>
</div>

]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>00480 Is investing in Index Fund guaranteed to be profitable? How can one consistently make profits in the market?</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1728203545381/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1728203545381/</guid><description>This session focuses on investment cycles, covering how to identify market cycles, emphasizing the challenge of differentiating between premature and incorrect judgments, and illustrating with Buffett&amp;#39;s actions during the 2008 financial crisis. It also touches upon risks associated with real estate investment, insurance choices, stock pledges, and asset allocation strategies, particularly comparing and offering advice for the Taiwanese and US markets. In the Q&amp;amp;A section, students raised questions and shared insights on topics such as the aircraft carrier investment strategy, property tax, central bank policy, currency devaluation, and James addressed each one in detail.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Part 1:
<lite-youtube videoid="ztdWeAncmqY" playlabel="ztdWeAncmqY" params=""></lite-youtube>
</li>
<li>Part 2:
<lite-youtube videoid="Xvv1cCV3dHA" playlabel="Xvv1cCV3dHA" params=""></lite-youtube>
</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">I. Main Topic 
    <div id="i-main-topic" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-main-topic" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This session centered around investment cycles, exploring how to assess market cycles, highlighting the difficulty in distinguishing between acting too early and making wrong judgments during cycle shifts. It used Buffett&rsquo;s actions during the 2008 financial crisis as a case study. Additionally, it discussed risks related to real estate investment, insurance, and stock pledges, while providing an in-depth analysis of asset allocation strategies, particularly comparing and recommending approaches for the Taiwanese and US markets.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">II.  Briefing Content 
    <div id="ii--briefing-content" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii--briefing-content" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<ol>
<li>
<p><strong>Investment Cycles</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Investor sentiment is likened to a pendulum, swinging between extreme fear and extreme optimism.</li>
<li>Differentiating between premature judgments and incorrect ones during cycle changes is challenging, as exemplified by Buffett&rsquo;s public announcement of buying stocks in late 2008, followed by a further 30% market decline.</li>
<li>Swing trading is no longer recommended, as the market perpetually rises, making long-term investment the key.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Risks of Real Estate Investment</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Real estate investment is considered high-risk, requiring maintenance and incurring high holding costs like property taxes and HOA fees.</li>
<li>US property tax is a holding tax; the longer you hold, the more tax you pay.</li>
<li>Rental yields are low, around 2% in the US Bay Area after deducting expenses.</li>
<li>The biggest risks of buying a house are job loss and having outstanding mortgage debt at retirement.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Insurance Choices</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Avoid commercial insurance, such as life insurance, long-term care insurance, universal life insurance, etc.</li>
<li>Necessary insurance includes health insurance and term life insurance. Term life insurance is suitable for those who are the sole income source for their family, providing support for children under 18.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Risks of Stock Pledging</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Stock pledging is extremely risky, especially in the Taiwanese market, with a maintenance ratio requirement of 167%.</li>
<li>Absolutely forbid using borrowed funds from stock pledges for reinvestment.</li>
<li>In Taiwan, leveraged ETFs can be pledged, but risks still exist.</li>
<li>Be cautious about diversifying risks in stock pledging in Taiwan. Do not pledge all assets to the same financial institution, and avoid pledging everything at once.</li>
<li>Taiwanese investors are advised to adopt the &ldquo;Situation 3&rdquo; asset allocation strategy: 30% cash, 30% leverage, and 40% QQQ or other broad-based index funds.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Asset Allocation Strategies</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>When selecting investment targets, understand their risk and return characteristics, and allocate assets reasonably based on your circumstances.</li>
<li>Long-term investment in QQQ index funds is like piloting an aircraft carrier—stable and offering considerable returns.</li>
<li>Investing in individual stocks and sectors is like sailing a small boat—high risk and susceptible to market fluctuations.</li>
<li>Investments in individual stocks and sectors are similar to the once-booming railway industry, which was eventually replaced by new technologies and industries. For example, the semiconductor industry may also be eliminated in the future.</li>
<li>QQQ index funds have a replacement mechanism to promptly remove underperforming stocks, maintaining overall growth momentum.</li>
<li>Investing in individual stocks requires the ability to identify potential opportunities and understand market and industry trends, as exemplified by James&rsquo; interaction with NVIDIA&rsquo;s CEO before its IPO and his purchase of Amazon shares during its slump.</li>
<li>For retirement accounts, it&rsquo;s recommended to invest all Rust account funds in leveraged ETFs, while 401K accounts can hold cash or bonds.</li>
<li>Be cautious when borrowing for investment; ensure cash flow can cover interest payments and manage risks effectively.</li>
<li>In the US, if capital gains tax is implemented, consider transferring funds to other countries.</li>
<li>Avoid investing in the Chinese market due to policy risks and economic downturn pressures.</li>
<li>Do not purchase annuity products; they offer low returns and carry risks.</li>
<li>After selling a house, do not deposit funds into IRA or traditional IRA accounts.</li>
<li>Be decisive in investing and avoid hesitation. For example, loss-making properties should be sold as soon as possible, and the funds should be invested in the stock market.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ol>


<h2 class="relative group">III. Q&amp;A Session 
    <div id="iii-qa-session" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii-qa-session" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p><strong>Eric:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing:</strong>  Used the analogy of QQQ index funds being like aircraft carriers and individual stocks being like small boats to illustrate the advantages of index fund investing.</li>
<li><strong>Sharing:</strong>  James&rsquo; channel not only shares investment knowledge but also many life stories, such as estate planning and tax planning, from which valuable lessons can be learned.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Brian:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Question:</strong>  For employed individuals using the &ldquo;Situation 2&rdquo; asset allocation strategy, is it possible to set a higher Beta value, such as 1.1 or 1.2?</li>
<li><strong>Answer:</strong>  There is no upper limit for Beta, as long as cash is at least twice the amount of borrowed funds. Excel spreadsheets can be used to simulate investment outcomes under different scenarios, allowing adjustments based on individual risk tolerance.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Mike:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing:</strong> The US is like a Bogue bird, adept at concealing its strength and waiting for the opportune moment to reap the rewards, which aligns with the long-term investment philosophy.</li>
<li><strong>Question:</strong>  Will the central bank ignore economic recession and focus solely on inflation?</li>
<li><strong>Answer:</strong>  The central bank will not ignore economic recession because it leads to increased unemployment, which is one of the central bank&rsquo;s key concerns. Economic recession and unemployment are closely related.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Cheng Ge (PC):</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing:</strong>  Illustrated the drawbacks of investment-linked insurance policies through a real-life case study, recommending early surrender and transferring funds to QQQ index funds to recoup losses within a shorter timeframe and achieve higher returns.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Lang:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Question:</strong>  Is it feasible to utilize market downturns to buy QLD leveraged ETFs using a Roth IRA account and convert a 401K account to cash, aiming to increase the proportion of funds in the Roth IRA account?</li>
<li><strong>Answer:</strong>  If Rust account funds are limited, they should all be invested in leveraged ETFs. The 401K account can hold cash as a hedge. There&rsquo;s no need to wait for market downturns to make the switch; asset allocation should be completed as early as possible.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Tina:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Question:</strong>  If the 401K account is already maxed out, is it still possible to invest in an IRA account?</li>
<li><strong>Answer:</strong> After maxing out the 401K account, you cannot contribute to a traditional IRA account, but you can contribute to a Roth IRA account. Specific eligibility depends on income level and IRA contribution limits. It&rsquo;s recommended to check the IRA contribution limit for relevant information.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>IAM:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Question:</strong>  Will events like the Malaysian currency devaluation and the Hong Kong emigration wave impact the US economy and the US dollar? How does the US prevent currency devaluation? Will the companies in the QQQ index fund be affected?</li>
<li><strong>Answer:</strong> A country&rsquo;s currency value depends on its creditworthiness, which is backed by national industries and power. The US possesses strong national strength and diversified industries, allowing the US dollar to maintain its strong position. The US government will safeguard the interests of American companies and citizens. It&rsquo;s uncertain whether US companies will be directly affected by US dollar devaluation, but they will undoubtedly be protected by the US government.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>TT:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Question:</strong>  Are you still considering cycle investing at present?</li>
<li><strong>Answer:</strong>  Yes, cycle investing will be considered, but not through the all-in, all-out approach used in the past. Instead, Beta adjustments will be employed to navigate market volatility, as it&rsquo;s difficult for a large number of investors to keep up with rapid trading, thus requiring a more robust strategy.</li>
<li><strong>Question:</strong>  Which US political party, Democrat or Republican, is more favorable to investors?</li>
<li><strong>Answer:</strong>  In the long run, policies of both parties have minimal impact on investors. The market adjusts according to policies; for example, higher tax rates may induce investors to hold assets for longer periods.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>YJ:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Question:</strong> Are there any differences in asset allocation strategies between Taiwan and the US? What is the role of the 00864B bond? Why is investing in 00757 no longer recommended?</li>
<li><strong>Answer:</strong> Asset allocation strategies are universally applicable. The main differences between Taiwan and the US lie in stock pledging rules and leveraged ETF choices. 00864B can be used as a cash alternative, similar to a USD fixed deposit. Reasons for no longer recommending investment in 00757 can be found in the videos from 2021 and 2022.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Jason:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Question:</strong> Can dollar-cost averaging (DCA) be used to invest in leveraged ETFs like Q2D?</li>
<li><strong>Answer:</strong> When investing in any asset, including leveraged ETFs, lump-sum purchasing should be adopted instead of DCA. Returns from DCA are likely to be lower than lump-sum purchasing.</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">IV. Key Takeaways 
    <div id="iv-key-takeaways" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv-key-takeaways" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>QQQ index funds are like aircraft carriers, offering stability and substantial returns, while individual stock and sector investments are like sailing small boats, carrying high risk and vulnerability to market fluctuations.
&ndash; James &amp; Eric</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Choosing long-term investment in QQQ index funds can mitigate the risks associated with individual stocks and sector investments, providing more stable returns.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The central bank will not disregard economic recession, as it leads to rising unemployment, a key indicator that the central bank monitors.
&ndash;  James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>One of the objectives of the central bank&rsquo;s monetary policy is to maintain low unemployment; therefore, it will not stand idly by in the face of economic recession.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Loss aversion is a common mistake among investors. Losses should be cut promptly, and funds should be reallocated to higher-quality assets.
&ndash; Cheng Ge (PC)</p>
</blockquote>
<p>It&rsquo;s crucial to overcome the psychological barrier of loss aversion in investing, decisively cutting losses to prevent them from escalating.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The US&rsquo;s national strength rests on four pillars: government, the financial industry, businesses, and national defense. These four pillars work in synergy to achieve strategic goals.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>America&rsquo;s robust, comprehensive national strength is the cornerstone of the US dollar&rsquo;s strong position.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>In the long term, policies of both US parties have a limited impact on investors; the market adjusts itself based on policies.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>The market has a self-regulating mechanism, enabling it to adapt to various policy environments.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>When investing in any asset, including leveraged ETFs, lump-sum purchasing should be adopted instead of dollar-cost averaging (DCA). Returns from DCA are likely to be lower than lump-sum purchasing.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;Buy whenever you have money&rdquo; is the investment strategy James consistently emphasizes. DCA is less efficient for long-term investment.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">V. Summary 
    <div id="v-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#v-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This session primarily revolved around investment cycles, with James explaining how to identify market cycles and emphasizing the distinction between premature and incorrect judgments, using Buffett&rsquo;s actions during the 2008 financial crisis as an example. Furthermore, it provided detailed insights into the risks of real estate investment, insurance selection, stock pledging, and asset allocation strategies. In the Q&amp;A segment, students raised questions and shared their perspectives on topics such as the aircraft carrier investment strategy, property tax, central bank policy, currency devaluation, and investment strategy in the Taiwanese market. James offered comprehensive answers to each question and reiterated the importance of long-term investment in QQQ index funds, along with the &ldquo;buy whenever you have money&rdquo; investment strategy.</p>

  



<div
  
    class="flex px-4 py-3 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900"
  >

  <span
    
      class="text-primary-400 ltr:pr-3 rtl:pl-3 flex items-center"
    >

    

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M506.3 417l-213.3-364c-16.33-28-57.54-28-73.98 0l-213.2 364C-10.59 444.9 9.849 480 42.74 480h426.6C502.1 480 522.6 445 506.3 417zM232 168c0-13.25 10.75-24 24-24S280 154.8 280 168v128c0 13.25-10.75 24-23.1 24S232 309.3 232 296V168zM256 416c-17.36 0-31.44-14.08-31.44-31.44c0-17.36 14.07-31.44 31.44-31.44s31.44 14.08 31.44 31.44C287.4 401.9 273.4 416 256 416z"/></svg>

  </span>


  </span>

  <span
    
      class="dark:text-neutral-300"
    ><strong>Disclaimer:</strong> This document is for personal learning and note-taking purposes only and does not constitute any investment advice.</span>
</div>

]]></content:encoded></item></channel></rss>