<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>China&#39;s Economy on QQQ Investor</title>
    <link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/tags/chinas-economy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in China&#39;s Economy on QQQ Investor</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 28 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jomonylw.github.io/en/tags/chinas-economy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>00485 Buying a house will only make you poor. Investing makes you rich. Borrowing money to keep your assets growing is the way to become wealthy</title>
      <link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1728259977859/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1728259977859/</guid>
      <description>This episode focuses on investment philosophy, strategies to avoid scams, and the impact of China&amp;#39;s newest economic policies on the global market. James reiterates the importance of long-term investment in index funds, specifically QQQ, and advises investors to control their emotions and resist market volatility. He uses real-life examples and data to illustrate the concept of borrowing for consumption, investing for asset growth, and analyzes China&amp;#39;s recent economic stimulus policies, viewing them as a positive sign for global economic recovery. </description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<lite-youtube videoid="zJdXwFaec2c" playlabel="zJdXwFaec2c" params=""></lite-youtube>



<h2 class="relative group">I. Main Topic 
    <div id="i-main-topic" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-main-topic" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This episode primarily discusses proper investment philosophy, ways to avoid investment traps, and the implications of China&rsquo;s latest economic policies for the global market. James emphasizes the importance of long-term investment in index funds, particularly QQQ, and reminds investors to maintain emotional control and not be swayed by market fluctuations. He uses specific examples and data to illustrate the concept of &ldquo;borrow for consumption, invest for asset growth,&rdquo; while also analyzing China&rsquo;s recently introduced series of economic stimulus policies, believing them to be a positive signal for a global economic recovery.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">II. Briefing Content 
    <div id="ii-briefing-content" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii-briefing-content" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<ul>
<li><strong>Investment Philosophy:</strong>
<ul>
<li>Emotions are the biggest enemy in investing. You need to avoid being influenced by news and information, stay rational, and refrain from chasing rising or falling markets.</li>
<li>Investing requires a long-term perspective, aiming for a timeframe of 40 years or more. Warren Buffett acquired 99% of his wealth after the age of 50, demonstrating that patience is key to wealth creation.</li>
<li>Choose investment targets that are consistently stable and provide high returns. Index funds are the best option, especially QQQ, which boasts a long-term annualized return of 14%.</li>
<li>Adhere to the &ldquo;never sell&rdquo; strategy to allow assets to continue appreciating. Avoid selling stocks unless absolutely necessary.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Scam Avoidance Guide:</strong>
<ul>
<li>Be wary of various investment traps. Do not trust any projects that guarantee high returns, especially those that require you to sell existing assets for new investments.</li>
<li>Do not readily believe any investment or financial management information received via phone, text messages, or online platforms. Any information involving bank accounts or government departments must be verified through official channels.</li>
<li>Be cautious of aggressive sales tactics from financial institutions. Stick to your investment plan and avoid being lured by various fancy financial products.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Regarding Real Estate Investment:</strong>
<ul>
<li>James advises against homeownership for average working individuals, believing it turns them into &ldquo;mortgage slaves&rdquo; burdened with heavy loan pressure, hindering wealth accumulation.</li>
<li>He advocates for a &ldquo;rent instead of buy&rdquo; approach, suggesting using a stock pledge loan to rent high-quality housing at lower interest rates, then investing the saved funds for higher returns.</li>
<li>Consider purchasing real estate only when your assets reach a certain scale and you can comfortably afford the payment.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>New Trends in China&rsquo;s Economy:</strong>
<ul>
<li>The People&rsquo;s Bank of China recently introduced a series of potent fiscal policies, including reserve requirement ratio and interest rate cuts, injecting funds into banks, and encouraging stock purchases, to stimulate economic growth.</li>
<li>These policies will contribute positively to stabilizing China&rsquo;s real estate market, boosting consumer confidence, and promoting global economic recovery.</li>
<li>Investors should pay attention to developments in the Chinese market and seize new investment opportunities.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">III. Q&amp;A Session 
    <div id="iii-qa-session" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii-qa-session" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p><strong>IM:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Through conversations with individuals of different age groups, IM discovered that most people have insufficient awareness of long-term savings and are often constrained by mortgages and other factors. By comparing the returns of index funds in different countries and regions with those of fixed deposits and pensions, IM illustrated the advantages of long-term investment in index funds.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>INGYNYING:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: INGYNYING&rsquo;s mother wanted to sell all her assets to purchase a house but, after persuasion, realized that this would lead to losing opportunities for asset appreciation. Many of INGYNYING&rsquo;s friends are afraid of change, preferring to endure the hardships of their current situation rather than attempt new investment methods.</li>
<li>Question: How to convince family members to accept new investment concepts?</li>
<li>James&rsquo; answer: Utilize data and case studies for illustration, such as comparing the long-term returns of fixed deposits and index funds, and sharing success stories of investors. It&rsquo;s also important to respect family members&rsquo; choices and refrain from forcing them to accept new ideas.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Allen:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Questions:  Should someone with assets worth 50 times their annual living expenses use their salary to pay for a car? How can a couple combine their stock accounts for collateral purposes?</li>
<li>James&rsquo; answer: It is recommended to utilize Tesla&rsquo;s official website loan to purchase a vehicle, then use funds from a stock pledge loan to repay the car loan. Dedicate your salary entirely to investment. Couples can combine their accounts through a joint account for collateral, sharing the limit, while their accounts remain individually managed.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Eric:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Question: Eric&rsquo;s mother is visiting the US and is concerned about medical expenses. How should this be  handled?</li>
<li>James&rsquo; answer:  Purchasing travel insurance is advised, but excessive worry is unnecessary. Most non-emergency situations can be treated back home. If encountering extremely high medical costs, attempting negotiation with the hospital or seeking alternative solutions is possible. Due to the specific circumstances of foreign nationality and lack of income, the hospital may choose not to pursue the medical expenses.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Dean:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Dean purchased a new car using Tesla&rsquo;s website loan and a stock pledge loan, conserving a significant amount of capital. Learning about investing boosted Dean&rsquo;s confidence to decline a high-paying job and choose to stay home with their child.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Michael:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Questions: How to secure a loan from Tesla&rsquo;s official website for a car purchase? Can funds from 401k or IRA accounts be used for collateral? What are the options if QQQ is not available in their company&rsquo;s 401k plan?</li>
<li>James&rsquo; answer: To apply for a car loan through Tesla&rsquo;s website, choose the desired model and configuration, click &ldquo;Order Now&rdquo;, and select &ldquo;Finance&rdquo;. Funds in retirement accounts cannot be used as collateral; it is recommended to transfer part of those funds to a brokerage account for collateral purposes.  Alternative options include choosing an S&amp;P 500 index fund or inquiring with the company about the possibility of Blockage Link to invest in QQQ.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>EVA:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Question: As a single, middle-aged woman with limited savings, how to balance work and investment? Should selling the house be considered for investment purposes?</li>
<li>James&rsquo; answer: Continue working diligently while consistently making monthly investments. Even small amounts will accumulate over 8-9 years, reaching the threshold for collateral, allowing you to leverage and accelerate wealth growth. Selling a house for investment is an option but requires careful consideration based on personal circumstances.  If renting is more cost-effective, choose to rent and allocate the funds to investments yielding higher returns.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Jenny:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Questions:  Any knowledge regarding the latest Roth SEP IRA policy?</li>
<li>James&rsquo; answer: The policy information is quite recent, and the accuracy of the $69,000 limit requires verification. Consulting with professionals like a financial advisor at Chase or Lisa is recommended. As it is a new product, not all institutions may offer it.</li>
<li>Sharing: Jenny shared a personal experience of being scammed, reminding everyone to exercise caution and avoid trusting any investment information, particularly those spread through unofficial channels.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Haoqing:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Haoqing relayed the experiences of close friends falling victim to scams, lamenting that scam tactics are constantly evolving and are hard to guard against, even for highly educated individuals.</li>
<li>Question: How can investment concepts be better conveyed to people around us to prevent them from being deceived? Is there a need to explain professional investment knowledge?</li>
<li>James&rsquo; answer: Avoid explaining intricate investment knowledge; simply emphasize the core principle of long-term investment in index funds. Excessive professional details may confuse them, making them more susceptible to being misled by other investment information and ultimately falling prey to scams.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Jason:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Recounted an NFT scam incident encountered on Clubhouse, warning everyone to be wary of risks in the cryptocurrency world. Expressed gratitude toward James&rsquo; investment philosophy for helping them avoid such traps.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Amy:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Amy shared personal encounters with scams, including impersonations of government departments and courier companies. She emphasized the importance of relying only on written communication and ignoring any investment information delivered through phone calls or text messages. Amy suggested that, when in doubt, contact official channels for clarification.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Becky:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Suggestion: Avoid answering calls from unfamiliar numbers, set up spam filters, and use a less important email address when necessary to share personal information to minimize the risk of scams.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Mike:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Question: What are your thoughts on China&rsquo;s most recent economic policies? Are they sustainable?</li>
<li>James&rsquo; answer: The People&rsquo;s Bank of China has introduced powerful policies that are having a positive impact on economic confidence. Investors should keep an eye on these developments. Although the policies appear to be heading in a positive direction, their sustainability remains to be seen.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Julia:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Question:  Any updates on the Roth SEP IRA policy? Are there any financial institutions already offering related products?</li>
<li>James&rsquo; answer: The policy information is fairly new, and the $69,000 limit&rsquo;s accuracy is debatable. Consulting with a professional is advised. Being a new product, not all institutions might offer it yet.</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">IV. Noteworthy Points 
    <div id="iv-noteworthy-points" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv-noteworthy-points" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>“You have enough money when you have enough.&quot;
&ndash; Many people</p></blockquote>
<p>Many individuals believe that having just enough to get by is sufficient. This is a mistaken notion, as money is never truly enough. True financial freedom lies in possessing the power of choice – going wherever you want, doing whatever you desire – instead of being constrained by finances.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;Never borrow money for investments.&rdquo;
&ndash; Many people</p></blockquote>
<p>Many believe that borrowing for investment is unwise; however, this viewpoint is overly cautious. True investors, like Warren Buffett, skillfully leverage debt. Following the principle of &ldquo;borrow for consumption, invest for asset growth&rdquo;, the correct approach is to use borrowed money for expenses and personal money for investment. This enables rapid wealth accumulation.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“All investment information received through phone calls, text messages, or online platforms is not trustworthy.”
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>Nowadays, numerous scams operate through these channels. It&rsquo;s crucial to exercise caution and avoid blindly believing any financial advice or information. Anything involving bank accounts or government departments must be verified through official sources. Additionally, seeking guidance from qualified professionals is essential.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“Investment must be consistently stable over the long term, which is why index funds are the only viable option.&quot;
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>Within the complex investment landscape, index funds stand out as a few reliable options capable of offering consistent stability and high returns. Index funds are like living organisms; they will never die, whereas all individual stocks will eventually disappear within a century.  If you&rsquo;re looking for generational wealth, index funds are the way to go.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">V. Summary 
    <div id="v-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#v-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This episode is packed with valuable information and insights. It not only reiterates the importance of long-term index fund investment but also offers practical tips on scam prevention and provides an in-depth analysis of China&rsquo;s newest economic policies.  It is recommended to apply this knowledge to your investment practices and strive for financial freedom.</p>

  



<div
  
    class="flex px-4 py-3 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900"
  >

  <span
    
      class="text-primary-400 ltr:pr-3 rtl:pl-3 flex items-center"
    >

    

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M506.3 417l-213.3-364c-16.33-28-57.54-28-73.98 0l-213.2 364C-10.59 444.9 9.849 480 42.74 480h426.6C502.1 480 522.6 445 506.3 417zM232 168c0-13.25 10.75-24 24-24S280 154.8 280 168v128c0 13.25-10.75 24-23.1 24S232 309.3 232 296V168zM256 416c-17.36 0-31.44-14.08-31.44-31.44c0-17.36 14.07-31.44 31.44-31.44s31.44 14.08 31.44 31.44C287.4 401.9 273.4 416 256 416z"/></svg>

  </span>


  </span>

  <span
    
      class="dark:text-neutral-300"
    ><strong>Disclaimer:</strong> This article serves solely as personal study notes and does not constitute any investment advice.</span>
</div>

]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
