<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Investment on QQQ Investor</title>
    <link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/tags/investment/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Investment on QQQ Investor</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jomonylw.github.io/en/tags/investment/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>00486 Market Trends and Future Investment Strategies:Navigating the New Economic Era</title>
      <link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1728231523948/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1728231523948/</guid>
      <description>In this session, James shares his analysis of the current market situation and investment advice. He also answers questions from the audience on topics like asset allocation, retirement planning, children&amp;#39;s education, handling stock options, leverage, and tax planning.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<lite-youtube videoid="mwchPrvkFMA" playlabel="mwchPrvkFMA" params=""></lite-youtube>



<h2 class="relative group">I. Main Topic 
    <div id="i-main-topic" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-main-topic" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>The theme of this session is <strong>Embrace the New Bull Market and Invest Long-Term.</strong> James believes that the global monetary easing policy and the rapid development of AI technology herald the arrival of a new bull market. He advises everyone to invest in the Nasdaq 100 index fund (QQQ or 00662) and view market fluctuations with a long-term perspective.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">II.  Content Summary 
    <div id="ii--content-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii--content-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<ul>
<li><strong>A new bull market is coming:</strong>  The world has entered an era of loose monetary policy with the start of a rate cut cycle, which will drive the stock market up. This bull market may be a slow one but will continuously rise.</li>
<li><strong>Invest confidently in the Nasdaq 100 index fund:</strong> QQQ could increase by 50 times in the next 20 years, with an annualized return of over 20%, making it the best investment target.</li>
<li><strong>Individual stocks are unreliable:</strong> Individual stock investment is risky, and in the long run, almost all of them will disappear. They are very difficult to outperform the market in the long term. It is recommended not to waste time and energy on stock selection.</li>
<li><strong>Do not invest in the Chinese stock market:</strong> The Chinese stock market is not mature enough; consider investing in it after 30 years.</li>
<li><strong>Comparison of household asset allocation in the US and Taiwan:</strong>  American families invest most of their assets in securities to create social value, while Taiwanese families prefer cash, insurance, and real estate, locking up funds in non-appreciating areas.</li>
<li><strong>Leveraging through stock pledges:</strong> Using stock pledges to borrow increases liquidity and allows for continued investment to enjoy the benefits of compound growth. With an understanding of asset allocation, the interest cost of borrowing can be almost negligible.</li>
<li><strong>Plan for retirement early:</strong> Young people are advised to invest in 00662, and retirees can choose 00646 (SPY) or 0056 according to their fund size.</li>
<li><strong>Emphasize family education:</strong> Parents should cultivate their children&rsquo;s financial management concepts from an early age, guide them to make long-term investments, stay away from bad habits such as short-term speculation and gambling, and lead by example.</li>
<li><strong>Don&rsquo;t blindly trust high-yield investment products:</strong> Any investment product promising high returns may be a scam. It is important to understand its operating mechanism and learn to discern between true and false.</li>
<li><strong>The dangers of short-term trading:</strong> Short-term trading will miss the best investment opportunities. Long-term investment in index funds will yield more stable returns.</li>
<li><strong>The purpose of cash allocation:</strong> It is not for profit, but for dealing with emergencies like unemployment or a market crash. It is advisable to keep more than 10% of your assets in cash.</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">III. Q&amp;A Session 
    <div id="iii-qa-session" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii-qa-session" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<ul>
<li>
<p><strong>Retired Doctor Poch:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: After learning about James&rsquo; investment philosophy, he found a more relaxing and suitable investment method.</li>
<li>Question: How to obtain a stable cash flow after retirement? Is it necessary to adjust the investment strategy of 00662?
<ul>
<li>Answer:  The investment target can be adjusted according to the size of the retirement fund. Choose 00646 (SPY) or 0056 with lower volatility to guarantee cash flow.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>IM:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: He tried to guide his child to invest by matching contributions and increased his vigilance against high-yield traps.</li>
<li>Question 1: How to guide a child to invest and prevent them from spending investment income?
<ul>
<li>Answer: Emphasize that investment is a long-term behavior. Income cannot be withdrawn for consumption. Funds should grow continuously through compound interest.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2: How to choose a safe and reliable trust company? How to avoid the traps of high-yield trust products?
<ul>
<li>Answer: Any trust company that promises high returns may be a scam. You should take control of your own investment and financial management rights, clearly stipulate investment in index funds in the trust clause, and set up a regulatory unit to ensure fund security.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Rose:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: She frankly talked about her past investment failures and the process of gradually establishing the correct investment concept under the guidance of James.</li>
<li>Question 1: What are the differences and pros and cons of Margin Loan and Pledge Loan?  The interest rate of Margin Loan from IB is relatively low. Is it necessary to transfer to Charles Schwab for Pledge Loan?
<ul>
<li>Answer:  Margin Loan is riskier, and Pledge Loan is relatively safe. If the interest rate of IB&rsquo;s Margin Loan is low, you can continue to use it, but pay attention to controlling the borrowing ratio, preferably no more than 20%.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2: The return on cash allocation will decrease in the interest rate cut cycle. Is it still necessary to allocate cash?
<ul>
<li>Answer: The purpose of cash allocation is not for profit but to deal with contingencies, such as unemployment or a market crash. It is advisable to keep more than 10% of your assets in cash.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 3: How to manage children&rsquo;s investment accounts? Under whose name should it be, yours or the child&rsquo;s?
<ul>
<li>Answer: It is recommended to open an account in the child&rsquo;s name to cultivate their financial management concept, but control the amount and provide proper investment guidance. Estate planning can be done after the child becomes an adult.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Phoenix:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: He shared his confusion about handling company stock options and finally adopted James&rsquo; suggestion.</li>
<li>Question 1: How to deal with the stock options of unlisted companies?
<ul>
<li>Answer: If the company has a high possibility of going public, it is recommended to sell it to an investment company before the listing to get cash and invest in QQQ.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2: What do you think of Bitcoin? Can I invest in it?
<ul>
<li>Answer: If you already hold a small amount of Bitcoin, you can continue to hold it, but do not invest any more capital. It is recommended to focus on investing in QQQ.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Allen:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: He shared his questions about 401k and stock investment and eventually made adjustments under James&rsquo; advice.</li>
<li>Question 1: What should I do if I have too much money in my 401k account?
<ul>
<li>Answer:  It is recommended to stop making further contributions to 401k and transfer some funds to the Roth IRA account through the Backdoor Roth IRA.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2: How to switch from holding Nvidia stock to QQQ?
<ul>
<li>Answer: Sell Nvidia stock as soon as possible, transfer funds to QQQ, and pledge stocks to borrow money to pay taxes.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Haoqing:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: He demonstrated the difficulty of stock selection through data analysis and illustrated the advantages of long-term investment in QQQ with practical examples.</li>
<li>Question: Can stock picking beat QQQ?
<ul>
<li>Answer: Stock selection is difficult to outperform QQQ in the long run. Even if it beats the market in the short term, transaction costs and taxes need to be considered.  Invest in index funds for the long term.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Xiang:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: He shared his confusion about saving for children&rsquo;s education and inheritance and finally found a solution under James&rsquo; advice.</li>
<li>Question 1: Is it better to use a 529 Education Fund or invest in QQQ for children&rsquo;s education savings?
<ul>
<li>Answer:  Investing in QQQ is recommended because it has higher long-term returns and is more flexible.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2: How to do estate planning?
<ul>
<li>Answer:  For larger estates, it is recommended to set up an irrevocable trust and consult an estate lawyer for planning.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Kevin:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Frankly admitted his past investment failures and regained confidence under the guidance of James, starting to embark on the road of steady investment.</li>
<li>Question: How many listeners are losing money on investments?
<ul>
<li>Answer: Past investment experience is not important. What is important is to establish the correct investment concept and believe in the value of long-term investment in index funds.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Julia:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Shared her lessons learned from investing in Chinese concept stocks and second-tier growth stocks, and how to guide children to make long-term investments.</li>
<li>Question 1: How to deal with losses caused by investment in Chinese concept stocks and second-tier growth stocks?
- Answer: It is advisable to &ldquo;cut your losses&rdquo; and switch funds to QQQ in a timely manner.</li>
<li>Question 2: How to guide children to make long-term investments?
- Answer: You can use an investment calculator to show children the power of compound interest and guide them with your own investment experience.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Peter:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Shared his experience working at Apple and confirmed that many high-income earners also choose to invest in index funds.</li>
<li>Question: How to balance family expenses and investment?
- Answer: It is recommended to use stock pledges to borrow money to meet living expenses and continue investing in QQQ, so that assets can continue to grow through compound interest.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Jason:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: He shared his confusion about company tax declaration and finally found a suitable solution under James&rsquo; advice.</li>
<li>Question: How to choose the tax filing method?
<ul>
<li>Answer: If your income is low, you can choose to file a 1099; if your income is high, you are advised to establish an S Corporation.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Cindy:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Shared her experience of guiding her child to invest in Roth IRA and keep away from gambling.</li>
<li>Question: How to guide children to invest in Roth IRA? How to guide children to stay away from gambling?
<ul>
<li>Answer: Open a Roth IRA account for the child and make matching contributions. Lead by example and educate your child with the experiences and stories of people around you.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">IV.  Highlights 
    <div id="iv--highlights" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv--highlights" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>Lending is more powerful than the atomic bomb; it&rsquo;s ten times the atomic bomb!
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>When encouraging people to use stock pledges for borrowing and investment, James used this analogy to vividly illustrate the power of leverage.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Investing should be easy and fun.
&ndash;  Hola</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This is what a listener said when she shared her investment experience. She also tried short-term trading, but finally found that long-term investment suited her better.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Each person has a different destiny when it comes to money.
&ndash; Peter</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Peter said this thought-provoking sentence when he shared his experience of persuading his father to invest in QQQ. This also reflects that investment and financial management should be combined with one&rsquo;s own situation to find a suitable way.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>All the money in the world is mine; you just need to take it and use it.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>James used humorous words to express his confidence in the market when encouraging everyone to invest, which also reflects his optimistic and positive attitude towards life.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">V. Conclusion 
    <div id="v-conclusion" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#v-conclusion" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>In this live broadcast, James once again emphasized the concept of long-term investment in index funds. He also provided specific investment advice for the audience based on the current market situation, covering asset allocation, retirement planning, children&rsquo;s education, stock options handling, leverage, and tax planning. The sharing from the students provided other listeners with valuable reference experience, showing their growth and earnings during the process of learning about investment and financial management.</p>

  



<div
  
    class="flex px-4 py-3 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900"
  >

  <span
    
      class="text-primary-400 ltr:pr-3 rtl:pl-3 flex items-center"
    >

    

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M506.3 417l-213.3-364c-16.33-28-57.54-28-73.98 0l-213.2 364C-10.59 444.9 9.849 480 42.74 480h426.6C502.1 480 522.6 445 506.3 417zM232 168c0-13.25 10.75-24 24-24S280 154.8 280 168v128c0 13.25-10.75 24-23.1 24S232 309.3 232 296V168zM256 416c-17.36 0-31.44-14.08-31.44-31.44c0-17.36 14.07-31.44 31.44-31.44s31.44 14.08 31.44 31.44C287.4 401.9 273.4 416 256 416z"/></svg>

  </span>


  </span>

  <span
    
      class="dark:text-neutral-300"
    ><strong>Disclaimer:</strong> This article is only for personal learning notes and does not constitute any investment advice.</span>
</div>

]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>00483 Rock-solid asset allocation,Investment strategies based on asset allocation and risk management</title>
      <link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1728265687577/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1728265687577/</guid>
      <description>This live stream focuses on the core concept of &amp;#34;wealth is a gift&amp;#34;. James explains the importance of investing and financial management, the advantages of index investing, the relationship between risk tolerance and investment returns, and how to allocate your assets reasonably.  During the Q&amp;amp;A session, students raised questions about TQQQ investment, Beta calculation, asset allocation strategies, and the investment market in mainland China. James answered these questions in detail and shared numerous experiences and cases to help students overcome psychological barriers in investment and solidify their long-term investment philosophy.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<lite-youtube videoid="eSkubAhBlhE" playlabel="eSkubAhBlhE" params=""></lite-youtube>



<h2 class="relative group">I. Theme of the Episode 
    <div id="i-theme-of-the-episode" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-theme-of-the-episode" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>The theme of this episode is &ldquo;Investing and Financial Management, Wealth is a Gift.&rdquo; The core viewpoints  are: <strong>Wealth is innate, but one must be informed to realize it; investing and financial management is an important way to accumulate wealth; index investing is an effective method to achieve long-term stable growth; rational asset allocation and risk control are the keys to investment success; and overcoming psychological barriers in investment and solidifying the long-term investment philosophy are crucial to ultimately achieving financial freedom.</strong></p>


<h2 class="relative group">II. Summary of the Briefing 
    <div id="ii-summary-of-the-briefing" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii-summary-of-the-briefing" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<ul>
<li><strong>Wealth is a Gift:</strong> Wealth is innate, and being informed of this fact makes a huge difference. While successful entrepreneurs like Elon Musk are a minority, most people need to be told that &ldquo;wealth is a gift,&rdquo; and they need to learn how to invest and manage their finances to achieve wealth growth.</li>
<li><strong>The Power of Index Investing and Compound Interest:</strong> Index investing is an effective way to achieve long-term stable returns, and its compounding effect is astonishing. For example, investing $1,500 per month for 40 years with a 14% annualized return will yield $2.6 million. <strong>Even small amounts of money can accumulate considerable wealth through consistent long-term investment.</strong></li>
<li><strong>High Risk, High Return?</strong>: High risk doesn&rsquo;t necessarily lead to high returns. Whether you can bear the risk determines whether you can ultimately achieve high returns. Don&rsquo;t overestimate your risk tolerance. Your risk appetite should be determined by an asset allocation that you can withstand even if your investment goes to zero. <strong>For example, if you cannot afford the risk of TQQQ going to zero, you should not invest in TQQQ.</strong></li>
<li><strong>Choosing Investment Targets</strong>: It is recommended to invest in the global Nasdaq 100 index fund (QQQ). Those with insufficient funds or who are already retired can consider investing in SPY or high-dividend ETFs. Avoid investing in individual stocks because they tend to disappear over the long term, while index funds can continue to exist. <strong>The half-life of individual stocks is 10 years; out of 100 stocks, there may be less than three left after 50 years.</strong></li>
<li><strong>Investment Mindset</strong>: The market will eventually rise, and investment requires patience. Always stay optimistic, even if the investment goes to zero. Learning about investing and financial management requires continuous thinking, like peeling an onion, layer by layer, to elevate the energy of the spiritual level. <strong>Investing is like the Yellow Mountain, eternally unchanging, yet different every day; every learning experience will bring new insights.</strong></li>
<li><strong>Asset Allocation</strong>: Asset allocation is like building a house; it is a big project that requires comprehensive planning, not something simple. It is necessary to consider many factors, such as whether you are retired, your age, income, debt, and cash flow, to formulate a reasonable asset allocation plan. <strong>You need to carefully study the articles and videos on asset allocation provided by James to develop a plan that suits you.</strong></li>
<li><strong>Do Not  Blindly Trust External Information</strong>: Financial professionals often only consider their interests, so do not easily believe their advice. Think independently, study carefully, and do not be swayed by external information and noise. <strong>Most of the outside information is garbage; do not be affected by it, focus on learning James&rsquo; investment philosophy.</strong></li>
<li><strong>Balancing Risk and Reward</strong>: Do not excessively pursue high returns or completely risk-free investments; balance risk and reward. Avoid changing investment strategies easily to prevent additional costs due to frequent trading. <strong>James&rsquo; investment methods can guarantee asset appreciation and relative safety, avoiding extreme situations.</strong></li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">III. Q&amp;A Session 
    <div id="iii-qa-session" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii-qa-session" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p><strong>IM:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>Sharing: Learning about investment is like peeling an onion; at first, the amount of information is overwhelming, but as you learn more, you will gradually understand the core idea and ultimately reach the realm of &ldquo;the great Dao is simple.&rdquo;</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Question 1: What do you think about the idea that &ldquo;investing is simple&rdquo;?</p>
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo; Response: Such views often mistake ignorance for inaction and do not truly understand the complexity and risks of investment.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p>Question 2: How should we communicate with friends who don&rsquo;t understand index investing?</p>
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo; Response: You can start by briefly introducing the concept and advantages of index investing and suggest that they watch related videos to learn. Don&rsquo;t force them to accept it, everyone has their own choices. <strong>Just like preaching, we can only try our best to spread the message; whether it&rsquo;s ultimately accepted depends on the individual.</strong></li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>LAN:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>Question 1: How to calculate Beta? What is the actual Beta value of a leveraged ETF?</p>
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo; Response: You can refer to the link to the article on Beta calculation on the message board. The actual Beta value of a leveraged ETF may deviate from the theoretical value due to factors such as market volatility and friction costs. <strong>When market volatility is large, the wear and tear of leveraged ETFs will be more serious, resulting in an actual Beta value lower than the theoretical value.</strong></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p>Question 2: Why is there a huge difference in final return between scenario 3 and scenario 4.1 in the 005 topic?</p>
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo; Response: Scenario 4.1 is where no money is withdrawn from the investment, so the final return will be higher.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p>Question 3: How to adjust Beta in a rising market?</p>
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo; Response:  The adjustment of Beta should be determined by your own risk tolerance, not by the market trend. <strong>Do not try to predict the market, just keep a fixed Beta value.</strong></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p>Question 4:  For investments in Taiwan, should I choose Q2D or 00670L?</p>
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo; Response: 00670L is recommended because it includes New Taiwan dollar hedging, which can reduce the risk caused by exchange rate fluctuations. <strong>Don&rsquo;t change investment targets frequently, choose one that suits you and hold it for the long term.</strong></li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Nai Xin:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Wealth is a gift, just as self-confidence is a gift; everyone has potential, but it needs to be stimulated. The key to investing and financial management lies in learning. Once you have mastered the correct investment method, you can focus on your own career and life and let wealth grow naturally over time. <strong>Overcome fear, build confidence, and you can realize your potential, gain wealth, and achieve success.</strong></li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Jason:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Understanding &ldquo;buy whenever you have money,&rdquo; but still finding it difficult to overcome psychological fluctuations when the market rises or falls sharply.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo; Response:  Overcoming psychological fluctuations takes time and experience. You can try to make a small number of trades, experience the impact of market fluctuations, and gradually adapt to market changes.</li>
<li>IM Supplement: You can overcome psychological barriers by imagining starting to invest two years later and understanding that &ldquo;money arrives at different points in time.&rdquo;<strong>Don&rsquo;t worry about buying at the lowest point; as long as you stick to long-term investment, you can get good returns.</strong></li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Hai Rui Ji:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>Sharing:</p>
<ol>
<li>Thank you James for selflessly sharing your investment philosophy; students learn from each other and make progress together.</li>
<li>James&rsquo; investment philosophy requires continuous learning and understanding to grasp it fully. &ldquo;Never sell&rdquo; does not mean you cannot sell, but that you should develop a reasonable investment strategy based on your own situation. ** &ldquo;Never sell&rdquo; refers to mentally ignoring market fluctuations and adhering to a long-term investment philosophy.**</li>
<li>Investment philosophy needs to keep pace with the times and adjust investment strategies according to changes in the environment.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<p>Question: Already answered in the video.</p>
</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Li Zi:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: To overcome psychological barriers to investment, manage accounts separately, using one part for long-term investment and the other for tentative operations, such as selling covered calls. This satisfies the desire to trade and avoids losses due to frequent trading.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo; Response: You only know what is best after you have experienced it. Experience in trading can lead to a firmer commitment to a long-term investment strategy. <strong>Trying different trading strategies can help you understand the advantages of long-term investment and ultimately achieve the state of &ldquo;daily reduction for the Dao.&rdquo;</strong></li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>T:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>Question 1: Why has the capital market in mainland China performed poorly for a long time?</p>
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo; Response: Emerging markets take time to mature. The Chinese market is like the Taiwanese market 50 years ago. It has the potential to rise in the long term, but its return may be lower than that of the US market. <strong>Investment should focus on sustainable development markets. The US market has advantages in terms of systems and industries.</strong></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p>Question 2: Under foreign exchange control, how do I invest in US index funds? Are there any risks?</p>
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo; Response: You can invest by purchasing ETFs listed in China that track US index funds, such as 513100. Foreign exchange controls mainly restrict the physical flow of funds, and buying ETFs is not restricted. The current scale of such investment is small and will not trigger a quota limit. <strong>Even with foreign exchange control, it is still possible to allocate global assets through legal channels.</strong></li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">IV. Key Takeaways 
    <div id="iv-key-takeaways" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv-key-takeaways" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>Wealth is a Gift
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Everyone has the potential for wealth, but they must be informed to realize it and learn how to invest and manage their finances to achieve wealth growth.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Learning Increases Daily, the Dao Decreases Daily
&ndash; IM</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Learning about investing and financial management is a process of continuous improvement. At first, you will be exposed to a large amount of information, but as your understanding deepens, you will gradually simplify your investment strategy and eventually reach the state of &ldquo;the great Dao is simple.&rdquo;</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The Difficult to Return to After Seeing a Vast Ocean
&ndash; Li Zi &amp; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Only after experiencing something can you know what is best. In investing, only after actually operating and experiencing market fluctuations and the impact of different investment strategies can you more firmly choose the long-term investment strategy that suits you.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The More Money You Borrow, the More Money You Have
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Understand and control risk, not avoid it. Understanding how to use leverage can accelerate wealth growth, but only with proper risk management, such as building a solid asset allocation.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Cash is Air
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Cash is very important and you must keep enough cash to deal with market fluctuations and emergencies.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">V. Summary 
    <div id="v-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#v-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This live stream focused on the theme of &ldquo;Wealth is a gift.&rdquo; James explained the importance of investing and financial management, the advantages of index investing, the relationship between risk tolerance and investment returns, and how to conduct reasonable asset allocation in a simple and profound way. During the Q&amp;A session, students actively questioned their own issues and confusions. James patiently and meticulously answered them by combining practical cases and his own experience, helping the students better understand and master the knowledge and methods of investing and financial management. He also guided the students to overcome psychological barriers in investments, establish a firm long-term investment philosophy, and ultimately achieve financial freedom.</p>

  



<div
  
    class="flex px-4 py-3 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900"
  >

  <span
    
      class="text-primary-400 ltr:pr-3 rtl:pl-3 flex items-center"
    >

    

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M506.3 417l-213.3-364c-16.33-28-57.54-28-73.98 0l-213.2 364C-10.59 444.9 9.849 480 42.74 480h426.6C502.1 480 522.6 445 506.3 417zM232 168c0-13.25 10.75-24 24-24S280 154.8 280 168v128c0 13.25-10.75 24-23.1 24S232 309.3 232 296V168zM256 416c-17.36 0-31.44-14.08-31.44-31.44c0-17.36 14.07-31.44 31.44-31.44s31.44 14.08 31.44 31.44C287.4 401.9 273.4 416 256 416z"/></svg>

  </span>


  </span>

  <span
    
      class="dark:text-neutral-300"
    ><strong>Disclaimer:</strong> This article is a personal learning summary and does not constitute any investment advice.</span>
</div>

]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
