<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Success on QQQ Investor</title>
    <link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/tags/success/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Success on QQQ Investor</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jomonylw.github.io/en/tags/success/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Personal Investment Bible - Investment Iron Law XIII</title>
      <link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1731056005972/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1731056005972/</guid>
      <description>This article explores the key to financial success, emphasizing that taking action is more important than knowledge. Through several stories, it illustrates that even with financial knowledge, wealth growth cannot be achieved without action.  The article encourages readers to overcome fear, dare to try, start with small investments, and learn from failures to ultimately achieve financial freedom.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[

<h2 class="relative group">Investment Iron Law XIII: Act Now 
    <div id="investment-iron-law-xiii-act-now" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#investment-iron-law-xiii-act-now" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>Those who require a fully justified reason for every action are never practitioners.</p>
</blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">Taking Action is Better Than Just Researching 
    <div id="taking-action-is-better-than-just-researching" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#taking-action-is-better-than-just-researching" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>A group of friends worked hard from sunrise to sunset, but their income remained meager.  They envied others who invested in stocks, real estate, or other ventures and became wealthy. They lamented, &ldquo;We toil all day, earning so little, while those investors make easy money.&rdquo;  Finally, they decided to seek guidance from an investment guru.</p>
<p><strong>Knowledge Without Action is Useless</strong></p>
<p>Touched by their sincerity, the guru agreed to teach them. The first lesson was &ldquo;Investment Principles,&rdquo; covering compound interest, returns, and risk management. The second lesson was &ldquo;Investment Practice,&rdquo; where the guru demonstrated how to invest in stocks, real estate, and other assets.  He then asked, &ldquo;Do you understand?&rdquo; They all replied, &ldquo;Yes!&rdquo; The guru said, &ldquo;Congratulations, you&rsquo;ve graduated!&rdquo;  The group rejoiced and returned to their jobs.</p>
<p>Decades later, at a reunion, they complained, &ldquo;Is there any way to make good money? Why do we always have to work so hard?&rdquo; They revisited the guru, who asked, &ldquo;Where did you put your earnings?&rdquo;  They answered, &ldquo;In bank savings accounts.&rdquo;</p>
<p>This story illustrates that education can change thinking but not necessarily behavior. <strong>Possessing knowledge and wisdom without action is no different from lacking them; you&rsquo;ll still rely on physical labor and skills for a living.</strong>  Wisdom without action is useless; one must be willing to act.</p>
<p>A survey of wealthy Americans revealed that one of their key traits is &ldquo;proactive action.&rdquo; In other words, financial success depends on what we do, not what we know.</p>
<p>Investment professors sometimes face student skepticism: &ldquo;If you know so much, why aren&rsquo;t you rich from investing?&rdquo;  A common response is, &ldquo;A teacher&rsquo;s duty is to impart knowledge, not necessarily to practice it. Just like the best coach isn&rsquo;t always the best athlete.&rdquo;</p>
<p>I often ponder this: Many teachers desire wealth.  Wealth accumulation and educating the next generation aren&rsquo;t mutually exclusive.  Why don&rsquo;t most investment professors, armed with financial knowledge, become wealthy?</p>
<p>Another common question is: &ldquo;Some uneducated, idle speculators get rich through investing without ever taking an investment course. How?&rdquo; The difference between professors and these speculators is simple: some professors know but don&rsquo;t act, while speculators act but don&rsquo;t necessarily know.  Financial knowledge alone doesn&rsquo;t guarantee wealth; action is key.</p>
<p><strong>Action is the Key to Investment Success</strong></p>
<p>Can investment skills be taught? No.  True skill comes from practice.  I often compare investing to ice skating, swimming, or cycling.  Can reading books on &ldquo;How to Ice Skate&rdquo; make you a skater? The best teacher is experience – falling hundreds of times, getting back up, and persevering.</p>
<p>Fear is the biggest obstacle to learning about investing.  A student once asked, &ldquo;What if I lose all my money before I learn how to invest?&rdquo;  I countered, &ldquo;Did you study fluid dynamics before learning to ride a bike, fearing you&rsquo;d crash before mastering it?&rdquo; Investors must understand that even extensive reading won&rsquo;t prevent losses; just like a perfect score in fluid dynamics doesn&rsquo;t guarantee perfect cycling.</p>
<p>Practice and experience are essential for practical skills.  Investing can&rsquo;t be taught. The key is to step away from books, enter the market, experiment, make mistakes, and learn from them.  Start small with a limited amount of money.</p>
<p>Achieving wealth through investing involves two stages: 1) acquiring correct investment knowledge, and 2) continuous practice and action. Both are essential.  Reading this book and understanding the principles is just the first step.</p>
<p><strong>Knowledge Becomes Power Through Action</strong></p>
<p>Knowledge is potential power.  Only through absorption, internalization, and action does it become real power.  &ldquo;Knowledge is power&rdquo; needs amending.</p>
<p>Correct understanding alone is insufficient.  Achieving wealth requires consistent action and practice. Otherwise, knowledge remains theoretical.  Investing is a skill honed through constant practice, like entrepreneur Wang Yung-ching, who continued massive investments in his 70s.</p>
<p><strong>We instinctively avoid risk; it&rsquo;s uncomfortable.  But investing for wealth requires calculated risks, learned through experience.</strong> Dear reader, action is paramount. Initial fear and anxiety are natural. The best way to overcome them is to act.</p>
<p><em>1. Those who put ideas and methods into action possess a competitive edge and grasp the opportunity for success.</em></p>
<p><em>2. In today&rsquo;s knowledge-rich world, the biggest obstacle to success is not knowing what to do, but doing what we know.</em></p>
<p><em>3. Many excel at thinking, analyzing, and identifying opportunities, but few act upon them.</em></p>
<p><strong>A Farmer Outperforms Market Veterans</strong></p>
<p>In early 1996, amid cross-strait tensions, Taiwan&rsquo;s stock market slumped. A farmer walked into a brokerage, placed a bag of cash (around 3-4 million NTD) on the counter, and said, &ldquo;I want to buy San Shang Yin.&rdquo;</p>
<p>The clerk, baffled, asked for his account number, which stock he wanted (San Shang Yin refers to three different bank stocks), and his desired price. He knew none of this, saying only, &ldquo;My friend said San Shang Yin is good. Here&rsquo;s the money.&rdquo;</p>
<p>The clerk explained the situation, helped him open an account, and bought 10 shares of each bank stock at around 90 NTD. Two months later, the prices rose to 160 NTD.</p>
<p>This farmer, lacking knowledge but daring to act, profited.  Meanwhile, market experts who thoroughly analyzed San Shang Yin missed out because they hesitated to act.</p>
<p>Does knowledge or action bring wealth? The farmer&rsquo;s lack of knowledge might have been his advantage, while overthinking paralyzed the experts. How much do analysis and knowledge truly contribute to wealth creation? It&rsquo;s worth pondering.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Active action makes dreams come true.  A strong desire for wealth fuels action.</p>
</blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">Your Future Wealth is in Your Hands 
    <div id="your-future-wealth-is-in-your-hands" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#your-future-wealth-is-in-your-hands" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>Many attendees at my seminars nod in agreement but fail to act. Remember, action, not knowledge, determines your future.  This book is useless unless you act upon it.</p>
<p><strong>Dreams Alone Won&rsquo;t Make You Rich</strong></p>
<p>Many dream of wealth, but few succeed.  It&rsquo;s not luck or intelligence, but the unity of thought and action. Success and wealth are earned through planning, action, and consistent effort.</p>
<p>For most, wealth is a fantasy. They think and talk, but don&rsquo;t act. Some lack the know-how, which is understandable.  Sadly, others know but don&rsquo;t act.  &ldquo;Knowing and not doing is not knowing.&rdquo;  Wealth won&rsquo;t come to those who only dream or accumulate knowledge without action.  People attribute wealth to luck, but does luck favor those dreaming at home or those actively seeking opportunities?</p>
<p>Reading this book won&rsquo;t magically make you rich.  Financial success depends on what we do.  We&rsquo;ve all seen seemingly unintelligent, not particularly hard-working, or frugal people who are wealthy.</p>
<p>The difference between self-made millionaires and us isn&rsquo;t intellect, effort, frugality, or knowledge, but where our money is placed.  They invest in high-return assets, while we often settle for low returns.  Most make excuses: not enough money, time, knowledge, or opportunity, or blaming age.  These are merely excuses preventing wealth accumulation.</p>
<p><em>1. The principles of financial management are simple; the difficulty lies in overcoming fear, greed, and laziness to do what we know we should.</em></p>
<p><em>2. Investing is an art and a science, but more art.  The best way to learn is by doing.</em></p>
<p><em>3. Without putting money to work, you&rsquo;ll rely on physical labor and skills your entire life.</em></p>
<p><strong>The First Step: Open a Brokerage Account and Buy Stocks</strong></p>
<p>An elderly British writer lamented, &ldquo;I&rsquo;ve seen many talented young people remain obscure, their potential unfulfilled because they lacked the courage to try.  Guidance and encouragement to take risks could have unleashed their talents and benefited society.&rdquo;</p>
<p>Over 13% of seniors in Taiwan rely on continued work or family support.  Many ended up this way because they didn&rsquo;t invest in risky assets like stocks or real estate in their youth.  Had they been guided to invest wisely, they could be enjoying retirement, reducing social inequality and promoting harmony.</p>
<p>Inspired by this writer, I now encourage my students to open brokerage accounts and buy stocks (or closed-end funds if unsure) on the first day of my investment courses.  I advise them to hold long-term, regardless of price fluctuations, aiming for practical experience over theoretical knowledge.</p>
<p><strong>Paying for Experience</strong></p>
<p>In 1983, while pursuing my PhD at UC Berkeley, a Wall Street analyst lectured at the university.  I asked him for book recommendations on stock investing.  He advised, &ldquo;The best way to learn is to invest. You&rsquo;ll learn more from one real investment than from several books.&rdquo; I followed his advice, lost money, and learned valuable lessons that shaped my future investment approach.</p>
<p>Financial management can&rsquo;t be learned solely in the classroom. Can attending ten lectures on swimming theory and reading ten books on &ldquo;Swimming Secrets&rdquo; make you a swimmer?  The first step is to get in the water.  Taiwan&rsquo;s education system overemphasizes book learning and neglects practical experience.</p>
<p>What&rsquo;s the first step in learning to invest?  Some suggest reading books, subscribing to financial magazines, or taking courses.  My advice: after reading this book, invest a small amount in stocks or mutual funds (especially index funds) if unsure.</p>
<p>Mutual funds offer diversification and professional management, generally performing close to market averages, minimizing potential losses and discouraging fear.</p>
<p>Outperforming mutual funds through individual stock picking is challenging.  Fund managers have experience, expertise, and research teams.  Consider mutual funds, especially index funds like CTBC Harmony Fund or China 100 Fund, in the initial stages.  &ldquo;Beating the index&rdquo; is every fund manager&rsquo;s dream, but most admit it&rsquo;s incredibly difficult.  If so, mirroring the market through index funds is a viable strategy.</p>
<p><strong>If you have savings and don&rsquo;t own property, consider buying a home as your first investment.</strong></p>
<blockquote>
<p>We learn more from failure than from success.  Success is built upon countless failures.</p>
</blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">Learning from Mistakes 
    <div id="learning-from-mistakes" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#learning-from-mistakes" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>Successful American investors share two traits: 1) they don&rsquo;t strive for perfection, and 2) they don&rsquo;t dwell on failures, focusing instead on future challenges.  High returns come with high risks.  Failure is inevitable and part of the learning process. Most successful investors have experienced multiple failures.</p>
<p><strong>No Success Without Failure</strong></p>
<p>Anyone claiming to have never lost money in investing is either lying or has never invested.  It&rsquo;s like a baseball player claiming to have never missed a swing.  Even the best hitters don&rsquo;t have a 100% batting average.</p>
<p>A top baseball player once attributed his success to &ldquo;missing more swings than others.&rdquo; To achieve a high batting average, he must have swung and missed more times than others.  Biographies of successful people often reveal that they&rsquo;ve experienced more failures than those less successful.  Failure is the mother of success, especially in investing.</p>
<p>Aspiring investors must withstand losses.  <strong>Those who haven&rsquo;t failed can&rsquo;t achieve greatness; those who haven&rsquo;t experienced losses can&rsquo;t expect to make a fortune.</strong>  Demanding a perfect track record leads to extreme conservatism and eliminates opportunities for success.</p>
<p><strong>The biggest failure is to never fail.</strong>  Avoiding mistakes eliminates chances for success. The best path to success is through failure and learning from it.  Never forget your losses; they are the keys to victory.  Successful investors analyze failures, learn from them, and improve their strategies.</p>
<p><strong>Reflect and Restart</strong></p>
<p>My failures have led to reflection, reassessment, and improved investment strategies.  Most failures bring unexpected benefits.  Treat failure as a necessary lesson, and your courage will grow.</p>
<p>Failure can&rsquo;t be learned secondhand.  You won&rsquo;t find books on &ldquo;How to Lose 10 Million in Investments.&rdquo;  People brag about successes, not failures.  Therefore, lessons from failure must come from personal experience.</p>
<p>Everyone makes mistakes in investing.  Even correct decisions can lead to losses.  Since losses and failures are inevitable, accepting them and learning from them is crucial.  Failure is not shameful or terrifying.  Face it, overcome it, and success will follow.</p>
<p><em>1. Take calculated risks for high rewards, be prepared for losses, and avoid undue self-blame.</em></p>
<p><em>2. Learn from every failure, identify flawed decision-making habits, and avoid repeating them.</em></p>
<p><em>3. Study valuable lessons from failures and discover opportunities for wealth creation.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Property of Money: Book Notes</title>
      <link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1728564107112/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1728564107112/</guid>
      <description>Korean entrepreneur Kim Seung-ho shares his personal journey from poverty to wealth, providing practical guidance on wealth accumulation, management, and the pursuit of financial freedom.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[

<h2 class="relative group">I. Summary 
    <div id="i-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>&ldquo;Property of Money&rdquo; is Korean entrepreneur Kim Seung-ho&rsquo;s insightful account of his path to financial success. Starting from humble beginnings, he climbed the economic ladder, gaining profound insights into the multifaceted nature of money.  Driven by a desire to share his valuable experiences, the book explores five key attributes of money and outlines four essential skills necessary for achieving wealth. Through compelling stories and real-life examples, Kim Seung-ho demystifies complex economic concepts and investment principles, offering readers a practical guide towards financial freedom.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">II.  Chapter Summary 
    <div id="ii--chapter-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii--chapter-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Part 1: The Essence of Money 
    <div id="part-1-the-essence-of-money" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#part-1-the-essence-of-money" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>
<p><strong>Money is Personified:</strong> Kim personifies money, suggesting it possesses emotions and will. Your attitude towards money influences how it behaves towards you. Respect and treat it like a friend to earn its favor.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Investing in Superior Entrepreneurs:</strong>  Investing in companies and entrepreneurs more competent than oneself is a wise move, akin to partnering with them and reaping the rewards of their success. The author shares how he invested in successful companies like Microsoft, Amazon, and Nike, effectively becoming their &ldquo;partner.&rdquo;</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>The Secret of Compound Interest:</strong>  Compound interest is a fundamental principle in investment, capable of multiplying wealth. However, one must also be wary of its power when applied to debt. The author uses Warren Buffett&rsquo;s &ldquo;Mona Lisa&rdquo; analogy to illustrate the impact of compound interest.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>The Strength of Fixed Income:</strong> Stable cash flow surpasses inconsistent income, attracting and accumulating wealth. Kim compares fixed income to a well-trained army, capable of efficiently managing a large-scale organization despite smaller numbers.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Money&rsquo;s Gravitational Force:</strong> Substantial wealth attracts more wealth. Starting with small accumulations, compound interest propels wealth multiplication, much like the Earth formed from the gradual attraction of minuscule particles. The author illustrates this concept with the Han River and the Amazon River, demonstrating how small streams can converge to form vast rivers.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Highest Risk, Lowest Risk:</strong> The stock market is riskiest when everyone is bullish and chasing the latest hot stock; conversely, it&rsquo;s least risky when fear grips the market and everyone is selling.  Maintain a balanced perspective on fear and greed, embracing opportunity during widespread fear and exercising caution when greed prevails. Warren Buffet&rsquo;s famous quote, &ldquo;Be fearful when others are greedy, and greedy when others are fearful,&rdquo; encapsulates this wisdom.  The author uses the example of increased airline safety a week after an accident to illustrate this point.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Treat Others&rsquo; Money as You Treat Your Own:</strong> Treating others&rsquo; money with respect safeguards your own from similar disrespect.  Respect for others&rsquo; money is reciprocated. The author uses his attitude towards shopping carts at supermarkets to emphasize the importance of respecting others&rsquo; money.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Inheriting Millions with a &ldquo;No Loss&rdquo; Clause:</strong>  Through a hypothetical scenario, Kim highlights that preserving wealth is not straightforward. It requires learning, accumulating experience, and recognizing the significance of consistent income. The protagonist in the story inherits a substantial sum with the stipulation of no loss, ultimately realizing that maintaining wealth&rsquo;s value is no easy feat.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Rejecting Quick Riches:</strong>  The pursuit of quick wealth often leads to speculative traps and the perils of greed, ultimately ending in failure.  Building wealth demands a steady and gradual approach.  The author uses the analogy of constructing a house to demonstrate the importance of gradual wealth accumulation.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Can Economists Predict the Future?:</strong>  No one can accurately predict the macroeconomic future, especially in the long term, due to inherent uncertainties. Resist blindly following expert predictions; cultivate independent thinking and continuous learning.  Kim quotes economist John Kenneth Galbraith: &ldquo;There are two kinds of people in the world: those who don&rsquo;t know and those who don&rsquo;t know they don&rsquo;t know.&rdquo;</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Buying Samsung Stock at Samsung Securities:</strong> This anecdote illustrates the need for knowledge before venturing into investments. Avoid assumptions; understand market rules and investment tools. Kim compares the stock market to a ruthless jungle, where knowledge is essential for survival.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Changing Your Destiny Through Respectful Address:</strong> A personal experience highlights the importance of respecting others and showing genuine interest in their affairs, leading to trust, goodwill, and ultimately, good fortune.  The entrepreneur in the story habitually addresses everyone as &ldquo;that person,&rdquo; ultimately losing friends and connections.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Repeated Luck is Skill, Repeated Failure is Habit:</strong> Lucky individuals often possess greater astuteness and intelligence. They excel at observation, learning, and accumulating experience.  Conversely, repeated failure calls for introspection and addressing personal shortcomings.  The author uses examples like lottery tickets, rock-paper-scissors, and parking spots to illustrate the interplay of luck and skill.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Discerning Fact from Investment Hype in News:</strong> Using the COVID-19 pandemic as an example, Kim underlines the importance of focusing on facts and data, rather than blindly trusting media reports and expert predictions. He reached a more accurate assessment by comparing the total number of infections with the infection rate.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Each Dollar Experiences Time Differently:</strong> Borrowing Einstein&rsquo;s theory of relativity, the author suggests that money is also subject to the influence of time. Different sources of money experience time differently; always invest with money that has ample time.  Kim compares &ldquo;time-rich&rdquo; money to individuals who have more time to build relationships, fall in love, and raise children.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Diversification Isn&rsquo;t Enough:</strong> Kim critiques the misinterpretation of the saying &ldquo;Don&rsquo;t put all your eggs in one basket.&rdquo; Diversifying within a single market is merely using multiple baskets on the same shelf, still exposed to risk. He recommends spreading investments across diverse markets such as stocks, bonds, and real estate.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Three Paths to Wealth:</strong>  The author outlines three ways to become wealthy: inheritance, winning the lottery, and business success. He encourages young people to pursue entrepreneurship or engage in long-term investment. Kim elaborates on two paths to business success: starting a business or investing in successful companies.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Why Savings Don&rsquo;t Grow:</strong>  The root causes of stagnant savings lie in spending future income, neglecting asset management, undervaluing small amounts of money, and lacking investment knowledge. The author advises readers to ditch credit cards, use debit cards, and appreciate the power of accumulating small amounts of money.</p>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Part 2: The Wisdom of Investment 
    <div id="part-2-the-wisdom-of-investment" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#part-2-the-wisdom-of-investment" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>
<p><strong>Identifying Financial Illiteracy:</strong>  Kim presents a list of 90+ economic and financial terms, encouraging readers to study and master this foundational knowledge, enhancing their financial literacy. He believes financial literacy is a vital survival skill for modern individuals.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Traits of Successful Stock Market Investors:</strong> These individuals perceive themselves as business owners, hold high-quality money, and excel at buying at low prices. The author emphasizes selecting quality company stocks for long-term holding, engaging with the company&rsquo;s progress as if they were owners.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Defining True Wealth:</strong>  Genuine wealth encompasses owning a mortgage-free home, a steady stream of passive income, and the mentality of &ldquo;not needing to work.&rdquo; Kim recognizes that the standard of wealth is relative, and true wealth lies in inner freedom.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Daily Habits for Wealth Protection:</strong>  The author shares his routine of diligently reading news, scanning economic websites, and collecting information. He believes continuous learning and market awareness are crucial for maintaining investment sensitivity and making informed decisions.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>The Harsh Realities of Poverty:</strong> Drawing from personal experience, Kim paints a grim picture of poverty, encouraging readers to believe in their potential for wealth. He underscores poverty&rsquo;s power to strip dignity and even dismantle family relationships.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Three Responses to Financial Panic:</strong>  The author categorizes people&rsquo;s responses to financial panics: those who suffer losses, those unaffected, and those who capitalize and profit. He analyzes the characteristics of each group, noting that individuals with no debt and stable income weather the storm while those who seize opportunities emerge wealthier.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Rewinding Time for Wealth:</strong>  Reflecting on his experience, Kim encourages young people to start investing early and highlights the limitations of relying solely on bank savings. He suggests young people focus on long-term investments in quality company stocks instead of traditional bank savings.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>The Foundation of Wisdom:</strong> Learning fundamental knowledge is a prerequisite for gaining wisdom.  The author encourages young people to study languages and mathematics, cultivating logical thinking abilities.  He believes learning new languages broadens horizons while studying mathematics sharpens logical reasoning.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Immediate Action for Wealth:</strong>  Drawing inspiration from Marie Kondo&rsquo;s organizational methods, Kim recommends readers declutter their homes, fostering respect for possessions, and reflecting on their spending habits. He suggests that the way we treat possessions reflects our attitude towards money; respecting belongings leads to cherishing wealth.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Will the Stock Market Rise?:</strong>  Don&rsquo;t obsess over short-term market fluctuations. Focus on long-term investment, select quality companies, and patiently wait for value to return. He advises readers to identify quality companies that warrant long-term investment and maintain unwavering confidence.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Unlocking the Value of Rent Payments:</strong>  Entrepreneurs consistently paying rent possess the capacity to purchase property. The author encourages them to become property owners and capitalize on the potential for greater returns.  He emphasizes that rental income can translate into property appreciation, while property ownership offers greater security and returns.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Real Estate vs. Stock Market:</strong>  Instead of fixating on which market is superior, choose an investment approach aligned with your style and risk tolerance. Kim provides a comparative analysis of real estate and stock market investments, highlighting their unique features and potential risks.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>My Independence Day:</strong>   Using the concept of a personal &ldquo;independence day&rdquo; marked by financial independence, the author emphasizes the significance of economic self-reliance. He encourages readers to develop financial strategies and strive for early financial freedom, recognizing its role as a foundation for personal liberty.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Four Skills of Money Management:</strong>  Kim outlines four essential skills for managing money: earning, saving, preserving, and spending. He provides insights into the characteristics of each skill and recommends learning methods. He emphasizes that these are interconnected skills that need to be mastered for effective wealth management.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Investing with Values:</strong> The author shares his investment principles, avoiding industries that profit from misfortunes. He believes such money carries negative consequences and clashes with his values. He exemplifies this with businesses centered around firearms, cigarettes, and drugs.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Insurance is not Savings:</strong>  Kim criticizes the practice of insurance companies selling high-commission, low-return products disguised as savings. He advises readers to choose insurance primarily for its protection function, not as investment vehicles, and to select suitable products based on their individual needs.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Beautiful Junk:</strong>  Drawing from a luxurious travel experience, Kim conveys that experiences and memories are more valuable than material possessions.  He urges readers to avoid accumulating &ldquo;beautiful junk,&rdquo; recognizing that many purchases become unused clutter, wasting both money and space.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Separating Economics from Political Bias:</strong>  Readers are urged to approach economic news with a critical eye, avoiding interpretation solely from a political standpoint. Refer to factual data to form judgments.  Kim suggests that many media reports are politically charged, encouraging independent thinking and caution against being swayed by media biases.</p>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Part 4: The Mindset and Responsibilities of the Wealthy 
    <div id="part-4-the-mindset-and-responsibilities-of-the-wealthy" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#part-4-the-mindset-and-responsibilities-of-the-wealthy" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>The Underdog Advantage:</strong>  Using historical and business examples, the author illustrates that underdogs overcoming giants is a recurring theme. He encourages young people to embrace challenges and strive for success. He believes individuals from humble backgrounds often possess greater drive and innovation, enabling them to seize opportunities and achieve upward mobility.</li>
<li><strong>Your Personal PER:</strong>  Kim introduces the concept of Price-to-Earnings Ratio (PER) and applies it to personal careers and businesses, reminding readers to focus on the stability and sustainability of income sources. He emphasizes that high income doesn&rsquo;t equate to wealth; building systems that generate consistent income is crucial.</li>
<li><strong>Wealth Is Not Predestined:</strong> Great wealth arises from a combination of opportunities, hard work, intelligence, and luck, not from predetermined destiny. The author encourages readers to actively seek opportunities and prepare themselves, believing everyone holds the potential for success, provided they believe in themselves and strive diligently.</li>
<li><strong>Start Small, Dream Big:</strong> Young aspiring entrepreneurs are advised to gain experience and build connections by initially working in small companies.  He believes small companies offer more opportunities for learning and practical experience, facilitating rapid growth.</li>
<li><strong>Perseverance is Power:</strong>  The author emphasizes the importance of consistency and perseverance, advising readers to devote 100 days or three months to mastering a skill or forming a good habit. He believes persistence is key to success, as any skill requires continuous effort to achieve mastery.</li>
<li><strong>Limitless Business Opportunities:</strong>  Kim encourages readers to think outside the box and be receptive to business opportunities. He shares his experience of launching a flower shop, demonstrating that opportunities are present in everyday life; a keen eye can unearth suitable ventures.</li>
<li><strong>Entrepreneurship: The Path to Freedom:</strong> Entrepreneurship is championed as the only profession offering genuine control over one&rsquo;s destiny. The author encourages young people to pursue entrepreneurship, breaking free from the limitations of corporate employment. He highlights that entrepreneurship offers greater freedom, a sense of accomplishment, and the potential for significant wealth creation.</li>
<li><strong>Discerning the Nature of Money:</strong> Earn money of good character, avoiding ill-gotten gains from sources like gambling or fraud. Kim believes that good money brings blessings, while bad money carries misfortune, using examples of money obtained through gambling or fraud to illustrate the harmful effects of ill-gotten gains.</li>
<li><strong>Navigating Family Responsibilities as the Wealthiest Sibling:</strong> Kim shares guidance based on his own experience, recommending different strategies for supporting and caring for family members, depending on the scale of wealth.
<ul>
<li><strong>Under 100 Million Won:</strong> Prioritize women in the family who have contributed significantly but are often overlooked, such as sisters-in-law, along with nieces and nephews. Buy them gifts, cover family meal expenses, and provide regular financial support to parents. Avoid lending money to siblings for business ventures or assisting parents in upgrading their homes or cars.</li>
<li><strong>Under 500 Million Won:</strong> You can purchase a house or car for your parents, cover all their living expenses, and assist nieces and nephews with education costs. At this stage, you can offer measured support to siblings.</li>
<li><strong>Over 1 Billion Won:</strong> Actively help siblings escape poverty, select suitable siblings to participate in the management of family businesses, and lead the entire family to prosperity.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>The Right to Fail:</strong>  Young people are encouraged to embrace challenges without fear of failure, viewing failure as a valuable learning opportunity. He believes failure is a precious life experience, making success more appreciated when achieved.</li>
<li><strong>Can Books Create Wealth?:</strong>  Reading alone cannot make one wealthy; the key is to cultivate independent thinking and draw inspiration from books.  He suggests reading with a discerning mind, applying what you learn to your own experiences.</li>
<li><strong>God&rsquo;s Impartiality:</strong>  God&rsquo;s fairness lies in his non-intervention in earthly affairs. The author encourages readers to rely on their own efforts rather than placing their hope in divine intervention. He believes each individual is responsible for their own destiny and shouldn&rsquo;t place their hopes solely on divine intervention.</li>
<li><strong>The Passionate Entrepreneur and His Furious Wife:</strong>  A fictional story emphasizes the vital role of family harmony in business success, condemning the practice of prioritizing investments at the expense of family well-being.  The story features an entrepreneur, Mr. Song, who runs a successful dessert shop and a barbecue restaurant. He pours all the profits back into developing new menu items and his research lab, leading to financial strain at home and his wife&rsquo;s understandable frustration.</li>
<li><strong>Partnerships: A Delicate Dance:</strong>  Kim outlines the conditions and considerations for successful partnerships, emphasizing the importance of respecting partners&rsquo; money and drafting legally sound agreements.  He believes that trust and respect are paramount in any partnership, and all aspects of the agreement should be clearly defined in writing to prevent future disputes.</li>
<li><strong>Stick to the Main Road:</strong>  When investing in unfamiliar sectors, opt for companies that are industry leaders to mitigate risk. He compares investing in a leading company to navigating a well-defined road, reducing the risk of getting lost and generally offering greater security.</li>
<li><strong>The Quarter Rule:</strong>  The author unveils his personal &ldquo;Quarter Rule,&rdquo; advocating for living expenses to be capped at one-quarter of one&rsquo;s financial capacity.  This strategy allows for enjoying life while maintaining a financial safety net.</li>
<li><strong>Prayers Alone Won&rsquo;t Bring Riches:</strong>  True wealth comes through hard work, wisdom, and seizing opportunities, not reliance on divine intervention or supernatural forces. While prayer might offer spiritual solace, it cannot replace action.</li>
<li><strong>Four Habits of Saving:</strong>  Cultivate good habits early in life, starting with simple daily actions that lay a strong foundation for wealth accumulation. These habits are: stretching upon waking, making your bed, drinking a glass of water on an empty stomach each morning, and maintaining consistent sleep and wake times.</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">III. Notable Quotes 
    <div id="iii-notable-quotes" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii-notable-quotes" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;Money is personified.&rdquo;</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Money, like people, has emotions and a will; your attitude towards it influences its behavior towards you.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;Compound interest is the greatest invention of mankind, the eighth wonder of the world.&rdquo;</p>
</blockquote>
<p>The power of compounding is immense, capable of multiplying wealth. It is one of the most important principles in investing.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;Be fearful when others are greedy and greedy when others are fearful.&rdquo;</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Approach market sentiment rationally, seize opportunities during fear, exercise caution during greed.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;Treat others&rsquo; money as you treat your own.&rdquo;</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Respect for other people&rsquo;s money earns respect for yours. It reflects a fundamental principle of human interaction.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;The only way to quickly become rich is to not be in a hurry to become rich.&rdquo;</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Avoid the pitfalls of chasing quick riches, build wealth steadily and gradually.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;Not knowing is the right answer.&rdquo;</p>
</blockquote>
<p>The future is full of uncertainties. No one can accurately predict it. Maintain humility and a willingness to learn.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;An illiterate person might experience inconvenience, but a financially illiterate person cannot survive.&rdquo;</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Financial knowledge is essential for survival. Learn and master financial literacy to effectively manage wealth and avoid scams.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;The person paying rent is the landlord.&rdquo;</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Entrepreneurs capable of consistently paying rent possess the capability to own property. Seize opportunities to become property owners.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;The fastest way to become rich is to slowly become rich.&rdquo;</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Avoid the rush to wealth. Genuine wealth comes through persistent learning and gradual accumulation.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;Working hard doesn&rsquo;t guarantee wealth, acquiring wealth doesn&rsquo;t guarantee you&rsquo;ll be rich, and being rich doesn&rsquo;t guarantee happiness.&rdquo;</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Wealth is not an end but a means to an end. A balanced perspective on money is crucial for true happiness.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;Failure is a right.&rdquo;</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Young people should embrace challenges without fear of failure, viewing failure as a valuable learning experience.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“God will not make you rich.”</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Wealth comes from hard work, intelligence, and opportunity, not divine intervention or supernatural forces.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;Small change is the &ldquo;sprout&rdquo; of big money.&rdquo;</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Don&rsquo;t underestimate the power of accumulating small amounts of money. Start small and gradually build your wealth system.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“Money has different characters.”</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Earn money through ethical means and avoid ill-gotten gains like those from gambling or fraud.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">IV. Guiding Principles 
    <div id="iv-guiding-principles" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv-guiding-principles" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>&ldquo;The Attributes of Money&rdquo; provides practical guidance for finance and life, offering these key takeaways:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Perspective on Money:</strong> Respect money, utilize it wisely, and treat it as a tool to achieve your goals, not as an end in itself.</li>
<li><strong>Financial Management:</strong>  Cultivate strong financial habits, value savings, learn to invest, and protect yourself from scams.</li>
<li><strong>Investment Philosophy:</strong>  Interpret market emotions rationally, pursue long-term investments, choose quality companies, and implement a well-defined asset allocation strategy.</li>
<li><strong>Life Philosophy:</strong>  Embrace challenges, learn from failures, and continuously learn and grow. Strive for financial and spiritual freedom.</li>
<li><strong>Family Values:</strong>  Prioritize family harmony, cherish your loved ones, and fulfill your responsibilities towards them.</li>
<li><strong>Ethics in Action:</strong>  Show respect for others, be willing to help, and cultivate kindness in your interactions.</li>
</ul>
<hr>

<section class="space-y-10 w-full">
    
    
        
            






















  <a class="flex flex-wrap article " href="/en/posts/1728295490690-book-list/">
    
        
        <div class="w-full md:w-auto h-full thumbnail nozoom thumbnailshadow md:mr-7" style="background-image:url(/posts/1728295490690-book-list/featured_hu4424409690304057825.jpg);"></div>
        
      <div class=" mt-3 md:mt-0">
      <div class="items-center text-left text-xl font-semibold">
        
        <div class="font-bold text-xl text-neutral-800 decoration-primary-500 hover:underline hover:underline-offset-2 dark:text-neutral"
          href="/en/posts/1728295490690-book-list/">Recommended Reading List</div>
        
        
        
      </div>
      <div class="text-sm text-neutral-500 dark:text-neutral-400">
        











  



















<div class="flex flex-row flex-wrap items-center">
  
  
  <time datetime="2024-10-01T00:00:00&#43;00:00">1 October 2024</time>
  

  
  
</div>





<div class="flex flex-row flex-wrap items-center">
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  <span style="margin-top:0.5rem" class="mr-2" onclick="window.open(&#34;/en/tags/recommended/&#34;,'_self');">
    <span class="flex" style="cursor: pointer;">
  <span class="rounded-md border border-primary-400 px-1 py-[1px] text-xs font-normal text-primary-700 dark:border-primary-600 dark:text-primary-400">
    Recommended
  </span>
</span>
  </span>
  
  <span style="margin-top:0.5rem" class="mr-2" onclick="window.open(&#34;/en/tags/book/&#34;,'_self');">
    <span class="flex" style="cursor: pointer;">
  <span class="rounded-md border border-primary-400 px-1 py-[1px] text-xs font-normal text-primary-700 dark:border-primary-600 dark:text-primary-400">
    Book
  </span>
</span>
  </span>
  
  
  
  
</div>




      </div>
      
    </div>
  </a>

        
    
</section>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
