<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Warren Buffett on QQQ Investor</title>
    <link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/tags/warren-buffett/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Warren Buffett on QQQ Investor</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jomonylw.github.io/en/tags/warren-buffett/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Personal Investment Bible: The Ultimate Guide to Wealth Management</title>
      <link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1731056005973/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1731056005973/</guid>
      <description>This article explores the ultimate goal of wealth management – enhancing the quality of life, rather than simply pursuing money. Using the parable of a miser, it emphasizes that the true meaning of wealth lies in how it&amp;#39;s used to live the life you desire.  It examines the unique perspectives on money held by prominent figures like Li Ka-shing, Tsai Wan-lin, and Wang Yung-ching, highlighting how many become slaves to money, unable to utilize it for happiness. Finally, it introduces the three keys to wealth management – earning, managing, and utilizing money – emphasizing the importance of setting financial goals and using wealth wisely.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[

<h2 class="relative group">The Ultimate Guide to Wealth Management: Earning Money Requires a Goal 
    <div id="the-ultimate-guide-to-wealth-management-earning-money-requires-a-goal" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#the-ultimate-guide-to-wealth-management-earning-money-requires-a-goal" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>Money is merely a means; improving the quality of life is the ultimate goal.
Success is getting what you want, then enjoying what you have.</p>
</blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">Don&rsquo;t Be a Miser 
    <div id="dont-be-a-miser" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#dont-be-a-miser" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>A miser sold all his possessions, deposited the money in a bank, and took great satisfaction in calculating his daily interest earnings. His unscrupulous son, noticing his father&rsquo;s secretive behavior, discovered the large bank deposit. He stole the passbook and seal, withdrew all the money, and replaced the original with a forgery.  The miser, unaware of the deception, continued to calculate his imaginary wealth and interest.</p>
<p><strong>Not Spending Money Is Like Having No Money</strong></p>
<p>Months later, a sudden urge led the miser to the bank, where he discovered his account was empty. Devastated, he returned home, where his son consoled him: &ldquo;Don&rsquo;t be so upset. Just pretend the passbook is real. It serves the same purpose. You can still calculate your wealth daily. Money sitting unused in a bank is the same as having no money.&rdquo; This parable satirizes the miser to emphasize the true meaning of wealth.  Hoarding money without utilizing it is no different from having none.  Wealth, in any form, has no inherent meaning. Its value comes from what we ascribe to it and how we use it to live the life we want.</p>
<p>&ldquo;My philosophy is to live a simple life, be humble, and what significance does money hold for me?&rdquo;  Li Ka-shing, despite his immense wealth, focuses on making more money and training his successors – his two sons, Victor and Richard.</p>
<p>Wealthy Taiwanese tycoons seem to follow a similar pattern, leaving all their wealth to the next generation, even surpassing Li Ka-shing in their simple lifestyles. Tsai Wan-lin, once Taiwan&rsquo;s richest man, drove a Yulon car and ate nutritionally balanced but bland meals prepared by doctors. Even in his 70s, he went to work every day, saying, &ldquo;The thought of paying NT$20 million in salaries every day compels me to come to the office.&rdquo;</p>
<p>Taiwan has many such &ldquo;miserly&rdquo; tycoons. Wang Yung-ching, the founder of Formosa Plastics Group, was known for his frugality, even combining leftover soap scraps. He said, &ldquo;Food needs only to be nutritious, not necessarily luxurious. Simple meals are good.  Constant luxury makes one forget what happiness is.&rdquo;</p>
<p>&ldquo;I can live like an emperor or a commoner,&rdquo; said Huang Shih-hui, chairman of the Chinfon Group and a consistent top taxpayer in Taiwan. &ldquo;Even if I lost a third, or even half of my wealth, I could still live well.&rdquo; Ranked Taiwan&rsquo;s sixth richest man by Fortune magazine, Huang ate NT$50 lunches and drove an ordinary car. He said, &ldquo;How much can I wear? How much can I eat? Excessive desire will kill you!&rdquo; For these wealthy individuals, the meaning of earning so much lies in the sense of accomplishment, not enjoyment.</p>
<p><strong>Be the Master of Your Money</strong></p>
<p><em>If you don&rsquo;t master your money, your money will master you.</em></p>
<p>If asked, &ldquo;What&rsquo;s the next step after earning money?&rdquo; most people would instinctively answer, &ldquo;Spending it!&rdquo;  They&rsquo;re wrong. Those who answer this way usually haven&rsquo;t earned much. Most self-made millionaires continue to earn after becoming wealthy.</p>
<p>Some might say, &ldquo;It&rsquo;s foolish to have money and not spend it!&rdquo;  True, but such misers are not uncommon. Studies show that at least 90% of people continue to accumulate wealth, becoming slaves to money.</p>
<p>By now, you should realize that achieving financial wealth is relatively easy.  Avoid keeping all your money in the bank, invest most of it in stocks or real estate, and be patient.  However, teaching you to become a billionaire only to become a miserly hoarder is not my intention.  Therefore, it&rsquo;s crucial to discuss the meaning of wealth and the reasons for pursuing it.</p>
<p>Undeniably, with today&rsquo;s opportunities and living standards, hard work can ensure a comfortable life.  This book demonstrates that with proper financial management, wealth is attainable. However, without prior reflection on the meaning of wealth, you may become complacent, give up, or, even worse, become wealthy but not know how to use your money.  This benefits no one.  Before embarking on the path to riches, ask yourself what wealth means to you, then determine the steps to achieve it.</p>
<p><em>1. Don&rsquo;t be a miser.  Learn to spend wisely after earning.</em>
<em>2. Before pursuing wealth, understand your values regarding it.</em></p>
<blockquote>
<p>Money, a double-edged sword, has corrupted countless souls throughout history.
Poverty, a solitary grave, has buried countless heroes and talents.</p>
</blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">Why Earn So Much? 
    <div id="why-earn-so-much" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#why-earn-so-much" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>Everyone desires wealth.  Isn&rsquo;t that why you bought and are reading this book? Yet, not everyone prioritizes wealth. We often hear sentiments like: &ldquo;You can&rsquo;t take it with you,&rdquo; &ldquo;Wealth is fleeting,&rdquo; or &ldquo;One can only eat three meals a day, wear one outfit, and one pair of shoes. Why earn so much?&rdquo;</p>
<p>If you say, &ldquo;Why bother with financial management if you don&rsquo;t want wealth?&rdquo; I have nothing more to say.  This book is explicitly for those seeking financial independence and wealth.</p>
<p>The desire for wealth is a personal choice, determined by one&rsquo;s values and perspective on money. Some see it as a tool, content with enough to meet their needs; others view it as the root of all evil, associating the pursuit of wealth with something ignoble.  Undeniably, the single-minded pursuit of money is wrong. Life offers many other valuable pursuits: health, knowledge, family, love, friendship – all precious.</p>
<p>Money isn&rsquo;t everything. We often hear, &ldquo;If money can solve it, it&rsquo;s a simple problem.&rdquo;  While not the most important thing in life, its importance is undeniable. As the saying goes, &ldquo;Money isn&rsquo;t everything, but without it, you can do nothing.&rdquo;  A good life requires money, as does education, a higher quality of life, improving family life, and even philanthropy. The New England Journal of Medicine points out that the wealthy live longer, healthier lives than the poor.</p>
<p>Many aspire to a happy life and giving back to society.  Both require money. Thus, money is a necessary means to achieve life goals. You can disdain money, but you can&rsquo;t deny its utility in today&rsquo;s society.</p>
<p>One&rsquo;s status and worth are often judged by wealth.  It&rsquo;s unfair, but true.  Despite the absence of social classes, money divides people into &ldquo;rich&rdquo; and &ldquo;poor.&rdquo; Greater wealth translates to greater ability to acquire desired possessions, status, and lifestyles.</p>
<p>Money undoubtedly buys the best healthcare, food, clothing, and housing. It provides security and freedom from fear, improving the quality of life and making it more vibrant.  The poor have limited options, while the rich enjoy a wider range of experiences.</p>
<p><strong>Money Can Ruin the Next Generation</strong></p>
<p>The easiest way to ruin your children? Leave them a fortune.  The saying &ldquo;Wealth doesn&rsquo;t last three generations&rdquo; reflects this truth.</p>
<p>Many educators and I share a common experience: the most challenging students lack motivation, often stemming from wealthy backgrounds.  These children, wanting for nothing, don&rsquo;t understand the need for hard work or ambition.</p>
<p>I recall a case during my tenure as director of the Graduate Institute of Business Administration at Tunghai University. A student, admitted after fierce competition, struggled academically and seemed listless. During counseling, I inquired about learning difficulties.</p>
<p>His response: &ldquo;My engineering background makes these courses easy. I don&rsquo;t understand why I need to learn this.&rdquo; I explained that business school teaches profit maximization. He replied, &ldquo;What&rsquo;s the point of making money?&rdquo; Shocked, I learned that his family&rsquo;s wealth had shielded him from financial concerns, leaving him without a drive to earn. I then emphasized the value of business management for future employment. His response: &ldquo;My father owns a factory waiting for me, but I don&rsquo;t want it.&rdquo;  He didn&rsquo;t appreciate what he already had.  I asked about his apparent preoccupation.  Reluctantly, he confessed his biggest worry: &ldquo;Why can humans kill animals, but not the other way around?&rdquo; I truly didn&rsquo;t understand the mindset of the wealthy&rsquo;s offspring.  It reminded me of the Taiwanese saying: &ldquo;Some complain of hunger after a full meal.&rdquo;</p>
<p>We should be grateful if our parents didn&rsquo;t leave us a fortune that robbed us of our drive.  This book shows how financial management can lead to wealth.  However, I caution against leaving excessive wealth to your children.</p>
<p>Ideally, set a financial goal and stop actively pursuing wealth after reaching it.  Avoid becoming a lifelong slave to money, and don&rsquo;t ruin your children&rsquo;s future.</p>
<p><strong>Warren Buffett&rsquo;s Perspective on Money</strong></p>
<p>Billionaire Warren Buffett has arranged his estate to be managed by a trust controlled by wise individuals with absolute authority and no restrictions.  He avoids preconditions, hoping to prevent it from becoming a bureaucratic, traditional fund. He said, &ldquo;If they create a lofty palace and become conservative and closed-minded, my ghost will not let them rest.&rdquo;</p>
<p>Buffett left his children $3 million each, and they now live happily as farmers. I admire his perspective: &ldquo;True happiness isn&rsquo;t living in a palace but adding a room to your house each year, because happiness is a process, not a result.&rdquo;</p>
<p>Buffett&rsquo;s estate planning is unique.  As America&rsquo;s richest man, his financial decisions draw attention. Some criticize his perceived stinginess towards philanthropy. He countered, &ldquo;When I die, societal problems will remain.  Society will benefit more from my wealth then than now.&rdquo; He remains steadfast despite public opinion.</p>
<p>Buffett essentially ensures that his wealth, acquired from society, returns to it upon his death – a remarkably detached approach compared to many Eastern tycoons.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Acquiring wealth is difficult.
Maintaining wealth is harder.
Utilizing wealth is the hardest.</p>
</blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">The Three Keys to Wealth Management: Earning, Managing, and Utilizing 
    <div id="the-three-keys-to-wealth-management-earning-managing-and-utilizing" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#the-three-keys-to-wealth-management-earning-managing-and-utilizing" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>Wealth management comprises three levels: earning, managing, and utilizing money. Technically, earning is the hardest, followed by managing, then utilizing. However, my experience as a financial advisor suggests that teaching people how to earn is difficult, teaching them to manage is harder, and teaching them to utilize is the hardest.</p>
<p><strong>Few Spend Wisely</strong></p>
<p>Some challenge this: &ldquo;Spending is easy! Give me your money, and I&rsquo;ll spend it all quickly.&rdquo;  True, spending other people&rsquo;s money is easy; spending your life&rsquo;s earnings is not. Many wealthy individuals struggle to use their money meaningfully.</p>
<p>Many lifelong savers find it incredibly difficult to change their habits and spend appropriately, even after becoming wealthy.  When asked, &ldquo;What are you saving for?&rdquo; they often reply, &ldquo;I don&rsquo;t know.&rdquo;</p>
<p>Many people tirelessly pursue wealth without clarifying their goals.  They blindly follow the mantra &ldquo;Money is important.&rdquo;  No one takes their wealth to the grave. <strong>Many become so consumed with earning that they forget their initial purpose, mistaking the means for the end.  They fail to use their wealth for greater happiness, joy, or societal good, becoming slaves to money.  Their wealth becomes meaningless, bringing more harm than benefit.</strong></p>
<p><em>1. Money is a means to achieve life goals. Don&rsquo;t mistake the means for the end and blindly chase money.</em>
<em>2.  Learn to utilize your money to become a truly happy and wealthy individual.</em>
<em>3. Save when young, manage wisely in middle age, and spend thoughtfully in old age.</em></p>
<p><strong>The Wealth Journey of Chen Ding-chuan, Chairman of Everlight Chemical</strong></p>
<p>&ldquo;Before seeking wealth, cultivate the ability to manage money and control yourself.&rdquo; Chen Ding-chuan believes that those who don&rsquo;t understand how to use money become its slaves, losing themselves in the pursuit.  Those who master the art of utilizing money become its masters, prioritizing self-growth and attracting wealth naturally.</p>
<p>Chen founded Everlight Chemical at 40, transforming it from a producer of basic dyes to a supplier of advanced specialty chemicals and pharmaceutical ingredients.  By 1995, the company&rsquo;s revenue reached over NT$2.4 billion.  A devout Christian and former director of the International Foundation Taiwan, Chen holds a unique perspective on money. He believes earning is easy, but spending wisely is not. He&rsquo;s witnessed countless wealthy individuals squander their fortunes and lose themselves, while others hoard their wealth, living like paupers and inflicting misery on those around them. He believes most people don&rsquo;t understand how to use money.</p>
<p>Deeply religious, Chen dedicates himself to God and spreading the Gospel.  Despite his success, he&rsquo;s traveled a difficult path.  He left school after elementary to work, studying diligently at night school for seven years, never missing a class except due to illness.  While others took on extra jobs, he prioritized education, graduating with a degree in international trade at 35. Who would have predicted his future as a billionaire?</p>
<p><strong>Who Paid the Highest Estate Tax?</strong></p>
<p>&ldquo;Who paid the highest estate tax in Taiwan&rsquo;s history?&rdquo;  I often ask this during lectures.  Few know the correct answer: Chen De-shen.</p>
<p>&ldquo;Chen De-shen? Who is he?&rdquo;  Audiences always murmur after the reveal.  It&rsquo;s a shame that someone who paid nearly NT$2 billion in estate tax remains relatively unknown.  How?  The only explanation is that Chen mastered earning and managing money, but not utilizing it.</p>
<p>Chen died in 1991, leaving an estate valued at NT$10 billion, resulting in a record NT$1.9 billion estate tax bill.  He lived a remarkably frugal life, using public transportation, sleeping on a cot, and living in his office to avoid buying a house. His sister recounted how he even refused to replace worn-out underwear.</p>
<p>Unmarried and childless, his vast fortune went to his siblings, sparking a highly publicized inheritance dispute. He exemplifies the saying, &ldquo;Those enslaved by wealth are pitiable even in their riches.&rdquo;</p>
<p>I often wonder, had he allocated a portion of his wealth to establish a &ldquo;De-shen College&rdquo; or &ldquo;De-shen Hospital,&rdquo; or donated even 1% (NT$100 million) to Tunghai University&rsquo;s business school, his name would be remembered for generations.  Such philanthropy would have benefited society and avoided family conflict.</p>
<p>Stanford University, a prestigious institution nestled between San Francisco and Silicon Valley, owes its existence to a generous donation from the Stanford family a century ago.  What a profound and lasting impact!  We marvel at the wisdom and foresight behind such giving.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Personal Investment Bible: Investment Iron Law X</title>
      <link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1731056005969/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1731056005969/</guid>
      <description>This article introduces three stock investment strategies: value investing, growth investing, and contrarian investing. Value investing emphasizes buying stocks when the price is below their intrinsic value and selling when the price is above. Growth investing focuses on the future earnings growth potential of companies, selecting companies with sustained high growth for investment. Contrarian investing suggests going against the general market sentiment, being greedy when others are fearful, and fearful when others are greedy.  The article analyzes the advantages, disadvantages, and suitability of each strategy, pointing out that although these three strategies are theoretically effective, they are difficult to implement in practice.  Ordinary investors are more suited to adopt a long-term buy-and-hold strategy of &amp;#34;buy any stock, buy at any time, and don&amp;#39;t sell.&amp;#34;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[

<h2 class="relative group">Investment Iron Law X: Mastering the Tools of Stock Market Offense and Defense 
    <div id="investment-iron-law-x-mastering-the-tools-of-stock-market-offense-and-defense" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#investment-iron-law-x-mastering-the-tools-of-stock-market-offense-and-defense" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>Buy when Value is higher than Price.
Sell when Value is lower than Price.</p>
</blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">Value Investing 
    <div id="value-investing" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#value-investing" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>The strategy of &ldquo;buy any stock, buy at any time, and don&rsquo;t sell&rdquo; sounds simple, but most people can&rsquo;t follow it. Even if they acknowledge its potential for wealth creation, they lack the courage to implement it because it seems to contradict common investment beliefs and principles. Therefore, the author presents three superior investment strategies: value investing, growth investing, and contrarian investing. Before investing, using these strategies, you must ask yourself: Does the investment target hold this value? What is its future growth potential? Is everyone investing in it? These three investment strategies can help you make better decisions.</p>
<p><strong>Verifying Value Ensures Profitability</strong></p>
<p>During the 1920s, Florida&rsquo;s real estate prices skyrocketed daily, triggering a buying frenzy. One fortunate investor managed to secure a plot of land. Most buyers didn&rsquo;t care about the land&rsquo;s quality, but this investor prudently asked a real estate agent to show him the purchased land. He was shocked to discover it was swampland.  &ldquo;Can anyone live here?&rdquo; he exclaimed. The agent calmly replied, &ldquo;Why worry about that? As long as the price goes up.&rdquo;</p>
<p>&ldquo;Human behavior and decision-making are perfectly rational&rdquo; is a fundamental assumption in academic research and theoretical development. Generally, consumers won&rsquo;t rush to buy unless a product offers exceptional value. For instance, no one would pay $5 million for a car worth $500,000 unless they were foolish. Investment decisions, involving money and future wealth, are even more critical than buying a car. Logically, people should be more rational and cautious, making decisions only after careful calculations.</p>
<p>However, are investors truly rational?  In July 1985, China Development Corporation&rsquo;s stock price was NT$14 per share. Four years later, in September 1989, it reached NT$1075, a nearly 80-fold increase.  Remarkably, in 1985, when the price was low, investors shunned the stock, resulting in low trading volume. Conversely, in 1989, when the price soared to over NT$1000, investors rushed in, fearing they would miss out, driving trading volume to its peak.</p>
<p>Are these investment behaviors rational?  Consider the difference between China Development Corporation at NT$14 in 1985, at over NT$1000 in 1989, or even at NT$50 in 1983.  Essentially, the difference was minimal; it was the same company, managed by practically the same people, with similar assets. Why such a drastic price difference? The answer lies not in the company&rsquo;s intrinsic changes but in investors&rsquo; behavioral and decision-making biases.</p>
<p>Between 1989 and 1990, during the Taiwan stock market&rsquo;s peak, investors continued pouring in. The author often asked friends and family, &ldquo;Do you think the stocks you&rsquo;re buying are worth the price?&rdquo;  Most found the question perplexing and avoided answering. Some reluctantly admitted, &ldquo;Probably not.&rdquo;  The author would then ask, &ldquo;Why buy them then?&rdquo;  Their confident reply: &ldquo;They&rsquo;ll go up!&rdquo;</p>
<p>Some also questioned the author&rsquo;s lack of participation in this lucrative market.  The response: &ldquo;I&rsquo;ll wait until after 4000 points to invest.&rdquo; The author believed the Taiwan stock market&rsquo;s true value was below 4000 points (in 1989).  Those who heard this scoffed, &ldquo;Keep waiting.&rdquo;  As it turned out, overvalued assets cannot rise indefinitely. In August 1990, the Taiwan stock index plummeted to around 2000 points, proving the author&rsquo;s point.  No investment&rsquo;s price can remain perpetually above or below its true value.</p>
<p><strong>Buy When Value Exceeds Price</strong></p>
<p>Value investing, introduced by Benjamin Graham in his 1933 book <em>Security Analysis</em>, was later championed by his students, including Warren Buffett and John Templeton.  In the 1980s, value investing gained prominence in the US, becoming the strategy of choice for many successful long-term investors.</p>
<p>Value investing posits that every stock has an intrinsic value.  Price fluctuations arise from investor trading.  Prices exceeding intrinsic value will eventually revert, and prices falling below will eventually recover.</p>
<p>The principle is simple: buy when the value is higher than the price, regardless of market fluctuations.  If it&rsquo;s cheap, buy it. Conversely, sell when the value is lower than the price.  In short, buy low, sell high.  Sell when prices significantly exceed value amidst widespread buying, minimizing holdings. Buy when prices fall drastically below value amidst widespread fear, increasing holdings.</p>
<p>Typically, investors focus solely on price appreciation, neglecting value.  People meticulously research cars, refrigerators, or stereos for months, comparing models, reading reviews, and seeking advice, constantly evaluating value for money.  They&rsquo;ll wait for a sale if the price is too high.  Yet, when buying stocks, often on a whim based on a tip or hearsay, they overlook value, making hasty decisions involving sums far exceeding appliance purchases.</p>
<p><strong>Invest with an Owner&rsquo;s Mindset</strong></p>
<p>Warren Buffett&rsquo;s investment philosophy emphasizes investing with an owner&rsquo;s mindset and a long-term perspective. This involves buying stocks of companies with stable earnings growth, positive prospects, high asset value, or simply when the intrinsic value exceeds the price.</p>
<p>Crowds flock to department stores during sales and clearances. The steeper the discounts, the larger the crowds.  Conversely, shopping is most pleasant when there are no sales, as stores are less crowded.  This is because consumers are motivated by value, buying when prices are below perceived worth.</p>
<p>However, in stock markets, the opposite occurs. Brokerage houses are deserted when stock prices are at their lowest.  Conversely, they are packed when prices are soaring. Investors are motivated by rising prices.  A stock falling from $100 to $50 attracts little interest, while rapid price increases fuel buying frenzy.</p>
<p>The assumption of rational economic behavior applies well to consumer choices but not to investment behavior.  As illustrated, investment decisions are often driven by irrational emotions, impulses, and intuition.</p>
<p>Value investing advises emulating consumer behavior: buy when stocks are &ldquo;on sale,&rdquo; and avoid the herd when prices are inflated.</p>
<p><strong>Developing the Ability to Calculate Asset and Earnings Value</strong></p>
<p>The key to successful value investing is the ability to calculate a company&rsquo;s intrinsic value, encompassing asset value and earnings value.  Asset value represents the liquidation value of the company&rsquo;s assets per share. Earnings value represents the present value of the company&rsquo;s projected future earnings.  Estimating future earnings is challenging, requiring the development of forecasting skills.</p>
<p>Calculating intrinsic value is not easy.  Investing in familiar companies simplifies this process.  Taiwanese businesswoman Shirley Wang, CEO of FIC Global, primarily invested in FIC and related IT and semiconductor companies.  Her familiarity with the industry allowed her to better grasp its dynamics.</p>
<p>Many successful investors adhere to Buffett&rsquo;s philosophy, investing only in familiar companies.  Li-Ching Hsu, former Taiwan head of ING Group, frequently advised investors to focus on companies in their own industry or related sectors.</p>
<p>Investment decisions should always involve value analysis. Buy when the value is present or the price is attractive; sell otherwise.  Value investing encourages adopting consumer-like behavior in the stock market, buying low and selling high.</p>
<p><em>1. When investing in stocks, ask &ldquo;Is it worth buying?&rdquo; not just &ldquo;Will it go up?&rdquo;</em></p>
<p><em>2.  Learn from consumer behavior: buy when prices are discounted.</em></p>
<blockquote>
<p>Choose a great company, and if it keeps growing, you&rsquo;ll almost never have to sell.</p>
</blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">Growth Investing 
    <div id="growth-investing" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#growth-investing" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>Valuing a company is challenging.  Some professional investors therefore focus on earnings growth rate, a primary driver of value, as their investment criterion. Growth investing has been successfully employed by renowned investors, notably Peter Lynch, former manager of Fidelity&rsquo;s Magellan Fund, who achieved the highest 15-year return among hundreds of US mutual funds.</p>
<p><strong>Investing in High-Growth Potential Stocks</strong></p>
<p>Simply put, growth investing involves buying stocks of companies with high future growth potential and selling when that potential diminishes.  A key characteristic is maintaining full investment, ideally diversified.  Growth investors acknowledge their inability to predict short-term market movements but believe in the long-term upward trend of stocks, especially those with high growth potential.</p>
<p>They invest all their capital in high-growth stocks.  Peter Lynch maintained a nearly 100% invested portfolio during his tenure at Magellan Fund, keeping minimal cash reserves for redemptions.</p>
<p>The key to successful growth investing lies in identifying companies with high growth potential.  This is the challenge: finding high-growth stocks.  Investing in IBM 30 years ago, Microsoft 15 years ago, or Cathay Life Insurance in Taiwan would have yielded multifold returns.</p>
<p>However, countless seemingly high-growth companies fizzle out. No one can predict the future with certainty. Even Peter Lynch admitted that only half of his stock picks were truly successful, but that was enough.  Therefore, diversification is crucial for mitigating the higher risks of growth investing.</p>
<p>Growth investing believes that a company&rsquo;s real growth drives stock price appreciation.  Investment returns depend on the earnings over the next few years. For high returns, choose investments with 5-10 year growth potential. Invest in companies in high-growth industries with excellent performance and a sustainable growth outlook. Their stock prices are likely to rise with the company&rsquo;s growth, offering substantial long-term gains.</p>
<p><strong>Choosing the Right Industry is More Important Than Choosing the Right Company</strong></p>
<p>Growth investors prioritize future earnings growth potential.  Industry growth is crucial for a company&rsquo;s earnings.  Choosing the right industry is therefore more important than choosing the right company.  Consider the future 5-10 year demand for the company&rsquo;s products, focusing on the industry&rsquo;s growth potential. Peter Lynch advised against selling good stocks prematurely for small profits and recommended selling stocks of companies with deteriorating growth prospects, even at a loss.  This approach allows gains from successful picks to offset losses from unsuccessful ones, resulting in overall profit.</p>
<p>Peter Lynch advocated for a &ldquo;common sense&rdquo; approach to investing, illustrated in his book <em>One Up On Wall Street</em>. He profited from observing his wife&rsquo;s preference for certain hosiery and dish soap brands, and his children&rsquo;s preference for certain sneakers, leading him to invest in those companies.  This approach can be explained by market efficiency theory.  Retailers and observant consumers are often the first to notice a product&rsquo;s popularity, before analysts.  By adopting a consumer perspective and noticing trends overlooked by experts, investors can gain an edge.</p>
<p>In early 1996, after a frugal, retired court clerk passed away, her family discovered her substantial wealth. She had consistently invested small amounts in Coca-Cola stock for decades, capitalizing on its growth and share price appreciation. This illustrates the power of long-term investment in growing companies.</p>
<p><strong>Don&rsquo;t Just Focus on Price Fluctuations</strong></p>
<p>Many investors are unclear about their investment rationale.  If you can&rsquo;t explain your investment&rsquo;s business and growth potential in five minutes, you shouldn&rsquo;t own it.  Focus on monitoring the validity of your investment thesis, not daily price fluctuations.</p>
<p>Many investors prefer startups or pre-IPO companies. However, established, profitable companies with growth potential are often better investments. Peter Lynch suggested capturing the middle five years of a company&rsquo;s 15-year growth trajectory, rather than the initial or mature phases.  If a stock has the potential to rise from $2 to $200, wait until it reaches $8 before buying. The potential gains are still substantial, and the risk is lower.  Losing money in the stock market is quick, but making money takes time. Most stocks take 3-5 years to rise significantly.</p>
<p>Regarding industry growth potential, in Taiwan, IT, communications, and semiconductors within the electronics industry are promising. Pharmaceuticals and biotechnology are also attractive due to increasing health consciousness. Taiwan&rsquo;s ten emerging industries (specialty chemicals, environmental protection, aerospace, telecommunications, semiconductors, IT, pharmaceuticals, precision machinery, etc.) offer future growth opportunities.  In the service sector, securities and investment trust, construction, and shipping also have good prospects.  <strong>Savvy investors should anticipate future trends, popular products, internet-driven products, and leverage their own consumer insights to identify investment opportunities.</strong></p>
<p>Growth investing is suitable for non-professional investors.  It requires no specialized training or constant monitoring.  To identify growth stocks, consider a company&rsquo;s potential performance over the next 5-10 years. Invest in companies with strong growth potential and hold them long-term, selling only when they transition from growth to maturity.  This strategy allows even amateur investors with limited time and expertise to achieve good results.</p>
<p><em>1. Real earnings growth drives stock price appreciation.</em></p>
<p><em>2. Diversify investments in companies with sustainable 5-10 year growth potential, patiently awaiting substantial returns.</em></p>
<blockquote>
<p>Don&rsquo;t follow the crowd; be rational. Figure out what most people are doing, then don&rsquo;t do it.</p>
</blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">Contrarian Investing 
    <div id="contrarian-investing" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#contrarian-investing" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>Many ask, &ldquo;Is there a better time to buy than &lsquo;any time&rsquo;?&rdquo; Research suggests there is: contrarian investing, a time-tested and remarkably effective strategy.</p>
<p><strong>Buy Straw Hats in Winter, Boats in a Drought</strong></p>
<p>A 19th-century American tycoon, when asked about his wealth-building secret, replied, &ldquo;Buy straw hats in winter.&rdquo;  Similarly, Fan Li, a wealthy merchant in ancient China, followed the principle of &ldquo;buying fur coats in summer, selling in winter; buying boats in a drought, selling when it rains.&rdquo;  These are examples of contrarian investing.</p>
<p>This investment concept originated in ancient China. According to <em>Records of the Grand Historian</em>, Ji Ran, an economist during the Warring States period, proposed the contrarian strategy of &ldquo;invest in boats during drought, invest in carts during floods.&rdquo;  He argued that during droughts, when everyone invests in cart production, one should invest in boats.  The oversupply of carts would lower prices and profits.  When the rains return, boat demand would surge, raising prices and profits.  Conversely, during floods, when everyone invests in boats, one should invest in carts.</p>
<p>Contrarian investing means investing when most people aren&rsquo;t and selling when everyone is eager to buy.  The concept is simple: go against the crowd.  However, implementing it is challenging. It requires overcoming human nature, resisting herd mentality, cultivating independent judgment, and enduring loneliness. Most investors follow the crowd, while contrarian investors look for opportunities when others are fearful.  This strategy relies on the belief that widespread consensus is often wrong and that reversals can be powerful.</p>
<p><strong>Don&rsquo;t Be Deceived by Net Buying or Selling</strong></p>
<p>Contrarian investing works because when most people are bullish, available capital is already invested, leading to overinflated prices.  With everyone already in the market, poised to sell, potential supply outweighs demand. Any negative news can trigger a sharp decline.</p>
<p>Conversely, when most people are bearish, selling pressure is minimal as most have already sold.  With potential buyers waiting on the sidelines, demand outweighs supply.  Any positive news can trigger a sharp rise.</p>
<p>Investors tend to extrapolate past trends, especially when reinforced by market sentiment. During initial market declines, most see it as temporary, while a few predict further declines. As the market continues falling, bears are rewarded, and bulls suffer.  At severely oversold levels, widespread pessimism creates buying opportunities.  Conversely, during initial market rallies, most see it as temporary, while a few predict further gains. As the market continues rising, bulls are rewarded, and bears suffer. At severely overbought levels, widespread optimism leads to overvaluation.</p>
<p><strong>Bullish When Rising, Bearish When Falling</strong></p>
<p>People tend to become more optimistic during optimistic periods and more pessimistic during pessimistic periods.  They rely on memory to predict the future.  A rising market breeds bullishness, and a falling market breeds bearishness.</p>
<p>At the peak of the Taiwan stock market in late 1989, the author taught an investment course. During one lecture, a student requested the author refrain from discussing stocks.  Surprised, the author asked why. The student explained that every class, from political science to calculus, included discussions about stocks.</p>
<p>Another anecdote from that period involves a professor asking his class the time. A student instinctively replied, &ldquo;9865 points, up 65 points.&rdquo;  Students were constantly monitoring stock prices during lectures. This illustrates the pervasive stock market mania at the time.  As it turned out, this widespread obsession was a harbinger of the impending crash.</p>
<p><strong>Great investments often involve defying conventional wisdom, selling when others are buying, and buying when others are selling.  Be bearish before others when everyone is bullish, and be bullish before others when everyone is bearish. As a Wall Street adage goes, &ldquo;Markets are born in despair, grow in skepticism, mature in optimism, and die in euphoria.&rdquo;</strong></p>
<p>Contrarian investing doesn&rsquo;t require constantly opposing the majority. It encourages resisting herd mentality and cultivating independent thinking.  The best buying opportunities may arise when most are afraid to buy, but buying solely for that reason is as foolish as following the crowd. The crowd isn&rsquo;t always wrong.  Develop independent judgment.  True contrarians don&rsquo;t blindly oppose the majority but wait for the dust to settle and buy when no one is paying attention.</p>
<p>Contrarian investing applies to stock selection. David Dreman, in his book <em>Contrarian Investment Strategies</em>, argued that unpopular companies often outperform expectations, while popular companies are susceptible to minor setbacks.</p>
<p>Timing the market is difficult. Mastering the principles of contrarian investing can be highly rewarding.</p>
<p><em>1. Invest when others aren&rsquo;t; sell when everyone is eager to invest.</em></p>
<p><em>2. Don&rsquo;t follow the crowd; buy when investor sentiment has cooled and no one is paying attention.</em></p>
<p><strong>Value, Growth, and Contrarian Strategies are Best Suited for Experts</strong></p>
<p>These seemingly disparate strategies are not mutually exclusive. Investors can choose or combine strategies based on their individual characteristics.  The most effective strategy is subjective and depends on individual circumstances. The author recommends value investing for those skilled in financial analysis, growth investing for those with foresight, and contrarian investing for independent, emotionally disciplined individuals.</p>
<p>Value investing is considered the most sophisticated technique, requiring strong financial knowledge and valuation skills. Most investors lack this expertise. Even among analysts, few truly understand valuation.  Growth investing requires foresight to identify high-growth industries and companies, which is also challenging.  Contrarian investing requires no specialized knowledge but is the hardest to implement due to its counterintuitive nature.  Most people are trend followers. Few can buy when everyone is selling or sell when everyone is buying.</p>
<p>These three strategies can enhance returns if mastered and applied correctly.  Countless self-proclaimed &ldquo;investment experts&rdquo; populate the market, but few consistently outperform using these strategies.  Misapplied, these strategies can lead to short-term speculation and losses.  Therefore, the author still recommends the simple, yet effective, long-term buy-and-hold strategy of &ldquo;buy any stock, buy at any time, and don&rsquo;t sell&rdquo; for most investors.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Personal Investment Bible: Investment Iron Law III</title>
      <link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1731056005962/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1731056005962/</guid>
      <description>This article explores the importance of investing and managing finances, emphasizing the principle of &amp;#39;the sooner, the better.&amp;#39; It points out that procrastination is the primary cause of financial failure and encourages young people to start managing their finances early, rather than waiting until middle or old age.  The article uses the success stories of Warren Buffett and Jeffrey Koo Jr. to illustrate the power of long-term investment and compound interest. It also emphasizes that even with limited funds, one should start managing their finances and learn how to utilize high-return investment tools to grow their wealth.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[

<h2 class="relative group">Investment Iron Law III: Invest Sooner Rather Than Later 
    <div id="investment-iron-law-iii-invest-sooner-rather-than-later" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#investment-iron-law-iii-invest-sooner-rather-than-later" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>Invest first, then wait for the opportunity,<br>
rather than waiting for the opportunity to invest.</p>
</blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">Procrastination: The Primary Cause of Financial Failure 
    <div id="procrastination-the-primary-cause-of-financial-failure" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#procrastination-the-primary-cause-of-financial-failure" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>The mentality of &ldquo;things will work out&rdquo; and a passive approach to financial management is the most common obstacle to personal finance. It&rsquo;s also the main reason why many people struggle to achieve financial independence by retirement.  Many individuals adopt a passive attitude towards financial planning, believing that things will naturally fall into place. As they age and witness the rapid growth of others&rsquo; wealth, they finally realize the importance of financial management.  However, by then, time is often limited, the power of compound interest cannot be fully utilized, and it becomes too late, even if they understand the principles of financial management.</p>
<p><strong>Financial Management Is Not Just for the Middle-Aged</strong></p>
<p>Many young people believe that financial management is something for middle-aged or wealthy individuals, and that it&rsquo;s not too late to worry about it in old age.  Here, I want to remind readers that the ability to build wealth through financial management has little correlation with the amount of money one possesses, but a significant correlation with the length of time invested.  People often reach middle age, facing retirement with some savings, and only then start thinking about preparing for their financial future. However, at this point, it&rsquo;s often too late. The reason is insufficient time to allow compound interest to work its magic.  Turning small amounts of money into substantial wealth requires at least two to three decades.  Recall the previous example: 10 years is not enough time to see significant growth.  A much longer period is needed for remarkable results.</p>
<p>Since we know that building wealth through investment requires investing in high-return assets and leveraging the long-term effects of compound interest, our approach, besides enriching our investment knowledge and skills, should involve immediate action.  Financial planning should start as early as possible, cultivating patience and a long-term perspective.</p>
<p>The reason for many financial failures today is the lack of knowledge about how to utilize funds effectively to achieve the goal of making money work for you and building wealth through investment. This is a flaw in our education system. Schools dedicate significant time to teaching students how to earn a living but fail to teach them how to manage their earnings.  College students exploring financial management through stock investment are often viewed as engaging in speculative and greedy behavior. In a future dominated by finance, the lack of proper financial knowledge not only erodes the dream of wealth accumulation but also harms the financial operations of businesses and the overall prosperity of society.</p>
<p>Don&rsquo;t delay your financial plan using the excuse of uncertain future price trends.  Who can predict when real estate or stock prices will rise?  Past price surges always lead to regret for those who missed out. There are no clear signs before prices start to rise, and no one will announce it with fanfare. <strong>For investments that are unpredictable in the short term but offer high expected returns in the long term, the safest strategy is to invest first and then wait for the opportunity, not the other way around.</strong></p>
<p><strong>Warren Buffett Started Investing at Age 11</strong></p>
<p><em>I believe every business school graduate should sign a contract pledging to make no more than 20 major decisions in their lifetime. If your career spans 40 years, that&rsquo;s one decision every two years.</em></p>
<p>Warren Buffett, ranked the second richest man in America by Forbes magazine in 1996, is widely regarded as the god of stock investment. He claims that more than half of his net worth is attributed to about ten investment decisions. He believes the key to investment is to buy stocks of good companies at good prices and hold them for the long term. As long as these companies continue to perform well, don&rsquo;t sell their stocks.</p>
<p>Buffett, with a net worth of $9 billion, amassed his fortune entirely from the stock market.  At 68, he held an MBA from Columbia University and was the son of a stockbroker-turned-congressman.  Buffett made his first investment at the age of 11, putting his and his sister&rsquo;s small savings into the stock market. Initially, he lost money, and his sister criticized him, but he insisted that it would take three to four years to see profits. His sister sold her shares, while he held on, ultimately proving his point.</p>
<p>At 20, while studying at Columbia University, Buffett immersed himself in finance books and insurance industry statistics while his peers focused on leisure activities.  Lacking capital and disliking borrowing, he often sold stocks prematurely to reinvest in others. Despite the limitations of his funds, his wealth continued to grow.</p>
<p>In 1954, he joined Professor Graham&rsquo;s investment firm. Two years later, he raised $100,000 from family and friends and established his own firm. After its assets increased thirtyfold, he dissolved the company in 1969, returned the partners&rsquo; money, and focused on his own investments.</p>
<p>He is a true stock market tycoon and has been America&rsquo;s richest man for years. Other wealthy Americans, like Bill Gates and Henry Lea Hillman, built their fortunes through businesses, while Buffett focused on stock investment. As long as the US economy continues to grow, his wealth will continue to increase.</p>
<p>Buffett&rsquo;s immense wealth, accumulated through nearly 60 years of investing, is a testament to the power of compound interest.  His early experiences with trial and error played a crucial role in honing his investment acumen.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Financial management is like farming.<br>
A bountiful harvest in the future depends on diligent sowing and watering today.</p>
</blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">Start Investing Today 
    <div id="start-investing-today" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#start-investing-today" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>If time is an indispensable element of financial management, the best strategy is to act now. Start managing your finances today!</p>
<p><strong>Don&rsquo;t Wait Until Your Hair Turns White</strong></p>
<p>The earlier you start investing, the sooner you&rsquo;ll achieve your financial goals and enjoy the fruits of your labor with your family. Furthermore, starting early maximizes the time for compound interest to work, requiring smaller initial investments and making financial management easier and more enjoyable.</p>
<p>Starting later requires significantly higher monthly investments to reach the same goals. The following table is based on these assumptions: an annual return of 15%, a target amount of 100 million yuan, and a retirement age of 65. It calculates the required monthly investment for different starting ages.</p>
<p><em>Monthly Investment Required to Become a Millionaire, by Starting Age</em></p>
<table>
  <thead>
      <tr>
          <th style="text-align: left">Starting Age</th>
          <th style="text-align: left">Monthly Investment (Yuan)</th>
      </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
      <tr>
          <td style="text-align: left">20</td>
          <td style="text-align: left">2324</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td style="text-align: left">25</td>
          <td style="text-align: left">4684</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td style="text-align: left">30</td>
          <td style="text-align: left">9458</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td style="text-align: left">35</td>
          <td style="text-align: left">19863</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td style="text-align: left">40</td>
          <td style="text-align: left">39163</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td style="text-align: left">45</td>
          <td style="text-align: left">81348</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td style="text-align: left">50</td>
          <td style="text-align: left">175143</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td style="text-align: left">55</td>
          <td style="text-align: left">410428</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td style="text-align: left">60</td>
          <td style="text-align: left">1235959</td>
      </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>
<p>The table clearly demonstrates that youth is a valuable asset in wealth accumulation. The younger you are, the better positioned you are to achieve the dream of building wealth from small investments.  Starting financial planning in old age requires monthly investments that are beyond the reach of most people. In short, start saving for retirement early. Don&rsquo;t wait until your hair turns white; time waits for no one.</p>
<p>Your future financial well-being depends on your actions today. Don&rsquo;t let hesitation hold you back. Follow the principles outlined in this book, invest your funds in the stock market, real estate, or other high-return investment vehicles, and over time, you too can become wealthy.</p>
<p><em>1. The earlier you start investing, the longer the time for compound interest to work, and the sooner you&rsquo;ll achieve your wealth goals.</em></p>
<p><em>2. Only young people can dream of building wealth from small investments.</em></p>
<p><em>3. The best time to start managing your finances is as early as possible.</em></p>
<p><strong>Jeffrey Koo Jr.&rsquo;s Path to Wealth</strong></p>
<p>Jeffrey Koo Jr., the eldest son of Jeffrey Koo Sr., chairman of Chinatrust Commercial Bank in Taiwan, and current Vice President of Chinatrust, is actively uniting the third generation of Taiwanese entrepreneurs. He organized a luncheon club primarily for the third generation of prominent Taiwanese business families to network and exchange information. To expand its influence, Koo Jr. has also strengthened the luncheon club&rsquo;s connections with Southeast Asian politicians and the second and third generations of overseas Chinese business families.</p>
<p>Koo Jr. is a representative figure among Taiwan&rsquo;s third-generation entrepreneurs and the heir apparent to his father. Many assume his wealthy background afforded him a comfortable financial situation. However, Koo Sr. instilled frugal habits in his children and didn&rsquo;t provide excessive allowances.  Koo Jr. had to find his own ways to become financially independent.</p>
<p>Sent to Japan for his education by his father, Koo Jr. returned to Taiwan for university after graduating high school with only his accumulated New Year&rsquo;s money, around NT$100,000, in his bank account. In early 1987, as the weighted stock price index climbed from 1,000 points, many people invested in the stock market. Koo Jr., then a junior in college, followed suit, investing all his savings.  His grandmother&rsquo;s daily routine of asking him to recite the stock market index further influenced him.  His frequent interactions with entrepreneurs from various industries provided him with business opportunities, enabling him to grow his NT$100,000 capital to NT$10 million during the bull market.</p>
<p>When the stock market crashed from over 10,000 points in 1990, he was already pursuing his Master&rsquo;s degree at the Wharton School of Business in the US. His father, hoping for him to join the family business sooner, disapproved of his overseas studies and threatened to withhold financial support. Koo Jr. confidently assured his father that he could support himself financially. He successfully completed his studies in the US and even bought his dream car, a Porsche, with his own money.  Koo Jr.&rsquo;s knack for investment and financial management from a young age made his dreams a reality. If you aspire to be wealthy, start now!</p>
<p><strong>Youth Is the Greatest Asset for Financial Success</strong></p>
<p>Successful people have a habit: they delay, but don&rsquo;t give up, the enjoyment of the fruits of their labor.</p>
<p>In Louis Cha&rsquo;s novel <em>The Book and the Sword</em>, the Qianlong Emperor tells his sworn brother, &ldquo;I don&rsquo;t envy anything about you except your youth.&rdquo; Even the emperor envied youth.</p>
<p>Similarly, from a financial perspective, youth is the most important asset. I often tell college students, &ldquo;Young people, your name is wealth!&rdquo;  The compound interest formula clearly shows that time is money, and youth is wealth.</p>
<p>The compound interest chart provides a clear roadmap for financial planning: focus on increasing income and saving during your youth and start investing early. Money saved during youth contributes significantly to wealth in old age.  NT$10,000 saved in your youth can grow to over NT$2.3 million in 30 years.  The same amount saved in old age will only grow to NT$60,000 in 10 years. Whether the statement &ldquo;Young people, your name is wealth&rdquo; becomes a reality depends on whether young people manage their finances wisely. Poor financial management, even with the advantage of youth, will not bring wealth.</p>
<p>The prevalent notion among young people today is that it&rsquo;s fine to indulge in enjoyment while young and worry about financial planning later. This is a misguided perspective. Many young people believe retirement is far off and their funds are limited, so there&rsquo;s no need to consider investment. They often miss the opportunity to start early.</p>
<p>In reality, starting financial planning in old age, even with some savings, is often too late due to limited time. The correct approach is: <strong>investing and managing finances is the job of young people, while managing wealth is the job of old age.</strong>  However, many young people prioritize immediate gratification, spending their money on sports cars, high-end audio systems, or travel, believing they can enjoy life now and worry about finances later.</p>
<p>If you understand the role of time in financial management, it&rsquo;s easy to see why such individuals are destined for mediocrity.  Countless examples in society demonstrate how prioritizing enjoyment in youth leads to poverty in old age. The key is their neglect of the importance of early financial planning. By the time they realize it, it&rsquo;s often too late.</p>
<p>As Taiwan&rsquo;s population ages and smaller family structures become the norm, future generations will rely on their own financial resources for living expenses. Therefore, the concept of starting financial planning in youth becomes increasingly critical.</p>
<p><strong>Youth Is the Best Time for Taking Risks</strong></p>
<p>Young people possess the most valuable asset in financial management - time. Youth is also the best time to take risks because family responsibilities are generally lighter. Young people should embrace a risk-taking mindset because the cost of failure is lower.  You can recover from setbacks more easily. Moreover, with limited funds, potential losses are smaller, providing valuable learning experiences.  Most importantly, young people have ample time for compound interest to work its magic.</p>
<p>Before 50, one shouldn&rsquo;t adopt an overly conservative approach to investment and financial management. The best time to learn about financial management is as early as possible. Sound financial judgment comes from experience, and experience comes from mistakes. Since developing good judgment requires making some mistakes along the way, why not gain this experience while you&rsquo;re young and the stakes are lower?  By the time you have more capital, you can apply your honed financial judgment effectively.</p>
<p>Young people should not just spend money but also understand the importance of saving. Start saving, and once you have a few thousand or tens of thousands of yuan, consider long-term, high-return investments, even if they carry some risk.</p>
<p>Some may feel they are no longer young and their current income is low, leaving no surplus for investment. Indeed, older individuals have less time to benefit from compound interest. However, don&rsquo;t be discouraged. Money can buy time, and you might still have opportunities to catch up.  By following sound financial principles, you can achieve unexpected gains. If you are past 50, help your children by sharing these fundamental wealth-building concepts so they don&rsquo;t miss out on the opportunity to build wealth early in their lives.  Instead of giving your next generation money, teach them the knowledge of making money work for them.</p>
<p><em>1. Youth is the greatest asset for building wealth through financial management. 2. Young people should embrace risk-taking because the cost of failure is lower.</em> <em>3. Invest when you&rsquo;re young to maximize the benefits of compound interest over time.</em></p>
<blockquote>
<p>Playing a good hand well is nothing special; playing a bad hand well is what deserves admiration.</p>
</blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">Don&rsquo;t Neglect Financial Management Due to Limited Funds 
    <div id="dont-neglect-financial-management-due-to-limited-funds" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#dont-neglect-financial-management-due-to-limited-funds" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>Some believe that financial management is exclusive to the wealthy and high-income families, requiring substantial capital to even consider it.  Indeed, financial management is about making money work for you. It&rsquo;s not about turning stone into gold or creating something from nothing, so you need some initial capital. However, what many don&rsquo;t realize is that the most influential factors on future wealth, according to the compound interest formula, are the rate of return and the length of the investment period, not the current amount of capital or future contributions.</p>
<p><strong>Small Beginnings Can Lead to Great Fortunes</strong></p>
<p>With the right approach, even a small amount of money can generate significant wealth over time, as illustrated in previous examples.  Even someone with no initial capital, by investing 14,000 yuan annually, can become a millionaire in 40 years.  <strong>The principle of investment and financial management is this: understanding how to utilize high-return tools and the long-term effects of compound interest is more important than the amount of money invested.</strong></p>
<p>A common misconception is that financial planning is only necessary after accumulating a large sum of money. In reality, the key factors influencing future wealth are the rate of return and the length of investment period, not the amount of capital.  The key to successful financial management lies in maximizing returns and holding investments for the long term.  While having more capital can accelerate wealth accumulation, it&rsquo;s not the decisive factor.</p>
<p>Perhaps you&rsquo;ve considered investing but dismissed the idea due to limited funds. By doing so, you&rsquo;ve missed a valuable opportunity to enhance your investment skills.  The focus of investment should not be on &ldquo;how much money is earned&rdquo; but on &ldquo;the rate of return&rdquo; at which money is earned.  For example, earning 5,000 yuan on a principal of 100,000 yuan represents a 5% return, which is a poor investment. Earning 2,000 yuan on a principal of 10,000 yuan represents a 20% return, which is a good investment.  Over time, the latter will significantly outperform the former.  Therefore, the earlier you learn financial management, the better. It allows limited funds to leverage the power of compound interest and create substantial wealth.</p>
<p><strong>Those with Less Should Strive Harder</strong></p>
<p>Some may question how to invest with only a few thousand or tens of thousands of yuan. In today&rsquo;s developed financial markets, investment units are highly divisible. Around 10,000 yuan can buy a lower-priced stock, and a few thousand yuan can be invested in mutual funds.  Real estate is also moving towards securitization. In short, there will be more investment options for smaller amounts in the future.  Therefore, any idle funds not needed in the short term, even a few thousand yuan, should be invested.</p>
<p>Are people truly too poor to manage small amounts of money?  During the Chang Hwa Credit Cooperative bank run, many ordinary people withdrew hundreds of thousands of yuan.  Statistics also show that the average bank deposit is 600,000 yuan, which is more than enough for investment purposes.</p>
<p>Even those with no current savings or expecting limited future income shouldn&rsquo;t underestimate themselves and give up on financial planning. While wealthy or high-income individuals have a head start, those with fewer assets or lower incomes should understand the principles of financial management and leverage it to compensate for their financial disadvantages, ultimately improving their lifetime financial situation.</p>
<p>Moreover, individuals from humble beginnings and with modest incomes can achieve a greater sense of accomplishment by building wealth through diligent financial management.  As the saying goes, &ldquo;<strong>There&rsquo;s nothing remarkable about playing a good hand well; it&rsquo;s playing a bad hand well that deserves admiration.</strong>&rdquo; If you truly have no money, find ways to increase income and reduce expenses, save some money, and then start managing your finances. Remember, even a small amount of money is enough to begin. While the path to wealth may be longer and more challenging with limited initial funds, the goal is still achievable, and the journey itself is valuable.</p>
<p><em>1. Investment and financial management are not exclusive to the wealthy or high-income earners.</em></p>
<p><em>2. Those with limited assets or low incomes should leverage financial management to catch up.</em></p>
<p><em>3. The amount of money you have when you start doesn&rsquo;t matter. Less money might even be better, allowing you to experiment with smaller investments initially and gradually increase your investment as you become more comfortable with risk.</em></p>
<p><em>4. Leverage other people&rsquo;s money to accelerate wealth building.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>00484 Buying at the market price immediately when you have money is the best investment strategy: a market with an unbreakable asset allocation doesn&#39;t exist</title>
      <link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1728261371758/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1728261371758/</guid>
      <description>This live session focused on long-term investment strategies, delving into investment philosophy, risk management, and values.  James shared personal experiences and insights, offering valuable guidance on understanding the nature of investing and its inherent risks, emphasizing the importance of being rational, patient, and vigilant.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<lite-youtube videoid="UGUV4GIqKVg" playlabel="UGUV4GIqKVg" params=""></lite-youtube>



<h2 class="relative group">I. Topic of the Session 
    <div id="i-topic-of-the-session" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-topic-of-the-session" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>The session centered on the core principle of long-term investment strategies. James reiterated his investment philosophy: &ldquo;Buy QQQ whenever you have money and hold it for the long term.&rdquo; The discussion expanded to cover aspects like investment philosophy, risk management, and values, incorporating current events and questions from attendees. James also shared insights from legendary investors like Warren Buffett, encouraging attendees to cultivate a sound investment mindset.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">II. Briefing Highlights 
    <div id="ii-briefing-highlights" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii-briefing-highlights" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<ol>
<li><strong>Buying at the Dip vs. Buying When You Have Money:</strong> James cited research from ChatGPT, indicating that even with the ability to accurately predict and buy at market dips, the long-term returns differed minimally compared to simply buying when one has available funds. Over a 20-year period, the difference was merely 8%, translating to a difference in annualized returns of less than 0.2%. Hence, rather than expending time and effort predicting market bottoms, it&rsquo;s more effective to seize opportunities and buy QQQ when you have the money.</li>
<li><strong>Risks of Leveraged Funds:</strong>  Using the 2000 tech bubble as an example, James explained how leveraged funds can accelerate losses in bear markets, potentially leading to devastating financial setbacks, even bankruptcy. He simulated a scenario where an investor repeatedly buys more leveraged funds as the market declines, culminating in financial ruin. This served as a cautionary tale against the &ldquo;buy the dip&rdquo; strategy with leveraged funds, emphasizing the importance of risk management.</li>
<li><strong>Keys to Investment Success:</strong> James emphasized that the key to successful investment lies in overcoming human weaknesses. Maintaining a detached and &ldquo;unfeeling&rdquo; attitude towards invested capital and short-term market fluctuations is crucial for adhering to a long-term investment approach.</li>
<li><strong>Market Cycles:</strong> James stated he wouldn&rsquo;t teach attendees about predicting market cycles or any trading techniques. He considers these unimportant and prone to misinterpretation and misapplication, potentially leading to increased risks. He advocated for a long-term investment strategy, likening it to riding a cable car, a smooth and steady ascent to the summit of financial success.</li>
<li><strong>Money and Values:</strong> Acknowledging that individuals have different values regarding money, James advised understanding and respecting diverse values, discouraging attempts to impose one&rsquo;s own values upon others. He used the example shared by an attendee about a mother preferring a financial subsidy over a family trip to illustrate the diverse ways people assign value to things.</li>
</ol>


<h2 class="relative group">III. Q&amp;A Session 
    <div id="iii-qa-session" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii-qa-session" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p><strong>IIM:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Shared:</strong> A story about a deceased friend, leading to reflections on money and values, and expressing confusion about balancing personal values with those of others.</li>
<li><strong>Question 1:</strong>  How to understand some people&rsquo;s &ldquo;frugality&rdquo; with money while being &ldquo;generous&rdquo; towards their pets.
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response:</strong> People manage their finances differently based on what they consider important and valuable. What might be significant to one person may hold little value for another.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question 2:</strong> How to understand a mother who prioritizes money over a family trip? How to better understand the needs of others?
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response:</strong>  This mother might have certain unmet needs, possibly requiring material security before pursuing leisurely experiences. Understanding true needs involves offering more choices (e.g., money plus a trip). Avoid trying to change others&rsquo; values; focus on understanding and respecting them.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Brian:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Shared:</strong> Encountering a friend who suggested leveraging to purchase Nvidia stock, leading to questions about investment advice.</li>
<li><strong>Question:</strong> How to evaluate investment advice received from others?
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response:</strong>   The validity of investment advice depends on individual judgment and risk tolerance. It&rsquo;s important to avoid blindly following the advice of others and to think independently.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Iny:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Shared:</strong>  Experiencing a sense of calm and reduced anxiety after adopting James&rsquo;s investment approach.  This newfound peace of mind allows for dedicating more time to important matters like family, and interestingly, focusing on work has led to increased income.</li>
<li><strong>Question:</strong>  How to understand the phenomenon of increased income resulting from a dedicated focus on work?
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response:</strong> This exemplifies the principle that altruism ultimately benefits oneself. By focusing on serving clients and enhancing product or service quality, one ultimately gains client recognition and rewards, leading to higher income and a sense of accomplishment.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Haoqing:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Shared 1:</strong>  An experience with check fraud, prompting concerns about bank security and the risks of using checks.
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response:</strong>  Banks do not verify the identity of check depositors. Checks present security vulnerabilities, making it advisable to use safer online banking and digital payment methods like Apple Pay.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Shared 2:</strong> Thoughts on the decline of US manufacturing and the rise of Asia, attributing this to factors like US regulations, labor laws, and unions.
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response:</strong> The decline of US manufacturing and the rise of Asia are multifaceted issues stemming from a complex interplay of factors, including national policies, labor laws, and unions. While Asian countries might resort to suppressing labor rights and environmental regulations to gain a competitive edge, the US places a higher value on worker well-being and environmental protection. This divergence in values contributes to different developmental paths.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Becky:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Shared:</strong> Based on personal experience working in a digital payment company, Becky recommended that everyone stop using checks due to inherent security risks. Digital payment methods offer greater security and convenience, with features such as spending alerts that enable prompt response and recovery in case of issues.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Mike:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Shared:</strong> As a long-time follower of James, Mike witnessed the evolution of his investment philosophy, from initially holding 30% SPY to converting to 100% QQQ, and eventually incorporating leveraged funds. He also shared personal investment experiences, like selling NIO and allocating a portion of his portfolio to private market investments.</li>
<li><strong>Question 1:</strong> Is investing in Intel after its acquisition worthwhile?
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response:</strong>  James advised against investing in large companies that are acquisitive. Acquisitions often lack efficiency, posing integration challenges and potentially hindering productivity. While acquiring smaller companies for technological advantages makes sense, acquiring large companies is akin to amassing a pile of scrap metal.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question 2:</strong>  How to view the supply chain security concerns stemming from the US outsourcing 3C product manufacturing, citing examples like the BBB Call explosion and walkie-talkie incidents?
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response:</strong> Espionage is ubiquitous, and supply chain security is just one facet of this broader issue. Governments might implant spy codes in chips and software for surveillance purposes. Explosions are a relatively rudimentary form of espionage; more sophisticated methods can be extremely difficult to detect and prevent.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question 3:</strong> Is it possible to offer advanced courses for more experienced attendees? He suggested using portfolio sharing as a means to differentiate attendees&rsquo; learning progress.
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response:</strong> James stated he wouldn&rsquo;t differentiate between attendees nor offer advanced courses. Assessing whether a student is genuinely learning is primarily based on their attitude, not investment returns or holding duration. Even portfolio sharing can&rsquo;t truly gauge learning progress. James mentioned his personal sensitivity to words and language, enabling him to discern learning attitudes from attendees&rsquo; emails and the way they pose questions.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">IV. Noteworthy Insights 
    <div id="iv-noteworthy-insights" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv-noteworthy-insights" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>The best time to buy is when you have money.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Many obsess over finding the perfect entry point, but research indicates that even if you could perfectly time market dips, the long-term returns barely differ from simply buying when funds are available. Instead of wasting time trying to predict the market, seize the opportunity and act promptly.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>To succeed in investing, you must be indifferent to the money you invest and the fluctuations in stock prices.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Overcoming the human tendency to fixate on money and fear short-term market swings is essential for maintaining a long-term investment strategy and achieving stable returns.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>To achieve effortless investing, you need to be numb to money.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>When investing becomes a habit, free from emotional impulses and external distractions, you can achieve optimal results.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The concept of a &ldquo;benefactor&rdquo; is relative.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>People perceive and absorb information differently. Who you consider a benefactor might not be perceived as such by others.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Don&rsquo;t try to change other people&rsquo;s values.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Everyone has their own values and ways of life. It&rsquo;s important to understand and respect diverse choices.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Espionage is everywhere.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Information security is a growing concern. Be vigilant and protect your personal data.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Acquisitions of large companies are generally inefficient, and leaders who are fond of acquisitions usually have inflated egos.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Integration complexities and high management costs associated with mergers often outweigh the benefits gained.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The US excels in areas such as finance and technology design, while Asian countries can only substitute and supplement in specific aspects.
&ndash; Haoqing</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Within the global division of labor, different countries have distinct strengths and weaknesses, leading to divergent paths of development.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The best judgments are validated by facts.
&ndash; Mike</p>
</blockquote>
<p>The success of an investment philosophy is ultimately determined by its long-term returns, not short-term fluctuations or gut feelings.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Your attitude determines my response.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>James adjusts his responses based on the learning attitude of the attendees. Attendees who are truly dedicated to learning will receive greater guidance.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Investing in individual stocks will ultimately lead to bankruptcy; holding onto individual stocks will also ultimately lead to bankruptcy.<br>
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Companies have lifecycles.  Holding onto a single stock long term significantly increases the risk of encountering bankruptcy. Diversification is key in investing.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">V. Summary 
    <div id="v-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#v-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This live session once again emphasized the importance of long-term investing while reminding attendees to stay rational, patient, and vigilant. James addressed attendees&rsquo; questions regarding investment strategies, risk management, and the relationship between money and values, sharing personal experiences and insights. Key takeaways include avoiding market timing, leveraged funds, and individual stock investments, and embracing an attitude of indifference towards money. Attendees actively shared their own investment experiences and reflections, prompting deeper contemplation on investment, money, life, and more. The session also delved into the philosophies of renowned investors like Warren Buffett and discussed various social phenomena, creating a rich and informative experience.</p>

  



<div
  
    class="flex px-4 py-3 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900"
  >

  <span
    
      class="text-primary-400 ltr:pr-3 rtl:pl-3 flex items-center"
    >

    

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M506.3 417l-213.3-364c-16.33-28-57.54-28-73.98 0l-213.2 364C-10.59 444.9 9.849 480 42.74 480h426.6C502.1 480 522.6 445 506.3 417zM232 168c0-13.25 10.75-24 24-24S280 154.8 280 168v128c0 13.25-10.75 24-23.1 24S232 309.3 232 296V168zM256 416c-17.36 0-31.44-14.08-31.44-31.44c0-17.36 14.07-31.44 31.44-31.44s31.44 14.08 31.44 31.44C287.4 401.9 273.4 416 256 416z"/></svg>

  </span>


  </span>

  <span
    
      class="dark:text-neutral-300"
    ><strong>Disclaimer:</strong> This transcript serves as personal learning notes only and does not constitute investment advice.</span>
</div>

]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
