<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Artificial Intelligence on QQQ Investor</title>
    <link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/tags/artificial-intelligence/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Artificial Intelligence on QQQ Investor</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 26 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jomonylw.github.io/en/tags/artificial-intelligence/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>00513 The world is evolving: choosing the top index (e.g., Nasdaq 100), a reverie of the AI age</title>
      <link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1745714790157/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1745714790157/</guid>
      <description>In this episode, James first announced the upcoming two-week Clubhouse hiatus and then emphasized that market volatility is normal and there&amp;#39;s no need to over-analyze the reasons behind it. The core arguments revolved around the importance of long-term investing and index funds (especially the Nasdaq 100), and discussed the selection of specific ETFs (such as 00864B/00865B, BRK, HXQ). He also shared his fantasies about the future development of AI, exploring its potential impact on social structures, work, and the meaning of life. The Q&amp;amp;A session covered a range of practical issues, including market predictions, asset allocation ratios (70/30 rule, Beta value), ETF selection in different countries, digital currency risks, differences in investment philosophies between spouses, and retirement cash reserves.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<lite-youtube videoid="5WJ_23Gpcg0" playlabel="5WJ_23Gpcg0" params=""></lite-youtube>



<h2 class="relative group">I. Episode Theme 
    <div id="i-episode-theme" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-episode-theme" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This episode revolves around the core concept of long-term investing, emphasizing the importance of maintaining composure amidst inevitable market fluctuations, adhering to investments in high-quality index funds (such as the Nasdaq 100), and exploring the profound impact of AI development on the future of society and personal wealth. It also provides in-depth answers to specific questions raised by students regarding investment tool selection, asset allocation strategies, and market psychology.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">II. Summary 
    <div id="ii-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Operations and Reminders 
    <div id="operations-and-reminders" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#operations-and-reminders" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Clubhouse Hiatus Announcement</strong>: Clubhouse and video uploads will be suspended for the next two weeks (May 3rd and May 10th), resuming on May 17th (Saturday).</li>
<li><strong>Clubhouse Technical Issues</strong>: Recent issues with sound being inaudible or too low. It&rsquo;s recommended to leave and re-enter the room, or completely close and reopen the app.</li>
<li><strong>Speaking Rules</strong>: Accidental stage entries are fine, just stay on stage; no need to repeatedly enter and exit.</li>
<li><strong>Disclaimer</strong>: All sharing is for reference only. Investment decisions are the individual&rsquo;s responsibility. We are not professional investment advisors or tax professionals; sharing is based on personal experience. Long-term investment has low risk, short-term investment has high risk. Those who cannot tolerate short-term losses or are worried about asset devaluation should not invest and can choose fixed deposits instead.</li>
<li><strong>Learning Resources</strong>: Lecture notes are pinned in the Clubhouse comment section or the YouTube comment section. Newcomers are advised to start with video 00451, then 398-402, and then the latest for systematic learning (although there are as many as four or five hundred videos).</li>
<li><strong>Community Groups</strong>: No official groups are established. Participation in unofficial groups requires caution. If the group information is noisy, annoying, and not beneficial to life, it is recommended to leave. Groups aimed at sharing CLEC concepts, helping each other answer questions, and providing information are welcome.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Investment Philosophy and Strategies 
    <div id="investment-philosophy-and-strategies" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#investment-philosophy-and-strategies" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Market Volatility is Normal</strong>: The market is always fluctuating; this is the unchanging rule. No need to analyze specific reasons (international situation, trade war, financial report forecasts, etc.). Many analysts themselves do not truly understand. The market is like the sea, unaffected by streams and storms.</li>
<li><strong>Long-Term Investing</strong>: True investment is buying with the intention of never selling. Intending to sell at a high point is speculation. Investment must be long-term.</li>
<li><strong>Index Investing</strong>:
<ul>
<li><strong>Core Recommendation</strong>: Nasdaq 100 Index Fund (QQQ and its global equivalents). Reason: Compared to the S&amp;P 500 (500 companies, possibly 450 &ldquo;bad companies&rdquo;), the Nasdaq 100 focuses more on high-quality technology companies, aligning with the &ldquo;the bigger, the stronger&rdquo; trend.</li>
<li><strong>Retirees/Those with Less Capital</strong>: Consider Taiwan 0056 or US SPHD (dividend yield ~3.5%, providing stable cash flow).</li>
<li><strong>Nasdaq 100 ETF List</strong>: Provides a list of relevant ETFs including various countries (Canada HXQ.t, Singapore, Malaysia, Norway, UK, Australia, etc.). HXQ.t is recommended because it does not pay dividends (tax-free).</li>
<li><strong>Historical Experience</strong>: Watching videos since 2018 can provide insights into investor sentiment and responses during market fluctuations, giving a sense of the long-term perspective.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Stay Optimistic</strong>: Investors need to be extremely optimistic, always facing the sunlight, believing that the market will be good in the long run, even if there is a world war, the market still exists and continues to rise (only rises, never falls).</li>
<li><strong>Investment Target Selection</strong>:
<ul>
<li><strong>00864B vs 00865B (Taiwan Bond ETF)</strong>:
<ul>
<li>00864B: Pays dividends, generating National Health Insurance Supplementary Premium (2.11%), requires manual reinvestment (with handling fees, easy to forget resulting in no compounding), dividends are considered overseas income (requires declaration if it exceeds the limit, but usually not a problem with annual income below NT$1 million; according to student feedback, it is exempt from the second-generation health insurance supplementary premium).</li>
<li>00865B: Does not pay dividends, avoiding the above problems, simpler and more effective in the long run. Low trading volume is not a problem (market makers provide liquidity), initial performance differences will shrink as scale increases. <strong>Strongly recommend switching to 00865B; convenience is a value.</strong> Conversion will incur a one-time transaction cost, but worth it in the long run.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Berkshire Hathaway (BRK.A/B)</strong>:
<ul>
<li><strong>Not recommended for investment</strong>. Reason: Actively managed fund, more volatile than the index; times are changing, performance has lagged behind the S&amp;P 500; uncertainty after Buffett (&ldquo;the devil will come out&rdquo;); learning Buffett should be about learning his long-term investment spirit, investment discourse (such as the definition of investment), rather than stock picking. Investing in the S&amp;P 500 may be better than investing in BRK.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Asset Allocation (Beta)</strong>:
<ul>
<li><strong>Basic Principle</strong>: It is recommended that most people allocate an investment portfolio with a Beta value of less than 1, such as 70% index funds + 30% cash/money market funds (Beta is approximately 0.7).</li>
<li><strong>Risk Tolerance</strong>: The recent 20% drop has made many people uncomfortable (even those with a Beta of 1.2 configured at 4:4:2), indicating that actual risk tolerance may be lower than expected. Do not sacrifice the comfort of holding enough cash (&ldquo;don&rsquo;t gamble with the money you need for the money you don&rsquo;t need&rdquo;) for an extra 1-2% of return.</li>
<li><strong>Adjustment</strong>: If the initial Beta is high (such as 1.2), it is recommended to review it at the end of each year. If the market rises, you can sell part of the leveraged/index position and supplement the cash to more than 30%, gradually reducing the Beta to below 1.0. Consider smart rebalancing after the Beta is below 1.0.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Platform Interaction</strong>: Please subscribe, like, and leave comments on videos on various platforms.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">AI Development Fantasies and Impact 
    <div id="ai-development-fantasies-and-impact" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ai-development-fantasies-and-impact" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>AI Optimized Future</strong>:
<ul>
<li>Productivity greatly improved, most output is completed by AI (robots), and the cost of goods approaches zero.</li>
<li>Total social wealth accelerates, basic living needs (food, clothing, housing, transportation) may be free, uniformly supplied by the state/society (AI robots complete production, construction, and maintenance).</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Social Structure Changes</strong>:
<ul>
<li><strong>Classes Still Exist</strong>:
<ul>
<li><strong>Capitalists</strong>: Earn profits by investing in and holding the means of production (AI systems) without labor; the wealthiest. Everyone can become a capitalist (just need to know how to invest).</li>
<li><strong>High-Tech Workers</strong>: Personnel who maintain and manage AI systems, with excellent income, can enjoy entertainment beyond basic needs (such as space travel), but may fall into the &ldquo;cared-for&rdquo; class if they stop working and do not become capitalists.</li>
<li><strong>Cared-For Class (approximately 80%)</strong>: No need to work, basic life is guaranteed (food, clothing, housing, transportation, medical care), but cannot enjoy additional entertainment or resources. The standard of living may be similar to the current upper-middle class, but without work.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Philosophical Challenges</strong>:
<ul>
<li>When most people do not need to contribute for livelihood (&ldquo;nothing to serve&rdquo;), what is the meaning and purpose of life? (Analogous to being idle after retirement). May lead to widespread depression or social problems.</li>
<li>Human development may enter a stage of eternal life, facing greater philosophical and existential questions.</li>
<li>The focus should shift from &ldquo;unemployment&rdquo; to &ldquo;the meaning of life.&rdquo;</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Implications for Investors</strong>:
<ul>
<li>As capitalists, there is no need to worry about job loss due to AI development; on the contrary, they will become wealthier.</li>
<li>Start investing now to become part of the capitalist class.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">III. Q&amp;A Session 
    <div id="iii-qa-session" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii-qa-session" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Jacel 
    <div id="jacel" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#jacel" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question: SPY and QQQ have risen for three days, will they continue to rise or fall next week?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo; Response: Short-term market cannot be predicted, like flipping a coin. We invest for the long term (20+ years), focusing on long-term trends. Buy when you have money, never sell. Don&rsquo;t try to predict next week&rsquo;s market; ask the temple or the &ldquo;stock god&rdquo; in Clubhouse.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Sharing: Just started learning from the teacher&rsquo;s course two months ago, introduced by a friend in the United States. Currently in the learning stage, and has invested in some QQQ (cost between 515-530). After returning to Taiwan, considering investing in 00662. In the process of canceling previous insurance and converting individual stocks to 00662.</li>
<li>Question: Should I invest in US stocks (Firstrade account, worried about political risks in Taiwan for the child) or Taiwan stocks 00662? How to allocate at the beginning?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo; Response: Recommend investing in 00662 in Taiwan, no need to use a US broker (Firstrade). It&rsquo;s better for the child to rely on themselves rather than worry about politics. When starting to learn, it is recommended to divide the total funds into three parts: 1/3 buy 00662 immediately, 1/3 buy in batches over the next 3-6 months, and 1/3 hold in cash. The ultimate goal is 70% 00662 + 30% cash. Then slowly learn whether and how to allocate leveraged funds (adjust the Beta value to 0.8-0.9).</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Nibalao 
    <div id="nibalao" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#nibalao" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question 1: Who are QQQ and SPHD suitable for in terms of capital size?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo; Response: (Points out that students should watch the videos for repeated questions) This is a consideration for retirees. Need to calculate annual expenses after retirement. If 50 times the expenses equals your total assets, you can invest in QQQ (equivalent to a 2% annual withdrawal rate). If 2% is not enough, you need 3%, you may consider the S&amp;P 500. Only consider SPHD if you need even higher (~3.5-4%). Non-retirees should prioritize the high-growth QQQ.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2: Explain Beta value. Beta=1 is synchronized with the market? Beta=1.2 is 1.2 times the volatility? Is the Beta of an 80% QQQ + 20% SGOV portfolio 0.8?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo; Response: Basic understanding is correct. Beta measures the volatility of an asset relative to the market. The Beta of an 80/20 portfolio is approximately 0.8. (Reminds again that the videos explain it)</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 3: Will the principal of SGOV (Short-Term US Treasury ETF) fall and lose money?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo; Response: The principal risk is extremely low, almost no losses (except for minor fluctuations before and after dividend payments). SGOV invests in short-term Treasury bills (T-Bills) issued by the US Treasury Department with a maturity of 0-3 months (or within one year), backed by the credit of the United States.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Rui 
    <div id="rui" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#rui" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Joined for more than a month and reviewed the market decline in 2022 and the teacher&rsquo;s videos (especially #398 graduation episode, learned investment psychology).</li>
<li>Question 1: In January 2023 (#401), the teacher used technical indicators (50/100-day moving average crossover) to judge the market bottom and predict that 2023 would be a bull market, which was also verified afterwards. However, in later videos (#491), he emphasized not to predict market cycles and not to look at macroeconomic indicators (prosperity signals, macroeconomics, inventory cycles, etc.). Why this change? Are these indicators really useless in the long run? What was the basis for judging the bottom (just because of being optimistic about the stock market)? Should we just follow discipline and rebalance once a year?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo; Response: QQQ includes many industries (semiconductors, software, AI, biotechnology, retail such as Costco, Pepsico, Amazon, Google, Apple, etc.), and indicators for a single industry or country (such as Taiwan semiconductor economy, Taiwan prosperity signals, US prosperity signals) cannot reflect the overall index. Looking at all indicators is the same as looking at the index itself, so it is better to just focus on QQQ. The judgment in early 2023 was based on 40 years of experience (calculated that the 6-month moving average would cross upward), which is difficult to convey (&ldquo;unspeakable&rdquo;), and teaching technical analysis may cause students to misuse it and be harmed (&ldquo;go crazy&rdquo;), so it is not taught. Adhering to long-term investment discipline and holding enough cash buffer (such as 30%) is a more reliable method. Even if judging the bottom at that time, all cash would not be invested (such as still maintaining Beta 0.7), still maintaining a margin of safety. No need to take too much risk for small potential gains (referring to Buffett&rsquo;s philosophy).</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2: About the currency hedging of 00670L (Taiwan Leveraged QQQ ETF). Is the impact of exchange rate fluctuations significant in the long run? If the US dollar falls sharply (such as 1:13 against the Taiwan dollar), how will 00670L perform? (The teacher mentioned before that 00670L performs poorly when the US dollar rises)
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo; Response: 00670L is usually paired with 00865B (cash/short-term bonds). Exchange rate fluctuations have a hedging effect on both (when the US dollar rises, the hedging cost of 00670L increases, but the value of US dollar assets increases; the opposite is true when the US dollar falls). In the long run, exchange rate fluctuations are normal (such as the Taiwan dollar fluctuating between 28-32), but there is no fixed trend, and the expected value is zero. Currency hedging itself has a cost (wasting funds), which may not be necessary in the long run (it is recommended that fund companies consider canceling it), but the ETF is designed that way, and it does not hurt. The key is whether 00670L can achieve approximately twice the return of 00662 in the long run.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Mike 
    <div id="mike" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#mike" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Trump mentioned that 5.6 trillion in foreign investment may be invested in the United States in the future (may be exaggerated, even if halved, 2.8 trillion is also considerable), but the direction is beneficial to AI and QQQ. Observed that QQQ rebounded more strongly than SPY, DIA, and BRK recently, confirming the teacher&rsquo;s point of view (such as Katy Wood investing in AI-related companies when she saw mobile internet access). Compare the leadership styles of Chinese and American leaders (leader vs. manager) and the direction of attracting foreign investment (Saudi Arabia/Dubai vs. Myanmar/Vietnam/Malaysia).</li>
<li>Question: Please explain the difference between CIPS (Chinese RMB Cross-Border Payment System) and SWIFT. Why is CIPS faster (completed in 6 seconds)? Why does SWIFT take days? Can SWIFT be improved? Will this affect the status of the US dollar (AI replied that the two will coexist)?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo; Response: SWIFT is based on the traditional telegram transmission model (like a relay station), and information needs to be transferred through multiple layers (local bank -&gt; regional major bank -&gt; central bank -&gt; SWIFT center (Switzerland) -&gt; the other party&rsquo;s central bank -&gt; the other party&rsquo;s head office -&gt; the other party&rsquo;s branch), involving compliance checks (anti-money laundering), time difference, manual processing, etc., so it takes a long time (2+ days). CIPS is a modern real-time gross settlement system, similar to domestic payment systems in various countries, point-to-point or directly cleared through the central bank, and the speed is fast. CIPS uses RMB and is an alternative developed to deal with SWIFT being weaponized (such as sanctions against Russia), making people distrust the US dollar system. US sanctions opened a Pandora&rsquo;s box. Currently, CIPS is small (such as shipbuilding transactions between Malaysia and China), but it represents the trend of &ldquo;currency wars&rdquo; (such as Saudi Arabia and China being linked). Trump&rsquo;s visit to Saudi Arabia may be related to maintaining the status of the US dollar. Just watch the show.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Xiu 
    <div id="xiu" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#xiu" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question: Regarding the customized version of ChatGPT (CCTeams Investment Advisor) shared by the teacher, its knowledge cutoff date seems to be June of last year. Is the teacher using an updated version? Will the link change after the update? (Previously confused HXQ/HSQ).
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo; Response: Indeed, this AI is constantly being updated and trained. The link may change with updates. The latest link (showing content updated on April 26, such as 70/30 allocation recommendations) has been shared in the chat area. New links will be provided regularly (such as weekly or monthly) in the future. The teacher himself uses a more advanced personal &ldquo;Super AI&rdquo; account (possibly GPT-4o or higher, with memory function) to process and extract information, and then &ldquo;feeds&rdquo; the essence to this publicly shared GPTs version (similar to DIPS extraction). Feedback on AI answers is welcome for improvement.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Yao 
    <div id="yao" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#yao" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Because of recent trade tensions, I re-listened to the 2022 recordings. Two points are profound: 1. The biggest risk is missing the market (leaving the market). 2. Focus on long-term returns, not short-term fluctuations/shocks. The market is full of contradictory information (repeated presidential statements, pessimistic commentators) and bad news, but it often rebounds unintentionally. Friends who wait for a clear trend (such as buying after the big trend comes back) miss the rise. No one can accurately time the market. It is extremely difficult to obtain stable and high returns in the long term (such as an annualized return of 10% or more), like the sustained performance of top athletes (such as playing ball for 20 years); it is easy to have a good shot occasionally, but difficult to be stable in the long term. It is essential to stay in the market for a long time and focus on long-term growth.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo; Response: Strongly agree. Investing is like a long-distance race, continuing to stay in the front (such as 3rd or 4th place) will eventually win, because the leaders often make mistakes. This is how index funds are, not the best in a single year, but leading in the long term. Need an investment horizon of 15+ years. The key to persistence is having sufficient cash reserves (especially for retirees, it is recommended to have living expenses for 15+ years) or a continuous work income.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Monmon 
    <div id="monmon" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#monmon" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing 1: Started following the teacher last year, investing on my own and encouraging elders (sold insurance and invested). Recently, I have experienced a market decline and am at peace, but the elders are experiencing large fluctuations for the first time (they adopted a Beta 1.2 allocation). Through repeatedly watching videos and communicating, the elders&rsquo; confidence is still stable.</li>
<li>Sharing 2: Selling a house has been tortuous: difficulty communicating with my husband (disagreed at first, had disputes), cold market (the central bank fought housing speculation in September, difficult to get loans), price reduction (applied the teacher&rsquo;s concept of &ldquo;there is no house that cannot be sold, only a price that cannot be sold&rdquo;) to complete the sale (in February this year). The process was painful (communication, management, market changes, funds stuck, high taxes), and I learned a lesson that I don&rsquo;t want to experience again.</li>
<li>Sharing 3: Currently, half of the investment portfolio is QQQ-like, half is TSMC, and there is also a mortgage line of credit (financial mortgage). My husband wants to use this line of credit to increase positions when the market falls (TSMC?), but hesitates and is afraid in the middle of the actual fall (soft-handed, unable to do it). This decline allowed him to experience his true risk tolerance. My husband did not accept the full QQQ allocation before, but now he has some experience. It verifies the stability of the teacher&rsquo;s asset allocation method.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo; Response: Appreciate Monmon&rsquo;s peaceful state of mind (a good quality for investors, &ldquo;destiny&rdquo; + &ldquo;luck&rdquo; to meet the teacher). Communicating with family requires patience (it is a 15-30 year undertaking, no rush). The funds from the financial mortgage should be invested as soon as possible (such as 00662), buy blindly, and don&rsquo;t time the market. When investing, consider the overall asset allocation, include the loan amount in the total asset calculation, and ensure that the total Beta value is within the desired range (such as about 0.7, that is, maintaining an overall ratio of about 70/30), rather than investing all the borrowed money in high-risk assets. It is recommended to keep at least 30% cash (can be 4:1:5 or 5:1:4, Beta 0.6 or 0.7). This decline is a touchstone for risk tolerance, proving the necessity of conservative allocation. Even if young and have a job, 30% cash is also recommended.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">From Taiwan 
    <div id="from-taiwan" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#from-taiwan" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: The situation is similar to Monmon&rsquo;s. Both myself and the elders invested in 00662/00670L, using Beta 1.2 (4:4:2, that is, 40% 00662, 40% 00670L, 20% cash/00865B) allocation. I can bear the recent fluctuations (the government is quite amazing), but I am not sure whether the elders (who have not watched YouTube, have no financial common sense, but believe and invest) can bear greater future declines (such as 40-80%). Continuously accompany the elders and give them confidence. The elders have a good mentality so far.</li>
<li>Question: If I want to reduce the Beta for the elders, when and how should I operate?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo; Response: It is generally recommended now that the Beta should not exceed 1.0 (such as 70/30). For an existing allocation of 1.2, it is recommended to evaluate it at the end of each year: if the market rises (such as 00662 returning to the level at the beginning of the year or higher), you can sell part of the leveraged position (00670L) and transfer the funds to cash (00865B), so that the cash ratio is adjusted to 30% or higher. If the market is down at the end of the year, then do not move. The goal is to gradually reduce the Beta to below 1.0. Before that, there is no need to consider complicated rebalancing strategies. Don&rsquo;t operate too frequently (once a year) to avoid increasing the elders&rsquo; anxiety (they may secretly look at the APP).</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Lucy 
    <div id="lucy" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#lucy" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question 1: Investing in QQQ in Canada, the teacher recommends QQC, etc., and mentions avoiding Hedged funds? It seems that most Canadian versions are Hedged? Which one should I choose? (Previously confused HXQ/HSQ).
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo; Response: Recommend HXQ.t because it does not pay dividends, making tax treatment simpler. If you already hold QQC.to or ZQQ, there is no need to sell it, and new investments can be bought in HXQ.t. It is also acceptable if only Hedged versions are available locally.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2: Please explain the asset allocation ratio (such as 70/30, 4:4:2). Time is limited (working, back problems requiring exercise, blood sugar problems), it is difficult to find specific content in videos, and listening to Clubhouse is also time-consuming.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo; Response: (Emphasizing the importance of learning, earning money from work only accounts for a small part of a lifetime of wealth, so you should spend time learning about investment) For ordinary investors working in Canada, the simplest allocation is: 70% HXQ.t + 30% cash/money market fund (Money Market). Check and adjust annually (sell the ones that have risen more to supplement cash, or use cash to buy the ones that have fallen more) to maintain this ratio.</li>
<li>(Nibalao Supplement): Canadian local stock dividends have tax advantages, while US-sourced dividends (such as QQC) are taxed (I don&rsquo;t know how much, but higher than Canadian stock taxes). I agree with the teacher&rsquo;s point of view: focus on investment returns is higher than focusing on work.</li>
<li>James&rsquo; Response: Reiterating the advantage of HXQ.t not paying dividends. Canadian funds seem to be performing well, possibly because better compounding due to not paying dividends.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Sharing (Follow-up): Listening to the teacher&rsquo;s criticism is very comfortable and helpful. I am impatient, but after listening to the teacher&rsquo;s patient answers to &ldquo;stupid questions,&rdquo; I am more patient in helping others.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo; Response: Asking questions bravely is important.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Jason 
    <div id="jason" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#jason" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Detailed comparison of the advantages and disadvantages of Bitcoin/cryptocurrencies and QQQ, based on his personal experience in the blockchain industry (entered the industry in 2017, experienced the blockchain/cryptocurrency community, ICO explosion, 2018 bear market):
<ul>
<li>Storage Security: BTC requires self-management of private keys/hardware wallets (cold wallets), which are easy to lose or damage, high risk; QQQ is托管ed by brokers, which is safe.</li>
<li>Transaction Security: BTC is vulnerable to hacker attacks, phishing, and platform crashes; QQQ is protected by regulations.</li>
<li>Staking/Liquidity: BTC lacks standardized and safe staking channels (DeFi is high risk); QQQ can be easily staked and borrowed (pledged) through brokers without selling.</li>
<li>Taxes: Selling BTC requires capital gains tax; holding QQQ for a long time and using pledges can avoid/defer taxes.</li>
<li>Legality: BTC has legal risks in China (trading and mining are illegal), and cashing out may be frozen; QQQ (and QDII 513100/513300) are legal and compliant.</li>
<li>Volatility/Risk: BTC is extremely volatile (short-term drops of 50-80% are common, such as an 85% drop in 2018), and ordinary people cannot withstand the mental stress; QQQ has a much lower frequency of large fluctuations.</li>
<li>Liquidity: The actual circulating volume of BTC is limited (locked by large holders, lost coins), which is not as high as the global liquidity of QQQ.</li>
<li>Practicality: Not detailed.</li>
<li>Future Returns: BTC has a high market value (nearly 2 trillion US dollars, comparable to top technology companies), and the possibility of super high multiple growth in the future is reduced (even if it rises to 200,000 US dollars/coin, it is only 2-3 times), and the rate of return may tend to be stable, lower than QQQ.</li>
<li>Conclusion: Cryptocurrencies are &ldquo;demons and ghosts,&rdquo; not suitable for ordinary investors, highly tempting but extremely risky.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>James&rsquo; Comment: Completely agree, cryptocurrencies should not be touched. Shared cases of others losing huge amounts of Bitcoin (equivalent to 15 million US dollars) due to unfamiliarity with cross-chain transfer rules (such as transferring between different chains or exchanges that do not support the target chain), emphasizing its complexity and risk (may be a technical problem or fraud).</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Responding to Chat Room Questions 
    <div id="responding-to-chat-room-questions" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#responding-to-chat-room-questions" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>File Access</strong>: In areas with limited Google service, you can download the files and open them with local software (such as Excel).</li>
<li><strong>00864B Taxes</strong>: According to Angela&rsquo;s feedback, it is overseas income, which is tax-free if it is less than 1 million Taiwan dollars (or other high limit such as 7.5 million) per year, and is exempt from the second-generation supplementary health insurance premium. The main problem becomes the trouble of manual reinvestment. You need a principal of 25 million to possibly exceed 1 million in interest.</li>
<li><strong>AI Link</strong>: Confirmed that the latest link has been provided.</li>
<li><strong>Buying QQQ in China</strong>: Through QDII funds, such as 513100, 513300. See page 10 of the lecture notes.</li>
<li><strong>Conflicting Ideas Between Spouses</strong>: Patience, use your own controllable funds to set an example. Sometimes even if you prove it, the other person does not recognize it (&ldquo;past performance does not represent the future&rdquo;), it depends on fate (destiny).</li>
<li><strong>Technical Analysis/Prediction</strong>: The teacher does not make predictions (when will it bottom out, will there be a recession or crash).</li>
<li><strong>Robert Kiyosaki</strong>: The teacher is critical of him (&ldquo;he will go bankrupt&rdquo;).</li>
<li><strong>Trump Policy</strong>: No need to pay attention, high uncertainty, just &ldquo;drizzle,&rdquo; impossible to have zero income tax. In the long run, US taxes may increase to deal with the deficit. Do not make decisions based on unconfirmed conclusions.</li>
<li><strong>Mean Reversion</strong>: There is no simple mean reversion in the stock market. The growth of high-tech companies (such as TSMC) will not revert to traditional industries (such as China Steel, Formosa Plastics). Those who think it will revert are &ldquo;bookworms.&rdquo; Value stocks (such as Starbucks, McDonald&rsquo;s) also perform differently.</li>
<li><strong>442 Allocation</strong>: Not recommended for office workers, it is too risky. Those who have already used it should handle it according to the MM case.</li>
<li><strong>Investment vs Speculation</strong>: The teacher does not agree with the statement that &ldquo;all investments are speculation.&rdquo;</li>
<li><strong>12-Year Certificates of Deposit vs Compounding</strong>: 00865B/VOO etc. are compounded.</li>
<li><strong>AI Asset Allocation Advice</strong>: May be &ldquo;incorrect&rdquo; due to questioning methods or AI model understanding deviations.</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">IV. Highlights 
    <div id="iv-highlights" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv-highlights" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>The market is always fluctuating, the constant in the market is fluctuation, so fluctuation is certain to happen in the market, so you don&rsquo;t need to analyze where the fluctuation comes from&hellip; You see everyone talking so eloquently, in fact, he doesn&rsquo;t even know what he is talking about&hellip;
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>Context: James emphasized the normality and unpredictability of market fluctuations, advising investors not to waste time analyzing the causes of short-term fluctuations.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Investment is buying with the intention of never selling, this is investment. Buying with the intention of selling at a high point is called speculation.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>Context: James clearly distinguished the core criteria of investment and speculation: whether the purpose is to hold for the long term.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Making a decision about all investment and financial life is very simple, which is long-term, simple and effective&hellip; Convenience is a value. No trouble is a value.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>Context: When comparing 00864B and 00865B, James emphasized that choosing an investment method that is simpler and less troublesome in the long run has value in itself.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>You don&rsquo;t need to risk the money you need for the money you don&rsquo;t need.
&ndash; James (quoting/paraphrasing Buffett&rsquo;s idea)</p></blockquote>
<p>Context: Explained why even if it is judged that the market may rise, you should keep enough cash buffer (the money you need) and should not take too much risk for additional, potentially unnecessary returns (the money you don&rsquo;t need).</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Later you will find that when humans develop to the extreme, food, clothing, housing, and transportation are all free, all free&hellip; Then what does it mean to be alive?&hellip; But what is the meaning of a dog? This may be the question that the last 80% of people have to think about.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>Context: When fantasizing about the future when AI is extremely developed, James raised the question of the profound crisis of existential meaning that humans (especially the majority who do not need to work) will face after material needs are completely satisfied.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The biggest risk comes from [missing] the market&hellip; Focus on long-term returns, not this short-term [fluctuation].
&ndash; Yao</p></blockquote>
<p>Context: Sharing the profound experience after reviewing the teacher&rsquo;s teachings when the market information is chaotic, emphasizing the importance of being in the market for a long time and focusing on long-term goals.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>We don&rsquo;t want to be the first every time, we only want to be the third or fourth every time&hellip; Over the long term, we will be the first.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>Context: Using the analogy of racing to explain the logic of index investing: not pursuing short-term leadership, relying on continuous and steady performance, and ultimately winning in the long cycle.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>There is no house that cannot be sold, only a price that cannot be sold.
&ndash; Monmon</p></blockquote>
<p>Context: Sharing the experience of selling a house, mentioning that applying this point of view ultimately successfully sold the property.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>You should put your focus on investing, and the return is definitely much higher than if you put your focus on working.
&ndash; Nibalao</p></blockquote>
<p>Context: When discussing that students do not have time to learn about investment, this student emphasized that based on their own experience, the long-term return of putting energy into investment learning far exceeds that of putting it into work itself.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>[Cryptocurrencies] are one of the demons and ghosts&hellip; The future return of Bitcoin may tend to be stable, and the teacher also mentioned this issue before.
&ndash; Jason</p></blockquote>
<p>Context: Based on industry experience and risk analysis, the student qualified cryptocurrencies as a high-risk category unsuitable for ordinary investors, and pointed out that its future return may not be as good as index funds.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">V. Summary 
    <div id="v-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#v-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This Clubhouse episode was rich and insightful, ranging from the macro market philosophy (fluctuation is normal, long-term perspective, optimistic mentality), AI&rsquo;s disruptive vision of the future (productivity, social structure, meaning of life), to the micro investment practice (ETF selection such as 00865B vs 00864B, Canadian HXQ.t, asset allocation principles such as 70/30, Beta management, risk awareness), all detailed explanations and discussions were provided. The core information is still focused on: adhering to long-term holding of high-quality index funds (especially the Nasdaq 100), understanding and accepting market fluctuations, maintaining rationality and patience, using time compounding, and conducting sound asset allocation according to personal risk tolerance (emphasizing the importance of at least 30% cash), and being vigilant about market noise and high-risk speculative products (such as cryptocurrencies). The Q&amp;A session answered in detail the specific questions encountered by students in different countries, different stages, and different product selections, and emphasized the importance of continuous learning of investment knowledge. Finally, it was reminded again that the Clubhouse will be suspended for the next two weeks.</p>

  



<div
  
    class="flex px-4 py-3 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900"
  >

  <span
    
      class="text-primary-400 ltr:pr-3 rtl:pl-3 flex items-center"
    >

    

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M506.3 417l-213.3-364c-16.33-28-57.54-28-73.98 0l-213.2 364C-10.59 444.9 9.849 480 42.74 480h426.6C502.1 480 522.6 445 506.3 417zM232 168c0-13.25 10.75-24 24-24S280 154.8 280 168v128c0 13.25-10.75 24-23.1 24S232 309.3 232 296V168zM256 416c-17.36 0-31.44-14.08-31.44-31.44c0-17.36 14.07-31.44 31.44-31.44s31.44 14.08 31.44 31.44C287.4 401.9 273.4 416 256 416z"/></svg>

  </span>


  </span>

  <span
    
      class="dark:text-neutral-300"
    ><strong>Disclaimer:</strong> This article is only a personal learning note and does not constitute any investment advice.</span>
</div>

]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>00499 Future Wealth Planning: Capital Allocation in the Age of AI. Cash, QQQ, and QLD: Three Steps to Optimal Asset Allocation</title>
      <link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1737246178555/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1737246178555/</guid>
      <description>This episode introduces and discusses the relationship between investing in US dollars and US stocks, the concept of long-term investing, asset balancing methods, and shares the impact of AI development on future work and retirement. It also emphasizes the importance of learning and cognition, asset allocation and balancing, and answers related questions.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<lite-youtube videoid="YOTy3Tveq74" playlabel="YOTy3Tveq74" params=""></lite-youtube>



<h2 class="relative group">I. Episode Theme 
    <div id="i-episode-theme" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-episode-theme" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>The main theme of this episode is that <strong>investing in US indices means holding US assets, not holding US dollars.</strong> The discussion revolves around the <strong>US balance sheet, the relationship between the US dollar and US stocks</strong>, and deeply explores <strong>the philosophy of long-term investment and methods of asset allocation</strong>. In addition, it shares the impact of <strong>AI development on future work, social structures, retirement planning, and national competition</strong>, emphasizing the importance of <strong>learning and cognition, and asset allocation and balance</strong>.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">II. Briefing Contents 
    <div id="ii-briefing-contents" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii-briefing-contents" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Market Volatility and Long-Term Investing 
    <div id="market-volatility-and-long-term-investing" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#market-volatility-and-long-term-investing" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Market Volatility Is Irrelevant to Long-Term Investors</strong>: Short-term market fluctuations are normal. Long-term investors should adhere to the principle of &ldquo;buy when you have money, hold long term, and never sell,&rdquo; and not be swayed by market sentiment. Utilize the power of compound interest to hold quality assets for the long term. For example, even if the market experiences a significant pullback, as long as you hold a Nasdaq 100 index fund for the long term, you will ultimately achieve substantial returns.</li>
<li><strong>Disclaimer</strong>: The COEC Investment and Finance Channel is a non-profit channel aimed at sharing investment experiences and philosophies. All content is for reference only and does not constitute any investment advice. Advertisements on YouTube are not initiated by the channel. Please be wary of any investment schemes online that claim to guarantee returns, especially those using celebrity endorsements or AI-synthesized voiceovers; many are scams. COEC does not charge anyone a fee nor does it recommend any paid investment services.</li>
<li><strong>Investment Risk Warning</strong>: Investing involves risk, and the stock market is highly volatile. Investors should be fully aware of investment risks. For example, investing in stock index funds such as QQQ may face a short-term loss of 50% or even more of their market value.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Learning and Cognition 
    <div id="learning-and-cognition" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#learning-and-cognition" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Investing Requires Continuous Learning</strong>: James emphasizes the importance of learning and encourages everyone to watch the value investing lecture series videos, recommending episodes 00451, 00398, and 00288. There are also condensed short films in the playlist to help everyone quickly grasp the core content and to share with friends and family. Only through continuous learning can we enhance our investment knowledge and judgment.</li>
<li><strong>Q&amp;A Only Refines Your Existing Knowledge, Not Establishes It</strong>: This means that the Q&amp;A session can only help you further understand what you have already learned, but cannot replace systematic study. For example, concerning how to specifically implement the 433 asset allocation strategy, you need to first watch relevant videos for a systematic understanding.</li>
<li><strong>Nasdaq 100 Index Funds</strong>: James recommends long-term investment in Nasdaq 100 index funds (such as QQQ and TQQQ) and provides a list of Nasdaq 100 index fund options around the world for investors in different regions to reference.</li>
<li><strong>Investor Optimism</strong>: Despite market fluctuations and uncertainties, investors should maintain an extremely optimistic mindset. Market declines should be seen as opportunities to buy quality assets at lower prices. In the long run, the economy and the stock market will always trend upwards.</li>
<li><strong>Wealth Growth Requires Time</strong>: Investing is a long-term process. Wealth growth needs time to realize the effects of compound interest. For example, by investing in a Nasdaq 100 index fund for the long term, waiting for ten or twenty years, assets could potentially grow to a scale of hundreds of millions.</li>
<li><strong>Advantages of Long-Term Investing</strong>:
<ul>
<li><strong>Compound Interest Effect</strong>: Long-term investing can fully utilize the effects of compound interest, achieving exponential growth of wealth.</li>
<li><strong>Avoid Emotional Trading</strong>: Long-term investing can avoid making poor investment decisions due to short-term market fluctuations.</li>
<li><strong>Reduce Transaction Costs</strong>: Long-term investing can reduce the frequency of trading, thereby lowering transaction costs.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Relationship Between US Dollar and US Stocks 
    <div id="relationship-between-us-dollar-and-us-stocks" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#relationship-between-us-dollar-and-us-stocks" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Analysis of the US Balance Sheet</strong>:
<ul>
<li><strong>Detailed Data</strong>: James provided detailed US balance sheet data, including:
<ul>
<li><strong>Total US Government and Private Borrowing</strong>: This refers to the total domestic debt of all forms in the United States.</li>
<li><strong>Total Assets</strong>: $202 trillion, representing the total value of all US assets.</li>
<li><strong>Deficit</strong>: $36 trillion, referring to the US government&rsquo;s fiscal deficit.</li>
<li><strong>Total Liabilities</strong>: $101 trillion, including the total debt of the government and the public, which is actually the amount of US currency issued.</li>
<li><strong>GDP</strong>: $28.57 trillion, representing the total value of all goods and services produced within the US in one year.</li>
<li><strong>Federal Tax Revenue</strong>: $12 trillion, referring to the US federal government&rsquo;s tax revenue.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Income Estimation</strong>: Based on an average tax rate of 15%, it is estimated that the total income of US individuals and companies is about $80 trillion. James pointed out that because corporate tax rates are usually higher than 20%, this estimate may actually underestimate the actual income of the US, and the real number might be close to $100 trillion.</li>
<li><strong>Debt-to-Income Ratio</strong>: By comparing total liabilities to income, the US debt-to-income ratio was calculated and compared with individual debt-to-income ratios, explaining that the US balance sheet is very healthy and will not experience a debt crisis or bankruptcy as some people fear.</li>
<li><strong>Example</strong>: The US was compared to an individual with $202 million worth of real estate, owing $100 million, and with an annual income of $80 million, illustrating that its financial situation is very healthy. In comparison, many people have an income far less than $80 million but carry huge mortgage debts, and their personal financial situation is much worse than that of the US.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Relationship Between the US Dollar and US Stocks</strong>:
<ul>
<li><strong>Holding Assets, Not Currency</strong>: Investing in US index funds is actually holding a portfolio of assets composed of excellent US companies, rather than holding the US dollar as a currency.</li>
<li><strong>Impact of US Dollar Depreciation</strong>: Even if the US dollar depreciates, as long as the assets held (such as stocks) have value, the price of assets denominated in US dollars will rise.</li>
<li><strong>The US Dollar Is Just a Unit of Account</strong>: The US dollar is only a unit for measuring asset value and can be exchanged for assets using any other form of currency or valuable item. For example, real estate can be used to exchange for Apple shares or QQQ assets, without needing to go through the US dollar.</li>
<li><strong>US Dollar Credit Backing</strong>: The US dollar, as a fiat currency, is backed by national credit. The US government can repay its debt by taxing companies and individuals. Therefore, as long as US companies and individuals can continue to generate income, the US can repay its debts, and the US dollar will not collapse.</li>
<li><strong>Borrowing Strategy</strong>: Since the US dollar may depreciate, it is advisable to borrow as much US dollars as possible to invest or consume. In the future, debt can be repaid using depreciated US dollars.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Refuting the Bankruptcy Theory</strong>:
<ul>
<li>Cited data and facts to refute the view that &ldquo;excessive US debt will lead to bankruptcy.&rdquo;</li>
<li>Emphasized that the US has vast assets and a continuous source of income, which is enough to repay its debts.</li>
<li>Pointed out that those who spread such statements may have ulterior motives, and investors should think independently and not blindly believe them.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Long-Term Holding of Quality Assets</strong>:
<ul>
<li>Emphasized the importance of long-term holding of high-quality US assets (such as the Nasdaq 100 index fund).</li>
<li>Even if the US dollar depreciates, the value of quality assets will continue to grow.</li>
<li>Example: If QQQ is currently $500, after a large US dollar depreciation, QQQ may rise to $10,000 because it represents the assets of 100 excellent US technology companies.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>No Need to Worry About the US Dollar</strong>:
<ul>
<li>Investors should focus on the value of the assets themselves, rather than fluctuations in the US dollar.</li>
<li>US dollar depreciation is actually a good thing for investors holding quality assets because they can buy the same assets with fewer US dollars.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Asset Allocation and Balance 
    <div id="asset-allocation-and-balance" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#asset-allocation-and-balance" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>433 Asset Allocation</strong>:
<ul>
<li><strong>Definition</strong>: The 433 asset allocation is an investment strategy that allocates 40% of total assets to QQQ (Nasdaq 100 index fund), 30% to TQQQ (3x leveraged Nasdaq 100 index fund), and 30% to cash or money market funds.</li>
<li><strong>Purpose</strong>: By allocating assets with different risk levels, balance risk and return.</li>
<li><strong>Operation</strong>: Conduct &ldquo;smart rebalancing&rdquo; according to market conditions, that is, when the market rises, transfer some of the profits from TQQQ to cash; when the market falls, transfer cash to TQQQ.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Smart Rebalancing</strong>:
<ul>
<li><strong>Mechanism</strong>:
<ul>
<li><strong>When the market rises</strong>: Convert some of the profits (usually 30%) from leveraged funds (such as TQQQ) into cash.</li>
<li><strong>When the market falls</strong>: Convert cash into leveraged funds in a certain proportion (usually 20% of the cash portion).</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Effects</strong>:
<ul>
<li><strong>At market highs</strong>: The cash level is high, reducing the risk of a high-level pullback.</li>
<li><strong>At market lows</strong>: The cash level is low, allowing for buying more assets at lower prices, thus achieving greater returns when the market rebounds.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Auto-Pilot</strong>: The smart rebalancing mechanism can automatically adjust asset allocation according to market conditions without manual intervention.</li>
<li><strong>Examples</strong>: The internet bubble in 2000 and the financial crisis in 2008 were used to illustrate how the 433 asset allocation and smart rebalancing mechanism protect investors&rsquo; assets during significant market volatility.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Necessity of Long-Term Investment</strong>: Citing Howard Marks&rsquo;s views, it is explained that predicting short-term market trends is almost impossible, and frequent trading will only increase costs and risks. For ordinary investors, holding passive funds (such as QQQ) for the long term is a wiser choice.</li>
<li><strong>Avoid Frequent Trading</strong>: Combining data on the losses of Taiwanese day traders, the risks and harms of short-term trading are explained.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Other 
    <div id="other" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#other" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Essence of the Financial Industry</strong>: The goal of the financial industry is to maximize its own interests and may &ldquo;empty&rdquo; investors&rsquo; pockets through various means. Investors must improve their financial literacy to recognize and resist the traps and temptations of the financial industry. For example, long-term bond products may appear stable in name, but still have the potential to lose 30% or more.</li>
<li><strong>Information Filter Bubble Effect</strong>: The development of the internet and social media makes it easier for people to access information that matches their own views, thus forming information filter bubbles and making it difficult to hear different opinions. This leads to biases in people&rsquo;s understanding of the world and even conflicting emotions.</li>
<li><strong>Australian 2x Leveraged Fund GNDQ</strong>: Introduced an Australian market 2x leveraged fund called GNDQ, for Australian investors to reference.</li>
<li><strong>International Situation and Investment</strong>: Although we may know nothing about the international situation, this does not affect our long-term investments. The important thing is to choose the right investment targets and stick to them for the long term.</li>
<li><strong>Allocation Strategies for Roth IRA and Traditional IRA</strong>: It is recommended to invest all the funds in Roth IRA in TQQQ to maximize tax-free returns. Traditional IRA can allocate a portion to cash and a portion to QQQ, with the specific ratio depending on individual circumstances.</li>
<li><strong>Risks of Labor and Real Estate</strong>: Labor is facing the risk of unemployment, especially with the rapid development of artificial intelligence. Real estate also has risks, such as natural disasters and market volatility.</li>
<li><strong>Impact of AI on the Future</strong>: The development of AI will have a huge impact on the job market, with a large number of jobs being replaced by AI. In the future, society may only be left with a small number of capitalists and people who can control AI, while others may become &ldquo;useless&rdquo; laborers. Therefore, one should no longer learn coding but should use AI to serve oneself.</li>
<li><strong>Predictions on Future High-Tech Returns</strong>: Some finance professionals predict that future high-tech returns will decrease. James refuted this view, believing that these predictions are baseless and pointed out that the investment performance of these predictors is also poor.</li>
<li><strong>Encourage Learning and Sharing</strong>: Encourage everyone to watch the short films of the investment lectures and share them with more people to help them build correct investment philosophies.</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">III. Q&amp;A Session 
    <div id="iii-qa-session" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii-qa-session" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Cat 
    <div id="cat" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#cat" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing</strong>:
<ol>
<li>The annualized return rate of long-term investment does not mean that fixed returns can be obtained every year. If the investment period is too short, the desired results may not be achieved due to market fluctuations. She cited a chart from a book called &ldquo;The Long View,&rdquo; which shows the highest and lowest returns for different investment periods. For example, investing for one year, the highest return might be 66%, but it could also result in a loss of 38%; investing for two years, the highest return is 39.4%, but it could also lead to a loss of 31.7%; investing for five years, the highest return is 27.3%, but it could also result in a loss of 11.9%. Only when the investment period is more than 20 years is it possible to obtain a return ranging from a minimum of 6% to a maximum of 17%. In summary, the longer the investment period, the more the return rate tends to approach the long-term average.</li>
</ol>
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Comment</strong>: The longer the investment period, the closer the return is to the average. For example, if you invest for 25 years, the return will increasingly approach 10%. This explains the significance of the 433 asset allocation: short-term cash needs can be met with the cash position, while long-term investment is not affected. For example, if an investment portfolio has 10 million in long-term investments and 1 million for school tuition, the 1 million can be combined with the 10 million for 433 allocation. This would mean 300,000 in cash, and even if the market declines, the 300,000 cash can cover tuition needs. It was also emphasized that stock pledging can further reduce risk, because low-interest funds can be borrowed to meet emergency needs.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Four Five 
    <div id="four-five" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#four-five" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Question 1</strong>: The company&rsquo;s 401K plan can deposit 30% of income, which is far more than the IRS limit. The extra funds are put into an after-tax account. If the principal of this part is transferred to Roth IRA, and the appreciated part is transferred to Regular IRA, are there any tax issues with such operations?
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response</strong>: The after-tax 401K plan you mentioned is actually a tax-deferred account, which allows investors to put their after-tax income into it and conduct tax-free trading, but still have to pay taxes when finally withdrawn. For short-term operators, this type of account can avoid tax liabilities caused by frequent trading. However, for long-term investors like us, we do not make frequent buying and selling transactions, so this type of account does not have much appeal to us. The disadvantage of participating in this plan is that it actually increases the size of your Traditional IRA, and we generally advise against having too large a Traditional IRA because you will have to pay income tax when you withdraw in the future. Therefore, I do not recommend that you continue to participate and put money into this after-tax 401K plan.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question 2</strong>: I am 60 years old, and my current asset allocation is 70% of my money in Traditional IRA, 10% in Roth IRA, and 15% in Regular IRA. How should I allocate my assets?
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response</strong>: Given that your Roth IRA ratio is low, it is recommended to invest all the funds in your Roth IRA into TQQQ (3x leveraged Nasdaq 100 index fund) to maximize its potential for tax-free growth. For your Traditional IRA, it is recommended to allocate 20% to cash and 80% to QQQ (Nasdaq 100 index fund). This will make your overall asset allocation closer to the target of 433 (40% QQQ, 30% TQQQ, 30% cash).</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question 3</strong>: I am already using asset-backed loans, borrowing about 1% of the funds each year for use. According to the asset allocation ratio recommended by the teacher, my current cash ratio is insufficient. What should I do?
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response</strong>: In this case, you don&rsquo;t need to specifically increase your cash ratio. You only need to allocate 20% of the cash in your Traditional IRA and the remaining 80% to QQQ, and all the money in your Roth IRA to TQQQ. Use asset-backed loans to meet your daily expenses and tax payments, so that you do not need to use your investment principal. Continue to maintain the annual borrowing and use the loan to cover some expenses, so that your investment portfolio can continue to grow.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Ling 
    <div id="ling" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ling" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing 1</strong>: The US government has a very complete retirement plan. In contrast, Taiwan has a big gap in guaranteeing its people&rsquo;s retirement. Taiwan&rsquo;s labor insurance retirement account requires employers to set aside 6% of employees&rsquo; salaries in accordance with the law, and employees can choose to self-allocate 0% to 6% of their salaries. When Ling first started working, there was only the 6% set aside by the employer. Later, following the advice of colleagues, she chose to self-allocate 6% to increase retirement savings and deduct income tax.
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Comment</strong>: There is no need to participate, because Taiwan&rsquo;s securities accounts are tax-free.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Sharing 2</strong>: After listening to James&rsquo;s concept of investing in QQQ in November last year, Ling decided to change the self-allocated portion to 0% and use all the funds for investing in QQQ. In addition, Ling&rsquo;s company provides two options, &ldquo;employee stock trust&rdquo; and &ldquo;employee savings trust,&rdquo; aimed at helping employees increase retirement funds. Previously, she did not know enough and chose the &ldquo;employee stock trust&rdquo; investing in company stocks, but the return in the past six years was only about 38%. If she had followed James&rsquo;s QQQ investment philosophy, the performance might be higher. Therefore, she has recently made adjustments and has chosen the &ldquo;employee savings trust&rdquo; starting this year. However, the investment targets of this &ldquo;employee savings trust&rdquo; are limited and cannot be directly invested in QQQ. Only funds can be chosen. Currently, Ling plans to invest the company&rsquo;s portion in US technology funds and the self-allocated portion in Taiwan stock funds. Although the monthly investment amount is not large, Ling believes it still needs to be further optimized.
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Comment</strong>: Taiwan&rsquo;s securities accounts are tax-free, which is equivalent to the US Roth IRA, and there is no contribution limit, which is a very big advantage. Therefore, Taiwanese investors can directly use their own securities accounts for investments, especially in index funds such as QQQ, and do not need to participate in any retirement plans of the government or companies. These plans often have various restrictions, and the performance may not be good either. Taiwanese investors should take full advantage of this and invest funds directly into their securities accounts to enjoy tax-free investment income.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Sharing 3</strong>: Since November last year, Ling has watched all of James&rsquo;s videos before 2024 and continues to learn from the following videos. Ling compares investing in QQQ to a &ldquo;big pool.&rdquo; As soon as funds become available, she immediately puts them in, and regards it as her &ldquo;real estate.&rdquo; This &ldquo;big pool&rdquo; will continue to grow over time and is safer than traditional real estate. There is no need to worry about risks such as earthquakes, windstorms, or floods. When money is needed, she borrows through asset pledging to obtain funds instead of selling assets.
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Comment</strong>: Taiwan&rsquo;s financial environment is very friendly. In addition to tax-free securities accounts, the interest on asset-backed loans is also very low, which is an advantage that other regions cannot compare. Taiwanese investors should take full advantage of these &ldquo;free bullets&rdquo; and &ldquo;sophisticated weapons,&rdquo; do a good job in asset allocation, and the future wealth growth potential is huge. Regarding pledging, there is no need to wait until assets reach 10 million TWD to start. It can be decided based on your own circumstances and knowledge of assets. Even with only 2 million TWD of assets, you can try pledging to borrow a small amount of money each year (for example, 40,000 TWD) for use. As experience accumulates and assets grow, the borrowing amount can gradually be increased.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Warm Heart 
    <div id="warm-heart" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#warm-heart" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing 1</strong>: He began learning James&rsquo;s investment courses in 2022 and created an investment discussion group on Line in Taiwan in 2023. He emphasized that this group is self-organized, has no affiliation with the CLEC official, and has not received authorization or any form of assistance from James. The original intention of creating this group was to find more like-minded people to discuss investments, especially about 00662 (Yuanta Baoshu Shenzhen) and James&rsquo;s investment philosophy. Currently, this group has developed into a learning community of more than 500 people.</li>
<li><strong>Sharing 2</strong>: He mentioned that he is also facing a situation where his family does not understand his investment methods. For example, his father would question why he doesn&rsquo;t sell at high points but chooses to hold for the long term. In order to make his family better understand his investment philosophy, he invited his family to join the Line group he created, hoping that through the discussions within the group, his family could understand the advantages and value of long-term investment and reduce their concerns.</li>
<li><strong>Sharing 3</strong>: He particularly thanked several core members of the group, including Brother Chen, Mark, Chris, and QQM, for their contributions to the group&rsquo;s development.</li>
<li><strong>Sharing 4</strong>: He revealed that Brother Chen in the group will be sharing his experiences from 2 PM to 7 PM tomorrow (January 19th) and provided a link for everyone to participate.
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Comment</strong>: James expressed support and encouragement for this kind of self-organized learning community, believing that this form can help more people learn and spread the correct investment philosophy. He also emphasized that he himself does not privately provide any special resources or guidance to anyone or any group. All sharing will be done on public platforms to ensure transparency and fairness of information. He also reminded everyone that although these self-organized groups are usually made with good intentions, they should be vigilant and pay attention to potential risks. He himself and CLEC will not be responsible for the operation and management of these groups.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Mike 
    <div id="mike" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#mike" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing</strong>: He went hiking with a friend, who is also a member of CLEC. The two talked about the recent layoffs at Google due to AI development. This triggered their thinking about the future development of AI, especially whether AI will threaten humans due to its own &ldquo;rationality,&rdquo; for example, whether AI will deliberately leave bugs in its programs to avoid being shut down by humans.</li>
<li><strong>Question</strong>: What is the future development direction of AI? What impact will it have on human work? In particular, will AI develop self-awareness and threaten humans?
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response</strong>: The development of AI will have a huge impact on the job market. In the future, most people will face the risk of unemployment, and only a few capitalists and those who can control AI will be able to survive. Therefore, everyone should start learning and mastering AI tools now, and use them as assistants to improve work efficiency. At the same time, every country should pay attention to the development of AI, especially a comprehensive AI strategy. Currently, the United States and China are at the forefront in this area, while Europe and Taiwan are relatively lagging behind. If Taiwan wants to remain competitive in the AI era, it needs to significantly increase the salary levels of engineers and increase the TWD exchange rate to attract top talent from around the world. As for whether AI will develop self-awareness and threaten humans, this is indeed a concern. In the future, there may be a confrontation between &ldquo;righteous AI&rdquo; and &ldquo;villainous AI,&rdquo; just like in the movie &ldquo;The Matrix.&rdquo; This is also one of the reasons why Elon Musk is committed to developing more powerful AI and trying to guide it toward goodness.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question</strong>: How does James view the practice of restricting certain countries from accessing certain advanced technologies (such as AI)? Is this a form of discrimination?
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response</strong>: This is a complex issue that can be discussed publicly, but it is necessary to avoid political stances and remain objective and rational. Efforts should be made to make information public and transparent.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question</strong>: What is China&rsquo;s current asset situation? In addition, what impact does AI have on the stock markets of various countries?
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response</strong>: Every country has its own problems. China&rsquo;s data is not completely transparent, and it is difficult to obtain accurate information. Currently, AI has the most significant impact on the stock markets of the United States and Taiwan, while other countries are relatively less affected.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Jenny 
    <div id="jenny" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#jenny" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Question 1</strong>: James previously suggested keeping cash in an IRA account rather than a Brokerage Account. Why is that?
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response</strong>: Because the capital gains in the SEP IRA account also needs to be taxed, in order to avoid its rapid growth, it is recommended to keep your existing funds in your SEP IRA account as is and no longer contribute to it. The funds in the Brokerage Account can be used for asset-backed loans. You can continue to use the annual quota to deposit funds into your SEP IRA and then transfer it to a ROTH IRA.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question 2</strong>: Do I need to keep some cash in my Brokerage Account?
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response</strong>: No, you do not. You can obtain emergency funds through asset-backed loans. For example, if you have $5 million in Brokerage Account assets, you can obtain a credit line of approximately $3.5 million, which is sufficient to deal with most emergencies. You can first apply to open the asset-backed loan function, even if you don&rsquo;t use it for the time being. When you need money, you can borrow from it at any time, for example, occasionally borrowing $100,000 to pay taxes.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question 3</strong>: You always emphasize that QQQ should &ldquo;never be sold.&rdquo; So should QLD or TQQQ in a Roth IRA account also &ldquo;never be sold?&rdquo; But doesn&rsquo;t TQQQ have various fees and losses?
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response</strong>: Yes, even QLD and TQQQ should be held for the long term and not bought and sold frequently. Although TQQQ has some management fees and fluctuation losses, these losses are acceptable in the long term considering its huge growth potential. We should focus on long-term results rather than short-term fluctuations. For example, if QQQ increases 200 times in 40 years, then TQQQ may increase 600 times, which is a very substantial return.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question 4</strong>: In a Roth IRA account, if I don’t buy QLD, can I buy TQQQ?
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response</strong>: I don’t give specific investment advice. Whether to buy TQQQ is your own choice. I can only tell you that the data we use for backtesting is based on QQQ. If you change the volatility, I will not be able to answer the questions you may encounter.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question 5</strong>: For a child&rsquo;s Roth IRA account, do you recommend buying QLD or QQQ?
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response</strong>: For children’s accounts, regardless of the account type, as long as the investment period is long enough, for example, 40 years, it is okay to consider investing in QLD as much as possible to maximize tax-free gains.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Brian 
    <div id="brian" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#brian" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing</strong>: He used James&rsquo;s 433 asset allocation simulator to verify his investment logic and made adjustments according to his own circumstances. His current asset allocation is 80/20 (80% QQQ, 20% TQQQ). He plans to gradually transition to 40/30 (40% QQQ, 30% TQQQ, 30% cash) after retirement. He also shared his work experience in the AI field, mainly responsible for AI applications in power systems. He agrees with James&rsquo;s view that AI will eventually replace most human jobs, but some jobs are still difficult to replace in the short term, such as the construction industry. He also mentioned that the degree of demand for AI varies from region to region due to differences in labor costs. Finally, he shared that he would choose to stay in better hotels when he travels for business to enjoy life, rather than just saving money.
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response</strong>: In the process of market uptrend, your cash ratio must be greater than your liabilities. This is the most important principle. The 433 asset allocation has been verified by backtesting and can cope with the worst market conditions. If you cannot achieve the 433 allocation for the time being, you must at least ensure that the cash ratio is higher than your liabilities. At the same time, you can re-allocate your new capital each month. Regarding AI, although AI will eventually replace most jobs, some jobs are still difficult to replace in the short term. For example, the construction industry still requires a lot of physical labor, and AI cannot completely replace it in the short term.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">IM 
    <div id="im" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#im" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing</strong>: He didn’t quite understand what James meant by &ldquo;always being optimistic&rdquo; and the relationship between &ldquo;risk control&rdquo; before, nor did he fully understand the advice on consumption behaviors such as buying houses and cars. After a period of reflection, he gradually understood the logic behind these concepts.
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response</strong>: At this stage, you can spend more money appropriately and enjoy life. The key is to learn to borrow money for consumption, rather than spending your own money. Investing and consumption are not contradictory; the important thing is to master the methods. For example, you can choose to take a taxi instead of spending time waiting for a bus. You can choose to spend money to buy a better car and enjoy a better driving experience, as long as you don’t spend your own money but pay through loans or other means. In 40 years, you will have 80 billion. Now, what you should be thinking about is how to spend money, not how to save money.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">IV. Key Quotes 
    <div id="iv-key-quotes" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv-key-quotes" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>Investing in US indices means holding US assets, not holding US currency.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>Investing in US stock index funds is about holding the assets of excellent US companies. The value of these assets is not highly correlated with the value of the US dollar. Even if the US dollar depreciates, the value of quality assets will continue to increase.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The market always goes up. Investing requires patience. Wealth is worth the wait.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>In the long run, the market always goes up, and investors need to be patient and wait for wealth to grow. Short-term market fluctuations are normal and should not be overemphasized.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The financial industry wants to empty your pockets.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>The goal of the financial industry is to maximize its own interests and may use various methods to &ldquo;empty&rdquo; investors&rsquo; pockets. For example, they will design various complex financial products and use information asymmetry to induce investors to buy. Investors must improve their financial literacy to recognize and resist the traps and temptations of the financial industry.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>There are many walls in the world, but people inside the walls don’t know they are within the walls, because everyone thinks they are free and open-minded. Many who think they are outside the walls don’t know that they are inside the walls.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>The information filter bubble effect in the online world should make us realize that the world we perceive may not be the real world, and we should maintain an open mind. Everyone and every country has its own information barriers.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The least guaranteed are laborers, and the second least guaranteed is real estate.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>Laborers face the risk of unemployment, especially in the current era of rapid AI development. Real estate also has risks, such as natural disasters and market fluctuations. In comparison, the risk of long-term investing in quality stock assets (such as QQQ) is lower.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>All laborers, regardless of whether you are young or old, remember that now artificial intelligence is sweeping the world, you will face unemployment.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>The development of AI will have a huge impact on the job market, and a large number of jobs will be replaced by AI. This is both a challenge and an opportunity.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>In the future, the future will be left with very few capitalists and very few people who know how to control AI; the rest will be useless laborers.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>The social structure of the future will undergo tremendous changes, and you must become a capitalist or someone who can control AI. This means we need to continuously learn and master new skills in order to stand firm in the future society.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>We don&rsquo;t need to have a purpose in life, we don&rsquo;t need to do anything in life, we just need to be happy.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>Encourage everyone to enjoy life and not set too many goals and pressures for themselves. The meaning of life lies in experiencing and feeling, rather than pursuing material wealth or social status.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>We don&rsquo;t necessarily have to like capitalist society, but we need to know how it makes money. We must stand on the same side as it, and then we can make a lot of money.
&ndash; Cat</p></blockquote>
<p>We don&rsquo;t need to like capitalism, but we need to understand the rules of capitalism in order to profit from it. Only by understanding how capitalism works can we better use it to achieve our wealth goals.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>If I still criticize, it means I still care.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>The criticism of Taiwan is because of the love for this land and the hope that it will become better.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">V. Summary 
    <div id="v-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#v-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This episode is full of information and covers many aspects such as investment philosophy, market analysis, asset allocation, and future outlook. James explained the underlying logic of investing in US index funds in an easy-to-understand way, emphasized the importance of long-term investment and holding high-quality assets, and provided an in-depth analysis of hot topics such as the relationship between the US dollar and US stocks, and the impact of AI on the future, in conjunction with the current economic situation and technological development trends. In addition, James also shared many practical investment tips and operational methods, such as the 433 asset allocation, smart rebalancing, and how to use asset-backed loans.</p>
<p>In conclusion, this episode is of great value to listeners who want to improve their investment knowledge and practice, helping them to better understand the essence of investment, master scientific investment methods, and become more stable and forward-looking on their future investment journey.</p>

  



<div
  
    class="flex px-4 py-3 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900"
  >

  <span
    
      class="text-primary-400 ltr:pr-3 rtl:pl-3 flex items-center"
    >

    

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M506.3 417l-213.3-364c-16.33-28-57.54-28-73.98 0l-213.2 364C-10.59 444.9 9.849 480 42.74 480h426.6C502.1 480 522.6 445 506.3 417zM232 168c0-13.25 10.75-24 24-24S280 154.8 280 168v128c0 13.25-10.75 24-23.1 24S232 309.3 232 296V168zM256 416c-17.36 0-31.44-14.08-31.44-31.44c0-17.36 14.07-31.44 31.44-31.44s31.44 14.08 31.44 31.44C287.4 401.9 273.4 416 256 416z"/></svg>

  </span>


  </span>

  <span
    
      class="dark:text-neutral-300"
    ><strong>Disclaimer:</strong> This article is for personal learning notes only and does not constitute any investment advice.</span>
</div>

]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
