<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Compounding on QQQ Investor</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/tags/compounding/</link><description>Recent content in Compounding on QQQ Investor</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jomonylw.github.io/en/tags/compounding/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>00479 Three Easy Examples of Getting Rich, The Power of Starting Early and Compound Interest</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1728391134352/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1728391134352/</guid><description>In this session, James reiterates the importance of long-term index fund investing, illustrating the power of compounding interest with multiple examples. He also explains how to avoid common investment pitfalls to achieve financial freedom. Additionally, James addresses audience questions on asset allocation, real estate investment, trusts, and children&amp;#39;s education funds.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<lite-youtube videoid="1VSo2I6xqG0" playlabel="1VSo2I6xqG0" params=""></lite-youtube>



<h2 class="relative group">I. Main Topic 
    <div id="i-main-topic" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-main-topic" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This session focuses on long-term index fund investing. The core message is: hold index funds firmly, ignore market fluctuations, maintain a proper asset allocation, and leverage the compounding effect of time to achieve financial freedom.  James also warns against investment scams and emphasizes avoiding unnecessary risks, while offering advice on investing in children&rsquo;s education funds.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">II. Presentation Summary 
    <div id="ii-presentation-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii-presentation-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<ul>
<li><strong>Advantages of Index Funds:</strong> Long-term index fund investing eliminates the need to follow short-term market fluctuations, international affairs, financial reports, and economic data.  Focus on asset allocation and consistent investment.</li>
<li><strong>The Power of Compounding:</strong> James uses several examples to illustrate the magic of compounding:  A monthly investment of 1000 TWD can grow to 17.3 million TWD in 40 years; a lump-sum investment of 100,000 TWD can reach 18.8 million TWD in 40 years;  starting early is crucial, as a 10-year delay significantly impacts final returns; one share of QQQ at 500 USD will become 25,000 USD in 30 years and 94,000 USD in 40 years.</li>
<li><strong>Safe Asset Allocation:</strong> Asset allocation is more critical than any market commentary. James recommends deleveraging and reducing debt for those nearing retirement, holding a larger cash position.  For younger individuals with stable income, leveraging can be considered. He suggests using a beta of 1.0 as a benchmark, reducing beta when the market is overheated, and increasing it back to 1.0 during market downturns.  For cash allocation, he references Buffett and suggests a sample allocation (Scenario 3): 40% index funds, 30% 2x leveraged funds, and 30% cash.</li>
<li><strong>Beware of Investment Scams:</strong>  Don&rsquo;t trust investment information from unknown accounts or websites. Choose legitimate financial institutions.</li>
<li><strong>Don&rsquo;t Give Money Directly to Children:</strong> James uses personal anecdotes and case studies to caution against putting assets directly in children&rsquo;s names, as this may discourage their initiative or cause family conflicts.  However, investing children&rsquo;s &ldquo;lucky money&rdquo; (red envelopes) for them is recommended as an educational fund.</li>
<li><strong>Risks of Real Estate Investment:</strong> James reiterates his advice against early homeownership for young people, arguing that real estate is illiquid, high-risk, and ties up capital that could be used for other investments.  He highlights the added risk in Taiwan, where mortgage debt remains even after foreclosure.</li>
<li><strong>Recommended Learning Resources:</strong> He recommends a YouTube channel called &ldquo;什么值得读&rdquo; (What&rsquo;s Worth Reading) for valuable content on value investing.</li>
<li><strong>Emergency Fund:</strong> Maintain a cash reserve equivalent to six months of living expenses in a money market fund account. Investing this emergency fund in stocks is not recommended.</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">III. Q&amp;A Session 
    <div id="iii-qa-session" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii-qa-session" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p><strong>Jeff:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Shares:  Highlights misconceptions about investing held by two listeners and emphasizes the importance of carefully studying James&rsquo;s lecture notes, particularly the chart on page two.</li>
<li>James&rsquo;s response:  Affirms Jeff&rsquo;s points and re-emphasizes the importance of a solid investment philosophy to avoid being swayed by market noise.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Cat:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Shares: A listener holding 35 million TWD in 00662 still finds the 2% withdrawal rate insufficient. Discusses the spending needs and inheritance considerations of single individuals.</li>
<li>James&rsquo;s response: Different indices have different volatility and dividend yields, requiring adjustments to withdrawal rates. For higher withdrawals, consider ETFs with higher dividend yields, such as 0056, which yields around 4-5%.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>H:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Question:  High rental costs for young people, should they buy a house?  Mortgages offer tax deductions, while renting does not.  Concerned about insufficient funds for leveraged investing.</li>
<li>James&rsquo;s response:  Recommends watching the &ldquo;30 Years of Different Destinies&rdquo; video, which analyzes the pros and cons of renting versus buying.  Young people should prioritize investing in index funds to build wealth through compounding and consider buying a house later.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Yonglin:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Question: Should money be invested in children&rsquo;s names for long-term holding?  Should a mortgage-free house be sold to invest in index funds after retirement?</li>
<li>James&rsquo;s response:  Advises against putting money directly in children&rsquo;s names.  Retirees should deleverage, and selling a mortgage-free house to invest in index funds is a viable option.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Mike:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Shares: Success story of investing his children&rsquo;s education fund in QQQ.  Gives the example of Taoyuan Language in Taiwan, suggesting potential leveraged investment through real estate mortgages.</li>
<li>Question: How to establish a family trust and manage generational wealth like the Rockefeller family?</li>
<li>James&rsquo;s response:  Recommends contacting Lisa for trust advice when assets reach a certain level and age. For now, focus on investing. Trusts can be considered around 70-80 years old. Single individuals or those without children should rely on trusts, appointing guardians and executors.  Those with children can consider Trust 2.0, with the bank as executor and children as supervisors.  Family foundations managed by professional institutions are also an option.  Recommends the Walmart family&rsquo;s living trust as a model.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Becky, Jessie, and Other Participants:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Becky: Difficulties of renting at an older age.</li>
<li>Jessie: How to balance saving for an emergency fund, paying off a mortgage, and investing simultaneously.</li>
<li>Other Participants: Questions about real estate investment, cash management, insurance, Bitcoin, and Japanese government bonds.</li>
<li>James&rsquo;s response:  Addresses each question and reiterates his investment philosophy.  For example, young people should avoid real estate and insurance due to high risks; long-term bonds and municipal bonds are not suitable for emergency funds.</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">IV. Key Takeaways 
    <div id="iv-key-takeaways" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv-key-takeaways" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>Time is the source of all power.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>James uses examples like the evolution of Earth&rsquo;s ecosystem and human evolution to illustrate the power of time and emphasize the importance of long-term investing.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Don&rsquo;t casually help others with money.  People will resent you for it for a lifetime.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Cautions against testing human nature with money and emphasizes setting boundaries with financial assistance.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The earlier you invest, the better.  Keep enough emergency funds. The earlier you invest, the lower the risk.
&ndash; Jeff</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Emphasizes the importance of early investing and maintaining an emergency fund.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Laugh a little; how long a scammer can scam is determined by the fool.
&ndash; Mike</p>
</blockquote>
<p>A cynical comment on the prevalence of scammers and a reminder to stay vigilant.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">V. Conclusion 
    <div id="v-conclusion" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#v-conclusion" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>The core message of this session remains long-term index fund investing. James uses clear language and vivid examples to reiterate the power of compounding and the importance of starting early. He also addresses audience questions on asset allocation, real estate, trusts, emergency funds, and children&rsquo;s education funds, sharing advice on avoiding common investment traps and achieving financial freedom.  He further recommends learning resources and provides commentary on social phenomena.</p>

  



<div
  
    class="flex px-4 py-3 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900"
  >

  <span
    
      class="text-primary-400 ltr:pr-3 rtl:pl-3 flex items-center"
    >

    

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M506.3 417l-213.3-364c-16.33-28-57.54-28-73.98 0l-213.2 364C-10.59 444.9 9.849 480 42.74 480h426.6C502.1 480 522.6 445 506.3 417zM232 168c0-13.25 10.75-24 24-24S280 154.8 280 168v128c0 13.25-10.75 24-23.1 24S232 309.3 232 296V168zM256 416c-17.36 0-31.44-14.08-31.44-31.44c0-17.36 14.07-31.44 31.44-31.44s31.44 14.08 31.44 31.44C287.4 401.9 273.4 416 256 416z"/></svg>

  </span>


  </span>

  <span
    
      class="dark:text-neutral-300"
    ><strong>Disclaimer:</strong> This document is for personal learning notes only and does not constitute any investment advice.</span>
</div>

]]></content:encoded></item></channel></rss>