<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Market Volatility on QQQ Investor</title>
    <link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/tags/market-volatility/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Market Volatility on QQQ Investor</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 26 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jomonylw.github.io/en/tags/market-volatility/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>00513 The world is evolving: choosing the top index (e.g., Nasdaq 100), a reverie of the AI age</title>
      <link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1745714790157/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1745714790157/</guid>
      <description>In this episode, James first announced the upcoming two-week Clubhouse hiatus and then emphasized that market volatility is normal and there&amp;#39;s no need to over-analyze the reasons behind it. The core arguments revolved around the importance of long-term investing and index funds (especially the Nasdaq 100), and discussed the selection of specific ETFs (such as 00864B/00865B, BRK, HXQ). He also shared his fantasies about the future development of AI, exploring its potential impact on social structures, work, and the meaning of life. The Q&amp;amp;A session covered a range of practical issues, including market predictions, asset allocation ratios (70/30 rule, Beta value), ETF selection in different countries, digital currency risks, differences in investment philosophies between spouses, and retirement cash reserves.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<lite-youtube videoid="5WJ_23Gpcg0" playlabel="5WJ_23Gpcg0" params=""></lite-youtube>



<h2 class="relative group">I. Episode Theme 
    <div id="i-episode-theme" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-episode-theme" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This episode revolves around the core concept of long-term investing, emphasizing the importance of maintaining composure amidst inevitable market fluctuations, adhering to investments in high-quality index funds (such as the Nasdaq 100), and exploring the profound impact of AI development on the future of society and personal wealth. It also provides in-depth answers to specific questions raised by students regarding investment tool selection, asset allocation strategies, and market psychology.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">II. Summary 
    <div id="ii-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Operations and Reminders 
    <div id="operations-and-reminders" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#operations-and-reminders" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Clubhouse Hiatus Announcement</strong>: Clubhouse and video uploads will be suspended for the next two weeks (May 3rd and May 10th), resuming on May 17th (Saturday).</li>
<li><strong>Clubhouse Technical Issues</strong>: Recent issues with sound being inaudible or too low. It&rsquo;s recommended to leave and re-enter the room, or completely close and reopen the app.</li>
<li><strong>Speaking Rules</strong>: Accidental stage entries are fine, just stay on stage; no need to repeatedly enter and exit.</li>
<li><strong>Disclaimer</strong>: All sharing is for reference only. Investment decisions are the individual&rsquo;s responsibility. We are not professional investment advisors or tax professionals; sharing is based on personal experience. Long-term investment has low risk, short-term investment has high risk. Those who cannot tolerate short-term losses or are worried about asset devaluation should not invest and can choose fixed deposits instead.</li>
<li><strong>Learning Resources</strong>: Lecture notes are pinned in the Clubhouse comment section or the YouTube comment section. Newcomers are advised to start with video 00451, then 398-402, and then the latest for systematic learning (although there are as many as four or five hundred videos).</li>
<li><strong>Community Groups</strong>: No official groups are established. Participation in unofficial groups requires caution. If the group information is noisy, annoying, and not beneficial to life, it is recommended to leave. Groups aimed at sharing CLEC concepts, helping each other answer questions, and providing information are welcome.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Investment Philosophy and Strategies 
    <div id="investment-philosophy-and-strategies" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#investment-philosophy-and-strategies" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Market Volatility is Normal</strong>: The market is always fluctuating; this is the unchanging rule. No need to analyze specific reasons (international situation, trade war, financial report forecasts, etc.). Many analysts themselves do not truly understand. The market is like the sea, unaffected by streams and storms.</li>
<li><strong>Long-Term Investing</strong>: True investment is buying with the intention of never selling. Intending to sell at a high point is speculation. Investment must be long-term.</li>
<li><strong>Index Investing</strong>:
<ul>
<li><strong>Core Recommendation</strong>: Nasdaq 100 Index Fund (QQQ and its global equivalents). Reason: Compared to the S&amp;P 500 (500 companies, possibly 450 &ldquo;bad companies&rdquo;), the Nasdaq 100 focuses more on high-quality technology companies, aligning with the &ldquo;the bigger, the stronger&rdquo; trend.</li>
<li><strong>Retirees/Those with Less Capital</strong>: Consider Taiwan 0056 or US SPHD (dividend yield ~3.5%, providing stable cash flow).</li>
<li><strong>Nasdaq 100 ETF List</strong>: Provides a list of relevant ETFs including various countries (Canada HXQ.t, Singapore, Malaysia, Norway, UK, Australia, etc.). HXQ.t is recommended because it does not pay dividends (tax-free).</li>
<li><strong>Historical Experience</strong>: Watching videos since 2018 can provide insights into investor sentiment and responses during market fluctuations, giving a sense of the long-term perspective.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Stay Optimistic</strong>: Investors need to be extremely optimistic, always facing the sunlight, believing that the market will be good in the long run, even if there is a world war, the market still exists and continues to rise (only rises, never falls).</li>
<li><strong>Investment Target Selection</strong>:
<ul>
<li><strong>00864B vs 00865B (Taiwan Bond ETF)</strong>:
<ul>
<li>00864B: Pays dividends, generating National Health Insurance Supplementary Premium (2.11%), requires manual reinvestment (with handling fees, easy to forget resulting in no compounding), dividends are considered overseas income (requires declaration if it exceeds the limit, but usually not a problem with annual income below NT$1 million; according to student feedback, it is exempt from the second-generation health insurance supplementary premium).</li>
<li>00865B: Does not pay dividends, avoiding the above problems, simpler and more effective in the long run. Low trading volume is not a problem (market makers provide liquidity), initial performance differences will shrink as scale increases. <strong>Strongly recommend switching to 00865B; convenience is a value.</strong> Conversion will incur a one-time transaction cost, but worth it in the long run.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Berkshire Hathaway (BRK.A/B)</strong>:
<ul>
<li><strong>Not recommended for investment</strong>. Reason: Actively managed fund, more volatile than the index; times are changing, performance has lagged behind the S&amp;P 500; uncertainty after Buffett (&ldquo;the devil will come out&rdquo;); learning Buffett should be about learning his long-term investment spirit, investment discourse (such as the definition of investment), rather than stock picking. Investing in the S&amp;P 500 may be better than investing in BRK.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Asset Allocation (Beta)</strong>:
<ul>
<li><strong>Basic Principle</strong>: It is recommended that most people allocate an investment portfolio with a Beta value of less than 1, such as 70% index funds + 30% cash/money market funds (Beta is approximately 0.7).</li>
<li><strong>Risk Tolerance</strong>: The recent 20% drop has made many people uncomfortable (even those with a Beta of 1.2 configured at 4:4:2), indicating that actual risk tolerance may be lower than expected. Do not sacrifice the comfort of holding enough cash (&ldquo;don&rsquo;t gamble with the money you need for the money you don&rsquo;t need&rdquo;) for an extra 1-2% of return.</li>
<li><strong>Adjustment</strong>: If the initial Beta is high (such as 1.2), it is recommended to review it at the end of each year. If the market rises, you can sell part of the leveraged/index position and supplement the cash to more than 30%, gradually reducing the Beta to below 1.0. Consider smart rebalancing after the Beta is below 1.0.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Platform Interaction</strong>: Please subscribe, like, and leave comments on videos on various platforms.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">AI Development Fantasies and Impact 
    <div id="ai-development-fantasies-and-impact" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ai-development-fantasies-and-impact" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>AI Optimized Future</strong>:
<ul>
<li>Productivity greatly improved, most output is completed by AI (robots), and the cost of goods approaches zero.</li>
<li>Total social wealth accelerates, basic living needs (food, clothing, housing, transportation) may be free, uniformly supplied by the state/society (AI robots complete production, construction, and maintenance).</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Social Structure Changes</strong>:
<ul>
<li><strong>Classes Still Exist</strong>:
<ul>
<li><strong>Capitalists</strong>: Earn profits by investing in and holding the means of production (AI systems) without labor; the wealthiest. Everyone can become a capitalist (just need to know how to invest).</li>
<li><strong>High-Tech Workers</strong>: Personnel who maintain and manage AI systems, with excellent income, can enjoy entertainment beyond basic needs (such as space travel), but may fall into the &ldquo;cared-for&rdquo; class if they stop working and do not become capitalists.</li>
<li><strong>Cared-For Class (approximately 80%)</strong>: No need to work, basic life is guaranteed (food, clothing, housing, transportation, medical care), but cannot enjoy additional entertainment or resources. The standard of living may be similar to the current upper-middle class, but without work.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Philosophical Challenges</strong>:
<ul>
<li>When most people do not need to contribute for livelihood (&ldquo;nothing to serve&rdquo;), what is the meaning and purpose of life? (Analogous to being idle after retirement). May lead to widespread depression or social problems.</li>
<li>Human development may enter a stage of eternal life, facing greater philosophical and existential questions.</li>
<li>The focus should shift from &ldquo;unemployment&rdquo; to &ldquo;the meaning of life.&rdquo;</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Implications for Investors</strong>:
<ul>
<li>As capitalists, there is no need to worry about job loss due to AI development; on the contrary, they will become wealthier.</li>
<li>Start investing now to become part of the capitalist class.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">III. Q&amp;A Session 
    <div id="iii-qa-session" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii-qa-session" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Jacel 
    <div id="jacel" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#jacel" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question: SPY and QQQ have risen for three days, will they continue to rise or fall next week?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo; Response: Short-term market cannot be predicted, like flipping a coin. We invest for the long term (20+ years), focusing on long-term trends. Buy when you have money, never sell. Don&rsquo;t try to predict next week&rsquo;s market; ask the temple or the &ldquo;stock god&rdquo; in Clubhouse.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Sharing: Just started learning from the teacher&rsquo;s course two months ago, introduced by a friend in the United States. Currently in the learning stage, and has invested in some QQQ (cost between 515-530). After returning to Taiwan, considering investing in 00662. In the process of canceling previous insurance and converting individual stocks to 00662.</li>
<li>Question: Should I invest in US stocks (Firstrade account, worried about political risks in Taiwan for the child) or Taiwan stocks 00662? How to allocate at the beginning?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo; Response: Recommend investing in 00662 in Taiwan, no need to use a US broker (Firstrade). It&rsquo;s better for the child to rely on themselves rather than worry about politics. When starting to learn, it is recommended to divide the total funds into three parts: 1/3 buy 00662 immediately, 1/3 buy in batches over the next 3-6 months, and 1/3 hold in cash. The ultimate goal is 70% 00662 + 30% cash. Then slowly learn whether and how to allocate leveraged funds (adjust the Beta value to 0.8-0.9).</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Nibalao 
    <div id="nibalao" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#nibalao" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question 1: Who are QQQ and SPHD suitable for in terms of capital size?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo; Response: (Points out that students should watch the videos for repeated questions) This is a consideration for retirees. Need to calculate annual expenses after retirement. If 50 times the expenses equals your total assets, you can invest in QQQ (equivalent to a 2% annual withdrawal rate). If 2% is not enough, you need 3%, you may consider the S&amp;P 500. Only consider SPHD if you need even higher (~3.5-4%). Non-retirees should prioritize the high-growth QQQ.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2: Explain Beta value. Beta=1 is synchronized with the market? Beta=1.2 is 1.2 times the volatility? Is the Beta of an 80% QQQ + 20% SGOV portfolio 0.8?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo; Response: Basic understanding is correct. Beta measures the volatility of an asset relative to the market. The Beta of an 80/20 portfolio is approximately 0.8. (Reminds again that the videos explain it)</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 3: Will the principal of SGOV (Short-Term US Treasury ETF) fall and lose money?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo; Response: The principal risk is extremely low, almost no losses (except for minor fluctuations before and after dividend payments). SGOV invests in short-term Treasury bills (T-Bills) issued by the US Treasury Department with a maturity of 0-3 months (or within one year), backed by the credit of the United States.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Rui 
    <div id="rui" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#rui" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Joined for more than a month and reviewed the market decline in 2022 and the teacher&rsquo;s videos (especially #398 graduation episode, learned investment psychology).</li>
<li>Question 1: In January 2023 (#401), the teacher used technical indicators (50/100-day moving average crossover) to judge the market bottom and predict that 2023 would be a bull market, which was also verified afterwards. However, in later videos (#491), he emphasized not to predict market cycles and not to look at macroeconomic indicators (prosperity signals, macroeconomics, inventory cycles, etc.). Why this change? Are these indicators really useless in the long run? What was the basis for judging the bottom (just because of being optimistic about the stock market)? Should we just follow discipline and rebalance once a year?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo; Response: QQQ includes many industries (semiconductors, software, AI, biotechnology, retail such as Costco, Pepsico, Amazon, Google, Apple, etc.), and indicators for a single industry or country (such as Taiwan semiconductor economy, Taiwan prosperity signals, US prosperity signals) cannot reflect the overall index. Looking at all indicators is the same as looking at the index itself, so it is better to just focus on QQQ. The judgment in early 2023 was based on 40 years of experience (calculated that the 6-month moving average would cross upward), which is difficult to convey (&ldquo;unspeakable&rdquo;), and teaching technical analysis may cause students to misuse it and be harmed (&ldquo;go crazy&rdquo;), so it is not taught. Adhering to long-term investment discipline and holding enough cash buffer (such as 30%) is a more reliable method. Even if judging the bottom at that time, all cash would not be invested (such as still maintaining Beta 0.7), still maintaining a margin of safety. No need to take too much risk for small potential gains (referring to Buffett&rsquo;s philosophy).</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2: About the currency hedging of 00670L (Taiwan Leveraged QQQ ETF). Is the impact of exchange rate fluctuations significant in the long run? If the US dollar falls sharply (such as 1:13 against the Taiwan dollar), how will 00670L perform? (The teacher mentioned before that 00670L performs poorly when the US dollar rises)
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo; Response: 00670L is usually paired with 00865B (cash/short-term bonds). Exchange rate fluctuations have a hedging effect on both (when the US dollar rises, the hedging cost of 00670L increases, but the value of US dollar assets increases; the opposite is true when the US dollar falls). In the long run, exchange rate fluctuations are normal (such as the Taiwan dollar fluctuating between 28-32), but there is no fixed trend, and the expected value is zero. Currency hedging itself has a cost (wasting funds), which may not be necessary in the long run (it is recommended that fund companies consider canceling it), but the ETF is designed that way, and it does not hurt. The key is whether 00670L can achieve approximately twice the return of 00662 in the long run.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Mike 
    <div id="mike" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#mike" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Trump mentioned that 5.6 trillion in foreign investment may be invested in the United States in the future (may be exaggerated, even if halved, 2.8 trillion is also considerable), but the direction is beneficial to AI and QQQ. Observed that QQQ rebounded more strongly than SPY, DIA, and BRK recently, confirming the teacher&rsquo;s point of view (such as Katy Wood investing in AI-related companies when she saw mobile internet access). Compare the leadership styles of Chinese and American leaders (leader vs. manager) and the direction of attracting foreign investment (Saudi Arabia/Dubai vs. Myanmar/Vietnam/Malaysia).</li>
<li>Question: Please explain the difference between CIPS (Chinese RMB Cross-Border Payment System) and SWIFT. Why is CIPS faster (completed in 6 seconds)? Why does SWIFT take days? Can SWIFT be improved? Will this affect the status of the US dollar (AI replied that the two will coexist)?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo; Response: SWIFT is based on the traditional telegram transmission model (like a relay station), and information needs to be transferred through multiple layers (local bank -&gt; regional major bank -&gt; central bank -&gt; SWIFT center (Switzerland) -&gt; the other party&rsquo;s central bank -&gt; the other party&rsquo;s head office -&gt; the other party&rsquo;s branch), involving compliance checks (anti-money laundering), time difference, manual processing, etc., so it takes a long time (2+ days). CIPS is a modern real-time gross settlement system, similar to domestic payment systems in various countries, point-to-point or directly cleared through the central bank, and the speed is fast. CIPS uses RMB and is an alternative developed to deal with SWIFT being weaponized (such as sanctions against Russia), making people distrust the US dollar system. US sanctions opened a Pandora&rsquo;s box. Currently, CIPS is small (such as shipbuilding transactions between Malaysia and China), but it represents the trend of &ldquo;currency wars&rdquo; (such as Saudi Arabia and China being linked). Trump&rsquo;s visit to Saudi Arabia may be related to maintaining the status of the US dollar. Just watch the show.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Xiu 
    <div id="xiu" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#xiu" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question: Regarding the customized version of ChatGPT (CCTeams Investment Advisor) shared by the teacher, its knowledge cutoff date seems to be June of last year. Is the teacher using an updated version? Will the link change after the update? (Previously confused HXQ/HSQ).
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo; Response: Indeed, this AI is constantly being updated and trained. The link may change with updates. The latest link (showing content updated on April 26, such as 70/30 allocation recommendations) has been shared in the chat area. New links will be provided regularly (such as weekly or monthly) in the future. The teacher himself uses a more advanced personal &ldquo;Super AI&rdquo; account (possibly GPT-4o or higher, with memory function) to process and extract information, and then &ldquo;feeds&rdquo; the essence to this publicly shared GPTs version (similar to DIPS extraction). Feedback on AI answers is welcome for improvement.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Yao 
    <div id="yao" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#yao" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Because of recent trade tensions, I re-listened to the 2022 recordings. Two points are profound: 1. The biggest risk is missing the market (leaving the market). 2. Focus on long-term returns, not short-term fluctuations/shocks. The market is full of contradictory information (repeated presidential statements, pessimistic commentators) and bad news, but it often rebounds unintentionally. Friends who wait for a clear trend (such as buying after the big trend comes back) miss the rise. No one can accurately time the market. It is extremely difficult to obtain stable and high returns in the long term (such as an annualized return of 10% or more), like the sustained performance of top athletes (such as playing ball for 20 years); it is easy to have a good shot occasionally, but difficult to be stable in the long term. It is essential to stay in the market for a long time and focus on long-term growth.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo; Response: Strongly agree. Investing is like a long-distance race, continuing to stay in the front (such as 3rd or 4th place) will eventually win, because the leaders often make mistakes. This is how index funds are, not the best in a single year, but leading in the long term. Need an investment horizon of 15+ years. The key to persistence is having sufficient cash reserves (especially for retirees, it is recommended to have living expenses for 15+ years) or a continuous work income.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Monmon 
    <div id="monmon" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#monmon" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing 1: Started following the teacher last year, investing on my own and encouraging elders (sold insurance and invested). Recently, I have experienced a market decline and am at peace, but the elders are experiencing large fluctuations for the first time (they adopted a Beta 1.2 allocation). Through repeatedly watching videos and communicating, the elders&rsquo; confidence is still stable.</li>
<li>Sharing 2: Selling a house has been tortuous: difficulty communicating with my husband (disagreed at first, had disputes), cold market (the central bank fought housing speculation in September, difficult to get loans), price reduction (applied the teacher&rsquo;s concept of &ldquo;there is no house that cannot be sold, only a price that cannot be sold&rdquo;) to complete the sale (in February this year). The process was painful (communication, management, market changes, funds stuck, high taxes), and I learned a lesson that I don&rsquo;t want to experience again.</li>
<li>Sharing 3: Currently, half of the investment portfolio is QQQ-like, half is TSMC, and there is also a mortgage line of credit (financial mortgage). My husband wants to use this line of credit to increase positions when the market falls (TSMC?), but hesitates and is afraid in the middle of the actual fall (soft-handed, unable to do it). This decline allowed him to experience his true risk tolerance. My husband did not accept the full QQQ allocation before, but now he has some experience. It verifies the stability of the teacher&rsquo;s asset allocation method.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo; Response: Appreciate Monmon&rsquo;s peaceful state of mind (a good quality for investors, &ldquo;destiny&rdquo; + &ldquo;luck&rdquo; to meet the teacher). Communicating with family requires patience (it is a 15-30 year undertaking, no rush). The funds from the financial mortgage should be invested as soon as possible (such as 00662), buy blindly, and don&rsquo;t time the market. When investing, consider the overall asset allocation, include the loan amount in the total asset calculation, and ensure that the total Beta value is within the desired range (such as about 0.7, that is, maintaining an overall ratio of about 70/30), rather than investing all the borrowed money in high-risk assets. It is recommended to keep at least 30% cash (can be 4:1:5 or 5:1:4, Beta 0.6 or 0.7). This decline is a touchstone for risk tolerance, proving the necessity of conservative allocation. Even if young and have a job, 30% cash is also recommended.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">From Taiwan 
    <div id="from-taiwan" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#from-taiwan" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: The situation is similar to Monmon&rsquo;s. Both myself and the elders invested in 00662/00670L, using Beta 1.2 (4:4:2, that is, 40% 00662, 40% 00670L, 20% cash/00865B) allocation. I can bear the recent fluctuations (the government is quite amazing), but I am not sure whether the elders (who have not watched YouTube, have no financial common sense, but believe and invest) can bear greater future declines (such as 40-80%). Continuously accompany the elders and give them confidence. The elders have a good mentality so far.</li>
<li>Question: If I want to reduce the Beta for the elders, when and how should I operate?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo; Response: It is generally recommended now that the Beta should not exceed 1.0 (such as 70/30). For an existing allocation of 1.2, it is recommended to evaluate it at the end of each year: if the market rises (such as 00662 returning to the level at the beginning of the year or higher), you can sell part of the leveraged position (00670L) and transfer the funds to cash (00865B), so that the cash ratio is adjusted to 30% or higher. If the market is down at the end of the year, then do not move. The goal is to gradually reduce the Beta to below 1.0. Before that, there is no need to consider complicated rebalancing strategies. Don&rsquo;t operate too frequently (once a year) to avoid increasing the elders&rsquo; anxiety (they may secretly look at the APP).</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Lucy 
    <div id="lucy" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#lucy" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question 1: Investing in QQQ in Canada, the teacher recommends QQC, etc., and mentions avoiding Hedged funds? It seems that most Canadian versions are Hedged? Which one should I choose? (Previously confused HXQ/HSQ).
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo; Response: Recommend HXQ.t because it does not pay dividends, making tax treatment simpler. If you already hold QQC.to or ZQQ, there is no need to sell it, and new investments can be bought in HXQ.t. It is also acceptable if only Hedged versions are available locally.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2: Please explain the asset allocation ratio (such as 70/30, 4:4:2). Time is limited (working, back problems requiring exercise, blood sugar problems), it is difficult to find specific content in videos, and listening to Clubhouse is also time-consuming.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo; Response: (Emphasizing the importance of learning, earning money from work only accounts for a small part of a lifetime of wealth, so you should spend time learning about investment) For ordinary investors working in Canada, the simplest allocation is: 70% HXQ.t + 30% cash/money market fund (Money Market). Check and adjust annually (sell the ones that have risen more to supplement cash, or use cash to buy the ones that have fallen more) to maintain this ratio.</li>
<li>(Nibalao Supplement): Canadian local stock dividends have tax advantages, while US-sourced dividends (such as QQC) are taxed (I don&rsquo;t know how much, but higher than Canadian stock taxes). I agree with the teacher&rsquo;s point of view: focus on investment returns is higher than focusing on work.</li>
<li>James&rsquo; Response: Reiterating the advantage of HXQ.t not paying dividends. Canadian funds seem to be performing well, possibly because better compounding due to not paying dividends.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Sharing (Follow-up): Listening to the teacher&rsquo;s criticism is very comfortable and helpful. I am impatient, but after listening to the teacher&rsquo;s patient answers to &ldquo;stupid questions,&rdquo; I am more patient in helping others.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo; Response: Asking questions bravely is important.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Jason 
    <div id="jason" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#jason" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Detailed comparison of the advantages and disadvantages of Bitcoin/cryptocurrencies and QQQ, based on his personal experience in the blockchain industry (entered the industry in 2017, experienced the blockchain/cryptocurrency community, ICO explosion, 2018 bear market):
<ul>
<li>Storage Security: BTC requires self-management of private keys/hardware wallets (cold wallets), which are easy to lose or damage, high risk; QQQ is托管ed by brokers, which is safe.</li>
<li>Transaction Security: BTC is vulnerable to hacker attacks, phishing, and platform crashes; QQQ is protected by regulations.</li>
<li>Staking/Liquidity: BTC lacks standardized and safe staking channels (DeFi is high risk); QQQ can be easily staked and borrowed (pledged) through brokers without selling.</li>
<li>Taxes: Selling BTC requires capital gains tax; holding QQQ for a long time and using pledges can avoid/defer taxes.</li>
<li>Legality: BTC has legal risks in China (trading and mining are illegal), and cashing out may be frozen; QQQ (and QDII 513100/513300) are legal and compliant.</li>
<li>Volatility/Risk: BTC is extremely volatile (short-term drops of 50-80% are common, such as an 85% drop in 2018), and ordinary people cannot withstand the mental stress; QQQ has a much lower frequency of large fluctuations.</li>
<li>Liquidity: The actual circulating volume of BTC is limited (locked by large holders, lost coins), which is not as high as the global liquidity of QQQ.</li>
<li>Practicality: Not detailed.</li>
<li>Future Returns: BTC has a high market value (nearly 2 trillion US dollars, comparable to top technology companies), and the possibility of super high multiple growth in the future is reduced (even if it rises to 200,000 US dollars/coin, it is only 2-3 times), and the rate of return may tend to be stable, lower than QQQ.</li>
<li>Conclusion: Cryptocurrencies are &ldquo;demons and ghosts,&rdquo; not suitable for ordinary investors, highly tempting but extremely risky.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>James&rsquo; Comment: Completely agree, cryptocurrencies should not be touched. Shared cases of others losing huge amounts of Bitcoin (equivalent to 15 million US dollars) due to unfamiliarity with cross-chain transfer rules (such as transferring between different chains or exchanges that do not support the target chain), emphasizing its complexity and risk (may be a technical problem or fraud).</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Responding to Chat Room Questions 
    <div id="responding-to-chat-room-questions" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#responding-to-chat-room-questions" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>File Access</strong>: In areas with limited Google service, you can download the files and open them with local software (such as Excel).</li>
<li><strong>00864B Taxes</strong>: According to Angela&rsquo;s feedback, it is overseas income, which is tax-free if it is less than 1 million Taiwan dollars (or other high limit such as 7.5 million) per year, and is exempt from the second-generation supplementary health insurance premium. The main problem becomes the trouble of manual reinvestment. You need a principal of 25 million to possibly exceed 1 million in interest.</li>
<li><strong>AI Link</strong>: Confirmed that the latest link has been provided.</li>
<li><strong>Buying QQQ in China</strong>: Through QDII funds, such as 513100, 513300. See page 10 of the lecture notes.</li>
<li><strong>Conflicting Ideas Between Spouses</strong>: Patience, use your own controllable funds to set an example. Sometimes even if you prove it, the other person does not recognize it (&ldquo;past performance does not represent the future&rdquo;), it depends on fate (destiny).</li>
<li><strong>Technical Analysis/Prediction</strong>: The teacher does not make predictions (when will it bottom out, will there be a recession or crash).</li>
<li><strong>Robert Kiyosaki</strong>: The teacher is critical of him (&ldquo;he will go bankrupt&rdquo;).</li>
<li><strong>Trump Policy</strong>: No need to pay attention, high uncertainty, just &ldquo;drizzle,&rdquo; impossible to have zero income tax. In the long run, US taxes may increase to deal with the deficit. Do not make decisions based on unconfirmed conclusions.</li>
<li><strong>Mean Reversion</strong>: There is no simple mean reversion in the stock market. The growth of high-tech companies (such as TSMC) will not revert to traditional industries (such as China Steel, Formosa Plastics). Those who think it will revert are &ldquo;bookworms.&rdquo; Value stocks (such as Starbucks, McDonald&rsquo;s) also perform differently.</li>
<li><strong>442 Allocation</strong>: Not recommended for office workers, it is too risky. Those who have already used it should handle it according to the MM case.</li>
<li><strong>Investment vs Speculation</strong>: The teacher does not agree with the statement that &ldquo;all investments are speculation.&rdquo;</li>
<li><strong>12-Year Certificates of Deposit vs Compounding</strong>: 00865B/VOO etc. are compounded.</li>
<li><strong>AI Asset Allocation Advice</strong>: May be &ldquo;incorrect&rdquo; due to questioning methods or AI model understanding deviations.</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">IV. Highlights 
    <div id="iv-highlights" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv-highlights" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>The market is always fluctuating, the constant in the market is fluctuation, so fluctuation is certain to happen in the market, so you don&rsquo;t need to analyze where the fluctuation comes from&hellip; You see everyone talking so eloquently, in fact, he doesn&rsquo;t even know what he is talking about&hellip;
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Context: James emphasized the normality and unpredictability of market fluctuations, advising investors not to waste time analyzing the causes of short-term fluctuations.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Investment is buying with the intention of never selling, this is investment. Buying with the intention of selling at a high point is called speculation.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Context: James clearly distinguished the core criteria of investment and speculation: whether the purpose is to hold for the long term.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Making a decision about all investment and financial life is very simple, which is long-term, simple and effective&hellip; Convenience is a value. No trouble is a value.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Context: When comparing 00864B and 00865B, James emphasized that choosing an investment method that is simpler and less troublesome in the long run has value in itself.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>You don&rsquo;t need to risk the money you need for the money you don&rsquo;t need.
&ndash; James (quoting/paraphrasing Buffett&rsquo;s idea)</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Context: Explained why even if it is judged that the market may rise, you should keep enough cash buffer (the money you need) and should not take too much risk for additional, potentially unnecessary returns (the money you don&rsquo;t need).</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Later you will find that when humans develop to the extreme, food, clothing, housing, and transportation are all free, all free&hellip; Then what does it mean to be alive?&hellip; But what is the meaning of a dog? This may be the question that the last 80% of people have to think about.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Context: When fantasizing about the future when AI is extremely developed, James raised the question of the profound crisis of existential meaning that humans (especially the majority who do not need to work) will face after material needs are completely satisfied.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The biggest risk comes from [missing] the market&hellip; Focus on long-term returns, not this short-term [fluctuation].
&ndash; Yao</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Context: Sharing the profound experience after reviewing the teacher&rsquo;s teachings when the market information is chaotic, emphasizing the importance of being in the market for a long time and focusing on long-term goals.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>We don&rsquo;t want to be the first every time, we only want to be the third or fourth every time&hellip; Over the long term, we will be the first.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Context: Using the analogy of racing to explain the logic of index investing: not pursuing short-term leadership, relying on continuous and steady performance, and ultimately winning in the long cycle.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>There is no house that cannot be sold, only a price that cannot be sold.
&ndash; Monmon</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Context: Sharing the experience of selling a house, mentioning that applying this point of view ultimately successfully sold the property.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>You should put your focus on investing, and the return is definitely much higher than if you put your focus on working.
&ndash; Nibalao</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Context: When discussing that students do not have time to learn about investment, this student emphasized that based on their own experience, the long-term return of putting energy into investment learning far exceeds that of putting it into work itself.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>[Cryptocurrencies] are one of the demons and ghosts&hellip; The future return of Bitcoin may tend to be stable, and the teacher also mentioned this issue before.
&ndash; Jason</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Context: Based on industry experience and risk analysis, the student qualified cryptocurrencies as a high-risk category unsuitable for ordinary investors, and pointed out that its future return may not be as good as index funds.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">V. Summary 
    <div id="v-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#v-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This Clubhouse episode was rich and insightful, ranging from the macro market philosophy (fluctuation is normal, long-term perspective, optimistic mentality), AI&rsquo;s disruptive vision of the future (productivity, social structure, meaning of life), to the micro investment practice (ETF selection such as 00865B vs 00864B, Canadian HXQ.t, asset allocation principles such as 70/30, Beta management, risk awareness), all detailed explanations and discussions were provided. The core information is still focused on: adhering to long-term holding of high-quality index funds (especially the Nasdaq 100), understanding and accepting market fluctuations, maintaining rationality and patience, using time compounding, and conducting sound asset allocation according to personal risk tolerance (emphasizing the importance of at least 30% cash), and being vigilant about market noise and high-risk speculative products (such as cryptocurrencies). The Q&amp;A session answered in detail the specific questions encountered by students in different countries, different stages, and different product selections, and emphasized the importance of continuous learning of investment knowledge. Finally, it was reminded again that the Clubhouse will be suspended for the next two weeks.</p>

  



<div
  
    class="flex px-4 py-3 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900"
  >

  <span
    
      class="text-primary-400 ltr:pr-3 rtl:pl-3 flex items-center"
    >

    

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M506.3 417l-213.3-364c-16.33-28-57.54-28-73.98 0l-213.2 364C-10.59 444.9 9.849 480 42.74 480h426.6C502.1 480 522.6 445 506.3 417zM232 168c0-13.25 10.75-24 24-24S280 154.8 280 168v128c0 13.25-10.75 24-23.1 24S232 309.3 232 296V168zM256 416c-17.36 0-31.44-14.08-31.44-31.44c0-17.36 14.07-31.44 31.44-31.44s31.44 14.08 31.44 31.44C287.4 401.9 273.4 416 256 416z"/></svg>

  </span>


  </span>

  <span
    
      class="dark:text-neutral-300"
    ><strong>Disclaimer:</strong> This article is only a personal learning note and does not constitute any investment advice.</span>
</div>

]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>00512 Asset Allocation Simulation Full Guide: Practical Exercises in Leverage, Rebalancing, and Cash Conversion</title>
      <link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1745130594222/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1745130594222/</guid>
      <description>James discusses the investment mindset in volatile markets, updates the Excel tool for retirement withdrawals and leverage management, emphasizes the importance of long-term holding and early Roth conversion, and explores the operation of the financial system, coping with external pressure, and perspectives on the future of US technology.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<lite-youtube videoid="Wrcv9WKvu4s" playlabel="Wrcv9WKvu4s" params=""></lite-youtube>



<h2 class="relative group">I. Current Theme 
    <div id="i-current-theme" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-current-theme" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This episode focuses on the mindset and strategies that investors should adopt in the context of current market volatility and volatile international situations. James emphasizes that for long-term investors, short-term market fluctuations, macroeconomic conditions, and even wars should not be of excessive concern. The core strategy should be to insist on buying high-quality index funds (such as Nasdaq 100 QQQ) and holding them for the long term, never selling. At the same time, he shares an updated Excel financial simulation tool, discusses pre-retirement withdrawal strategies, leverage management, the significant advantages of early Roth conversion, and how to build a strong investment psychology to cope with external pressure and complex information.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">II. Briefing Content 
    <div id="ii-briefing-content" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii-briefing-content" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Core Investment Philosophy and Market Views 
    <div id="core-investment-philosophy-and-market-views" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#core-investment-philosophy-and-market-views" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Ignore the Noise, Keep Buying:</strong> Macro factors such as market volatility, international situations, tariff wars, trade wars, hot wars, and cold wars have little to do with long-term investing. Investors cannot and do not need to predict or respond to them. Just keep buying index funds (QQQ) and holding them for the long term.</li>
<li><strong>Halving is Inevitable:</strong> In the long-term investment process, a 50% or even greater reduction in assets is an inevitable event, not a matter of probability, but a certainty. Investors need to be psychologically prepared and ensure that they can still &ldquo;survive&rdquo; in this situation. Ask yourself every day: &ldquo;If the market halves again, can I still hold on?&rdquo;</li>
<li><strong>Long-Termism and Optimistic Mindset:</strong> Investing requires patience, and wealth is worth waiting for. The market always goes up in the long run. Investors should always be extremely optimistic, even if the market drops 80%, because the decline is part of the investment process, and the future is always bright. Buying is for future gains, not for leaving the market out of fear of future declines.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Excel Tool Updates and Applications (Refer to Lecture Notes from Page 18) 
    <div id="excel-tool-updates-and-applications-refer-to-lecture-notes-from-page-18" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#excel-tool-updates-and-applications-refer-to-lecture-notes-from-page-18" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Origin and Background of the Problem:</strong>
<ul>
<li>Some students reported problems with the old Excel version: 1) Increasing the spending ratio may actually reduce the final assets; 2) After a significant increase in assets (such as from 1 million to 4 million), spending directly at 2% of the new assets (i.e., 80,000) failed the stress test when simulating the 2000 tech bubble burst.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Main Updates and Usage Suggestions:</strong>
<ol>
<li><strong>Separating Spending and Rebalancing Ratios:</strong> Corrected the error of linking the spending ratio with the smart rebalancing ratio. The new version allows independent settings. It is recommended that the smart rebalancing ratio remain at 2% or be adjusted according to individual risk tolerance.</li>
<li><strong>New Strategy for Increasing Spending After Asset Growth (0.8% Rule):</strong>
<ul>
<li><strong>Simulation Conclusion:</strong> If assets increase significantly (such as from 1 million to 4.6 million, net worth 3.8 million, and borrowing 780,000 accounting for 17% of total assets), spending directly at 2% of the new assets (80,000/year) is too risky.</li>
<li><strong>Safety Recommendation:</strong> When assets have increased by more than <strong>2.5 times</strong> and the pledged loan ratio is controlled within <strong>20%</strong>, consider increasing the annual spending to <strong>0.7% or 0.8% of the new total assets</strong>. For example, assets of 4.6 million can spend about 36,800/year (4.6 million * 0.8%). After this adjustment, even if you encounter a market shock similar to 2000, you can maintain a sufficient margin of safety. This means that if assets grow 2.5 times, the annual spending can safely increase by about 2.2 times.</li>
<li><strong>Operation Guide (Using the &ldquo;Practice Version&rdquo; Excel):</strong>
<ul>
<li>Enter &ldquo;Scenario Nine&rdquo; (applicable to situations where you have started pledged borrowing and spending).</li>
<li>Modify the &ldquo;Amount Already Borrowed&rdquo; in the &ldquo;Personal Information&rdquo; or &ldquo;Scenario Eight Nine Information&rdquo; area in the front of the table (<strong>do not directly change the S2 cell inside Excel, go to the overview page in front to change it</strong>).</li>
<li>Return to the scenario nine simulation page and modify the initial asset allocation ratio (such as QQQ 33%, QLD/Leverage 45%, Cash 22%).</li>
<li>Adjust the &ldquo;Borrowing Expenses&rdquo; percentage (located in column T, such as changing to 0.8 or 0.7).</li>
<li>Adjust the &ldquo;Borrowing Interest&rdquo; according to the actual situation (cell S5, such as setting it to 3% for Taiwan).</li>
<li>Observe the &ldquo;Minimum Maintenance Rate&rdquo; (or &ldquo;Minimum Equity Ratio&rdquo;) in the results and ensure that it is higher than your set safety threshold (such as 150% or 160%).</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Cash Interest Assumption:</strong> When calculating the compound interest on the Cash portion in Excel, the interest rate used is half of the borrowing rate (S5) (i.e., <code>S5/2/12</code> calculated monthly). This is based on the conservative assumption that the deposit rate is usually lower than the borrowing rate and does not need to be modified.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li><strong>Version Description:</strong> Provides &ldquo;Easy Version&rdquo; (only needs to fill in the initial total assets, smart rebalancing %, and annual spending %) and &ldquo;Practice Version&rdquo; (allows you to modify more detailed parameters inside Excel, such as initial allocation ratio, profit transfer ratio, initial borrowing ratio/amount, withholding cash ratio, etc.). To perform detailed simulations and parameter adjustments, you need to use the &ldquo;Practice Version.&rdquo;</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Early Retirement and Roth Conversion (Refer to Lecture Notes on Page 20) 
    <div id="early-retirement-and-roth-conversion-refer-to-lecture-notes-on-page-20" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#early-retirement-and-roth-conversion-refer-to-lecture-notes-on-page-20" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Scenario Analysis:</strong> Compare a couple aged 50 with 2 million in Traditional IRA, expected return of 14%, and tax rate of 24%, under three different Roth conversion strategies for the long term (to age 100).
<ul>
<li>Scenario 1: No conversion, relying on RMD. The final assets are approximately <strong>330 million</strong>.</li>
<li>Scenario 2: Work until age 56 and then start converting. The final assets are approximately <strong>350 million</strong>.</li>
<li>Scenario 3: Retire immediately at age 50 and start converting. The final assets are as high as <strong>780 million</strong>.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Core Conclusion:</strong> Retiring 6 years early to perform Roth conversion, utilizing the low tax bracket window in the early stage of retirement, can bring more than <strong>300 million USD</strong> in additional wealth. Even for high-income earners (assuming a conversion tax rate of 40%), it takes an additional 9-10 years of work to make up for the huge opportunity cost of not converting early. <strong>It is strongly recommended that those who meet the conditions plan and execute Roth conversion as soon as possible.</strong></li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Financial System Operation and Personal Financial Wisdom 
    <div id="financial-system-operation-and-personal-financial-wisdom" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#financial-system-operation-and-personal-financial-wisdom" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Make Good Use of Financial Tools (Transmissive Power):</strong> Specifically pointed out that Taiwan&rsquo;s low interest rate environment provides investors with favorable conditions to use borrowing (pledged loans, etc.) to amplify investment returns (transmissive power).</li>
<li><strong>Bank Perspective and Customer Relationships:</strong> Banks view deposits as liabilities and loans as assets. They are happy to see customers borrow and pay interest on time. Large borrowing customers are VIPs of the bank and enjoy preferential treatment; ordinary depositors need to go through regular procedures.</li>
<li><strong>Wealth Circulation Mechanism:</strong> Commercial banks play an intermediary role in the capitalist system, transferring the idle funds (deposits) of risk-averse/non-investors to investors (borrowers) who are willing to take risks and know how to use funds, and earn interest spreads from them. Understanding this mechanism helps investors use leverage more confidently.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Investment Psychological Construction and Philosophy of Life 
    <div id="investment-psychological-construction-and-philosophy-of-life" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#investment-psychological-construction-and-philosophy-of-life" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Coping with External Pressure:</strong> When facing the worries or doubts of family and friends when the market falls, you need to build a strong inner self:
<ul>
<li><strong>Self-Belief:</strong> First of all, you must be firm in your investment philosophy and understand that volatility is a normal process.</li>
<li><strong>Shielding and Transcendence:</strong> Practice from the realm of &ldquo;not listening, not seeing, does not exist&rdquo; to &ldquo;both seeing and listening but also does not exist,&rdquo; that is, the inner self is not disturbed by external words.</li>
<li><strong>Positive Attitude:</strong> Show confidence and a good state to the outside world (&ldquo;I&rsquo;m fine, no problem, the market will rise&rdquo;).</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Decluttering and Value Ordering (Refer to Video 00351 &ldquo;Enlightenment&rdquo;):</strong>
<ul>
<li>Life should be simplified, and clarifying what you &ldquo;don&rsquo;t want&rdquo; is more important than what you &ldquo;want.&rdquo; Reducing unnecessary material pursuits and social relationships can bring more freedom and focus.</li>
<li>Reflect on the core values of life, such as &ldquo;relationships,&rdquo; &ldquo;sense of contribution,&rdquo; &ldquo;health,&rdquo; and &ldquo;soul&rdquo; shared by students, and work is only a part of it.</li>
<li>Get rid of the shackles of seeking external recognition (refer to &ldquo;The Courage to be Disliked&rdquo;).</li>
<li>Love and responsibility for children are the fundamental values that many people find difficult to give up.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Beware of Information Cocoons (Refer to Video 00420 Logic Class):</strong>
<ul>
<li>Realize that we may all be trapped in &ldquo;information cocoons&rdquo; by network algorithms, only accessing homogeneous information, resulting in a narrow vision and loss of independent thinking ability, like &ldquo;parrots&rdquo; repeating views.</li>
<li>Actively seek different information sources, use <strong>critical thinking</strong>, especially the ability to <strong>falsify</strong>, and maintain skepticism about the information received (first assume that 99% is wrong).</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">III. Q&amp;A Session 
    <div id="iii-qa-session" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii-qa-session" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Lily 
    <div id="lily" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#lily" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Share:</strong> Taiwanese firefighter, 40 years old, new investor (started in February), adopting a 442 allocation (40% QQQ, 40% leverage, 20% cash), investing approximately 6 million. Recently experienced a large single-day drop of 28% in the leveraged portion, but stated that they could withstand it. Few friends shared the same philosophy. Believes that never selling can achieve financial freedom.
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Comments:</strong> Thank you for sharing. The 442 allocation is more aggressive, and this decline is a good stress test. Reminded that firefighting work is physically demanding, and investment should focus more on stability. Suggested adjusting the allocation according to their own comfort level, such as 433 or more conservative 424 or even 505. The primary goal of asset allocation is to make yourself &ldquo;comfortable&rdquo; and able to hold it for the long term. Cash is the key to &ldquo;surviving.&rdquo; When facing external doubts, maintaining a strong inner self and confidence is the most important.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Rui 
    <div id="rui" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#rui" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Share:</strong>
<ol>
<li><strong>Life Reflections:</strong> Reviewing last week&rsquo;s homework, combined with &ldquo;How Will You Measure Your Life?&rdquo; and Brian Dyson&rsquo;s five-ball theory, clarified that the second value of life is &ldquo;relationships,&rdquo; &ldquo;sense of contribution,&rdquo; and &ldquo;treating nature well&rdquo;; emphasized the irreplaceability of health, family, friendship, and soul; the current most wanted to get rid of is &ldquo;seeking recognition from others&rdquo;; believed that life regrets often stem from &ldquo;things not done.&rdquo;</li>
<li><strong>Origin of Excel Questions:</strong> Deeply studied Excel and discovered problems due to concerns about smart rebalancing causing Beta to continue to rise (such as &gt;1.2) and wanting to increase living expenses (at 2% of new assets) after asset growth.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li><strong>Question:</strong> Can leveraged ETFs (such as 00670L) commonly used by Taiwanese investors be included in the Excel model to calculate the maintenance rate (market value)? If included, even with a higher Beta (such as 1.24), it seems that a 433 allocation can pass the test.
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response:</strong>
<ul>
<li><strong>Philosophy of Life:</strong> Appreciated the in-depth thinking. Emphasized the importance of &ldquo;decluttering&rdquo; and clarifying &ldquo;what not to want.&rdquo; Agreed that there is no need for others to recognize, and shared that they value their relationship with their children the most. Recommended video 00351 &ldquo;Enlightenment.&rdquo;</li>
<li><strong>Excel and Taiwan Applications:</strong> Theoretically, the market value of leveraged ETFs can be included in the maintenance rate calculation. The existing model is based on the US situation and is conservative (high interest rate assumptions, not explicitly including the market value of leverage), aimed at being universal and safe. Taiwanese investors can take advantage of the no capital gains tax (easy to reduce leverage) and lower interest rates, and modify Excel themselves (such as changing the interest rate and adjusting the maintenance rate formula) to better fit reality. If the model can pass, it is usually easier in Taiwan. Thanked them for their question, which prompted the optimization of the &ldquo;how to increase spending after asset growth&rdquo; strategy (0.7%-0.8% rule or reducing leverage).</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Yaowen 
    <div id="yaowen" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#yaowen" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Question:</strong> Observed that the recovery time of historical bear markets seems to be shortening. Combined with the evolution of US financial policies (QE, pandemic response, etc.), does it mean that the government&rsquo;s control efficiency has improved and the market recovery is accelerating?
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response:</strong> Agreed with the observation. With the accumulation of financial theory and practical experience, policy tools are more effective, and the ability to respond to known crises has indeed increased, shortening the recovery period. But the real risk lies in <strong>unknown, unprecedented crises</strong>. There is no need to worry too much about known patterns, and be optimistic about the future but have risk awareness.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Weijun 
    <div id="weijun" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#weijun" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Share:</strong> 433 allocation is already All in. Although they thought they were prepared, when actually facing the decline, it was difficult to bear the pressure from their parents&rsquo; &ldquo;caring&rdquo; worries, and they were even afraid to tell them about the losses. Glad that this decline occurred when the invested proportion was not yet high.</li>
<li><strong>Question:</strong> How to cope with this kind of caring pressure from relatives and friends (especially parents)? (Especially for office workers who cannot physically avoid it like retirees).
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response:</strong> Cannot control others, only cultivate the inner self. From shielding information (&ldquo;not listening, not seeing, does not exist&rdquo;) to the inner self not being disturbed (&ldquo;both seeing and listening but also does not exist&rdquo;). The key is to have firm self-belief, understand the current situation, and show confidence to the outside world (&ldquo;I&rsquo;m fine&rdquo;). The decline is the norm for investing, or a good opportunity to rebalance. When the inner self is strong enough to realize a certain illusion of the external world, its influence can be reduced.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">JJ 
    <div id="jj" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#jj" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Question:</strong> Expressed concerns about the US&rsquo;s leading position in technology, listed multiple negative information (loss of scientists, tightening of visas, damage to funding/independence of research institutions, anti-vaccine stance of the Minister of Health and public health incidents), and asked about the impact of the US losing its position as a technology center on QQQ investment and whether it is necessary to adjust the strategy.
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response:</strong>
<ul>
<li><strong>Macro Level:</strong> Refer to video 00430C. Admitted that global competition is intensifying, but the US has not declined, and the foundation of technological strength remains. The US democratic system has resilience and self-correcting ability, and there is no need to be overly pessimistic due to short-term policies or personnel changes.</li>
<li><strong>Investment Indicators:</strong> The criteria for judgment is the composition of the top ten technology companies in the world by market value. If it is still dominated by the United States, then there is no need to change the strategy. If the future pattern changes significantly (such as non-US companies accounting for more than half), consider adjusting the proportion accordingly. Unlikely to happen within 50 years.</li>
<li><strong>Specific Concerns:</strong> Much information may be amplified or biased (information cocoon effect). Believe in the basic integrity system and institutional resilience of American society. Individual incidents (such as anti-vaccine rhetoric, measles outbreaks), while worrying, are unlikely to subvert the entire system. Stay focused, but don&rsquo;t panic, and focus on verifiable facts.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">David 
    <div id="david" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#david" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Share and Response:</strong>
<ol>
<li>Questioned the information mentioned by JJ, emphasizing the need to verify the source and scientific nature of the information (such as the measles vaccine issue), and compared the different practices of China and the United States in areas such as autonomous driving, pointing out the prudence and regulatory constraints in the US system.</li>
<li>Questioned the authenticity of reports about cuts in social welfare (lack of examples).</li>
<li>Cited historical data from the 2018 trade war to prove that the US market and economic regulation are more resilient than China.</li>
<li>Suggested actively searching for reverse information and historical data to overcome fear.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Comments:</strong> Highly praised David&rsquo;s emphasis on information discrimination. Further elaborated on the dangers of <strong>information cocoons</strong>, which deprive people of independent thinking ability and turn them into <strong>parrots</strong>. Called on everyone to be vigilant, actively break down information barriers, and use <strong>critical thinking</strong> and <strong>falsification</strong> methods (refer to video 00420 Logic Class) to examine information.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Tony 
    <div id="tony" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#tony" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Question:</strong> Why is the annual borrowing rate (S5) divided by 2 in the monthly compound interest calculation of the cash portion in the Excel practice version?
<ul>
<li><strong>James/慶 (Qing) Response:</strong> This is the design assumption of the model: The <strong>deposit rate</strong> (cash yield) is set to half of the <strong>borrowing rate</strong>. This is a simplified, conservative estimate that reflects the reality of the bank&rsquo;s deposit and loan interest rate spread. The formula <code>principal * (1 + S5/2/12)</code> is correct, reflecting this safety margin, and does not need to be modified.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">IV. Wonderful Views 
    <div id="iv-wonderful-views" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv-wonderful-views" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>Market volatility, international situations, trade wars, hot and cold wars&hellip; have nothing to do with our investment, just buy, don&rsquo;t sell. Long-term is investment.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Background: Emphasizes that long-term investment should focus on holding high-quality assets, ignoring short-term market noise and macro events.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>You will definitely encounter several opportunities for asset depreciation of 50% in the market, this is not a probability problem, this is a certainty.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Background: Reminds investors that a significant market correction is an inevitable part of long-term investment and that they need to be psychologically and financially prepared for it.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Asset allocation is not done for performance, asset allocation is done for your comfort.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Background: Explains that the primary goal of asset allocation (especially the proportion of cash holdings) is to ensure that investors can hold it with peace of mind and get through the cycle, rather than simply pursuing the highest returns.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Commercial banks are intermediaries that transfer the money of the poor to the rich for use, and this revolving door takes place in banks. This is the reason why the capitalist system makes the poor poorer and the rich richer.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Background: Reveals the core role of the modern banking system in capital flow and its impact on the wealth distribution pattern.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>People who borrow money are VIPs&hellip; those who don&rsquo;t have much money and don&rsquo;t borrow money, please go to the counter to draw a number and line up.
&ndash; James (quoting student Benson&rsquo;s observation)</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Background: Vividly compares the vast difference in the way banks treat large borrowing customers and ordinary depositors.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>You push out all the things you don&rsquo;t want first&hellip; then what are the things you have left that you want? It&rsquo;s very little&hellip; the less you want, the less homework you have.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Background: Applies the concept of &ldquo;decluttering&rdquo; to life planning, advocating that by reducing desires and unnecessary pursuits, inner freedom and focus can be achieved.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>We are besieged by the network and locked in an information prison, you can&rsquo;t break out&hellip; all our thoughts are not our thoughts&hellip; we are all parrots.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Background: Deeply warns of the erosion of individual cognition and independent thinking ability by &ldquo;information cocoons,&rdquo; calling for vigilance.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Both seeing and listening but also does not exist.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Background: Describes an advanced state of psychological practice, where even when exposed to negative or disturbing information, the inner self can remain calm and unaffected.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Things that have happened in the past are less worried about, we are worried about things that have never happened before.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Background: Distinguishes between known and unknown risks, pointing out that historical experience helps to deal with recurring crises, but the real challenge lies in dealing with new, unknown shocks.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>If you retire six years early (to perform Roth conversion), you will be short of 300 million (USD).
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Background: Based on simulation calculation results, strongly emphasizes the huge long-term wealth effect that can be brought about by using the low tax rate window to convert Roth IRA/401k as early as possible.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">V. Summary 
    <div id="v-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#v-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This lecture, against the background of increased market volatility, strengthened the core concept of long-term investment: ignore the noise and insist on holding high-quality index funds (QQQ). James not only updated and explained in detail the important financial planning tool Excel model (especially the adjustment of withdrawal strategies after asset growth), but also persuasively demonstrated the amazing value of doing Roth conversion as early as possible. At a deeper level, the course focused on the construction of investment psychology, discussed how to understand and use financial system rules, how to cope with external pressure (worries from relatives and friends, social information) with a strong inner self, and especially emphasized the extreme importance of maintaining independent thinking and being wary of &ldquo;information cocoons&rdquo; in the era of information explosion. The ultimate goal is to help investors cultivate both their inner skills and achieve a double improvement in cognition and mindset on the road to pursuing financial freedom.</p>

  



<div
  
    class="flex px-4 py-3 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900"
  >

  <span
    
      class="text-primary-400 ltr:pr-3 rtl:pl-3 flex items-center"
    >

    

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M506.3 417l-213.3-364c-16.33-28-57.54-28-73.98 0l-213.2 364C-10.59 444.9 9.849 480 42.74 480h426.6C502.1 480 522.6 445 506.3 417zM232 168c0-13.25 10.75-24 24-24S280 154.8 280 168v128c0 13.25-10.75 24-23.1 24S232 309.3 232 296V168zM256 416c-17.36 0-31.44-14.08-31.44-31.44c0-17.36 14.07-31.44 31.44-31.44s31.44 14.08 31.44 31.44C287.4 401.9 273.4 416 256 416z"/></svg>

  </span>


  </span>

  <span
    
      class="dark:text-neutral-300"
    ><strong>Disclaimer:</strong> This article is only a personal study note and does not constitute any investment advice.</span>
</div>

]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>00511 Risk and Cash Are the Real Starting Points for Investing</title>
      <link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1744504450104/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1744504450104/</guid>
      <description>In this episode, James emphasizes that in any market environment, the primary consideration for investing is having sufficient cash reserves, followed by holding index funds for the long term. He discusses risk tolerance, asset allocation models (such as 433 and 424), the principles for using leveraged funds, and caution regarding paid groups and conflicts of interest. Students share their experiences and questions regarding market volatility, tax planning, retirement preparation, and more.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<lite-youtube videoid="xmD_sz5rYlU" playlabel="xmD_sz5rYlU" params=""></lite-youtube>



<h2 class="relative group">I. Current Theme 
    <div id="i-current-theme" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-current-theme" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>The core viewpoint of this episode emphasizes that investment decisions should be <strong>independent of market volatility</strong>, with <strong>sufficient cash reserves</strong> serving as the first step and cornerstone of investment planning. After determining the cash level based on individual risk tolerance and living needs, then proceed with long-term (15+ years) investment in index funds (especially the Nasdaq 100). Beta is a result of asset allocation, not the starting point. At the same time, be wary of various risks in investment, especially cognitive risks and behavioral biases, and remain vigilant about conflicts of interest in financial services.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">II. Briefing Content 
    <div id="ii-briefing-content" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii-briefing-content" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Market Volatility and Long-Term Perspective 
    <div id="market-volatility-and-long-term-perspective" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#market-volatility-and-long-term-perspective" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Market fluctuations are normal. Having experienced multiple major crashes (2000, 2008, 2020, 2022), the current volatility is relatively mild.</li>
<li>In the long run, most of the current concerns will &ldquo;leave no trace.&rdquo; Don&rsquo;t panic over short-term events. Time is the best medicine, but people are prone to repeating mistakes (old habits die hard).</li>
<li>Investing is a long-term matter (15+ years), and dips are buying opportunities. James has been investing for 40 years and has never &ldquo;seen&rdquo; a market crash, only buying opportunities.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Core Investment Principles 
    <div id="core-investment-principles" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#core-investment-principles" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Focus on Doing the Right Things:</strong> The core is &ldquo;Han Xin Counts Soldiers&rdquo; (i.e., using affordable and safe borrowing, such as mortgages and credit lines, for investment), putting borrowed money into the market, but with sufficient cash reserves.</li>
<li><strong>Investment Targets:</strong> Only invest in the Nasdaq 100 index fund (such as QQQ, 00662, 513100, etc.), as it represents human growth and innovation and has a self-evolving mechanism of survival of the fittest. Related materials are linked on page 10 of the handout. It is mentioned that HXQ and other Nasdaq 100-based funds may outperform QQQ in certain periods.</li>
<li><strong>Long-Term Holding:</strong> Holding for 15+ years after purchase is key, &ldquo;never selling.&rdquo; Only inaction can lead to wealth, not frequent trading.</li>
<li><strong>Stay Optimistic:</strong> Investment is based on confidence in the long-term development of humanity.</li>
<li><strong>Independent Learning:</strong> Investment requires self-study, understanding the reasons behind the strategy and the then-current market environment, and not blindly following.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Asset Allocation: Cash First 
    <div id="asset-allocation-cash-first" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#asset-allocation-cash-first" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Primary Question:</strong> The first step in investing is not what to buy, but <strong>how much cash needs to be retained</strong> to live securely and cope with emergencies. This is the most important thing.</li>
<li><strong>Cash Needs Determine Allocation:</strong>
<ul>
<li><strong>Young People:</strong> First, prepare an emergency fund (e.g., NT$400,000/CNY100,000), and only invest surplus funds.</li>
<li><strong>Asset Allocation Model Examples:</strong>
<ul>
<li><strong>433 (Beta 1.0):</strong> 40% Index + 30% Leverage + 30% Cash. Requires 30% Cash &gt; Emergency Fund (e.g., NT$400,000), requiring total assets of NT$1.33 million to implement.</li>
<li><strong>424 (Beta 0.8):</strong> 40% Index + 20% Leverage + 40% Cash. Requires 40% Cash &gt; Emergency Fund (e.g., NT$400,000), requiring total assets of NT$1 million to implement. Illustrates that reducing Beta can lower the funding threshold.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>High-Net-Worth Individuals:</strong> The principle is the same, determine the cash ratio according to personal comfort (potentially millions of RMB or hundreds of thousands of USD).</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Beta is the Result, Not the Goal:</strong> First determine cash needs and risk tolerance, naturally forming the allocation ratio, and finally calculate the Beta value as a measurement tool. Don&rsquo;t set a target Beta from the beginning.</li>
<li><strong>Allocation Irrelevant Factors:</strong> Asset allocation is <strong>unrelated</strong> to age, fund size, or market level, only related to how to prevent accidents and how much accident can be tolerated.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Risk Management and Cognition 
    <div id="risk-management-and-cognition" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#risk-management-and-cognition" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Risk Tolerance:</strong>
<ul>
<li>Young people have less experience, so risk tolerance may not be high, and should not blindly pursue high Beta (e.g., 442).</li>
<li>Wealthy people are usually more conservative, pursuing stability rather than extreme returns (Beta 0.5 may be sufficient).</li>
<li>Conclusion: Taking risks beyond your tolerance is foolish. Investment is like eating spicy food, do what you can handle.</li>
<li>Recommendation: Start conservatively. If you believe you can tolerate Beta 1.2, start with 1.0; if you believe you can tolerate 1.0, start with 0.8.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Leveraged Fund Usage Principles:</strong> The ratio of leveraged funds should not exceed the ratio of cash or the ratio of the original fund. This suggests that a 442 allocation (40% Index + 40% Leverage + 20% Cash) is not suitable for most people.</li>
<li><strong>Behavioral Biases:</strong> Retail investors often feel sad when the market falls (regret buying early) and also sad when the market rises (regret not going all-in). The correct allocation should achieve &ldquo;happy when it rises, comfortable when it falls,&rdquo; maintaining &ldquo;immovability.&rdquo;</li>
<li><strong>Individual Stock Risk:</strong> No company lasts forever (examples: Intel, Kodak, Blackberry), individual stock risk is high. Index funds mitigate individual stock risk through a mechanism of survival of the fittest.</li>
<li><strong>Borrowing Risk:</strong>
<ul>
<li><strong>Safe Borrowing:</strong> Mortgages, credit lines (Han Xin Counts Soldiers), assuming income can cover monthly payments, unrelated to market fluctuations.</li>
<li><strong>Dangerous Borrowing:</strong> Margin trading, stock-pledged reinvestment. Market declines can lead to forced liquidation or even bankruptcy. <strong>These operations are strictly prohibited.</strong></li>
<li>James&rsquo;s pledge loan: Based on holding cash far exceeding debt, ensuring absolute security.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Specific Funds Use Risk:</strong> Money earmarked for short-term use (e.g., down payment on a house) within a short period (e.g., 3 years) <strong>absolutely cannot</strong> be invested in the stock market. Someone recently defaulted because of this.</li>
<li><strong>Tax Risk:</strong> Tax planning is very important and can affect significant wealth. Rules need to be carefully studied (e.g., the application of the U.S. Wash Sale Rule across accounts).</li>
<li><strong>Spending Ability Mindset:</strong> True &ldquo;affordability&rdquo; means being able to easily repurchase an item if it breaks down, as in James&rsquo;s example of replacing a juicer. Large expenditures (e.g., buying a house) should also have this mindset, otherwise the risk is too high.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Be Wary of Paid Services and Conflicts of Interest 
    <div id="be-wary-of-paid-services-and-conflicts-of-interest" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#be-wary-of-paid-services-and-conflicts-of-interest" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Firmly Do Not Charge:</strong> James emphasizes that his services are free because charging easily creates conflicts of interest. His YouTube channel also does not have monetization enabled.</li>
<li><strong>Warning Signals:</strong> Be highly vigilant about any paid groups, paid recommendations, or financial services that charge commissions or kickbacks (e.g., account opening, buying funds). Mentions feedback that some groups may be transferring benefits through financial service referrals.</li>
<li><strong>Harm of Conflicts of Interest:</strong> Those who charge may recommend unsuitable or even harmful products/strategies for commissions.</li>
<li><strong>Self-Protection:</strong> Learn independently, compare multiple sources, understand financial products yourself, and do not easily trust introductions. Be especially wary of &ldquo;pits&rdquo; introduced by acquaintances.</li>
<li><strong>U.S. Regulations:</strong> The U.S. prohibits paying commissions to referrers for financial product recommendations (account opening rewards are usually given to the account opener themselves) to prevent conflicts of interest. Regulations may vary in other regions.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Other Suggestions 
    <div id="other-suggestions" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#other-suggestions" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Emergency Fund:</strong> Do not use the emergency fund to buy the dip. Survival is the most important thing.</li>
<li><strong>Regular Investment:</strong> Buy index funds immediately with new income (e.g., salary).</li>
<li><strong>Financial Literacy:</strong> Financial intelligence requires learning, there are no shortcuts. Be wary of the &ldquo;get rich quick&rdquo; mentality. Discuss with his daughter the mindset of speculators: it may be &ldquo;greed,&rdquo; it may be &ldquo;poverty,&rdquo; or it may be &ldquo;not wanting to get rich slowly.&rdquo;</li>
<li><strong>Video Viewing:</strong> New friends are advised to watch video #451, then start from #398 (January 2023) and watch in order.</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">III. Q&amp;A Session 
    <div id="iii-qa-session" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii-qa-session" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">CAD 
    <div id="cad" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#cad" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing:
<ol>
<li>Observed that regardless of wealth, some people are keen on short-term trading, possibly due to addictive pleasure or a sense of accomplishment. Poor people may say they need quick returns, while rich people may enjoy the process.</li>
<li>Emphasized the strict prohibition of margin trading or stock-pledged reinvestment. Recently, with the market decline, someone was forced to liquidate and even became indebted because of it. Compared this to his own use of credit lines/mortgages for investment, stating that as long as he can afford the monthly payments, the market decline does not affect his survival.</li>
<li>Mentioned a senior who was forced to liquidate due to margin calls during the Kuo Wan-Jung incident (Taiwan stock market historical event) and has been in debt ever since, warning future generations.</li>
<li><strong>Important Reminder:</strong> When observing an investment portfolio, you should pay attention to the <strong>fluctuation range of the overall assets</strong> rather than just staring at the leveraged portion with the biggest decline, which helps manage emotions.</li>
</ol>
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Comment: Agreed. Explained the risk of illiquidity under the Taiwan stock market&rsquo;s limit-down mechanism, compared to the U.S. market. Re-emphasized the danger of margin/pledge reinvestment. Explained that while he uses pledge loans, he holds cash far exceeding his debt to ensure security. Criticized putting house-buying money into the stock market as ignoring risk.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">BG 
    <div id="bg" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#bg" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing:
<ol>
<li>Agreed that money management (cash ratio, position control) takes precedence over buying and selling signals.</li>
<li>Money management should start from oneself (capital amount, risk tolerance willingness).</li>
<li>Backtesting is not just to verify signals, but also to understand the money drawdown of the strategy under historical market conditions, to adjust positions to suit one&rsquo;s own tolerance.</li>
<li>Under the buy-and-hold strategy, investment funds must be strictly separated from living funds to avoid affecting long-term investment plans and mentality due to living needs.</li>
</ol>
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Comment: Distinguished between strategy (long-term goals, cash planning, asset class allocation) and tactics (specific buying and selling points, short-term adjustments). Emphasized that tactics should not interfere with strategy, for example, one should not liquidate due to market panic or use the emergency fund to buy the dip.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Rui 
    <div id="rui" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#rui" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing:
<ol>
<li>Thanked James for solving many investment confusions (cash first, the use of leverage, asset allocation, etc.) through learning videos.</li>
<li>Adopted the teacher&rsquo;s advice and used 2% of his assets (through pledging) to pay for the Tesla purchase.</li>
<li>After adopting the 433 allocation, he felt excited when the market fell, in contrast to the panic of his colleagues.</li>
<li>Used a brokerage account (transfer from Yuantai Securities) that does not show the cost price, which helped reduce anxiety.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>Questions:
<ol>
<li>Has reached the retirement goal (50x annual expenses), but his current salary is equivalent to 6% of total assets. He hopes for a higher retirement replacement rate in the future (assets need to increase by another 2-3 times). Between 433 (30% cash + 2% withdrawal) and 442 (20% cash + no withdrawal), how to further think about the choice from the perspective of safety and applicability?</li>
<li>(Implicit question) Should he continue working for a sense of accomplishment, or retire early?</li>
</ol>
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Response:</li>
</ul>
<ol>
<li><strong>Regarding Purchasing the Car:</strong> Praised his use of &ldquo;non-own funds&rdquo; for consumption, pointing out that being able to borrow money is itself a manifestation of wealth, the key is controllable risk (sufficient cash).</li>
<li><strong>Regarding Retirement Choices:</strong> This is a classic question. Cited another case to illustrate that early retirement may bring huge benefits due to tax planning (such as Roth conversions). Suggested that Rui reflect: if work had no salary or recognition, would he still want to go? The value of work may change with stage, and there may be new pursuits in the future. Looking back from age 90, would he regret working several more decades? With financial freedom, the work mentality can be more relaxed.</li>
<li><strong>Regarding 433 vs 442 Safety:</strong> Assuming the market goes to zero, which is safer? The answer is the one with a higher cash ratio (433 has 30% cash, 442 has only 20%).</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Kai Xin 
    <div id="kai-xin" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#kai-xin" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question: Regarding whether the interest on the U.S. Pledged Asset Line (PAL, pledge loan) can be tax-deductible, and how to operate? Feels that the rules are complex and there are many restrictions.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Response: The money borrowed from PAL is mainly used for consumption, not reinvestment. The issue of interest tax deduction is complicated and may require adjusting the type of capital gains (e.g., converting long-term to short-term), relying on accountant operations. James himself does not pay attention to this operation because his strategy is to hold a lot of cash, making interest income far exceed PAL interest expenses, and PAL interest is close to zero. The more fundamental strategy is to achieve &ldquo;zero income, zero capital gains,&rdquo; so there is no need to consider tax deduction.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Derek 
    <div id="derek" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#derek" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Thanks to James and the community (Chen Feng, Sister K, etc.). Recently joined, the teacher&rsquo;s reply and teaching made him have the courage to operate according to the plan when the market fell, and deeply realized the importance of risk control. Listening to the teacher&rsquo;s videos can bring a sense of stability.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Comment: This is precisely the reason why he insists on teaching, knowing that it is difficult to succeed in investing alone, and guidance and companionship are needed.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Nai Xi 
    <div id="nai-xi" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#nai-xi" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: As the founding moderator of the Taiwan 00662 community, thanks to James&rsquo;s inspiration three years ago for changing his life. Thanks to all 19 administrators of the community (mentioning the rotation system, member contributions such as Chen Feng bringing it to a new height, Chris developing tools, etc.) for their hard work. Reiterated that he was inspired by the teacher&rsquo;s &ldquo;eliminate poverty&rdquo; mission and hopes to help more people through the community.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Comment: Recalled the meeting with Nai Xi and the community backbone (eighteen arhats), praised their quality and Nai Xi&rsquo;s persistence and humility. Affirmed the value and operation of the 00662 community and regretted that it was limited by the LINE platform and could not cover the world.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Ming Yu 
    <div id="ming-yu" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ming-yu" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: No questions or sharing.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Yao 
    <div id="yao" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#yao" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Mentioned recent rumors about Trump&rsquo;s friends profiting from trade war news, and extended thoughts about the relationship between the morality of politicians and social progress. Lamented that moral constraints are limited, but human technology is still developing.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Comment: Agreed that the world is full of unknowns (quoting Buffett), and the market always has surprises (epidemic circuit breakers, drastic trade war fluctuations). Need to remain humble and prepare for extreme risks (such as market closure/continuous decline for 10-15 years). Re-distinguished between safe borrowing (fixed repayment) and dangerous borrowing (linked to the market).</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Julia 
    <div id="julia" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#julia" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Revealed an American tax trap: the Wash Sale Rule may apply to all accounts (including 401k/IRA and other retirement accounts). If you sell a loss-making asset (such as QQQ) in a taxable account for Tax Loss Harvesting (TLH) and automatically buy a similar asset (such as an SP500 index fund) in a retirement account at the same time, the loss in the taxable account may be permanently disallowed (because retirement accounts are taxed at ordinary income rates when withdrawn, with no capital gains concept). This is especially important for high-tech employees, as they often hold a large number of RSUs and perform TLH.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Comment: Tax issues are extremely important. Pointed out that TLH itself also has risks, such as the market rebounding after selling, making it impossible to buy back the original asset (QQQ) at an ideal price, or generating new capital gains when buying back. If James himself has no need (such as no capital gains without selling stocks), he tends to let the loss carry forward and deduct $3,000 of ordinary income each year, rather than use it to offset capital gains. However, for Julia, who needs to offset a large amount of RSU capital gains, TLH is a reasonable strategy and needs to be operated carefully. Discussed the problem of high tax rates in California. Re-emphasized the ultimate goal of pursuing a zero-tax state, and the value of tax planning far exceeds the salary itself.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">DDF 
    <div id="ddf" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ddf" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question: Asked about the risk of the Pacific War two years ago, at that time the teacher suggested reducing 50% of QQQ. Now that he has adopted the strategy of holding a large amount of cash (such as 433/424), can he withstand this type of risk, insist on holding it and rebalancing at the end of the year, without selling in the middle?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Response: The evolution of the strategy is because the introduction of leveraged instruments allows holding a large amount of cash more effectively. The core risk management issue is not specific events (wars, disasters, etc.), but <strong>whether it is possible to survive in extreme market conditions (such as closure/deep decline for 10-15 years)</strong>. If cash reserves are sufficient to support such a long time, there is no need to make predictive operations for specific events. Comparing risks: for young people, the risk of carrying a mortgage and facing unemployment + market decline may be more realistic and fatal than the risk of war. Buying a house should be as easy and stress-free as buying slippers to be considered affordable.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Jason 
    <div id="jason" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#jason" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Summarized two major investment risks:
<ol>
<li><strong>Choosing the wrong asset:</strong> The market is full of various temptations, choosing a high-quality asset for the long term (such as QQQ) is the foundation. Thanks to the teacher for continuing to emphasize this.</li>
<li><strong>Missing the upside:</strong> Statistics show that missing the 10 days with the biggest market gains (in the past 20 years) will cut total returns in half. These big rally days often occur during periods of extreme panic (such as 2008, 2020). This confirms the importance of the &ldquo;never sell&rdquo; strategy to avoid timing the market.</li>
</ol>
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Comment: Highly Agreed. Defined <strong>the real, permanent loss</strong> as <strong>the returns that should have been earned but were not</strong> (such as missing a 12% rally). Book losses caused by market declines are temporary and will recover. Compared buying QQQ at a high point (540) with buying at a low point (440), the difference in annualized returns after holding for 40 years is extremely small (11.98% vs 12.5%), indicating that the timing of the purchase is not important, but long-term holding is key. Use a long-term perspective (40 years later) to review current decisions.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Jing 
    <div id="jing" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#jing" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question: Approaching retirement, but savings have not reached the 30-50x target. There is a stable high income in the next 5 years, and Pension/Social Security will cover most expenses after retirement. Does not use pledging due to concerns about risk. Can I not retain 20% cash and take a 100% stock holding strategy, relying on future income, emergency fund, and future pledgeable options to accelerate asset growth?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Response: <strong>No.</strong> Risk tolerance decreases as retirement approaches, the time window is short, and you should be more conservative. Since the Pension already covers most of the expenses, the urgency for asset growth should be reduced. <strong>The most aggressive allocation for retirement or near retirement, without using pledges and without holding leveraged funds, is 80% QQQ + 20% cash.</strong> Pension should be regarded as a stable source of income, and when calculating the total amount of retirement funds required, the <strong>Pension portion should be deducted</strong> from annual expenses first, and then the remaining net expenditure needs should be multiplied by a multiple (such as 30 or 50 times). If you hold leveraged funds, you must sell them and deal with tax issues before retirement.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Frank (from the comments section) 
    <div id="frank-from-the-comments-section" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#frank-from-the-comments-section" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question: Should global diversification be carried out?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Response: Not recommended. The U.S. market is optimal in terms of innovation, transparency, and long-term risk-reward ratio. Other markets have higher risks and relatively low return potential. Investing in U.S. index funds is sufficient.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">IV. Wonderful Views 
    <div id="iv-wonderful-views" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv-wonderful-views" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>The first step in investing is not to say, ah, I come in and start, what should the teacher buy, how much leveraged funds should I buy&hellip; No&hellip; The first thing to invest in is how much cash you need, how much cash you need to keep, this is more important than anything.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Background: Emphasizes the primacy of cash reserves in investment planning.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Our strategy has nothing to do with market volatility&hellip; What are investment plans or investments supposed to do? It is to be based on your own risk tolerance&hellip; How much cash is appropriate to keep, this is the first step in investing.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Background: Explains the core concept of his investment strategy, which is not affected by short-term market sentiment.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Beta is naturally formed in the end, not set at the beginning&hellip; So you have to ask the first few questions, how much cash do you keep to feel comfortable&hellip; An accident may come in the next second.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Background: Explains the role of Beta in asset allocation, which is a result, not a goal, emphasizing safety first.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Young people should not take risks, because they lack experience, and rich people do not take risks much&hellip; Coming back to the point, taking risks is not very worthwhile, taking risks beyond what you can afford is just very stupid.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Background: Refutes traditional concepts, pointing out that excessive risk-taking is not advisable, regardless of whether you are young or wealthy.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Don&rsquo;t turn your tactics into a strategy&hellip; It seems that the emergency fund should have been so much, but you, ah, it&rsquo;s dropped so much, quickly buy it all in. That turns tactics into a strategy, you can&rsquo;t do that.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Background: When commenting on student sharing, distinguishes the boundaries between strategic determination and tactical flexibility.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>What you should look at is not your single stock (referring to leveraged ETFs)&hellip; Drops a lot, you should look at the range of fluctuations in your entire asset&hellip; Don&rsquo;t pay too much attention to the part that is dropping the most.
&ndash; CAD (Student)</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Background: Reminds that when holding leveraged ETFs, you should pay attention to the volatility of the overall investment portfolio rather than a single product, to stabilize your mentality.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>What is the real risk of the market? The real risk of the market is your investment return, the real risk is the returns that you should have earned but didn&rsquo;t, that you will never earn&hellip; A drop in losses is not a loss.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Background: Redefines investment risk, emphasizing that opportunity cost (missing the upside) is the real permanent loss.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The risk of buying a house is higher than the risk of war&hellip; If you treat buying a house like buying slippers, then you can buy a house.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Background: Responding to questions about geopolitical risks, compared and pointed out that for ordinary people, financial leverage (such as mortgages) may bring more direct and serious risks.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>If you don&rsquo;t manage your finances and taxes well, you may pay 85% of your assets in taxes in this life, and you actually only get 15%&hellip; Saving taxes can save tens of billions.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Background: When discussing tax planning, emphasizes its huge impact on long-term wealth accumulation.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Because being poor is also right to do speculation&hellip; So it&rsquo;s also right that most people who speculate are poor&hellip; Many people who speculate don&rsquo;t even know it, they don&rsquo;t know what they don&rsquo;t know, which is very strange.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Background: When discussing speculative psychology with his daughter, reflected on the relationship between poverty and greed, and that speculators often lack self-awareness.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">V. Summary 
    <div id="v-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#v-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This lecture once again consolidates James&rsquo;s core investment philosophy: <strong>taking sufficient cash reserves as a prerequisite for ultra-long-term (15+ years) holding of the Nasdaq 100 index fund.</strong> It emphasizes the priority of risk management, especially determining the cash ratio based on individual circumstances and building asset allocation based on this, rather than pursuing a specific Beta value or being driven by market sentiment. The differences in risk perception at different life stages and wealth levels were discussed, and the use of high-risk leverage (such as margin trading) for investment was strongly opposed. In addition, practical advice and warnings were shared on tax planning, retirement preparation, financial service selection, and consumption mentality. The Q&amp;A session delved into the specific problems encountered by students in practice, further clarifying strategy details and risk considerations, such as retirement fund calculation, the view on global diversification, and psychological management techniques (focus on overall portfolio rather than local volatility). Overall, this content revolves around the two words <strong>&ldquo;determination&rdquo;</strong> and <strong>&ldquo;safety,&rdquo;</strong> that is, maintaining strategic determination and financial security in a volatile market, and adhering to the correct principles.</p>

  



<div
  
    class="flex px-4 py-3 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900"
  >

  <span
    
      class="text-primary-400 ltr:pr-3 rtl:pl-3 flex items-center"
    >

    

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M506.3 417l-213.3-364c-16.33-28-57.54-28-73.98 0l-213.2 364C-10.59 444.9 9.849 480 42.74 480h426.6C502.1 480 522.6 445 506.3 417zM232 168c0-13.25 10.75-24 24-24S280 154.8 280 168v128c0 13.25-10.75 24-23.1 24S232 309.3 232 296V168zM256 416c-17.36 0-31.44-14.08-31.44-31.44c0-17.36 14.07-31.44 31.44-31.44s31.44 14.08 31.44 31.44C287.4 401.9 273.4 416 256 416z"/></svg>

  </span>


  </span>

  <span
    
      class="dark:text-neutral-300"
    ><strong>Disclaimer:</strong> This article is only a personal study note and does not constitute any investment advice.</span>
</div>

]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>00509 Don&#39;t Let Greed and Fear Ruin Your Investment Life: Investing Isn&#39;t About Being the Fastest, But About Who Laughs Last</title>
      <link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1743323578617/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1743323578617/</guid>
      <description>In this episode, James discusses the normalcy of market fluctuations, emphasizes the importance of long-term holding of index funds, analyzes the actual situation of U.S. Treasury bonds, and shares insights on asset allocation, leverage use, investment psychology, real estate, children&amp;#39;s education, and consumption concepts.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<lite-youtube videoid="p6vRBnH2VqA" playlabel="p6vRBnH2VqA" params=""></lite-youtube>



<h2 class="relative group">I. Current Theme 
    <div id="i-current-theme" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-current-theme" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>The market is always fluctuating; this is normal. Investors should have a long-term perspective, ignoring short-term volatility and market noise (such as international situations, economic analysis, financial reports, etc.). The core strategy is to hold high-quality index funds (such as QQQ) for the long term, and to make reasonable asset allocation (including cash reserves) based on individual risk tolerance, while overcoming the greed and fear of human nature. Learning and building a firm belief are essential.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">II. Briefing Content 
    <div id="ii-briefing-content" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii-briefing-content" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Market Volatility and Long-Term Investing 
    <div id="market-volatility-and-long-term-investing" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#market-volatility-and-long-term-investing" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Market volatility is normal</strong>: A 10% market drop is normal, 20% happens about every two or three years, and 50% may happen every five to ten years. This is like the tides, wind, rain, and earthquakes in nature; it&rsquo;s an inevitable natural phenomenon. Don&rsquo;t think &ldquo;this year is different&rdquo;; every year is the same.</li>
<li><strong>Importance of a long-term perspective</strong>: As long as you stay in the market long enough, you will understand that there is nothing new in the market. The core laws of the market are &ldquo;always rising&rdquo; and &ldquo;always fluctuating.&rdquo;</li>
<li><strong>Ignore the noise</strong>: Market fluctuations, international situations, market analysis, financial reports, and economic situations are all irrelevant to the decisions of long-term investors.</li>
<li><strong>Recommended strategy</strong>: Hold the Nasdaq 100 index fund (QQQ) for the long term; it can be bought worldwide. This is the simplest and most effective strategy.</li>
<li><strong>Interactive request</strong>: Hope everyone likes, leaves comments, and most importantly, subscribes on various platforms (Podcast, Bilibili, YouTube).</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Learning and Mindset 
    <div id="learning-and-mindset" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#learning-and-mindset" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Learning to build belief</strong>: Investing is simple (buy index funds), but there are many external distractions (monsters and ghosts). You need to build firm belief and willpower through learning, so that you will not be easily swayed by other people&rsquo;s opinions.</li>
<li><strong>Overcoming human weaknesses</strong>: Greed and fear are the biggest enemies of investment.
<ul>
<li><strong>Manifestations of greed</strong>: Chasing high when the market rises, thinking that the opportunity to &ldquo;buy the dip&rdquo; has come when the market falls, and using up all cash too early (e.g., constantly adding positions when the market has just fallen 5%-13%).</li>
<li><strong>Manifestations of fear</strong>: Not daring to buy when the market rises, only FOMOing (fear of missing out) All-in when it has risen too much; panicking when the market falls and selling at a loss at the bottom.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Importance of cash</strong>: Ample cash is a magic weapon to overcome human nature (especially fear), as important as air. It makes you feel comfortable and secure when the market falls. Don&rsquo;t exhaust your cash when the market just starts to fall.</li>
<li><strong>Living in the present</strong>: Don&rsquo;t dwell on past mistakes (such as losses in real estate investment), don&rsquo;t worry too much about future uncertainties, focus on the present, and do your current investment and learning well.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Asset Allocation and Leverage 
    <div id="asset-allocation-and-leverage" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#asset-allocation-and-leverage" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Finding the comfort zone</strong>: Everyone has a different risk tolerance. You need to find your comfortable asset allocation ratio through market fluctuations (such as 442, 433, 523, 514, 505, etc.), and the cash ratio is very important. If you feel uncomfortable when the market falls, you should adjust to a configuration that you can hold with peace of mind during rebounds.</li>
<li><strong>Leverage risk</strong>: Few people can withstand fluctuations of more than 1.2 times Beta. When the market falls, many people will not be able to stand it and reduce leverage. Don&rsquo;t be overconfident in adding leverage when the market is good.
<ul>
<li><strong>Example</strong>: Some people went from 442 to 0.9x leverage or even lower.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Rebalancing</strong>: It is recommended to do rebalancing once a year. Only use a small amount of cash (e.g., 2% per year) to buy if the market is down at the end of the year. Don&rsquo;t operate frequently or exhaust your cash due to monthly or short-term declines.</li>
<li><strong>About full-position leverage</strong>: It is not recommended for young people to use &ldquo;full-position two-times leverage,&rdquo; because there will always be a big bubble in life. High leverage may lead to a significant asset drawdown (e.g., falling to 0.1), which is difficult to recover, and you may reach your goal later than with a stable investment.</li>
<li><strong>Tortoise and hare</strong>: A stable configuration (tortoise) will outperform an aggressive high-leverage strategy (hare) in the long run. Even if the Beta is lower than 1, it doesn&rsquo;t matter.</li>
<li><strong>Purpose of secured borrowing</strong>: The purpose of secured borrowing is not to pursue extreme returns, but to meet living needs or make better configurations while holding high-quality assets for the long term. The risk lies in the ability to repay the principal, not the interest burden.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">U.S. Treasury Bonds and the Economy 
    <div id="us-treasury-bonds-and-the-economy" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#us-treasury-bonds-and-the-economy" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>US Debt Clock Update</strong>: The website has been updated, adding data such as DoJ Waste Recovery of federal wasted funds and U.S. Hidden Wealth Assets (including gold, minerals, real estate, land, stocks, Recaptured Assets, etc.).</li>
<li><strong>U.S. Balance Sheet</strong> (as of March 27, 2025, approximate numbers):
<ul>
<li>Total Assets: Approximately 168 Trillion (T)</li>
<li>Federal Government Debt (in bond form): Approximately 36 T</li>
<li>Total Liabilities (including credit represented by cash M1/M2, etc.): Approximately 102 T</li>
<li>Annual Income (GDP): Approximately 28 T</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Interpretation</strong>: It&rsquo;s like a person having 1.68 million in assets (and the assets are growing at a rate of about 10%), 1.02 million in debt (of which 360,000 is core debt), and an annual salary of 280,000 (which is also growing). The debt is controllable, and the risk of bankruptcy is very low. U.S. dollar cash itself is also a liability, but it will depreciate with inflation, reducing the actual repayment pressure.</li>
<li><strong>Interest problem</strong>: Federal debt interest expenditure is about 1T, which is controllable relative to federal tax revenue (about 4.9T + state tax) and GDP (28T). There is no need to worry too much about the so-called interest exceeding defense spending (about 0.9T), as this comparison is not meaningful.</li>
<li><strong>Clarification of Musk&rsquo;s views</strong>: Musk mainly criticized the <strong>inefficiency and waste</strong> of the U.S. government&rsquo;s spending, rather than the debt itself being unsustainable.</li>
<li><strong>Impact of tariffs</strong>: Raising tariffs essentially shifts costs to consumers, leading to rising prices, which is equivalent to a disguised tax. This is just a different form from directly collecting federal taxes (paying in installments in daily consumption vs. paying once a year). The impact on the overall economy is complex, but for individuals, it may just be &ldquo;shifting from the left pocket to the right pocket.&rdquo;</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Other Sharing 
    <div id="other-sharing" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#other-sharing" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>HSBC Hong Kong Account Opening Experience (Student Sharing)</strong>:
<ul>
<li>Threshold: May require assets equivalent to HK$1 million to avoid monthly fees (approximately HK$380).</li>
<li>Transaction fee: Relatively high, but has little impact on long-term holders.</li>
<li>Stock pledge interest rate: HIBOR + 1.2%, currently about 4.92%, which is acceptable.</li>
<li>Suggestion: It is more convenient to sell stocks in other brokerages for cash and transfer them in than to perform complex cross-system transfers. Don&rsquo;t delay important matters for small fees.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Canadian Real Estate Investment Issues (Student Sharing)</strong>:
<ul>
<li>Non-tax residents face high withholding tax on selling property (35% of the selling price, not the profit), and transaction costs are high (brokerage fees, prepayment penalties, lawyer and accounting fees).</li>
<li>Conclusion: Houses are &ldquo;invisible cages&rdquo; and tools for governments, the financial industry, and capitalism to bind labor. Don&rsquo;t hesitate to sell the house; past investments are sunk costs. James also shared his experience of losing money selling a house in Longtan, Taiwan.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Retirement Planning Case (Student Question)</strong>:
<ul>
<li>NT$15 million in funds + NT$5 million in financial-type mortgage.</li>
<li>Suggestion: For the part that needs cash flow, consider buying ETFs such as 0050/0056 that provide dividends, but be aware that their dividends may include principal (selling component stocks).</li>
<li>Investment of NT$15 million: If you don&rsquo;t need to withdraw money from it, you can consider leveraged allocation (such as 433); if you need to withdraw money, you cannot use leverage. Choose the allocation based on the withdrawal rate (the amount needed after deducting Social Security benefits) (e.g., 2% withdrawal with 80/20 QQQ/cash; 3% withdrawal with SPY). The withdrawal rate is key, not the traditional 4% rule.</li>
<li>Core: Any configuration must consider whether you can withstand a 50% market drop.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Tesla FSD Experience (Student and Teacher Sharing)</strong>:
<ul>
<li>FSD V12 is amazing, close to fully autonomous driving, able to handle complex road conditions (such as San Francisco), and significantly reduces driving stress and fatigue.</li>
<li>FSD has a certain &ldquo;perception&rdquo; ability and can judge the intentions of other vehicles/pedestrians and make intelligent reactions.</li>
<li>Value: The teacher believes that FSD is worth the money (willing to spend $100,000 to buy it), improves safety (saves lives), improves the driving experience (reduces family quarrels), and may even reduce insurance premiums (using Tesla Insurance). Strongly recommends buying a Tesla car with FSD (the new Model Y comes standard). Use the teacher&rsquo;s referral code for discounts.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Consumption Concepts and Family (Student Question)</strong>:
<ul>
<li>Problem: Family members (such as spouses, parents) continue to demand new car replacements and other consumption due to &ldquo;laborer thinking&rdquo; or material needs, which conflicts with their own goals of accumulating wealth, and they feel annoyed.</li>
<li>Teacher&rsquo;s suggestion:
<ul>
<li>Understand the needs and feelings of family members (love what they love).</li>
<li>Learn to &ldquo;consume smartly,&rdquo; using financial tools (such as secured loans, adjusting allocation ratios) to meet some reasonable needs without excessively affecting the growth of core investments. For example, sell 100,000 QQQ, exchange it for 50,000 QLD (keeping some exposure) + 50,000 cash to buy a car.</li>
<li>The goal of capitalists is to make money generate money and ultimately use it to improve the quality of life, not just to save money. Find a balance between accumulation and consumption.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Technology Product Consumption</strong>: The teacher shared that buying high-quality displays (Nano-texture display) and AirPods Pro 2 (with hearing aid function, about $249) is to protect health and improve the quality of life. These investments are worthwhile, and financial operations (such as secured loans, credit card rebates reinvestment) can be used to make them feel like &ldquo;no money is spent.&rdquo;</li>
<li><strong>Defining Purchasing Power</strong>: True purchasing power means that when the purchased items (such as houses and cars) are accidentally damaged, you have the ability to easily buy another one without feeling financial pressure or heartache. Otherwise, you are exceeding your consumption capacity.</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">III. Q&amp;A Session 
    <div id="iii-qa-session" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii-qa-session" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">K 
    <div id="k" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#k" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Often explains to friends that market fluctuations are normal and not to panic. Also dissuaded friends from borrowing too much to invest just because their income could afford the interest.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s comment: Agreed. The main risk of secured borrowing is not the ability to pay interest, but the ability to repay the principal (Margin Call) when the market falls. Adjusting leverage to a comfortable level during market rebounds is important.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">C 
    <div id="c" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#c" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Thanks for the teacher&rsquo;s inspiration, sharing that he and a friend were deeply touched and started taking action, but also lamented that many people would rather eat, drink, and have fun than squeeze out a small amount of money to invest each month. Cognition determines wealth.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s comment: Glad to see students agree and execute, eventually becoming wealthy. Shared the example of an early student (2006) who persisted and has achieved financial freedom. Becoming a capitalist requires cognition and persistence, and it is indeed a minority of people.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Tommy 
    <div id="tommy" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#tommy" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Reviewed his 16-year investment journey: early purchases of 0050/0056 -&gt; chasing biotech stocks (heavy losses) -&gt; starting to invest in U.S. stocks (VOO/VTI/bonds, diversified) after the pandemic -&gt; epiphany after listening to the course, and is now concentrating assets into QQQ. Realized that dividends (0056) are not as good as total return (0050), paying off the mortgage too early was a wrong decision, and the cost of time is terrible.</li>
<li>Question 1: Should asset allocation (such as 442/433) be achieved on all accounts (Taiwan, US Brokerage, IRA, Roth 401k, etc.) as a whole, or should each account follow?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s reply: All accounts should be regarded as a whole for allocation. Leveraged funds (such as QLD) can only be placed in tax-free growth Roth accounts. Cash can be placed in Brokerage or Traditional IRA/401k (doing so can slow down the growth of pre-tax accounts, which is beneficial for future taxes). The final Beta value will be limited by the size of the Roth account. Even if the Beta is lower than 1, it doesn&rsquo;t matter. Stability (tortoise) may outperform aggression (hare).</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2: There are historical contributions in Traditional 401k (mutual funds have been converted to QQQ), and now it is a mix of Roth and Traditional. Should the Traditional portion be converted to Roth?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s reply: Whether to convert depends on the amount and current tax rate. If the amount is not large, you can convert it all at once. If the amount is large (e.g., 500,000), in order to avoid high tax burdens, it should be converted over many years. You can use the Investment Calculator to calculate how much amount to convert each year to reduce the Traditional balance to zero within a set period (e.g., 10 years) while controlling the annual tax burden. Fidelity clearly distinguishes the shares of Roth and Traditional internally.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">MMA 
    <div id="mma" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#mma" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Experienced Tesla FSD V12 and felt it was very good. 99% of the journey can be driven automatically, including handling cut-ins, traffic jams, and complex slopes in San Francisco, which greatly improves driving efficiency and comfort. Admired Tesla&rsquo;s technology and efficiency (the AI ​​department has few people but significant results).
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s comment: Very much agree. FSD is not just mechanical execution, but can also &ldquo;feel&rdquo; the intentions of other vehicles and pedestrians and make intelligent judgments. FSD greatly reduces driving pressure and improves safety (saves lives). Using FSD also helps reduce the insurance premium for Tesla Insurance. Strongly recommends buying a Tesla with FSD, and stocks can be held through QQQ.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Iam 
    <div id="iam" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iam" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Encountered a brokerage that promoted an IPO and realized that it was an interference from &ldquo;monsters and ghosts.&rdquo;</li>
<li>Question: How to deal with close people (parents, spouses, children) who continue to hold &ldquo;laborer thinking&rdquo; and constantly demand material consumption (such as changing to a new car), which conflicts with their own wealth accumulation philosophy and feels annoyed and pressured? Is there a good way to deal with it?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s reply:
<ol>
<li><strong>Understanding and love</strong>: Understand the needs of family members and love them (love what they love). Meeting reasonable needs is part of maintaining family harmony.</li>
<li><strong>Smart consumption</strong>: Capitalists don&rsquo;t not consume, but consume smartly. Use financial tools (secured loans, adjusting investment portfolios such as selling QQQ for QLD + cash) to meet consumption needs as much as possible without affecting the compound growth of core assets.</li>
<li><strong>Balance</strong>: Find a balance between wealth accumulation and enjoyment of life. It is not necessary to meet all requirements, but it is not possible to completely reject them. It is necessary to meet one or two needs that family members value every year or every few years.</li>
<li><strong>No need to explain too much</strong>: Actions speak louder than words. Express love through practical actions (such as buying a car), but there is no need to argue too much about concepts.</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Ling 
    <div id="ling" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ling" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Describes a complex arbitrage strategy: Using secured borrowing (leverage may exceed 1.5 times), puts some funds into a digital account in Taiwan (about 2% interest), and buys 00864B (USD money market fund) to try to cover the 2.8% borrowing cost. Also shared how to use credit card payments to get 0% interest installments and then use the money to buy 00864B for arbitrage.</li>
<li>Question: Is this operation feasible? Does it conform to the 442 configuration idea?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s reply:
<ol>
<li><strong>Not 442</strong>: What you described is an arbitrage strategy, not the 442 asset allocation based on long-term growth that we discussed.</li>
<li><strong>Arbitrage efficiency</strong>: Putting borrowed money (cost 2.8%) into a NTD account with 2% interest is losing money. All of it should be put into 00864B with higher returns (about 4.5%) and matching currencies (USD) for arbitrage. Exchange rate fluctuations are not important.</li>
<li><strong>Credit card arbitrage</strong>: It is feasible to use 0% interest installments for arbitrage, but it is a &ldquo;sesame green bean&rdquo; small trick and should not be distracted too much.</li>
<li><strong>Risk</strong>: As long as the target (00864B) itself does not fall, this pure arbitrage strategy has low risk and will not be margin called.</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Sandy 
    <div id="sandy" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#sandy" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Experienced the 2008 financial crisis, assets were halved, and since then has attached importance to cash, maintaining 30-40% cash all year round. Dared to buy in when the market fell sharply in 2022 and made a profit at the end of the year.</li>
<li>Question 1: Made considerable profits last year and early this year and wanted to sell some at a high level to avoid a callback, but her husband prevented it because of concerns about high taxes (believing that it would push the tax bracket to 50%). How to deal with it?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s reply: Her husband&rsquo;s understanding of tax law is wrong. Long-term Capital Gain Tax is calculated separately from ordinary income tax. Its tax rate is tiered (usually 0%, 15%, 20%), and the highest is 20% (plus a possible 3.8% NIIT). Selling capital gains will not push ordinary income to an extremely high tax bracket (such as 50%). The tax rate for selling a lot of LTCG is basically fixed (it is 20% after reaching a certain amount). However, it is not recommended to time the market to sell. If you really want to operate, you should prioritize doing so in retirement accounts (such as IRA/401k). Selling has no immediate tax impact, and you can even buy reverse ETFs (such as SQQQ) for hedging in retirement accounts (advanced operation, not recommended).</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2: Is it better to buy dividend-paying stocks or other things with the cash (Money Market) held? Worried about the tax on dividend-paying stocks.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s reply: Don&rsquo;t use dividend-paying stocks to hold cash, the tax efficiency is low. You should use money market funds. If you want to avoid both federal and state taxes, you can consider municipal bond funds (Muni Bond Fund, such as Vanguard&rsquo;s VOOX). If you only consider federal tax, you can use U.S. Treasury money market funds (such as SGOV, BIL). There is a capital gains tax problem only when selling.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 3: I want to anonymously sponsor a talented child (a friend&rsquo;s child, with decent family conditions), but I don&rsquo;t want the other party to know now, how to operate? Worried about tax issues.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s reply: Anonymous operation is difficult, especially involving opening an account. And the other party&rsquo;s family may not need sponsorship. A safer way is to write this child (providing name, address, and other information) into your own trust file as a beneficiary of future inheritance. This operation is simple and usually tax-free.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">CL 
    <div id="cl" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#cl" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question 1: In the United States, in addition to mortgage loans and stock pledges, what other similar low-cost sources of funds can be used like &ldquo;Han Xin counting soldiers&rdquo;?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s reply: The U.S. financial market is highly efficient and has a lot of &ldquo;smart money,&rdquo; so the interest rate on unsecured personal loans is usually higher (such as 8% +). Unlike Taiwan, which has a large amount of low-cost funds (due to export-oriented currency abundance), there are indeed not many other low-cost, flexible sources of funds besides stock pledges (Pledge Loan). If you have channels in Taiwan to borrow low-interest NTD funds, you can consider it.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2: Regarding children&rsquo;s college tuition fees, is it better for them to apply for student loans themselves (and we will use the pledged money to pay them back after graduation), or to pay directly with the pledged money? Which is better?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s reply: There is no absolute right or wrong, it depends on the child&rsquo;s personality and feelings. If the child feels stressed about debt, pay directly. If the child understands financial leverage and the student loan conditions are favorable (such as interest only after graduation), you can let them take out the loan and the parents will pay it back later. The key is to communicate well with the child. The teacher shared his experience of paying his daughter&rsquo;s tuition fees directly.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Sharing: Fortunate to have followed the teacher&rsquo;s advice to sell the expensive house in Los Angeles and exchange it for a cheaper one and use a pledge loan. Now I feel relaxed, unlike some friends who are trapped in expensive houses and facing difficulties under the wave of layoffs.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s comment: Yes, real estate has poor liquidity, especially when bought at a high price, which easily limits life choices and financial flexibility. Young people should be especially cautious.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Hao Qing (浩清) 
    <div id="hao-qing-%E6%B5%A9%E6%B8%85" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#hao-qing-%E6%B5%A9%E6%B8%85" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Told about his difficult experiences in the United States in the early stages of immigration: meager salary (less than 30,000 USD/year), relying on friends to introduce jobs, being questioned by the boss for his ability, saving money, working long hours and studying every day to support his family. Shared the process and feelings of raising three children: Children are motivation and will find their own way out. Responded to the teacher&rsquo;s video case about hesitating whether to have a third child, encouraged having children, and believed that children have their own future.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s comment: Shared his own experience of being poor when he first came to the United States (borrowing money to come to the United States, living in Motel 6, cooking by himself). Emphasized that the hardship of life is a process and also a valuable wealth and memory. Encouraged everyone to face life challenges bravely. Marriage and childbirth are not that terrible, love is the key, and money is usually not the biggest problem.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Terry 
    <div id="terry" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#terry" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question 1: Concerns about U.S. Treasury bonds (such as the debt-to-GDP ratio, interest burden), is it possible that the world will stop buying U.S. bonds?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s reply: U.S. assets (168T) far exceed debt (federal debt 36T). The interest burden is controllable relative to fiscal revenue and GDP. Countries around the world hold a large amount of USD reserves and must purchase USD assets (government bonds, treasury bills, money market funds, etc.) to store them. There are no other large-scale options to replace them. Therefore, the world will not stop buying U.S. bonds. A strong U.S. dollar is in the best interest of the United States.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2: The price of SGOV (short-term treasury bond ETF) is rising slightly every day, while the price of TLT (long-term treasury bond ETF) has been falling recently, why?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s reply: SGOV tracks short-term interest rates. Its mechanism is to accrue interest accumulation daily and the net value returns after dividends, showing a step-like slight oscillation. TLT represents long-term treasury bonds, and its price (yield) mainly reflects the market&rsquo;s <strong>expectations for future long-term inflation</strong>. If the market expects inflation to rise in the future (for example, worrying about tariffs leading to inflation), the yield on long-term treasury bonds will rise and the price of TLT will fall. This has little to do with the Fed&rsquo;s current short-term interest rate policy.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">IV. Highlighted Quotes 
    <div id="iv-highlighted-quotes" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv-highlighted-quotes" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>The market is always fluctuating&hellip; There is nothing new in the market, that is, as long as you stay in the market long enough.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>(Emphasizes the normalcy of market volatility and the importance of a long-term perspective)</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Cash is a magic weapon to overcome human nature.
&ndash; James (Cookie student also mentioned &ldquo;Cash is King&rdquo;)</p>
</blockquote>
<p>(Emphasizes the key role of cash in dealing with market fluctuations and psychological biases)</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Even if you are a god, you have many magic weapons. If you run out of magic weapons, you are not a god.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>(Uses metaphor to illustrate the importance of cash reserves, which cannot be easily exhausted)</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The purpose of capitalists is to spend money. Money is a tool, so what do we earn so much money for? It&rsquo;s to spend&hellip; We need to know how to spend money without reducing assets, killing other people&rsquo;s chickens, and our own chickens are still full of pits. This is our capitalist&rsquo;s philosophy, not saving money.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>(Explains a capitalist mindset that uses financial tools to achieve &ldquo;smart consumption&rdquo; and balance wealth growth and quality of life)</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Good individual stocks don&rsquo;t mean you can&rsquo;t get rich, they mean you can&rsquo;t get rich.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>(Explains the difficulty of holding a single stock with huge fluctuations, it&rsquo;s better to invest in index funds)</p>
<blockquote>
<p>When you can afford to buy two houses, you go buy one&hellip; You can buy something that, if it breaks, you&rsquo;re not sad at all, and you&rsquo;re even happy that you can buy a new one. That means you have the ability to consume.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>(Defines true &ldquo;purchasing power&rdquo; as the ability to afford losses without affecting life, advising young people to be cautious about buying houses)</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Long-term (capital gains) has nothing to do with income&hellip; Long-term capital gain is a fixed tax rate, it&rsquo;s either 15% or 20% and that&rsquo;s it, it won&rsquo;t be higher than 20%&hellip; You sell 10 million and it&rsquo;s still 20%.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>(Clarifies the calculation of U.S. long-term capital gains tax, it is not mixed with ordinary income and progressively increases)</p>
<blockquote>
<p>A strong dollar is in the best interest of the United States.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>(Points out the core interest orientation of the United States in monetary policy)</p>
<blockquote>
<p>TLT&hellip; Its interest is linked to inflation, linked to inflation expectations. So it has nothing to do with the central bank&rsquo;s interest rate.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>(Explains the core drivers of long-term treasury bond yields)</p>


<h2 class="relative group">V. Summary 
    <div id="v-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#v-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>In this CLEC investment and financial management sharing session, James reiterated the core philosophy of long-term investment: embrace market volatility, adhere to holding index funds represented by QQQ, and build firm belief through continuous learning. The teacher analyzed the real situation of U.S. Treasury bonds in detail, believing that there is no need to worry too much, and clarified the misunderstanding about its interest burden and Musk&rsquo;s criticism. At the same time, it discussed the rational use of leverage, the importance of cash reserves (like air and magic weapons), and how to overcome psychological biases in investment. The Q&amp;A session involved asset allocation across accounts, Roth conversion, real estate processing (including Canadian non-resident tax issues and personal experience), children&rsquo;s education funding planning, the excellent value and experience of Tesla FSD, consumption concept balance (smart consumption vs. laborer thinking), the limited sources of low-cost funds in the United States, the driving factor differences between long-term and short-term treasury bond ETFs, and the correct understanding of U.S. long-term capital gains tax and other practical issues, providing specific operational suggestions and thinking frameworks. The core message is to maintain a long-term perspective, make rational decisions, use financial tools to achieve a balance between wealth growth and quality of life, while understanding and respecting the needs of the people around you.</p>

  



<div
  
    class="flex px-4 py-3 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900"
  >

  <span
    
      class="text-primary-400 ltr:pr-3 rtl:pl-3 flex items-center"
    >

    

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M506.3 417l-213.3-364c-16.33-28-57.54-28-73.98 0l-213.2 364C-10.59 444.9 9.849 480 42.74 480h426.6C502.1 480 522.6 445 506.3 417zM232 168c0-13.25 10.75-24 24-24S280 154.8 280 168v128c0 13.25-10.75 24-23.1 24S232 309.3 232 296V168zM256 416c-17.36 0-31.44-14.08-31.44-31.44c0-17.36 14.07-31.44 31.44-31.44s31.44 14.08 31.44 31.44C287.4 401.9 273.4 416 256 416z"/></svg>

  </span>


  </span>

  <span
    
      class="dark:text-neutral-300"
    ><strong>Disclaimer:</strong> This article is for personal study notes only and does not constitute any investment advice.</span>
</div>

]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>00481 Asset Allocation Strategies to Avoid Market Pitfalls; How to Achieve Steady Wealth through Proper Investment Strategies</title>
      <link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1728285792652/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1728285792652/</guid>
      <description>In this session, James emphasizes the crucial role of mental strength in investment success. He discusses asset allocation, the use and rebalancing of leveraged ETFs, provides supplementary explanations of 401(k) and IRA accounts, and touches upon choosing the right brokerage. The Q&amp;amp;A session addresses audience questions concerning investing with mortgage loans, market crash risks, the risks associated with single brokerage accounts, and how to cope with the psychological pressure stemming from market fluctuations. Furthermore, the discussion includes insights on investment target selection, the purpose of holding cash, and life planning. </description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<lite-youtube videoid="ZvTM4--CaKw" playlabel="ZvTM4--CaKw" params=""></lite-youtube>



<h2 class="relative group">I. Main Theme 
    <div id="i-main-theme" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-main-theme" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This session centers around the importance of psychological resilience in investing. James&rsquo;s core message is that mental strength is the key to investment success, while other skills and calculations are secondary. Investors need to maintain a highly optimistic mindset, viewing market fluctuations as opportunities rather than crises in the long run. Long-term investing, rational analysis, and maintaining a healthy mindset are more crucial than striving for precise calculations.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">II. Briefing Content 
    <div id="ii-briefing-content" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii-briefing-content" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<ul>
<li><strong>Correction on 401(k) and IRA:</strong> James corrects a statement from the previous session regarding 401(k) and IRA contribution limits, clarifying that the limits for each are independent, but that IRAs have income restrictions. He provides further explanations about the Backdoor Roth IRA conversion, advising listeners to manage pre-tax and after-tax funds carefully to avoid account confusion and complications during tax filing.</li>
<li><strong>Asset Allocation Strategy:</strong> He emphasizes the significance of asset allocation and suggests listeners refer to existing articles and Excel spreadsheets for simulations, discouraging impulsive decision-making. He offers various asset allocation plans catering to different risk tolerances and retirement stages, stressing the concept of &ldquo;fuzzy accuracy&rdquo; – that it is not necessary to pursue overly precise ratios, but ensuring sufficient cash reserves is crucial. Example: A listener proposes an allocation of 60% QQQ and 40% cash, which James believes carries a risk of bankruptcy and advises them to consult the provided asset allocation plans.</li>
<li><strong>Leveraged ETFs and Rebalancing:</strong> Using QQQ&rsquo;s beta value of 1.0 as a benchmark, he simplifies beta calculations for leveraged ETFs, for instance, QLD is considered 2.0. He recommends a gradual approach when adjusting beta during rebalancing, advising against drastic changes. For investors with earned income, the frequency and ratio of rebalancing can be more flexible. Example: He suggests that young investors can rotate investments among QQQ, QLD, and TQQQ every six months, then rebalance at the end of the year.</li>
<li><strong>Long-Term Investing and Market Volatility:</strong> James reiterates the importance of long-term investing, using the dot-com bubble of 2000 as an example to demonstrate that long-term investors ultimately profit, even after enduring prolonged market downturns. Market dips are opportunities, and investors should remain optimistic, buying whenever they have funds available. He refutes the notion that &ldquo;investments in 2000 took 15 years to break even,&rdquo; emphasizing that the market always recovers in the long run. Example: An investment of $5 million at the peak of the market in 2000, despite experiencing the burst of the internet bubble, would still have grown to $32.375 million by 2024.</li>
<li><strong>Brokerage Selection:</strong> He advises choosing brokerages with physical branch offices and understanding how stocks and cash are held in custody to ensure asset security. Example: He explains the risks of nominee accounts and recommends selecting brokerages that allow for direct ownership of stocks, encouraging listeners to inquire about the brokerage&rsquo;s custodian banks for stocks and cash.</li>
<li><strong>Purpose of Holding Cash:</strong> He underlines that cash holdings are meant for emergencies and to seize buying opportunities during market downturns, not for pursuing interest income. Example: He suggests maintaining a 20% cash position, a portion of which can be utilized for adding to leveraged ETFs during dips.</li>
<li><strong>Investment Target Selection:</strong> He recommends selecting suitable investment targets based on individual circumstances. For instance, retirees or individuals with limited funds may consider high-dividend ETFs, while younger individuals or those with ample funds should focus on growth-oriented ETFs like QQQ. Example: Addressing a listener holding SCH, James advises them to assess whether high-dividend ETFs are appropriate based on their asset level and annual expenses.</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">III. Q&amp;A Session 
    <div id="iii-qa-session" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii-qa-session" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p><strong>Danny:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Shares: He has been following James&rsquo;s investment strategy for three years and achieved a return of approximately 35%.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Chang&rsquo;an:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Question: Brokerage security and recommendations in Hong Kong.</li>
<li>James&rsquo;s Response: Choose brokerages with physical branch offices in the region, understand the custodian banks for stocks and cash, and avoid easily dissolved online brokerages.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Eric:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Shares: He began investing during the pandemic, experienced the hardships of short-term trading, and eventually recognized the importance of long-term investing and psychological control. He uses the example of Jesse Livermore to illustrate the risks of trading.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Jessie:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Shares: Both she and her husband are nearing 60 years old, and a portion of their investment funds comes from a mortgage loan. She expresses concerns about a potential market crash and the risk of USD devaluation.</li>
<li>Questions:</li>
</ul>
<ol>
<li>How to cope with a possible future market crash, especially with a mortgage due before retirement?</li>
<li>What about USD devaluation?</li>
<li>Are there risks associated with concentrating large sums of money in a single brokerage account?</li>
<li>Is it feasible to refinance the mortgage in five years or repay it early with funds from the investment account?</li>
</ol>
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Response:</li>
</ul>
<ol>
<li>The market is unlikely to experience losses within a 15-year timeframe. Ensure you can comfortably handle mortgage payments for the next 13 years; the most secure approach is to sell the house and repay the loan.</li>
<li>He declines to answer hypothetical questions.</li>
<li>Stocks are registered under the investor&rsquo;s name, hence the risk of brokerage failure is manageable.</li>
<li>Refinancing or early repayment is not recommended. Excessive focus on short-term interest gains is akin to &ldquo;penny wise, pound foolish,&rdquo; and ultimately increases risk.</li>
</ol>
<p><strong>Sam:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Shares: He went all-in on QQQ, but after some short-term trading, realized it wasn&rsquo;t suitable for him and experienced psychological pressure due to large position fluctuations.</li>
<li>Question: How to overcome the psychological pressure brought about by fluctuations in a large portfolio?</li>
<li>James&rsquo;s Response:</li>
</ul>
<ol>
<li>Focus on realized gains rather than unrealized gains.</li>
<li>Maintain 20% cash and 20% leveraged ETFs to stabilize your mindset.</li>
<li>Exercise caution with short-term trading, as it may not be sustainable in the long run.</li>
</ol>
<p><strong>Haoqing:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Shares: He uses examples of friends gambling and raising children to illustrate the importance of moderate expectations and nurturing interests. He compares and contrasts education philosophies and Nobel Prize achievements between China and the US, emphasizing the significance of financial freedom for the next generation.</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">IV. Highlights 
    <div id="iv-highlights" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv-highlights" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>Mental fortitude is the equipment for investing, it determines whether you will succeed.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Investment skills and calculations are undoubtedly important, but psychological resilience is the ultimate factor that decides investment success. Even for simple index fund investing, a sound mental state is needed to navigate market volatility.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>A market downturn is not a disaster, it&rsquo;s an opportunity.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>From a long-term investment perspective, market downturns provide excellent opportunities to acquire high-quality assets.  Maintain a long-term outlook and don&rsquo;t be intimidated by short-term fluctuations.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>There should be a limit to human pessimism.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Excessive pessimism and worry are detrimental to investments. One should rationally analyze risks and develop sensible coping strategies. Do not let extreme scenarios or low-probability events unduly influence investment decisions.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Parents sometimes have these expectations for their children, don&rsquo;t impose your unfulfilled aspirations on them.
&ndash; Haoqing</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Parents should respect their children&rsquo;s individuality and interests and refrain from forcing their own unaccomplished goals onto them. Allowing children to have a joyful childhood and the autonomy to choose their own paths in life is more important than chasing conventional success.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">V. Summary 
    <div id="v-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#v-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>In this session, James reiterates the importance of mental fortitude in investing and the effectiveness of long-term investment and asset allocation strategies. By addressing listeners&rsquo; practical concerns, such as retirement planning, market volatility, and capital security, he helps them better understand and apply these investment principles. James also provides advice on choosing appropriate investment targets and the purpose of holding cash, aiding listeners in constructing more comprehensive investment strategies. Haoqing&rsquo;s sharing sparked reflection on educational philosophies and life values, advocating for a focus on children&rsquo;s overall development and mental well-being.</p>

  



<div
  
    class="flex px-4 py-3 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900"
  >

  <span
    
      class="text-primary-400 ltr:pr-3 rtl:pl-3 flex items-center"
    >

    

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M506.3 417l-213.3-364c-16.33-28-57.54-28-73.98 0l-213.2 364C-10.59 444.9 9.849 480 42.74 480h426.6C502.1 480 522.6 445 506.3 417zM232 168c0-13.25 10.75-24 24-24S280 154.8 280 168v128c0 13.25-10.75 24-23.1 24S232 309.3 232 296V168zM256 416c-17.36 0-31.44-14.08-31.44-31.44c0-17.36 14.07-31.44 31.44-31.44s31.44 14.08 31.44 31.44C287.4 401.9 273.4 416 256 416z"/></svg>

  </span>


  </span>

  <span
    
      class="dark:text-neutral-300"
    ><strong>Disclaimer:</strong> This document is only for personal learning and note-taking purposes and does not constitute any investment advice.</span>
</div>

]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
