<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Tax Planning on QQQ Investor</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/tags/tax-planning/</link><description>Recent content in Tax Planning on QQQ Investor</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jomonylw.github.io/en/tags/tax-planning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>00511 Risk and Cash Are the Real Starting Points for Investing</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1744504450104/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1744504450104/</guid><description>In this episode, James emphasizes that in any market environment, the primary consideration for investing is having sufficient cash reserves, followed by holding index funds for the long term. He discusses risk tolerance, asset allocation models (such as 433 and 424), the principles for using leveraged funds, and caution regarding paid groups and conflicts of interest. Students share their experiences and questions regarding market volatility, tax planning, retirement preparation, and more.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<lite-youtube videoid="xmD_sz5rYlU" playlabel="xmD_sz5rYlU" params=""></lite-youtube>



<h2 class="relative group">I. Current Theme 
    <div id="i-current-theme" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-current-theme" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>The core viewpoint of this episode emphasizes that investment decisions should be <strong>independent of market volatility</strong>, with <strong>sufficient cash reserves</strong> serving as the first step and cornerstone of investment planning. After determining the cash level based on individual risk tolerance and living needs, then proceed with long-term (15+ years) investment in index funds (especially the Nasdaq 100). Beta is a result of asset allocation, not the starting point. At the same time, be wary of various risks in investment, especially cognitive risks and behavioral biases, and remain vigilant about conflicts of interest in financial services.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">II. Briefing Content 
    <div id="ii-briefing-content" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii-briefing-content" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Market Volatility and Long-Term Perspective 
    <div id="market-volatility-and-long-term-perspective" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#market-volatility-and-long-term-perspective" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Market fluctuations are normal. Having experienced multiple major crashes (2000, 2008, 2020, 2022), the current volatility is relatively mild.</li>
<li>In the long run, most of the current concerns will &ldquo;leave no trace.&rdquo; Don&rsquo;t panic over short-term events. Time is the best medicine, but people are prone to repeating mistakes (old habits die hard).</li>
<li>Investing is a long-term matter (15+ years), and dips are buying opportunities. James has been investing for 40 years and has never &ldquo;seen&rdquo; a market crash, only buying opportunities.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Core Investment Principles 
    <div id="core-investment-principles" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#core-investment-principles" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Focus on Doing the Right Things:</strong> The core is &ldquo;Han Xin Counts Soldiers&rdquo; (i.e., using affordable and safe borrowing, such as mortgages and credit lines, for investment), putting borrowed money into the market, but with sufficient cash reserves.</li>
<li><strong>Investment Targets:</strong> Only invest in the Nasdaq 100 index fund (such as QQQ, 00662, 513100, etc.), as it represents human growth and innovation and has a self-evolving mechanism of survival of the fittest. Related materials are linked on page 10 of the handout. It is mentioned that HXQ and other Nasdaq 100-based funds may outperform QQQ in certain periods.</li>
<li><strong>Long-Term Holding:</strong> Holding for 15+ years after purchase is key, &ldquo;never selling.&rdquo; Only inaction can lead to wealth, not frequent trading.</li>
<li><strong>Stay Optimistic:</strong> Investment is based on confidence in the long-term development of humanity.</li>
<li><strong>Independent Learning:</strong> Investment requires self-study, understanding the reasons behind the strategy and the then-current market environment, and not blindly following.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Asset Allocation: Cash First 
    <div id="asset-allocation-cash-first" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#asset-allocation-cash-first" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Primary Question:</strong> The first step in investing is not what to buy, but <strong>how much cash needs to be retained</strong> to live securely and cope with emergencies. This is the most important thing.</li>
<li><strong>Cash Needs Determine Allocation:</strong>
<ul>
<li><strong>Young People:</strong> First, prepare an emergency fund (e.g., NT$400,000/CNY100,000), and only invest surplus funds.</li>
<li><strong>Asset Allocation Model Examples:</strong>
<ul>
<li><strong>433 (Beta 1.0):</strong> 40% Index + 30% Leverage + 30% Cash. Requires 30% Cash &gt; Emergency Fund (e.g., NT$400,000), requiring total assets of NT$1.33 million to implement.</li>
<li><strong>424 (Beta 0.8):</strong> 40% Index + 20% Leverage + 40% Cash. Requires 40% Cash &gt; Emergency Fund (e.g., NT$400,000), requiring total assets of NT$1 million to implement. Illustrates that reducing Beta can lower the funding threshold.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>High-Net-Worth Individuals:</strong> The principle is the same, determine the cash ratio according to personal comfort (potentially millions of RMB or hundreds of thousands of USD).</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Beta is the Result, Not the Goal:</strong> First determine cash needs and risk tolerance, naturally forming the allocation ratio, and finally calculate the Beta value as a measurement tool. Don&rsquo;t set a target Beta from the beginning.</li>
<li><strong>Allocation Irrelevant Factors:</strong> Asset allocation is <strong>unrelated</strong> to age, fund size, or market level, only related to how to prevent accidents and how much accident can be tolerated.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Risk Management and Cognition 
    <div id="risk-management-and-cognition" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#risk-management-and-cognition" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Risk Tolerance:</strong>
<ul>
<li>Young people have less experience, so risk tolerance may not be high, and should not blindly pursue high Beta (e.g., 442).</li>
<li>Wealthy people are usually more conservative, pursuing stability rather than extreme returns (Beta 0.5 may be sufficient).</li>
<li>Conclusion: Taking risks beyond your tolerance is foolish. Investment is like eating spicy food, do what you can handle.</li>
<li>Recommendation: Start conservatively. If you believe you can tolerate Beta 1.2, start with 1.0; if you believe you can tolerate 1.0, start with 0.8.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Leveraged Fund Usage Principles:</strong> The ratio of leveraged funds should not exceed the ratio of cash or the ratio of the original fund. This suggests that a 442 allocation (40% Index + 40% Leverage + 20% Cash) is not suitable for most people.</li>
<li><strong>Behavioral Biases:</strong> Retail investors often feel sad when the market falls (regret buying early) and also sad when the market rises (regret not going all-in). The correct allocation should achieve &ldquo;happy when it rises, comfortable when it falls,&rdquo; maintaining &ldquo;immovability.&rdquo;</li>
<li><strong>Individual Stock Risk:</strong> No company lasts forever (examples: Intel, Kodak, Blackberry), individual stock risk is high. Index funds mitigate individual stock risk through a mechanism of survival of the fittest.</li>
<li><strong>Borrowing Risk:</strong>
<ul>
<li><strong>Safe Borrowing:</strong> Mortgages, credit lines (Han Xin Counts Soldiers), assuming income can cover monthly payments, unrelated to market fluctuations.</li>
<li><strong>Dangerous Borrowing:</strong> Margin trading, stock-pledged reinvestment. Market declines can lead to forced liquidation or even bankruptcy. <strong>These operations are strictly prohibited.</strong></li>
<li>James&rsquo;s pledge loan: Based on holding cash far exceeding debt, ensuring absolute security.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Specific Funds Use Risk:</strong> Money earmarked for short-term use (e.g., down payment on a house) within a short period (e.g., 3 years) <strong>absolutely cannot</strong> be invested in the stock market. Someone recently defaulted because of this.</li>
<li><strong>Tax Risk:</strong> Tax planning is very important and can affect significant wealth. Rules need to be carefully studied (e.g., the application of the U.S. Wash Sale Rule across accounts).</li>
<li><strong>Spending Ability Mindset:</strong> True &ldquo;affordability&rdquo; means being able to easily repurchase an item if it breaks down, as in James&rsquo;s example of replacing a juicer. Large expenditures (e.g., buying a house) should also have this mindset, otherwise the risk is too high.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Be Wary of Paid Services and Conflicts of Interest 
    <div id="be-wary-of-paid-services-and-conflicts-of-interest" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#be-wary-of-paid-services-and-conflicts-of-interest" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Firmly Do Not Charge:</strong> James emphasizes that his services are free because charging easily creates conflicts of interest. His YouTube channel also does not have monetization enabled.</li>
<li><strong>Warning Signals:</strong> Be highly vigilant about any paid groups, paid recommendations, or financial services that charge commissions or kickbacks (e.g., account opening, buying funds). Mentions feedback that some groups may be transferring benefits through financial service referrals.</li>
<li><strong>Harm of Conflicts of Interest:</strong> Those who charge may recommend unsuitable or even harmful products/strategies for commissions.</li>
<li><strong>Self-Protection:</strong> Learn independently, compare multiple sources, understand financial products yourself, and do not easily trust introductions. Be especially wary of &ldquo;pits&rdquo; introduced by acquaintances.</li>
<li><strong>U.S. Regulations:</strong> The U.S. prohibits paying commissions to referrers for financial product recommendations (account opening rewards are usually given to the account opener themselves) to prevent conflicts of interest. Regulations may vary in other regions.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Other Suggestions 
    <div id="other-suggestions" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#other-suggestions" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Emergency Fund:</strong> Do not use the emergency fund to buy the dip. Survival is the most important thing.</li>
<li><strong>Regular Investment:</strong> Buy index funds immediately with new income (e.g., salary).</li>
<li><strong>Financial Literacy:</strong> Financial intelligence requires learning, there are no shortcuts. Be wary of the &ldquo;get rich quick&rdquo; mentality. Discuss with his daughter the mindset of speculators: it may be &ldquo;greed,&rdquo; it may be &ldquo;poverty,&rdquo; or it may be &ldquo;not wanting to get rich slowly.&rdquo;</li>
<li><strong>Video Viewing:</strong> New friends are advised to watch video #451, then start from #398 (January 2023) and watch in order.</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">III. Q&amp;A Session 
    <div id="iii-qa-session" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii-qa-session" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">CAD 
    <div id="cad" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#cad" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing:
<ol>
<li>Observed that regardless of wealth, some people are keen on short-term trading, possibly due to addictive pleasure or a sense of accomplishment. Poor people may say they need quick returns, while rich people may enjoy the process.</li>
<li>Emphasized the strict prohibition of margin trading or stock-pledged reinvestment. Recently, with the market decline, someone was forced to liquidate and even became indebted because of it. Compared this to his own use of credit lines/mortgages for investment, stating that as long as he can afford the monthly payments, the market decline does not affect his survival.</li>
<li>Mentioned a senior who was forced to liquidate due to margin calls during the Kuo Wan-Jung incident (Taiwan stock market historical event) and has been in debt ever since, warning future generations.</li>
<li><strong>Important Reminder:</strong> When observing an investment portfolio, you should pay attention to the <strong>fluctuation range of the overall assets</strong> rather than just staring at the leveraged portion with the biggest decline, which helps manage emotions.</li>
</ol>
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Comment: Agreed. Explained the risk of illiquidity under the Taiwan stock market&rsquo;s limit-down mechanism, compared to the U.S. market. Re-emphasized the danger of margin/pledge reinvestment. Explained that while he uses pledge loans, he holds cash far exceeding his debt to ensure security. Criticized putting house-buying money into the stock market as ignoring risk.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">BG 
    <div id="bg" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#bg" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing:
<ol>
<li>Agreed that money management (cash ratio, position control) takes precedence over buying and selling signals.</li>
<li>Money management should start from oneself (capital amount, risk tolerance willingness).</li>
<li>Backtesting is not just to verify signals, but also to understand the money drawdown of the strategy under historical market conditions, to adjust positions to suit one&rsquo;s own tolerance.</li>
<li>Under the buy-and-hold strategy, investment funds must be strictly separated from living funds to avoid affecting long-term investment plans and mentality due to living needs.</li>
</ol>
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Comment: Distinguished between strategy (long-term goals, cash planning, asset class allocation) and tactics (specific buying and selling points, short-term adjustments). Emphasized that tactics should not interfere with strategy, for example, one should not liquidate due to market panic or use the emergency fund to buy the dip.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Rui 
    <div id="rui" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#rui" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing:
<ol>
<li>Thanked James for solving many investment confusions (cash first, the use of leverage, asset allocation, etc.) through learning videos.</li>
<li>Adopted the teacher&rsquo;s advice and used 2% of his assets (through pledging) to pay for the Tesla purchase.</li>
<li>After adopting the 433 allocation, he felt excited when the market fell, in contrast to the panic of his colleagues.</li>
<li>Used a brokerage account (transfer from Yuantai Securities) that does not show the cost price, which helped reduce anxiety.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>Questions:
<ol>
<li>Has reached the retirement goal (50x annual expenses), but his current salary is equivalent to 6% of total assets. He hopes for a higher retirement replacement rate in the future (assets need to increase by another 2-3 times). Between 433 (30% cash + 2% withdrawal) and 442 (20% cash + no withdrawal), how to further think about the choice from the perspective of safety and applicability?</li>
<li>(Implicit question) Should he continue working for a sense of accomplishment, or retire early?</li>
</ol>
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Response:</li>
</ul>
<ol>
<li><strong>Regarding Purchasing the Car:</strong> Praised his use of &ldquo;non-own funds&rdquo; for consumption, pointing out that being able to borrow money is itself a manifestation of wealth, the key is controllable risk (sufficient cash).</li>
<li><strong>Regarding Retirement Choices:</strong> This is a classic question. Cited another case to illustrate that early retirement may bring huge benefits due to tax planning (such as Roth conversions). Suggested that Rui reflect: if work had no salary or recognition, would he still want to go? The value of work may change with stage, and there may be new pursuits in the future. Looking back from age 90, would he regret working several more decades? With financial freedom, the work mentality can be more relaxed.</li>
<li><strong>Regarding 433 vs 442 Safety:</strong> Assuming the market goes to zero, which is safer? The answer is the one with a higher cash ratio (433 has 30% cash, 442 has only 20%).</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Kai Xin 
    <div id="kai-xin" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#kai-xin" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question: Regarding whether the interest on the U.S. Pledged Asset Line (PAL, pledge loan) can be tax-deductible, and how to operate? Feels that the rules are complex and there are many restrictions.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Response: The money borrowed from PAL is mainly used for consumption, not reinvestment. The issue of interest tax deduction is complicated and may require adjusting the type of capital gains (e.g., converting long-term to short-term), relying on accountant operations. James himself does not pay attention to this operation because his strategy is to hold a lot of cash, making interest income far exceed PAL interest expenses, and PAL interest is close to zero. The more fundamental strategy is to achieve &ldquo;zero income, zero capital gains,&rdquo; so there is no need to consider tax deduction.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Derek 
    <div id="derek" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#derek" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Thanks to James and the community (Chen Feng, Sister K, etc.). Recently joined, the teacher&rsquo;s reply and teaching made him have the courage to operate according to the plan when the market fell, and deeply realized the importance of risk control. Listening to the teacher&rsquo;s videos can bring a sense of stability.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Comment: This is precisely the reason why he insists on teaching, knowing that it is difficult to succeed in investing alone, and guidance and companionship are needed.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Nai Xi 
    <div id="nai-xi" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#nai-xi" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: As the founding moderator of the Taiwan 00662 community, thanks to James&rsquo;s inspiration three years ago for changing his life. Thanks to all 19 administrators of the community (mentioning the rotation system, member contributions such as Chen Feng bringing it to a new height, Chris developing tools, etc.) for their hard work. Reiterated that he was inspired by the teacher&rsquo;s &ldquo;eliminate poverty&rdquo; mission and hopes to help more people through the community.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Comment: Recalled the meeting with Nai Xi and the community backbone (eighteen arhats), praised their quality and Nai Xi&rsquo;s persistence and humility. Affirmed the value and operation of the 00662 community and regretted that it was limited by the LINE platform and could not cover the world.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Ming Yu 
    <div id="ming-yu" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ming-yu" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: No questions or sharing.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Yao 
    <div id="yao" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#yao" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Mentioned recent rumors about Trump&rsquo;s friends profiting from trade war news, and extended thoughts about the relationship between the morality of politicians and social progress. Lamented that moral constraints are limited, but human technology is still developing.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Comment: Agreed that the world is full of unknowns (quoting Buffett), and the market always has surprises (epidemic circuit breakers, drastic trade war fluctuations). Need to remain humble and prepare for extreme risks (such as market closure/continuous decline for 10-15 years). Re-distinguished between safe borrowing (fixed repayment) and dangerous borrowing (linked to the market).</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Julia 
    <div id="julia" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#julia" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Revealed an American tax trap: the Wash Sale Rule may apply to all accounts (including 401k/IRA and other retirement accounts). If you sell a loss-making asset (such as QQQ) in a taxable account for Tax Loss Harvesting (TLH) and automatically buy a similar asset (such as an SP500 index fund) in a retirement account at the same time, the loss in the taxable account may be permanently disallowed (because retirement accounts are taxed at ordinary income rates when withdrawn, with no capital gains concept). This is especially important for high-tech employees, as they often hold a large number of RSUs and perform TLH.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Comment: Tax issues are extremely important. Pointed out that TLH itself also has risks, such as the market rebounding after selling, making it impossible to buy back the original asset (QQQ) at an ideal price, or generating new capital gains when buying back. If James himself has no need (such as no capital gains without selling stocks), he tends to let the loss carry forward and deduct $3,000 of ordinary income each year, rather than use it to offset capital gains. However, for Julia, who needs to offset a large amount of RSU capital gains, TLH is a reasonable strategy and needs to be operated carefully. Discussed the problem of high tax rates in California. Re-emphasized the ultimate goal of pursuing a zero-tax state, and the value of tax planning far exceeds the salary itself.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">DDF 
    <div id="ddf" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ddf" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question: Asked about the risk of the Pacific War two years ago, at that time the teacher suggested reducing 50% of QQQ. Now that he has adopted the strategy of holding a large amount of cash (such as 433/424), can he withstand this type of risk, insist on holding it and rebalancing at the end of the year, without selling in the middle?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Response: The evolution of the strategy is because the introduction of leveraged instruments allows holding a large amount of cash more effectively. The core risk management issue is not specific events (wars, disasters, etc.), but <strong>whether it is possible to survive in extreme market conditions (such as closure/deep decline for 10-15 years)</strong>. If cash reserves are sufficient to support such a long time, there is no need to make predictive operations for specific events. Comparing risks: for young people, the risk of carrying a mortgage and facing unemployment + market decline may be more realistic and fatal than the risk of war. Buying a house should be as easy and stress-free as buying slippers to be considered affordable.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Jason 
    <div id="jason" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#jason" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Summarized two major investment risks:
<ol>
<li><strong>Choosing the wrong asset:</strong> The market is full of various temptations, choosing a high-quality asset for the long term (such as QQQ) is the foundation. Thanks to the teacher for continuing to emphasize this.</li>
<li><strong>Missing the upside:</strong> Statistics show that missing the 10 days with the biggest market gains (in the past 20 years) will cut total returns in half. These big rally days often occur during periods of extreme panic (such as 2008, 2020). This confirms the importance of the &ldquo;never sell&rdquo; strategy to avoid timing the market.</li>
</ol>
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Comment: Highly Agreed. Defined <strong>the real, permanent loss</strong> as <strong>the returns that should have been earned but were not</strong> (such as missing a 12% rally). Book losses caused by market declines are temporary and will recover. Compared buying QQQ at a high point (540) with buying at a low point (440), the difference in annualized returns after holding for 40 years is extremely small (11.98% vs 12.5%), indicating that the timing of the purchase is not important, but long-term holding is key. Use a long-term perspective (40 years later) to review current decisions.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Jing 
    <div id="jing" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#jing" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question: Approaching retirement, but savings have not reached the 30-50x target. There is a stable high income in the next 5 years, and Pension/Social Security will cover most expenses after retirement. Does not use pledging due to concerns about risk. Can I not retain 20% cash and take a 100% stock holding strategy, relying on future income, emergency fund, and future pledgeable options to accelerate asset growth?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Response: <strong>No.</strong> Risk tolerance decreases as retirement approaches, the time window is short, and you should be more conservative. Since the Pension already covers most of the expenses, the urgency for asset growth should be reduced. <strong>The most aggressive allocation for retirement or near retirement, without using pledges and without holding leveraged funds, is 80% QQQ + 20% cash.</strong> Pension should be regarded as a stable source of income, and when calculating the total amount of retirement funds required, the <strong>Pension portion should be deducted</strong> from annual expenses first, and then the remaining net expenditure needs should be multiplied by a multiple (such as 30 or 50 times). If you hold leveraged funds, you must sell them and deal with tax issues before retirement.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Frank (from the comments section) 
    <div id="frank-from-the-comments-section" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#frank-from-the-comments-section" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question: Should global diversification be carried out?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Response: Not recommended. The U.S. market is optimal in terms of innovation, transparency, and long-term risk-reward ratio. Other markets have higher risks and relatively low return potential. Investing in U.S. index funds is sufficient.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">IV. Wonderful Views 
    <div id="iv-wonderful-views" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv-wonderful-views" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>The first step in investing is not to say, ah, I come in and start, what should the teacher buy, how much leveraged funds should I buy&hellip; No&hellip; The first thing to invest in is how much cash you need, how much cash you need to keep, this is more important than anything.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>Background: Emphasizes the primacy of cash reserves in investment planning.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Our strategy has nothing to do with market volatility&hellip; What are investment plans or investments supposed to do? It is to be based on your own risk tolerance&hellip; How much cash is appropriate to keep, this is the first step in investing.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>Background: Explains the core concept of his investment strategy, which is not affected by short-term market sentiment.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Beta is naturally formed in the end, not set at the beginning&hellip; So you have to ask the first few questions, how much cash do you keep to feel comfortable&hellip; An accident may come in the next second.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>Background: Explains the role of Beta in asset allocation, which is a result, not a goal, emphasizing safety first.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Young people should not take risks, because they lack experience, and rich people do not take risks much&hellip; Coming back to the point, taking risks is not very worthwhile, taking risks beyond what you can afford is just very stupid.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>Background: Refutes traditional concepts, pointing out that excessive risk-taking is not advisable, regardless of whether you are young or wealthy.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Don&rsquo;t turn your tactics into a strategy&hellip; It seems that the emergency fund should have been so much, but you, ah, it&rsquo;s dropped so much, quickly buy it all in. That turns tactics into a strategy, you can&rsquo;t do that.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>Background: When commenting on student sharing, distinguishes the boundaries between strategic determination and tactical flexibility.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>What you should look at is not your single stock (referring to leveraged ETFs)&hellip; Drops a lot, you should look at the range of fluctuations in your entire asset&hellip; Don&rsquo;t pay too much attention to the part that is dropping the most.
&ndash; CAD (Student)</p></blockquote>
<p>Background: Reminds that when holding leveraged ETFs, you should pay attention to the volatility of the overall investment portfolio rather than a single product, to stabilize your mentality.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>What is the real risk of the market? The real risk of the market is your investment return, the real risk is the returns that you should have earned but didn&rsquo;t, that you will never earn&hellip; A drop in losses is not a loss.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>Background: Redefines investment risk, emphasizing that opportunity cost (missing the upside) is the real permanent loss.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The risk of buying a house is higher than the risk of war&hellip; If you treat buying a house like buying slippers, then you can buy a house.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>Background: Responding to questions about geopolitical risks, compared and pointed out that for ordinary people, financial leverage (such as mortgages) may bring more direct and serious risks.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>If you don&rsquo;t manage your finances and taxes well, you may pay 85% of your assets in taxes in this life, and you actually only get 15%&hellip; Saving taxes can save tens of billions.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>Background: When discussing tax planning, emphasizes its huge impact on long-term wealth accumulation.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Because being poor is also right to do speculation&hellip; So it&rsquo;s also right that most people who speculate are poor&hellip; Many people who speculate don&rsquo;t even know it, they don&rsquo;t know what they don&rsquo;t know, which is very strange.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>Background: When discussing speculative psychology with his daughter, reflected on the relationship between poverty and greed, and that speculators often lack self-awareness.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">V. Summary 
    <div id="v-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#v-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This lecture once again consolidates James&rsquo;s core investment philosophy: <strong>taking sufficient cash reserves as a prerequisite for ultra-long-term (15+ years) holding of the Nasdaq 100 index fund.</strong> It emphasizes the priority of risk management, especially determining the cash ratio based on individual circumstances and building asset allocation based on this, rather than pursuing a specific Beta value or being driven by market sentiment. The differences in risk perception at different life stages and wealth levels were discussed, and the use of high-risk leverage (such as margin trading) for investment was strongly opposed. In addition, practical advice and warnings were shared on tax planning, retirement preparation, financial service selection, and consumption mentality. The Q&amp;A session delved into the specific problems encountered by students in practice, further clarifying strategy details and risk considerations, such as retirement fund calculation, the view on global diversification, and psychological management techniques (focus on overall portfolio rather than local volatility). Overall, this content revolves around the two words <strong>&ldquo;determination&rdquo;</strong> and <strong>&ldquo;safety,&rdquo;</strong> that is, maintaining strategic determination and financial security in a volatile market, and adhering to the correct principles.</p>

  



<div
  
    class="flex px-4 py-3 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900"
  >

  <span
    
      class="text-primary-400 ltr:pr-3 rtl:pl-3 flex items-center"
    >

    

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M506.3 417l-213.3-364c-16.33-28-57.54-28-73.98 0l-213.2 364C-10.59 444.9 9.849 480 42.74 480h426.6C502.1 480 522.6 445 506.3 417zM232 168c0-13.25 10.75-24 24-24S280 154.8 280 168v128c0 13.25-10.75 24-23.1 24S232 309.3 232 296V168zM256 416c-17.36 0-31.44-14.08-31.44-31.44c0-17.36 14.07-31.44 31.44-31.44s31.44 14.08 31.44 31.44C287.4 401.9 273.4 416 256 416z"/></svg>

  </span>


  </span>

  <span
    
      class="dark:text-neutral-300"
    ><strong>Disclaimer:</strong> This article is only a personal study note and does not constitute any investment advice.</span>
</div>

]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>00506 How to Leverage Your Investment Returns Through Stock Financing? Index Investing Community Exchange: Learn, Share, and Grow Together</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1741528316040/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1741528316040/</guid><description>This episode delves into the specifics of stock financing in China, including operations, risk control, and broker selection, emphasizing the importance of risk management and compliance. James also stresses the importance of managing investment psychology, reminding everyone not to overreact to market fluctuations and to stick to a long-term investment strategy. This episode also provides detailed answers to questions on asset allocation, tax planning, and leveraged funds.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<lite-youtube videoid="rrEKsIfR84g" playlabel="rrEKsIfR84g" params=""></lite-youtube>



<h2 class="relative group">I. Current Topic 
    <div id="i-current-topic" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-current-topic" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>The core of this episode is to analyze the specific operation process, risk control points, and broker selection criteria of stock financing in mainland China, while also taking into account the management of investment psychology.  The aim is to help investors utilize financial tools for asset appreciation while ensuring risk control and compliance. Teacher James emphasizes the concept of long-term investment and cautions investors not to be affected by short-term market fluctuations.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">II. Briefing Content 
    <div id="ii-briefing-content" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii-briefing-content" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">1. Stock Financing 
    <div id="1-stock-financing" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#1-stock-financing" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Cost of Capital:</strong>
<ul>
<li>Three common types of loans in China:
<ul>
<li><strong>Personal Credit Loan:</strong> For individuals with stable jobs, such as civil servants. No collateral is required.  Borrowers can obtain 200,000 to 300,000 RMB with an annual interest rate of around 3%.  Typically, only interest is paid for the first three years, followed by principal repayment.</li>
<li><strong>Mortgage-backed Business Loan:</strong> Requires the borrower to have a business.  Real estate is used as collateral.  It is possible to arrange a loan where only interest is paid for the first ten years, followed by principal repayment.  The current lowest annual interest rate can reach 2.4%.</li>
<li><strong>Broker Stock Financing:</strong> Financing services provided by brokers.  Currently, friendly brokers in China can offer an annual interest rate of 4%, which can be reduced to 3.6% depending on the asset amount.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Stock financing is the best borrowing method. The key is that the principal can be extended indefinitely, interest accrual can be deferred indefinitely, and the loan duration is considered 0.  This means that, in theory, the principal never needs to be repaid; only interest needs to be paid.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Prerequisites:</strong>
<ul>
<li><strong>Choosing the Best Broker:</strong> Compare the fees and interest charging methods of different brokers.  Choose the broker with the lowest interest rate and the most favorable repayment policy.</li>
<li><strong>Familiarize Yourself with Stock Financing Rules:</strong> Understand concepts like margin ratio, warning line, and liquidation line to avoid the risk of forced liquidation due to improper operation. Stock financing is essentially borrowing money to speculate in stocks, and high-leverage operations should be approached with caution.</li>
<li><strong>Coordinate the General Account and Margin Account:</strong> Understand the rules for transferring funds and stocks between the two accounts.</li>
<li><strong>Combine the &ldquo;Never Sell Nasdaq&rdquo; and &ldquo;Never Repay Debt&rdquo; Strategies:</strong> Use long-term holdings of the Nasdaq as collateral to utilize low-cost financing for other investments or consumption.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Specific Operation:</strong>
<ul>
<li>Having over 500,000 RMB in Nasdaq assets allows you to open a stock financing account (margin account) with a broker.</li>
<li>Transfer the Nasdaq ETF (e.g., 513100) from the general account to the margin account as collateral.</li>
<li>Example using 10% financing:
<ul>
<li>Use the financing to buy 100,000 RMB worth of Nasdaq ETF.</li>
<li>After the transaction is completed, transfer the ETF to the general account through collateral transfer (can only be transferred on the second trading day).</li>
<li>Sell the Nasdaq ETF in the general account to obtain cash, which can be used for other investments or consumption.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Most brokers offer a six-month extension service, which can theoretically be extended indefinitely as long as interest is paid on time.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Considerations When Choosing a Broker:</strong>
<ul>
<li><strong>Interest Calculation Method:</strong> Some brokers calculate interest including the start date but excluding the end date, while others include both. The latter will charge one more day of interest.</li>
<li><strong>Whether Unpaid Interest Incurs Penalties:</strong> Pay attention to the broker&rsquo;s charging policy for interest overdrafts.</li>
<li><strong>Whether Unpaid Interest is Included in Debt (Simple/Compound Interest):</strong> The best situation is simple interest accounting, where unpaid interest does not accrue to the financing debt.</li>
<li>Summary: Find a broker with low interest, simple interest accounting, and where unpaid interest is not transferred to the financing debt.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Familiarize Yourself with Financing Rules (Focus on Margin Ratio):</strong>
<ul>
<li>Margin Ratio = Total Account Assets / Total Financing Amount.</li>
<li>Only stocks with a margin ratio exceeding 300% can be transferred to the general account, indicating that excessive borrowing prevents transfers.</li>
<li><strong>Warning Line:</strong> If the margin ratio is 150%, the broker will notify you to add margin or make a repayment.</li>
<li><strong>Liquidation Line:</strong> If the margin ratio is 130%, the broker will forcibly liquidate, selling stocks to repay the debt.</li>
<li>Example:
<ul>
<li>1 million RMB in Nasdaq, financed 100,000 RMB, transfer 100,000 RMB worth of Nasdaq to the general account.</li>
<li>Margin Ratio = 1 million RMB / 100,000 RMB = 1000%, very safe.</li>
<li>If 513100 drops 85%, the total account assets remaining are 150,000 RMB, and the margin ratio reaches 150%, triggering the warning line.</li>
<li>If 513100 drops 87%, the total account assets remaining are 130,000 RMB, and the margin ratio reaches 130%, triggering the liquidation line.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Why Do This:</strong>
<ul>
<li>Chinese Broker Rules: If there is cash in the margin account, it will be used to repay the stock loan principal first.</li>
<li>By transferring the financed Nasdaq to the general account and selling it, you can obtain cash.</li>
<li>There is no capital gains tax in China, and the commission is extremely low, as low as 0.05% for some brokers.</li>
<li>The operation is completely compliant and in accordance with the broker&rsquo;s financing rules.</li>
<li>It is recommended that the stock pledge ratio should not exceed 10%, which is considered a safe leverage.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Operational Precautions:</strong>
<ul>
<li>Always keep zero cash in the margin account.</li>
<li>When you need to invest more funds to buy 513100, transfer the funds to the general account to purchase and then transfer them to the margin account.</li>
<li>When you need to borrow money and sell stocks, transfer the financed portion to the general account to sell and convert it to cash.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">2. Supplementary Notes on Domestic Stock Financing in China 
    <div id="2-supplementary-notes-on-domestic-stock-financing-in-china" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#2-supplementary-notes-on-domestic-stock-financing-in-china" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Thanks to Teacher James&rsquo; selfless dedication, taking the elimination of poverty as his lifelong career.</li>
<li>Sharing being &ldquo;electrified&rdquo; by the 00451 video, agreeing with its underlying logic and belief, buying all 513100 and holding it for the long term.</li>
<li>Thinking about how to borrow low-cost &ldquo;garbage&rdquo; (debt) and convert it into assets, let the assets grow by compound interest, never sell, let the debt be accounted for by simple interest and never be repaid, at most borrow new debt to repay old debt, to ensure that the assets are not damaged.</li>
<li>Amazed that Teacher James&rsquo; investment system continues to evolve, from the initial 70% QQQ to InQQQ, and then integrating credit, stock pledges, leveraged funds, and cash to form an all-around large-scale operational system across sea, land, and air.</li>
<li>Due to the imperfect financial tools in China, there are no stock pledges and leveraged funds, so it can only stay at the Nasdaq credit stage, and the power is greatly reduced.</li>
<li>Emphasize practicing internal strength, learning Teacher James&rsquo; investment philosophy and spirit, combining it with the domestic financial environment, integrating it, and driving it with profound internal strength.</li>
<li>Supplement the comparison of the advantages and disadvantages of stock pledge/financing from the perspective of learning, thinking, and practice:
<ul>
<li><strong>Taxation:</strong> The United States has a capital gains tax, while the securities account in China is similar to the American ROTH IRA, which is tax-free. Nasdaq assets grow by compound interest, and financing is accounted for by simple interest, doubling the happiness.</li>
<li><strong>Interest:</strong> The interest rate on stock pledges in the United States is relatively high, currently about 7%+, and it is compounded into the debt; the interest rate on stock financing in China is relatively low, about 4%, with simple interest accounting, which is more cost-effective in the long run.</li>
<li><strong>Mechanism:</strong> Stock pledges in the United States can only be used for consumption, with a safety buffer, and are relatively stable; currently, in China, it can only be used by converting stock financing into cash for consumption, which is riskier and requires strict control of the proportion within 10%.</li>
<li><strong>Humanity:</strong> Emphasize controlling risks, including controlling humanity. Greed when rising, fear when falling. The teacher changed from the previous 20% M to strictly prohibiting financing, because when the number of people increases, it is difficult to comply with the safety margin, and fear will be amplified when it falls.</li>
<li><strong>Principle:</strong> Financial tools are neutral, and the risk lies in the user.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">3. Others 
    <div id="3-others" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#3-others" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Nasdaq 100 is listed in Hong Kong (code 03455).</li>
<li>Recommend listening to books and podcasts on YouTube Music.  Using YouTube Music allows you to listen only to audio, saving data. You can listen to the CLEC channel through YouTube podcasts.</li>
<li>The 2025 Buffett Shareholder Meeting can be found on YouTube.</li>
<li>Li Lu&rsquo;s speech is worth listening to. He not only talks about investment, but also macroeconomics and social systems, and has in-depth analysis of the Japanese and Chinese systems.</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">III. Q&amp;A 
    <div id="iii-qa" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii-qa" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Dev 
    <div id="dev" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#dev" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Supplementing the premise of stock pledge borrowing in mainland China, there may be policy risks with brokers, who may require immediate debt repayment at any time. Therefore, it is necessary to always keep enough cash to cover the debt.
<ul>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo; Comment: Emphasizes that borrowing should not exceed 10%, otherwise, it is not meaningful.  If you buy leveraged funds in Hong Kong and keep a certain proportion of cash, you can break through the 10% limit and achieve a similar effect to the American 442.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">JOYCE 
    <div id="joyce" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#joyce" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question: Living in the US, there is no credit loan like in Taiwan. Besides HLOC, are there any other ways to borrow to accelerate asset growth?
<ul>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo; Reply: There are no credit loans in the United States, and the interest rates on credit cards are very high.  Due to cultural reasons, credit loans are more common in Taiwan and China, and the interest rates are also lower.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">James 
    <div id="james" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#james" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question 1: For the 442 asset allocation, when it falls, you need to add 2% to QLD, but LIIA can only put in $7,000 per year, which is not enough.  How to deal with it? Should a portion of the two layers of cash be placed in LIIA?
<ul>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo; Reply:
<ul>
<li>No.  Keep cash in a Traditional IRA or Brokerage Account, preferably in a Traditional IRA for better tax benefits.</li>
<li>Do a Conversion, from IRA to Roth IRA to add leverage, especially when the market falls, it is more beneficial to do Conversion.  Transferring the same 100 shares of QQQ requires less funds when it falls.</li>
<li>Or convert QLD to TQQQ, but it is not recommended.  If you must do this, calculate how much QLD needs to be converted to TQQQ to achieve 2% leverage.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2: Two weeks ago, the teacher said that QQQ would rise higher after the adjustment.  In these two weeks, QQQ has declined.  Did the teacher see the phenomenon and predict the adjustment, or did he just say it casually, and it happened to fall?
<ul>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo; Reply: Unspeakable, don&rsquo;t know.  Even if I knew, I wouldn&rsquo;t say.  The key is that you should not try to predict the market.  Even if you have escaped a few bubbles, you cannot guarantee that you will succeed every time.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">VIC 
    <div id="vic" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#vic" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question: I have 1 million in loan funds.  Should I use 721 or 633 for asset allocation? I am currently working and have some time before retirement.
<ul>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo; Reply:
<ul>
<li>You can choose 442 or 433. 442 is more aggressive and suitable for young people.</li>
<li>442 is 40% QQQ/006200, 40% QLD/00679L, 20% cash 864B.</li>
<li>Balance according to the proportion at the end of the year.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Supplement:
<ul>
<li>Risk tolerance is very important. Find a comfortable situation for yourself.</li>
<li>Investment is not about pursuing the highest rate of return, but about being stable.</li>
<li>50% investment and 50% cash is also very comfortable, and the return rate can also reach 9.25%.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Further Supplement:
<ul>
<li>For stock pledge borrowing, Smart Rebalancing is based on the initial assets.</li>
<li>When the market rises, move 30% of the appreciation for the year to cash.</li>
<li>Emphasize referring to the Smart Rebalancing document.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>One More Supplement: The 2% of 442 comes from cash to supplement leveraged funds.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Ah Xia 
    <div id="ah-xia" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ah-xia" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Contacted the teacher&rsquo;s course in October last year.  After the New Year, I put all my mortgage into it.  Now I block all stock market news and focus on work and spending time with my family.</li>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo; Comment: Well done.</li>
<li>Question: If my family needs money, can I borrow a small amount from the stock pledge as household expenses?
<ul>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo; Reply: Absolutely correct, that&rsquo;s the purpose of stock pledges.</li>
<li>Supplement: If you are truly proficient, you can remove the app and place orders by calling the broker.</li>
<li>Further Supplement: Market fluctuations have nothing to do with me, international situations have nothing to do with me, market analysis has nothing to do with me, financial reports have nothing to do with me, economic situations have nothing to do with me, everything has nothing to do with me, ignore the deep ups and downs of the market.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Kk 
    <div id="kk" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#kk" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>
<p>Question: Why shouldn&rsquo;t we buy when the market falls?</p>
<ul>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo; Reply: You shouldn&rsquo;t have any bullets when it falls.  All bullets should have been fired.  A fall means you have already made a lot of money.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p>Question: I just sold a house.  How should I buy?</p>
<ul>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo; Reply: Buy everything at the market price immediately.  There is nothing to hesitate about.</li>
<li>If you always keep cash and prepare to buy when it falls, you shouldn&rsquo;t be listening to my class.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Haoqin 
    <div id="haoqin" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#haoqin" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question: What do you think of TSMC building a factory in the United States and setting up an R&amp;D department in the United States?
<ul>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo; Reply:
<ul>
<li>It is very normal to move towards a truly world-class company.  Don&rsquo;t worry, the company&rsquo;s decisions are based on maximizing its own interests.</li>
<li>It is normal to set up R&amp;D in the United States.  Whether it surpasses Taiwan is not important.  It is all for TSMC&rsquo;s use.</li>
<li>Don&rsquo;t use it too outrageously.  Does Microsoft need to explain to all Americans when it opens an R&amp;D center in Taiwan?  TSMC should not be linked to the &ldquo;national protection mountain.&rdquo;</li>
<li>Don&rsquo;t have a small-country mentality. You should be happy that TSMC has become a world-class company.</li>
<li>The most talented people in the United States are not going into factories now.  The most talented people in the United States are doing software.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Yao 
    <div id="yao" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#yao" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: I just came across the teacher&rsquo;s channel two weeks ago.  Besides working and sleeping, I have been listening to the teacher&rsquo;s videos and continuing to invest. My sleep quality has improved, and I pay less attention to financial news.</li>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo; Comment: Well done.</li>
<li>Question: I have a lot of pressure at work.  Do you have any good suggestions?
<ul>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo; Reply:
<ul>
<li>It&rsquo;s not that important.  Don&rsquo;t think too highly of yourself.  It&rsquo;s not your problem if the world collapses.</li>
<li>Do only three things a day.  Finish them and go home.  Don&rsquo;t put all the monkeys on your shoulders.</li>
<li>If you are stressed, go out and eat ice cream. Give yourself time to relax.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Others 
    <div id="others" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#others" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>
<p>Question: I have some investments in Taiwan and will have a fixed income in New Taiwan Dollars every year.  Should I buy 00662 or convert it to US dollars to buy QQQ?</p>
<ul>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo; Reply:
<ul>
<li>Keep it in Taiwan and buy 00662 first.</li>
<li>Convert to the United States after you have status.</li>
<li>You can apply for a credit loan in Taiwan and use 662 as collateral to borrow.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p>Question: About BXMX.</p>
<ul>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo; Reply:
<ul>
<li>BXMX is a box trade that earns time value.  It is essentially arbitrage.</li>
<li>Time value is close to the risk-free rate, which is the federal funds rate.</li>
<li>BXMX is tax-free.  People with dividend tax need to use BXMX, which can be used to legally avoid taxes in the United States.</li>
<li>You can apply for a refund of the withholding tax, but the operation is complicated.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Supplement: Consider account risks, inheritance risks, especially for overseas accounts.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p>Question: Can I put money in a money market if I have money to invest?</p>
<ul>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo; Reply: Of course, you can put money in a Money Market once you have the funds to invest.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p>Question: I have to withdraw a certain amount from my retirement account every year to pay taxes.</p>
<ul>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo; Reply: The withholding tax amount is enough to pay the taxes.  You don&rsquo;t need to withdraw money from your retirement account to pay taxes.  This situation is not normal.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">IV. Key Takeaways 
    <div id="iv-key-takeaways" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv-key-takeaways" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>Market analysis has nothing to do with me.
&ndash; Teacher James</p></blockquote>
<p>This emphasizes that long-term investors should ignore short-term market fluctuations and focus on long-term value investing.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>You have to train until there is no market, you have to train until we investors train to ignore the existence of the market.
&ndash; Ah Xia</p></blockquote>
<p>This emphasizes the importance of mentality in the investment process, to overcome human greed and fear, and not to be affected by market sentiment.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Since you have already recognized the teacher&rsquo;s path, don&rsquo;t let those outside messages affect your normal life.
&ndash; Ah Xia</p></blockquote>
<p>This encourages investors to stick to their own investment strategies and not be easily interfered with by external information.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Cultivation comes from falling.
&ndash; Teacher James</p></blockquote>
<p>This illustrates that the path of investment is not smooth sailing, and you need to experience the test of the market to truly grow.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>A truly good building is not made by the builder, but by the designer.
&ndash; Haoqin</p></blockquote>
<p>This is a metaphor, illustrating that in the value chain, the importance of design and concept is often higher than execution.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The concept is the most valuable.
&ndash; Haoqin</p></blockquote>
<p>Echoing the previous point, emphasizing the importance of innovation and thinking.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>It&rsquo;s not your problem if the world collapses, it&rsquo;s the company&rsquo;s problem if the company collapses.
&ndash; Teacher James</p></blockquote>
<p>This aims to relieve the audience&rsquo;s work pressure and let them understand that life is not just about work, and they should learn to relax.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The company&rsquo;s collapse is the company&rsquo;s business, what does it have to do with me?
&ndash; Teacher James</p></blockquote>
<p>Further emphasizing that work is not all of life, and there is no need to be overly anxious.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The withholding tax amount is enough to pay the taxes.  You don&rsquo;t need to withdraw money from your retirement account to pay taxes.
&ndash; Teacher James</p></blockquote>
<p>Addressing the tax question raised by the audience, giving direct advice and stating that this situation should not occur.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">V. Summary 
    <div id="v-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#v-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This episode delves into the operational details and risks of stock financing, emphasizing the importance of mindset management and long-term investment.  Through detailed explanations and practical case analysis, Teacher James helps investors better understand investment strategies and reminds everyone to develop appropriate asset allocation plans based on their own circumstances.</p>

  



<div
  
    class="flex px-4 py-3 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900"
  >

  <span
    
      class="text-primary-400 ltr:pr-3 rtl:pl-3 flex items-center"
    >

    

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M506.3 417l-213.3-364c-16.33-28-57.54-28-73.98 0l-213.2 364C-10.59 444.9 9.849 480 42.74 480h426.6C502.1 480 522.6 445 506.3 417zM232 168c0-13.25 10.75-24 24-24S280 154.8 280 168v128c0 13.25-10.75 24-23.1 24S232 309.3 232 296V168zM256 416c-17.36 0-31.44-14.08-31.44-31.44c0-17.36 14.07-31.44 31.44-31.44s31.44 14.08 31.44 31.44C287.4 401.9 273.4 416 256 416z"/></svg>

  </span>


  </span>

  <span
    
      class="dark:text-neutral-300"
    ><strong>Disclaimer:</strong> This article is only a personal learning note and does not constitute any investment advice.</span>
</div>

]]></content:encoded></item></channel></rss>