<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Index Fund on QQQ Investor</title>
    <link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/tags/index-fund/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Index Fund on QQQ Investor</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jomonylw.github.io/en/tags/index-fund/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>00486 Market Trends and Future Investment Strategies: Navigating the New Economic Era</title>
      <link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1728231523948/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1728231523948/</guid>
      <description>In this session, James shares his analysis of the current market situation and investment advice. He also answers questions from the audience on topics like asset allocation, retirement planning, children&amp;#39;s education, handling stock options, leverage, and tax planning.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<lite-youtube videoid="mwchPrvkFMA" playlabel="mwchPrvkFMA" params=""></lite-youtube>



<h2 class="relative group">I. Main Topic 
    <div id="i-main-topic" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-main-topic" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>The theme of this session is <strong>Embrace the New Bull Market and Invest Long-Term.</strong> James believes that the global monetary easing policy and the rapid development of AI technology herald the arrival of a new bull market. He advises everyone to invest in the Nasdaq 100 index fund (QQQ or 00662) and view market fluctuations with a long-term perspective.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">II.  Content Summary 
    <div id="ii--content-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii--content-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<ul>
<li><strong>A new bull market is coming:</strong>  The world has entered an era of loose monetary policy with the start of a rate cut cycle, which will drive the stock market up. This bull market may be a slow one but will continuously rise.</li>
<li><strong>Invest confidently in the Nasdaq 100 index fund:</strong> QQQ could increase by 50 times in the next 20 years, with an annualized return of over 20%, making it the best investment target.</li>
<li><strong>Individual stocks are unreliable:</strong> Individual stock investment is risky, and in the long run, almost all of them will disappear. They are very difficult to outperform the market in the long term. It is recommended not to waste time and energy on stock selection.</li>
<li><strong>Do not invest in the Chinese stock market:</strong> The Chinese stock market is not mature enough; consider investing in it after 30 years.</li>
<li><strong>Comparison of household asset allocation in the US and Taiwan:</strong>  American families invest most of their assets in securities to create social value, while Taiwanese families prefer cash, insurance, and real estate, locking up funds in non-appreciating areas.</li>
<li><strong>Leveraging through stock pledges:</strong> Using stock pledges to borrow increases liquidity and allows for continued investment to enjoy the benefits of compound growth. With an understanding of asset allocation, the interest cost of borrowing can be almost negligible.</li>
<li><strong>Plan for retirement early:</strong> Young people are advised to invest in 00662, and retirees can choose 00646 (SPY) or 0056 according to their fund size.</li>
<li><strong>Emphasize family education:</strong> Parents should cultivate their children&rsquo;s financial management concepts from an early age, guide them to make long-term investments, stay away from bad habits such as short-term speculation and gambling, and lead by example.</li>
<li><strong>Don&rsquo;t blindly trust high-yield investment products:</strong> Any investment product promising high returns may be a scam. It is important to understand its operating mechanism and learn to discern between true and false.</li>
<li><strong>The dangers of short-term trading:</strong> Short-term trading will miss the best investment opportunities. Long-term investment in index funds will yield more stable returns.</li>
<li><strong>The purpose of cash allocation:</strong> It is not for profit, but for dealing with emergencies like unemployment or a market crash. It is advisable to keep more than 10% of your assets in cash.</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">III. Q&amp;A Session 
    <div id="iii-qa-session" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii-qa-session" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<ul>
<li>
<p><strong>Retired Doctor Poch:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: After learning about James&rsquo; investment philosophy, he found a more relaxing and suitable investment method.</li>
<li>Question: How to obtain a stable cash flow after retirement? Is it necessary to adjust the investment strategy of 00662?
<ul>
<li>Answer:  The investment target can be adjusted according to the size of the retirement fund. Choose 00646 (SPY) or 0056 with lower volatility to guarantee cash flow.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>IM:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: He tried to guide his child to invest by matching contributions and increased his vigilance against high-yield traps.</li>
<li>Question 1: How to guide a child to invest and prevent them from spending investment income?
<ul>
<li>Answer: Emphasize that investment is a long-term behavior. Income cannot be withdrawn for consumption. Funds should grow continuously through compound interest.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2: How to choose a safe and reliable trust company? How to avoid the traps of high-yield trust products?
<ul>
<li>Answer: Any trust company that promises high returns may be a scam. You should take control of your own investment and financial management rights, clearly stipulate investment in index funds in the trust clause, and set up a regulatory unit to ensure fund security.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Rose:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: She frankly talked about her past investment failures and the process of gradually establishing the correct investment concept under the guidance of James.</li>
<li>Question 1: What are the differences and pros and cons of Margin Loan and Pledge Loan?  The interest rate of Margin Loan from IB is relatively low. Is it necessary to transfer to Charles Schwab for Pledge Loan?
<ul>
<li>Answer:  Margin Loan is riskier, and Pledge Loan is relatively safe. If the interest rate of IB&rsquo;s Margin Loan is low, you can continue to use it, but pay attention to controlling the borrowing ratio, preferably no more than 20%.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2: The return on cash allocation will decrease in the interest rate cut cycle. Is it still necessary to allocate cash?
<ul>
<li>Answer: The purpose of cash allocation is not for profit but to deal with contingencies, such as unemployment or a market crash. It is advisable to keep more than 10% of your assets in cash.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 3: How to manage children&rsquo;s investment accounts? Under whose name should it be, yours or the child&rsquo;s?
<ul>
<li>Answer: It is recommended to open an account in the child&rsquo;s name to cultivate their financial management concept, but control the amount and provide proper investment guidance. Estate planning can be done after the child becomes an adult.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Phoenix:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: He shared his confusion about handling company stock options and finally adopted James&rsquo; suggestion.</li>
<li>Question 1: How to deal with the stock options of unlisted companies?
<ul>
<li>Answer: If the company has a high possibility of going public, it is recommended to sell it to an investment company before the listing to get cash and invest in QQQ.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2: What do you think of Bitcoin? Can I invest in it?
<ul>
<li>Answer: If you already hold a small amount of Bitcoin, you can continue to hold it, but do not invest any more capital. It is recommended to focus on investing in QQQ.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Allen:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: He shared his questions about 401k and stock investment and eventually made adjustments under James&rsquo; advice.</li>
<li>Question 1: What should I do if I have too much money in my 401k account?
<ul>
<li>Answer:  It is recommended to stop making further contributions to 401k and transfer some funds to the Roth IRA account through the Backdoor Roth IRA.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2: How to switch from holding Nvidia stock to QQQ?
<ul>
<li>Answer: Sell Nvidia stock as soon as possible, transfer funds to QQQ, and pledge stocks to borrow money to pay taxes.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Haoqing:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: He demonstrated the difficulty of stock selection through data analysis and illustrated the advantages of long-term investment in QQQ with practical examples.</li>
<li>Question: Can stock picking beat QQQ?
<ul>
<li>Answer: Stock selection is difficult to outperform QQQ in the long run. Even if it beats the market in the short term, transaction costs and taxes need to be considered.  Invest in index funds for the long term.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Xiang:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: He shared his confusion about saving for children&rsquo;s education and inheritance and finally found a solution under James&rsquo; advice.</li>
<li>Question 1: Is it better to use a 529 Education Fund or invest in QQQ for children&rsquo;s education savings?
<ul>
<li>Answer:  Investing in QQQ is recommended because it has higher long-term returns and is more flexible.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2: How to do estate planning?
<ul>
<li>Answer:  For larger estates, it is recommended to set up an irrevocable trust and consult an estate lawyer for planning.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Kevin:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Frankly admitted his past investment failures and regained confidence under the guidance of James, starting to embark on the road of steady investment.</li>
<li>Question: How many listeners are losing money on investments?
<ul>
<li>Answer: Past investment experience is not important. What is important is to establish the correct investment concept and believe in the value of long-term investment in index funds.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Julia:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Shared her lessons learned from investing in Chinese concept stocks and second-tier growth stocks, and how to guide children to make long-term investments.</li>
<li>Question 1: How to deal with losses caused by investment in Chinese concept stocks and second-tier growth stocks?
- Answer: It is advisable to &ldquo;cut your losses&rdquo; and switch funds to QQQ in a timely manner.</li>
<li>Question 2: How to guide children to make long-term investments?
- Answer: You can use an investment calculator to show children the power of compound interest and guide them with your own investment experience.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Peter:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Shared his experience working at Apple and confirmed that many high-income earners also choose to invest in index funds.</li>
<li>Question: How to balance family expenses and investment?
- Answer: It is recommended to use stock pledges to borrow money to meet living expenses and continue investing in QQQ, so that assets can continue to grow through compound interest.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Jason:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: He shared his confusion about company tax declaration and finally found a suitable solution under James&rsquo; advice.</li>
<li>Question: How to choose the tax filing method?
<ul>
<li>Answer: If your income is low, you can choose to file a 1099; if your income is high, you are advised to establish an S Corporation.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Cindy:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Shared her experience of guiding her child to invest in Roth IRA and keep away from gambling.</li>
<li>Question: How to guide children to invest in Roth IRA? How to guide children to stay away from gambling?
<ul>
<li>Answer: Open a Roth IRA account for the child and make matching contributions. Lead by example and educate your child with the experiences and stories of people around you.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">IV.  Highlights 
    <div id="iv--highlights" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv--highlights" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>Lending is more powerful than the atomic bomb; it&rsquo;s ten times the atomic bomb!
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>When encouraging people to use stock pledges for borrowing and investment, James used this analogy to vividly illustrate the power of leverage.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Investing should be easy and fun.
&ndash;  Hola</p></blockquote>
<p>This is what a listener said when she shared her investment experience. She also tried short-term trading, but finally found that long-term investment suited her better.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Each person has a different destiny when it comes to money.
&ndash; Peter</p></blockquote>
<p>Peter said this thought-provoking sentence when he shared his experience of persuading his father to invest in QQQ. This also reflects that investment and financial management should be combined with one&rsquo;s own situation to find a suitable way.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>All the money in the world is mine; you just need to take it and use it.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>James used humorous words to express his confidence in the market when encouraging everyone to invest, which also reflects his optimistic and positive attitude towards life.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">V. Conclusion 
    <div id="v-conclusion" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#v-conclusion" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>In this live broadcast, James once again emphasized the concept of long-term investment in index funds. He also provided specific investment advice for the audience based on the current market situation, covering asset allocation, retirement planning, children&rsquo;s education, stock options handling, leverage, and tax planning. The sharing from the students provided other listeners with valuable reference experience, showing their growth and earnings during the process of learning about investment and financial management.</p>

  



<div
  
    class="flex px-4 py-3 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900"
  >

  <span
    
      class="text-primary-400 ltr:pr-3 rtl:pl-3 flex items-center"
    >

    

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M506.3 417l-213.3-364c-16.33-28-57.54-28-73.98 0l-213.2 364C-10.59 444.9 9.849 480 42.74 480h426.6C502.1 480 522.6 445 506.3 417zM232 168c0-13.25 10.75-24 24-24S280 154.8 280 168v128c0 13.25-10.75 24-23.1 24S232 309.3 232 296V168zM256 416c-17.36 0-31.44-14.08-31.44-31.44c0-17.36 14.07-31.44 31.44-31.44s31.44 14.08 31.44 31.44C287.4 401.9 273.4 416 256 416z"/></svg>

  </span>


  </span>

  <span
    
      class="dark:text-neutral-300"
    ><strong>Disclaimer:</strong> This article is only for personal learning notes and does not constitute any investment advice.</span>
</div>

]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>00477 Eternal Freedom from Worry and Stress: Wisdom and Strategies for Long-Term Investing</title>
      <link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1728565408053/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1728565408053/</guid>
      <description>In this session, James shares his investment philosophy, emphasizing the importance of independent thinking and risk management. He also answers questions from students on topics such as TQQQ, emergency funds, MAGS fund, and real estate investment.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<lite-youtube videoid="CfFEQJkTCBw" playlabel="CfFEQJkTCBw" params=""></lite-youtube>



<h2 class="relative group">I. Main Theme 
    <div id="i-main-theme" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-main-theme" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This session focuses on the philosophy of long-term investing, emphasizing the importance of independent thinking and risk management. James reiterates his long-held investment philosophy: choose the right investment target (such as QQQ), buy in early and hold for the long term, ignoring short-term market fluctuations, and ultimately achieve steady wealth growth. In addition, he discusses how to maintain a positive mindset, deal with stress and anxiety that may arise during the investment process, and how to choose a reliable brokerage to ensure account security.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">II. Briefing Content 
    <div id="ii-briefing-content" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii-briefing-content" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<ul>
<li><strong>Wealth is accumulated slowly, and enjoying the process of wealth accumulation is the meaning of life.</strong> Getting rich overnight or quickly is not the best way. Slowly accumulating wealth and enjoying it allows you to experience the true meaning of life and learn and grow from it.</li>
<li><strong>Don&rsquo;t blindly pursue high returns while ignoring risks.</strong> Many people pursue quick riches and hope for super high returns, but often overlook the risks involved, which may ultimately lead to losses outweighing gains. Learn to assess risk and choose an investment strategy that matches your risk tolerance.</li>
<li><strong>Investing requires finding a definite eternity, ignoring market noise, and maintaining inner peace.</strong> Index fund investing is a definite and eternal strategy that does not require painstaking research and operation. Simply holding for the long term can yield considerable returns.</li>
<li><strong>Investment is a loser&rsquo;s game, not seeking to win, but seeking not to lose.</strong>  In investing, avoiding mistakes is more important than pursuing victory. Index fund investing can help investors reduce mistakes and ultimately achieve victory.</li>
<li><strong>Buying in a lump sum at any time and holding for the long term is superior to other investment methods.</strong> Investing early and holding for the long term maximizes returns and delivers the best investment returns.</li>
<li><strong>Learn to distinguish between what can be done, what is effective, what can be worried about, and what is not worth worrying about.</strong> Focus your energy on important and solvable issues, ignore those that are irrelevant or beyond your control to improve efficiency and reduce unnecessary anxiety.</li>
<li><strong>Don&rsquo;t work too hard, let your money work for you.</strong> Put your money into the market and let it create wealth for you instead of devoting all your energy to work. Learn to utilize investment tools to achieve passive wealth growth.</li>
<li><strong>All pressure comes from expectations, and all worries come from not having a solution.</strong> Lower your expectations and actively seek solutions to relieve stress and anxiety.</li>
<li><strong>Learn to transfer pressure to those who can bear it and think about solutions for the worst-case scenario.</strong> Don&rsquo;t bear the pressure alone, learn to seek help, and think in advance about solutions to the worst-case scenario to calmly deal with challenges.</li>
<li><strong>Maintain inner peace, focus on the important things, and ignore the insignificant things.</strong> Stick to simple things, don&rsquo;t get involved in complex things, to maintain inner peace and focus on what really matters in life.</li>
<li><strong>Account security is the primary issue in investing. Choose a large, reputable brokerage to open an account and avoid using online brokers.</strong> Online brokers have security risks, such as account theft and asset freezing. Choosing a large, reputable brokerage can better protect your account security.</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">III. Q&amp;A Session 
    <div id="iii-qa-session" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii-qa-session" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p><strong>Dave:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing:</strong>
Shared the results of James&rsquo; TQQQ simulation backtest and raised the question of how to avoid the risk of a sharp TQQQ drawdown.</li>
<li><strong>Question and James&rsquo;s Reply:</strong>
James believes that it is impossible to predict the market and avoid all risks completely. The important thing is to control risk exposure and avoid over-betting. If you are worried about the volatility of TQQQ, you can choose a more conservative investment strategy, such as QQQ. James also reminds everyone to distinguish between personal thinking and public advice, and not to be easily swayed by the thoughts of others.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Minjianlian:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing:</strong>
Shared his experience of investing in stocks through his company&rsquo;s savings association, as well as discussions about the MAGS fund and emergency funds.</li>
<li><strong>Question and James&rsquo;s Reply:</strong>
<ol>
<li>About the MAGS fund: James believes that it is uncertain whether the MAGS fund can outperform QQQ in the long term. Investment should choose targets that have been tested by time, such as QQQ or SPY.</li>
<li>About emergency funds: James believes that emergency funds are a personal responsibility and government policies cannot be relied upon entirely. Everyone should prepare sufficient emergency funds according to their own circumstances to cope with contingencies.</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Learn:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Question and James&rsquo;s Reply:</strong>
Regarding the performance of 00670L, James explained the performance difference caused by USD hedging and how to solve it by investing in QLD through sub-brokerage. He emphasized that Beta and ROI are different concepts. Beta represents volatility, not ROI. The investment model in Taiwan needs to be adjusted according to specific circumstances, such as  maintenance margin requirements and exchange rate fluctuations.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>JJU:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing:</strong>
Shared his insights on market unpredictability and the importance of mentors and friends. He believes that investing, in addition to selecting good targets, is more about maintaining inner peace and enhancing one&rsquo;s spiritual level.</li>
<li><strong>Question and James&rsquo;s Reply:</strong>
<ol>
<li>About the difference between reinvest and buy share: James explained the difference between reinvesting and buying shares. The former automatically invests dividends or capital gains into the investment target, while the latter uses new funds to buy shares.</li>
<li>About the fund ratio of Roth IRA and Individual Brokerage Account: It is recommended to maximize the Roth IRA limit if possible.</li>
<li>About real estate mortgage investment: It is recommended to sell the property if possible to reduce the risk of investing in real estate. Otherwise, consider a Home Equity Line of Credit (HELOC) for investment, but pay attention to risk control and ensure that you can repay the loan on time. HELOC is a revolving credit line, similar to a credit card, which can be withdrawn and repaid at any time.</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Draft down:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing:</strong>
Proposed the possibility of leveraging 0% interest credit cards for investment and using the box spread strategy to increase capital utilization.</li>
<li><strong>Question and James&rsquo;s Reply:</strong>
<ol>
<li>About credit card investment: James believes that credit card limits are limited and there is a risk of not being able to renew the loan, making it unsuitable as a main source of investment funds. It is only suitable for short-term turnover of small amounts of funds.</li>
<li>About the box spread strategy: James believes that the box spread strategy is too complex and risky and is not recommended for ordinary investors.</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Jason:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Question and James&rsquo;s Reply:</strong>
<ol>
<li>How to overcome short-term pain in the investment process: James suggested lowering expectations, not pursuing perfection or getting rich quickly, finding solutions to problems, and transferring the pressure to those who can bear it, such as superiors or more experienced individuals. Think about solutions for the worst-case scenario, such as job loss or investment losses, and maintain a positive mindset, believing that the problem will eventually be solved.</li>
<li>About non-US tax resident investing in US stocks: James believes that non-US tax residents can use their passports to open brokerage accounts in the US without a Social Security Number. It is recommended to choose large, reputable brokers, such as Charles Schwab, and avoid using online brokers, such as Webull and Robinhood, as online brokers have security risks and imperfect regulations.</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">IV. Key Insights 
    <div id="iv-key-insights" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv-key-insights" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>Investment is a loser&rsquo;s game, not seeking to win, but seeking not to lose.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>In investing, avoiding mistakes is more important than pursuing victory. Choosing the right investment target, formulating a reasonable investment strategy and strictly adhering to discipline can reduce mistakes and ultimately achieve long-term stable returns.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Buying in a lump sum at any time and holding for the long term is superior to other investment methods.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>Investing early and holding for the long term maximizes returns and delivers the best investment returns. Time is a friend of investment. Starting early allows time to work its magic of compounding.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>All pressure comes from expectations, and all worries come from not having a solution.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>Lower your expectations and actively seek solutions to relieve stress and anxiety. When facing challenges, maintain a positive attitude and believe that you can find a way to solve the problem.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Wealth is accumulated slowly, and enjoying the process of wealth accumulation is the meaning of life.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>Getting rich overnight or quickly is not the best way. Slowly accumulating wealth and enjoying it allows you to experience the true meaning of life. Investing is a long-term process. Don&rsquo;t be impatient and enjoy the process of wealth accumulation, learning and growing from it.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Good teachers and helpful friends are important. You may not be right if you agree with someone.
&ndash; JJU</p></blockquote>
<p>In the investment process, be good at learning and thinking. Don&rsquo;t blindly believe anyone&rsquo;s point of view, including teachers and friends. Make your own independent thinking and judgment to make the right investment decisions.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Account security is the primary issue in investing.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>Choosing a large, reputable brokerage to open an account, such as Charles Schwab, can better protect your account security. Avoid using online brokers as online brokers have security risks and imperfect regulations.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">V. Summary 
    <div id="v-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#v-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This session focuses on the long-term investment philosophy, risk control, and mindset management. James helps students better understand the essence of investment through vivid examples and in-depth explanations. He answers students&rsquo; various questions encountered in the investment process, such as the risks of TQQQ, the importance of emergency funds, and real estate investment strategies. At the same time, students also actively share their experiences and confusion, such as using credit cards for investment and using the box spread strategy, triggering deeper thinking and discussion. James emphasizes the importance of independent thinking, advising against blindly believing anyone&rsquo;s point of view. He encourages making independent thinking and judgment to make the right investment decisions. At the same time, he also reminds everyone to pay attention to account security, choose large, reputable brokers to open accounts, and avoid using online brokers.</p>

  



<div
  
    class="flex px-4 py-3 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900"
  >

  <span
    
      class="text-primary-400 ltr:pr-3 rtl:pl-3 flex items-center"
    >

    

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M506.3 417l-213.3-364c-16.33-28-57.54-28-73.98 0l-213.2 364C-10.59 444.9 9.849 480 42.74 480h426.6C502.1 480 522.6 445 506.3 417zM232 168c0-13.25 10.75-24 24-24S280 154.8 280 168v128c0 13.25-10.75 24-23.1 24S232 309.3 232 296V168zM256 416c-17.36 0-31.44-14.08-31.44-31.44c0-17.36 14.07-31.44 31.44-31.44s31.44 14.08 31.44 31.44C287.4 401.9 273.4 416 256 416z"/></svg>

  </span>


  </span>

  <span
    
      class="dark:text-neutral-300"
    ><strong>Disclaimer:</strong> This article is only for personal learning notes and does not constitute any investment advice.</span>
</div>

]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
