<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Risk Control on QQQ Investor</title>
    <link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/tags/risk-control/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Risk Control on QQQ Investor</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jomonylw.github.io/en/tags/risk-control/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>00487 The Truth About Investing：Maximizing the Probability of Success, Not Returns; How to Navigate Market Volatility：Strategies to Avoid Interrupting Compound Growth</title>
      <link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1728777529388/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1728777529388/</guid>
      <description>James announces the discontinuation of short video updates, with content to be condensed into a Saturday briefing format. This session emphasizes the importance of risk control and how to maximize the success probability of an investment portfolio. James addresses audience questions on stock pledging, asset allocation, individual stock investments, and reiterates warnings about pump-and-dump schemes and scams. He also shares insights on market volatility, A-share market fluctuations, and investment psychology.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<lite-youtube videoid="ThLEX-IsszE" playlabel="ThLEX-IsszE" params=""></lite-youtube>



<h2 class="relative group">I. Session Topic 
    <div id="i-session-topic" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-session-topic" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This session revolves around risk control and investment strategies, with the core message being that investment success lies not in maximizing returns, but in maximizing the probability of success. It emphasizes avoiding forced interruption of compound growth due to market fluctuations, choosing an investment portfolio that can be held for the long term, and highlights the importance of cash. James announces the discontinuation of short video updates, with future sharing of investment philosophies and case studies through long videos and Saturday briefings.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">II. Briefing Content 
    <div id="ii-briefing-content" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii-briefing-content" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<ul>
<li><strong>Discontinuation of Short Videos:</strong> James announces the end of short video updates, with content to be streamlined and condensed into a briefing format, shared and discussed on Saturdays, covering case studies and life philosophies. Short videos have been produced up to March 27th of next year, at which point updates will cease.</li>
<li><strong>Prioritizing Risk Control:</strong> The most important aspect of investing is maximizing the probability of success, not maximizing returns. Risk control aims to safeguard the long-term success of an investment portfolio, avoiding forced exits due to market volatility. It&rsquo;s better to earn less and ensure long-term holding.</li>
<li><strong>Importance of Cash:</strong> Sufficient cash is a crucial asset for ensuring the safety of an investment portfolio, allowing investors  to weather periods of significant market decline with peace of mind. It&rsquo;s the key to &ldquo;sleeping well at night.&rdquo;</li>
<li><strong>Risks of Stock Pledging:</strong> Stock pledging, if not accompanied by proper asset allocation, carries a substantial risk of bankruptcy. Without adequate financial literacy, it should not be attempted lightly. Especially in Taiwan, borrowing 3 million against 5 million in assets is close to the pledging limit and extremely risky. James emphasizes understanding &ldquo;Scenario 1&rdquo; through &ldquo;Scenario 9&rdquo; and how to respond to different situations.</li>
<li><strong>Importance of Asset Allocation:</strong> Proper asset allocation is crucial, tailored to individual circumstances.  Those who don&rsquo;t understand stock pledging should avoid it. Recommendations are provided for different asset levels and retirement statuses:
<ul>
<li><strong>Not retired and with income:</strong> QQQ 60% + QLD 20% + Cash 20%. This is an aggressive investment strategy, with most funds allocated to Nasdaq 100 index funds.</li>
<li><strong>Retired and with sufficient assets (50x annual expenses and above):</strong> QQQ 80% + Cash 20%. Retirees with ample assets can adopt this allocation.</li>
<li><strong>Retired with assets between 20-50x annual expenses:</strong> SPY or High Dividend + Cash 20% (SPY/High Dividend ratio can be adjusted based on specific circumstances). Those who are retired but with insufficient assets can utilize an SPY or High Dividend strategy with a 20% cash allocation.</li>
<li><strong>Retired with assets below 20x annual expenses:</strong> 0056 or SPHD + 5% Cash (conservative strategy).  Individuals with even fewer assets should not engage in stock pledging due to the higher risk, and should adopt a more conservative strategy.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Beware of Pump-and-Dump Schemes and Scams:</strong>  Listeners are warned to be vigilant against pump-and-dump schemes and scams in the market, not to blindly trust so-called &ldquo;gurus&rdquo; and &ldquo;experts,&rdquo; and to avoid sending money to unknown websites. CLEC does not charge any fees, and all groups are open and transparent.</li>
<li><strong>Market Volatility is Normal:</strong> The market will eventually rise and continually reach new highs. Investors should remain optimistic and patiently await the growth of their wealth. &ldquo;Investors are always optimistic, always looking towards the sun.&rdquo;</li>
<li><strong>A-Share Market Volatility:</strong> The A-share market is highly volatile, reminding investors to remain rational and avoid impulsive buying and selling. The government&rsquo;s cooling measures are aimed at the long-term healthy development of the market, not at specific stocks or investors.</li>
<li><strong>Investing is Like Life&rsquo;s Cultivation:</strong> The example of Journey to the West is used to illustrate that both investing and life require continuous learning and progress. Making mistakes is not terrible; the important thing is to learn from them.</li>
<li><strong>Recommended Reading:</strong> Recommends Professor Zhou Guannan&rsquo;s book &ldquo;Long-Term Investing&rdquo; to learn about investment psychology.</li>
<li><strong>Guidance for Newcomers:</strong> Newcomers are advised to watch YouTube channel videos 00451, 00398 or 00288, as well as videos from 2023 to the present, to understand CLEC&rsquo;s investment philosophy and system.</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">III. Q&amp;A Session 
    <div id="iii-qa-session" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii-qa-session" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p><strong>Ethan:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Although stock pledging is not available in mainland China, a similar effect can be achieved through the margin financing function of brokerage firms, utilizing the transfer of collateral between margin accounts and regular accounts.</li>
<li>Sharing: The A-share market has experienced significant volatility recently, reminding everyone not to be swayed by market sentiment and to adhere to a long-term investment strategy. Many investors are easily influenced by market emotions, leading to buying high and selling low.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Jackie:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Describes her journey from initial skepticism to fully understanding and embracing the concept of long-term Nasdaq investing, including overcoming psychological barriers to finally going all-in on QQQ. This sharing mentions two psychological obstacles overcome: 1. Fear of buying at the highest point; 2. Comparison between investing in real estate and investing in QQQ.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>H:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Recounts her personal experience of investing in popular stocks, and the eventual process of cutting losses and switching to QQQ, emphasizing the importance of cutting losses. Shares her experience of listening to recommendations for popular stocks in 2021, which led to losses, and finally switching to QQQ in 2023.</li>
<li>Question: The ratio of QQQ and QLD is out of balance, how to rebalance?</li>
<li>James&rsquo;s reply: Suggests using the Smart Rebalancing strategy, transferring 30% of the profits from QLD to SGOV. When the market falls, transfer 2% of the total assets in cash to QLD.  Also recommends that H read articles about Smart Rebalancing.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Kevin:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>Questions:</p>
<ul>
<li>I&rsquo;d like to understand why Tesla has dropped so much.</li>
<li>Also, could the stock market ever really fall to zero?</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p>James&rsquo; responses:</p>
<ul>
<li>Tesla&rsquo;s Decline: James stated that he doesn&rsquo;t have a specific opinion on this. Daily fluctuations are unpredictable, and jokingly suggested asking a deity (&ldquo;Third Prince&rdquo;) for a more accurate prediction. He emphasized that investing in individual stocks requires an understanding of the company&rsquo;s business model that surpasses even the CEO&rsquo;s. If you don&rsquo;t have a stronger vision and ability than Elon Musk, you shouldn&rsquo;t be investing in Tesla. Market ups and downs are not the primary concern; understanding the company&rsquo;s value and long-term plan is crucial.</li>
<li>Stock Market Crashing to Zero: James explained that &ldquo;the market falling to zero&rdquo; is a figure of speech. It refers to a situation where the market might not literally hit zero, but it falls to a point where selling is impractical or impossible. There&rsquo;s a possibility of market closures, like what happened during 911. Closure is equivalent to zero in that context. He highlighted the importance of cash reserves, as they are essential for sustaining living expenses during market downturns.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>IM:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Uses the mural story from Journey to the West as an analogy for the investment journey, from the initial excitement of entering the market to the pain of being trapped, and finally to the enlightenment of finding the correct investment method.</li>
<li>Question: How to persuade friends who spend money lavishly?</li>
<li>James&rsquo;s reply: Explain the concept of long-term investing and show them the long-term upward trend of the market, illustrating that even small investments can accumulate wealth over time. If they still can&rsquo;t understand, then there&rsquo;s nothing more that can be done.</li>
<li>Question: How to control one&rsquo;s own lavish spending?</li>
<li>James&rsquo;s reply: Within the scope of risk control, it&rsquo;s normal for living standards to improve as wealth grows. The key is not to exceed one&rsquo;s own capabilities and to avoid selling stocks as much as possible. Spending money is a form of self-cultivation; it&rsquo;s important to live within one&rsquo;s means.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Ming:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Question: A series of questions about retirement accounts, stock pledging, cash allocation, etc. Ming has 3.3 million in assets, of which 2 million are in brokerage, 300,000 in Roth, and 1 million in a traditional account, with a monthly mortgage payment of 125,000.</li>
<li>James&rsquo;s reply: Provides detailed answers to Ming&rsquo;s questions and offers specific asset allocation advice based on her situation, including the allocation of brokerage, Roth, and traditional accounts, and how to utilize stock pledging and borrowing to reduce tax burden. Recommends brokerage 100% SPY, Roth 100% TQQQ, traditional 60% cash + 40% SPY.  Also suggests that Ming engage in stock pledging and use borrowed funds to cover living expenses and taxes.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Sara:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Question: As a 1099 worker nearing retirement, how to carry out asset allocation and borrow for investment?</li>
<li>James&rsquo;s reply: Since Sara lacks sufficient understanding of concepts like stock pledging, it&rsquo;s recommended that she not borrow money and adopt a simple allocation of 80% QQQ + 20% cash, with the cash portion allocated to BOXS. Also advises Sara to rebalance annually.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Tom:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Question: Questions about borrowing for investment, cash allocation, tax optimization, etc. Tom is concerned about the interest expenses and high tax rates associated with long-term borrowing, and how to maintain sufficient cash in brokerage accounts.</li>
<li>James&rsquo;s reply: Suggests that Tom keep leveraged funds and cash primarily in retirement accounts and engage in pledging operations based on specific circumstances. Emphasizes the flexibility of Roth accounts and the ability to transfer funds to brokerage accounts in emergencies. Explains that the interest calculation method is an estimate and doesn&rsquo;t need to be overly precise. Also recommends that Tom use Roth account funds for investing in TQQQ, traditional accounts for holding cash, and brokerage accounts for investing in QQQ and engaging in pledging.</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">IV. Key Insights 
    <div id="iv-key-insights" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv-key-insights" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>Don&rsquo;t make getting rich your goal, but rather strive not to die impoverished.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Investing is for a better life, not for becoming a billionaire. A sound investment strategy is more important than pursuing high returns.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>If you don&rsquo;t have the right understanding of the stock market, you&rsquo;ll become a victim. The stock market is a scam.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Emphasizes the importance of investor education and the risks present in the market.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>A rotten apple won&rsquo;t get better, and a broken elevator won&rsquo;t fix itself.
&mdash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Uses an analogy to illustrate the risk of individual stock investing and the importance of cutting losses in a timely manner.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Market fluctuations can sometimes exceed your imagination. If, midway, due to a sharp decline caused by fluctuations, you exit the market out of fear, or are forced to exit, the initially projected performance of your investment portfolio, no matter how good, will be useless.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Highlights the importance of risk control. Even if the expected return is high, if you can&rsquo;t withstand the risk, you may ultimately end up losing everything.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Human nature is what it is, but you must learn to control it.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Points out the importance of controlling human nature and emotions in investing.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">V. Summary 
    <div id="v-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#v-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This session underscores the importance of risk control and long-term investing. Avoid blindly chasing high returns while ignoring risks. The most important aspect of investing is long-term holding, avoiding forced exits due to market fluctuations. James announces the discontinuation of short video updates and addresses audience questions on stock pledging, asset allocation, individual stock investing (Tesla), and A-share market volatility. He reminds everyone again to be wary of pump-and-dump schemes and scams in the market, emphasizing that CLEC does not charge any fees. He encourages everyone to read Professor Zhou Guannan&rsquo;s book &ldquo;Long-Term Investing&rdquo; to gain knowledge about investment psychology. Based on the situations of different listeners, James provides specific asset allocation advice and explains in detail how to conduct stock pledging and rebalancing operations.</p>

  



<div
  
    class="flex px-4 py-3 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900"
  >

  <span
    
      class="text-primary-400 ltr:pr-3 rtl:pl-3 flex items-center"
    >

    

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M506.3 417l-213.3-364c-16.33-28-57.54-28-73.98 0l-213.2 364C-10.59 444.9 9.849 480 42.74 480h426.6C502.1 480 522.6 445 506.3 417zM232 168c0-13.25 10.75-24 24-24S280 154.8 280 168v128c0 13.25-10.75 24-23.1 24S232 309.3 232 296V168zM256 416c-17.36 0-31.44-14.08-31.44-31.44c0-17.36 14.07-31.44 31.44-31.44s31.44 14.08 31.44 31.44C287.4 401.9 273.4 416 256 416z"/></svg>

  </span>


  </span>

  <span
    
      class="dark:text-neutral-300"
    ><strong>Disclaimer:</strong> This article is for personal learning notes only and does not constitute any investment advice.</span>
</div>

]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>00478 Invest Immediately and Hold Long-Term：Key Strategies for Achieving Financial Freedom</title>
      <link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1728479738630/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1728479738630/</guid>
      <description>This episode focuses on risk control and investment mindset. James reiterates the importance of asset allocation, especially during market volatility. He explains in detail how to allocate assets in different scenarios and how to maintain a positive investment mindset. In addition, James answers questions from the audience regarding insurance and financial products, Apple Vision Pro, the role of Wall Street, and 401K accounts.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<lite-youtube videoid="neKoOJhqK3c" playlabel="neKoOJhqK3c" params=""></lite-youtube>



<h2 class="relative group">I. Main Topic 
    <div id="i-main-topic" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-main-topic" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>During periods of market volatility, investors should prioritize risk control and maintain a positive and optimistic mindset. By establishing a rational asset allocation strategy, such as holding cash, index funds, and leveraged funds, and selecting an appropriate allocation plan based on individual circumstances, investors can effectively mitigate market risks and ensure survival even in extreme situations.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">II. Briefing Content 
    <div id="ii-briefing-content" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii-briefing-content" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<ol>
<li>
<p><strong>Investment Objective:</strong> Identify high-quality investment targets, such as market-capitalization-weighted index funds, and hold them for the long term. Avoid chasing high-return investment targets, as excessive volatility may lead to an inability to hold, ultimately hindering returns.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Risk Control:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Do not overestimate your risk tolerance, as market downturns often exceed expectations.</li>
<li>Selling leads to permanent losses; the only mistake in the market is selling.</li>
<li>Investing is a process that goes against human nature, requiring the overcoming of fear and greed.</li>
<li>Always ensure survival in extreme market conditions, meaning possessing sufficient cash flow to sustain living expenses.</li>
<li>Holding cash is crucial for mitigating risks.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Investment Mindset:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Investors should remain perpetually optimistic, believing that the market will eventually rise.</li>
<li>Be patient, as wealth accumulation takes time.</li>
<li>Do not be swayed by short-term market fluctuations; adhere to a long-term investment strategy.</li>
<li>Do not attempt to predict the market, and ignore market noise.</li>
<li>Keep investing simple: buy when you have money and hold for the long term; avoid excessive trading.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Asset Allocation:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>The highest guiding principle of asset allocation is: you can still survive under extreme market conditions.</li>
<li>Retirees need to hold more cash and can utilize leveraged funds to enhance returns while reducing risks.</li>
<li>Employed individuals can choose different asset allocation plans based on their circumstances, but ensure a certain proportion of cash holdings.</li>
<li>Do not alter your asset allocation based on market ups and downs, as this constitutes short-term trading behavior.</li>
<li>Asset allocation needs to be adjusted based on individual situations. For example, when significant events like retirement or purchasing a house occur, reassessment and adjustment of the asset allocation plan are necessary.</li>
<li>Leverage initially carries higher risk, which gradually decreases as the market rises.</li>
<li>It is recommended that retirement accounts comprise at least 30% of total assets to effectively avoid taxes during rebalancing.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Market Efficiency:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>The market is efficient; it&rsquo;s nearly impossible to find opportunities for consistent excess returns.</li>
<li>Do not readily believe investment strategies claiming to achieve excess returns, as they are often unsustainable.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>The Role of Wall Street:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Wall Street&rsquo;s primary roles are to provide liquidity and investment products, establish the framework for investment transactions, and lower the barriers to entry, allowing ordinary investors to participate.</li>
<li>Investors need to understand how Wall Street operates to avoid falling into its traps.</li>
<li>Market makers are a crucial part of Wall Street. They profit by providing bid-ask spreads while also offering liquidity to the market.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ol>


<h2 class="relative group">III. Q&amp;A Session 
    <div id="iii-qa-session" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii-qa-session" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p><strong>IM:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Black swan events remind us that people are forgetful, easily becoming optimistic during market upswings and panicking during downturns.</li>
<li>Question: How to control optimism and avoid overconfidence leading to bankruptcy?</li>
<li>James&rsquo;s response: Remember the highest guiding principle of asset allocation, ensuring survival under extreme conditions. Cash is the lifeline for survival.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Sunny:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Question: How to persuade people around me not to purchase insurance and financial products?</li>
<li>James&rsquo;s response: By calculating the annualized return rate of insurance products and comparing it with the return rates of other investment products, you can demonstrate that insurance and financial products offer lower returns. You can compare the return rates of insurance products with the long-term returns of index funds and point out that the income source for insurance companies and insurance agents is the premiums paid by customers.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Jason:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Experienced Apple Vision Pro and found its spatial computing capabilities impressive, but currently, it has limited functionality and applications, along with a high price tag.</li>
<li>Question: If investing is so simple, what is the role of Wall Street experts?</li>
<li>James&rsquo;s response: Wall Street&rsquo;s role primarily lies in providing liquidity, investment products, and the trading infrastructure, lowering the barriers to entry, enabling ordinary investors to participate in the market. Market makers are an essential component of Wall Street, making profits by providing bid-ask spreads while also offering liquidity to the market.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Brian:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Question: How can employed individuals utilize the asset allocation plan in Scenario 9?</li>
<li>James&rsquo;s response: Scenario 9 is suitable for retired individuals with loans. If you are employed and have substantial loans, such as a mortgage, you need to adjust the plan based on your circumstances. For example, pay off a portion of the loan before proceeding with asset allocation. Moreover, leverage carries higher risk initially, which gradually decreases as the market rises.</li>
<li>Question: How to allocate and rebalance assets between a 401K account and a Roth IRA account?</li>
<li>James&rsquo;s response: It&rsquo;s recommended that retirement accounts comprise at least 30% of total assets for effective tax avoidance during rebalancing. Due to the limited investment options within a 401K account, direct purchase of QQQ may not be possible. You can use similar alternatives or transfer funds to a Roth IRA account for more flexibility.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Yingying:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Question: What&rsquo;s the difference between QQQ and QQQM?</li>
<li>James&rsquo;s response: The market is efficient. There won&rsquo;t be a significant difference in the long-term returns of QQQ and QQQM. Choose QQQ, which has lower fees.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Grace:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Question: Should I convert 0066 to 00670L during a market downturn?</li>
<li>James&rsquo;s response: Do not change your asset allocation based on market fluctuations, as this constitutes short-term trading behavior.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Using Fatality:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s response: Charles Schwab is recommended because it is both a brokerage and a bank, offering higher security. Fidelity only has brokerage services and lacks a banking license, potentially facing risks during financial crises.</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">IV. Key Insights 
    <div id="iv-key-insights" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv-key-insights" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>The highest guiding principle of investing is: you can still survive under extreme market conditions.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Under any circumstances, ensure that you have sufficient cash flow to sustain your living expenses. This is the bottom line of investing.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Where are Wall Street&rsquo;s yachts? Where are the clients&rsquo; yachts?
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This vividly illustrates Wall Street&rsquo;s profit model, reminding investors to be wary of its various fees and traps.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Look down upon the poor and favor the rich.
&ndash; Zero seven&rsquo;s teacher</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This phrase reveals the harsh reality of Wall Street in the past and reflects the inequality of investment opportunities.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The market is efficient; you cannot have excess profits.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This emphasizes the efficient market hypothesis, reminding investors not to seek easy opportunities for excess returns.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">V. Conclusion 
    <div id="v-conclusion" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#v-conclusion" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This episode reiterates the importance of risk control and investment mindset, providing a detailed explanation of how to allocate assets under different circumstances and how to perceive the market and the role of Wall Street. Through interactive Q&amp;A with the audience, James addresses various investment-related questions and offers practical advice.</p>

  



<div
  
    class="flex px-4 py-3 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900"
  >

  <span
    
      class="text-primary-400 ltr:pr-3 rtl:pl-3 flex items-center"
    >

    

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M506.3 417l-213.3-364c-16.33-28-57.54-28-73.98 0l-213.2 364C-10.59 444.9 9.849 480 42.74 480h426.6C502.1 480 522.6 445 506.3 417zM232 168c0-13.25 10.75-24 24-24S280 154.8 280 168v128c0 13.25-10.75 24-23.1 24S232 309.3 232 296V168zM256 416c-17.36 0-31.44-14.08-31.44-31.44c0-17.36 14.07-31.44 31.44-31.44s31.44 14.08 31.44 31.44C287.4 401.9 273.4 416 256 416z"/></svg>

  </span>


  </span>

  <span
    
      class="dark:text-neutral-300"
    ><strong>Disclaimer:</strong> This article is for personal learning notes only and does not constitute any investment advice.</span>
</div>

]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
