<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Lifestyle on QQQ Investor</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/tags/lifestyle/</link><description>Recent content in Lifestyle on QQQ Investor</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jomonylw.github.io/en/tags/lifestyle/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>00490 Workers are just picking up trash; Mortgages are a risk for retirees; Buying a house won't make you rich.</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1730597712367/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1730597712367/</guid><description>This session focuses on investment philosophy, asset allocation, lifestyle, and how to cope with market fluctuations. It emphasizes the importance of staying optimistic, continuous learning, and answers questions from the audience on Bitcoin, real estate, retirement planning, leveraged funds, and education funds.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<lite-youtube videoid="Ad9u7a-z6Ro" playlabel="Ad9u7a-z6Ro" params=""></lite-youtube>



<h2 class="relative group">I. Main Topic 
    <div id="i-main-topic" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-main-topic" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This session revolves around investment and life planning. The core ideas are: be optimistic about investment and keep learning, ignoring short-term market fluctuations; young people should focus on asset appreciation, with Nasdaq 100 index funds being the top choice; utilize leverage and allocate assets reasonably; retirees should plan carefully and avoid excessive debt; and one should stay optimistic and confident, avoid material comparisons, and pursue true freedom.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">II. Presentation Content 
    <div id="ii-presentation-content" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii-presentation-content" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Investment Philosophy and Market Analysis 
    <div id="investment-philosophy-and-market-analysis" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#investment-philosophy-and-market-analysis" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Market Fluctuations and Investment Mentality:</strong> The market is always fluctuating. Don&rsquo;t let short-term fluctuations affect your investment decisions. Stay optimistic.</li>
<li><strong>Currency Devaluation and Asset Appreciation:</strong> Money depreciates; only assets like stocks can preserve and increase in value. Currency devaluation is more severe in emerging countries, so it is advised to convert currency into assets. Taiwan&rsquo;s low wages and currency devaluation are related to the government&rsquo;s subsidy policies.</li>
<li><strong>Worker Mindset vs. Capitalist Mindset:</strong> Workers exchange labor for depreciating currency, while capitalists exchange currency for appreciating assets. Learn to invest and become a capitalist, exchanging &ldquo;trash&rdquo; (depreciating currency) for assets.</li>
<li><strong>Global Market Linkage:</strong> Global markets are highly interconnected, and diversifying investments into other regions has limited effectiveness. Focusing on the US stock market is recommended.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Asset Allocation Strategies 
    <div id="asset-allocation-strategies" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#asset-allocation-strategies" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Nasdaq 100 Index Funds:</strong> The preferred choice for young people. Long-term investment can yield substantial returns.  Global codes for purchasing Nasdaq 100 index funds were provided, and investing based on market conditions is recommended.</li>
<li><strong>The Importance of Cash:</strong> Cash reserves are crucial. 00864B and money market funds (like SWVXX, VOXX) are safeguards and should not be replaced with high-dividend products like SPHD, as principal safety is paramount.</li>
<li><strong>Smart Rebalancing:</strong> Suitable for those who use leveraged funds, are not retired, and have income.</li>
<li><strong>Risks of Real Estate Investment:</strong> Housing prices in the Bay Area are high, putting great pressure on young people to buy houses, which can easily lead to financial difficulties. Renting is recommended to maintain flexibility.</li>
<li><strong>Borrowing and Investment:</strong> Loans, mortgages, and car loans should be repaid with stable cash flow, not relying on stock market returns.</li>
<li><strong>Retirement Planning:</strong> Retirees should be cautious about borrowing and make plans based on the size of their retirement funds.  If retirement funds are 50 times the annual expenses, two options are available: 1. Keep the mortgage and car loan, using 2% of the retirement fund annually to cover all expenses; 2. Pay off the mortgage and car loan, invest 80% of the remaining funds in 00662, 20% in 00864B, and use 2% of the total funds annually for living expenses.</li>
<li><strong>Asset Allocation Case Study:</strong> A case study with 45 million Taiwan dollars illustrated asset allocation strategies when withdrawals are not needed. An 80/20 allocation or a combination of leveraged funds (60% 00662, 20% 00670L, 20% 00864B) is recommended.  For those with stable income and no need to withdraw from investments, 100% investment in QQQ can be considered.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Other Matters 
    <div id="other-matters" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#other-matters" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Class Suspension Notice:</strong> Class is suspended on November 9th and resumes on November 16th. After daylight saving time ends, the class time will be changed to 6:00 AM Pacific Time and 10:00 PM Taiwan time.</li>
<li><strong>Stay Optimistic:</strong> Maintain an optimistic mindset; the market will reward you. Like, subscribe, and leave comments on various platforms to benefit more people.</li>
<li><strong>Contact Information:</strong> Two email addresses were provided for contact.</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">III. Q&amp;A Session 
    <div id="iii-qa-session" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii-qa-session" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Brian: 
    <div id="brian" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#brian" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing 1: Read &ldquo;Investing is Asset Allocation, What You Don&rsquo;t Know,&rdquo; agreeing with the importance of accumulating the first pot of gold early; learning investment allows for more focus on work and personal improvement, spending time each day learning new skills and increasing self-worth.  Investment enables people to be more motivated to improve their professional skills rather than &ldquo;lying flat.&rdquo;</li>
<li>Sharing 2: Individuals can improve their earning potential through learning, even if their investment assets are reduced to zero, they can still rely on professional skills to make a comeback.</li>
<li>Question 1: What should I do if the Beta value is very low when the asset value plummets in the Excel sheet?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: The sheet is designed for acceleration during market rises and deceleration during falls. A low Beta value is normal and a reflection of risk control; no adjustment is needed.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2: Even knowing that investment should be mindless, I still worry when the Beta value drops. How should I cope?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: Deceleration during declines is the purpose of the investment strategy. Don&rsquo;t worry, stick to the plan, just like autopilot.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">LU: 
    <div id="lu" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#lu" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question 1: What is the impact of Trump&rsquo;s potential return to office on Bitcoin?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: The US has abandoned the gold standard and will not adopt a Bitcoin standard. Bitcoin is similar to gold and has an anti-inflationary function, but its future development is limited.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2: Can QQQ break through its previous high?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: It definitely can. The current market is bullish; there&rsquo;s no need to worry.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Wendy: 
    <div id="wendy" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#wendy" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing 1: Learned James&rsquo;s investment philosophy and successfully recouped the income lost during unemployment. Started reading recommended books such as &ldquo;The Richest Man in Babylon&rdquo; and &ldquo;The Most Important Thing.&rdquo;</li>
<li>No Questions</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Peter: 
    <div id="peter" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#peter" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing 1: Agrees with James&rsquo;s philosophy and has increased the investment proportion of QQQ, but some individual stocks have not been completely sold due to tax reasons.</li>
<li>Question 1: Advantages and disadvantages of converting 401K to Roth 401K?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: Just put new contributions into Roth 401K; don&rsquo;t convert existing funds. Convert at retirement.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2:  How to use HSA and 529 accounts?  Is there any problem with using a credit card to pay medical bills from an HSA?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply:  HSA, 529, and college fund accounts are not recommended because they lead to a loss of control over the funds. Using your own funds or loans is recommended.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 3: Are there any suggestions for increasing income and saving money besides a full-time job?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: Excessive saving is not recommended. Plan for retirement funds first, and the remaining money can be freely used and enjoyed.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Yi Jie (First Sister): 
    <div id="yi-jie-first-sister" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#yi-jie-first-sister" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing 1: Previously followed the advice of online influencers and invested in US stocks and treasury bonds, currently converting to QQQ.  Has a modest salary and one child.</li>
<li>Question 1: Can the 20% cash in the 80/20 allocation be replaced with Fubon 50 2X leverage?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply:  QQQ 2X leverage (00670L) is recommended. He explained the use of leveraged funds.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2: Is it feasible to regularly invest equal amounts in QQQ and 2X leverage?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: Feasible, but pay attention to cash reserves. A Beta of 1.1 or 1.2 allocation is recommended, adjusting according to market conditions.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 3: Can a child&rsquo;s Lunar New Year money be all-in on 2X leverage?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: If you can guarantee continuous regular investment for more than 30 years, it&rsquo;s worth considering, but be aware of the risks and be able to withstand significant asset shrinkage.  In the long run, the returns can be substantial, but psychological barriers must be overcome.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 4: Are the views of online influencers recommending treasury bonds correct? Are treasury bonds more valuable during a market crash?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: Incorrect. During market downturns, bond declines can be even greater.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">IAM: 
    <div id="iam" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iam" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing 1: Reflecting on the value of money, learning gratitude, and paying attention to community articles, realizing that spending money is spending one&rsquo;s life energy.</li>
<li>Sharing 2: Made 100 pages of notes and calculated the return on an 80,000 loan invested for 40 years; the result was shocking.</li>
<li>Question 1: Why are people not accustomed to borrowing for investment?  Confused about the phenomenon of young people being afraid to borrow for investment but willing to use installment plans for consumption.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: This is due to cultural influences.  Change your mindset and recognize that good debt can help accumulate wealth. Shared personal experiences and spending philosophy, emphasizing the freedom of spending after becoming wealthy.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">YJ Yuanlin: 
    <div id="yj-yuanlin" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#yj-yuanlin" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing 1: Investing boosts confidence, enabling focus on work and hobbies.</li>
<li>Question 1: In a down year, can TQQ replace QLD in smart rebalancing?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: Both are possible, but pay attention to risk control and avoid excessive pursuit of high risk. TQQ has greater volatility and requires a stronger psychological capacity.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">T: 
    <div id="t" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#t" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question 1: What are your thoughts on Elon Musk supporting Trump?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: Politicians&rsquo; decisions are the result of weighing pros and cons. Elon Musk&rsquo;s support for Trump stems from personal interests and positions, such as opposing certain liberal policies.  Entrepreneurs also have to choose between different political forces.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Yi Ni: 
    <div id="yi-ni" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#yi-ni" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question 1: How to invest and use Canadian education fund accounts?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: It&rsquo;s recommended to thoroughly research the specific rules of the account and consider methods like pledged loans to avoid locking up funds. Inquired about whether it&rsquo;s possible to withdraw all funds and the limitations, suggesting consulting with professionals.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Meng: 
    <div id="meng" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#meng" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing 1: In the high-tech era, privacy and freedom are difficult to have both.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Peter: 
    <div id="peter-1" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#peter-1" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing 1: It can be difficult for beginners to invest in QQQ, etc. It&rsquo;s suggested to start by buying one share and gradually build confidence.  James&rsquo;s explanations are very patient and benefit everyone.</li>
<li>Question 1: How to strengthen mental and psychological well-being?  James&rsquo;s experience sharing on meditation and hypnosis.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: Recommended Rachel&rsquo;s hypnosis channel and shared personal methods of using hypnosis and positive psychological suggestions. Suggested listening to hypnotic audios every night before sleep.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">IV. Key Takeaways 
    <div id="iv-key-takeaways" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv-key-takeaways" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>Rise faster, fall slower.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>This is one of James&rsquo;s core investment philosophies. Through smart rebalancing strategies, increase investment during market rises to accelerate profits, and reduce investment during market downturns to mitigate losses.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Money is the least valuable thing when it has no value.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>This reflects James&rsquo;s unique view on wealth. When wealth accumulates to a certain extent, the value of money itself is no longer important; what matters more is pursuing freedom and happiness.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>If you want freedom, and you want privacy, you will not have freedom. In the future world, if you want privacy, you will not have freedom.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>This shows James&rsquo;s insight into future social trends. In the high-tech era, one needs to make trade-offs between privacy and freedom.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The more daring one is to borrow money, the broader their perspective.
&ndash; YJ Yuanlin</p></blockquote>
<p>YJ Yuanlin&rsquo;s sharing led to James&rsquo;s views on borrowing: good debt can help wealth growth.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>If you want freedom, you cannot care.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>Echoing the topic of Elon Musk supporting Trump and the entrepreneurial spirit, true freedom is not caring about external opinions and focusing on one&rsquo;s goals.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>If you don&rsquo;t use ChatGPT now, you are outdated and will be eliminated.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>James advocates for new technologies and maintains an open attitude towards learning new things.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">V. Summary 
    <div id="v-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#v-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This session covered various aspects of investment philosophy, asset allocation, lifestyle, and how to cope with market fluctuations.  James answered the audience&rsquo;s questions with easy-to-understand language and rich examples, sharing his life experiences and insights, and encouraging everyone to stay optimistic, continue learning, and pursue true freedom and happiness.</p>

  



<div
  
    class="flex px-4 py-3 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900"
  >

  <span
    
      class="text-primary-400 ltr:pr-3 rtl:pl-3 flex items-center"
    >

    

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M506.3 417l-213.3-364c-16.33-28-57.54-28-73.98 0l-213.2 364C-10.59 444.9 9.849 480 42.74 480h426.6C502.1 480 522.6 445 506.3 417zM232 168c0-13.25 10.75-24 24-24S280 154.8 280 168v128c0 13.25-10.75 24-23.1 24S232 309.3 232 296V168zM256 416c-17.36 0-31.44-14.08-31.44-31.44c0-17.36 14.07-31.44 31.44-31.44s31.44 14.08 31.44 31.44C287.4 401.9 273.4 416 256 416z"/></svg>

  </span>


  </span>

  <span
    
      class="dark:text-neutral-300"
    ><strong>Disclaimer:</strong> This article is for personal learning notes only and does not constitute any investment advice.</span>
</div>

]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Early Retirement Extreme: Book Notes</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1728390192272/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1728390192272/</guid><description>This book offers an unconventional philosophical and practical guide to financial independence and early retirement, encouraging readers to break free from the traditional &amp;#39;work-consume&amp;#39; cycle. By cultivating diverse skills, reducing consumption, and investing wisely, readers can achieve financial independence within a few years and live a more free and balanced life. The book also delves into how &amp;#39;the system&amp;#39; influences individual decisions and how to escape its constraints.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[

<h2 class="relative group">I. Summary 
    <div id="i-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This book&rsquo;s core is to guide readers in constructing a mindset of financial independence and encourage them to challenge and break free from the constraints of societal &ldquo;systems.&rdquo; The author argues that modern society, through education, careers, consumerism, and other means, &ldquo;locks&rdquo; people into a preset track, making them work and consume continuously to maintain the system&rsquo;s operation. This book encourages readers to break this cycle by cultivating diverse skills, reducing dependence on a single income and material possessions, and ultimately achieving financial independence and early retirement to pursue a more meaningful life.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">II. Chapter Summaries 
    <div id="ii-chapter-summaries" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii-chapter-summaries" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<ul>
<li><strong>About the Book:</strong> Explains the purpose and core ideas, emphasizing that it&rsquo;s a philosophical book about strategy, aiming to help readers build a framework for financial independence.</li>
<li><strong>A Different Thinking Framework:</strong> Challenges the traditional &ldquo;work-consume&rdquo; model and society&rsquo;s pursuit of material possessions, status, and happiness. It encourages readers to think like a &ldquo;Renaissance person&rdquo; by developing diverse skills and points out the challenges of implementing change.</li>
<li><strong>Locked In:</strong> Delves into how modern people are &ldquo;locked in&rdquo; by consumerism, social norms, and &ldquo;the system.&rdquo; It analyzes how &ldquo;the system,&rdquo; through education, careers, advertising, media, etc., influences individual decisions, limits choices, and creates dependencies.  The book encourages readers to break free from the limitations of &ldquo;the system&rdquo; and re-examine their lifestyles and values. (Example: The allegory of Plato&rsquo;s Cave, illustrating how people are trapped in limited cognition and experience, mistaking shadows for reality).</li>
<li><strong>Degrees of Economic Freedom:</strong> Introduces four economic states: Salaryman, Wage Earner, Businessman, and Renaissance Person. It analyzes their financial characteristics, strengths, weaknesses, and interactions with &ldquo;the system.&rdquo;  The concepts of financial coupling and job dependence are emphasized.</li>
<li><strong>The Renaissance Ideal:</strong> Explains the versatility and independence of the &ldquo;Renaissance person&rdquo; and contrasts it with the modern &ldquo;system&rsquo;s&rdquo; emphasis on specialization.
<ul>
<li><strong>Human Capital and Necessary Personal Assets:</strong> Details the specific meanings and goals of seven areas of competence, emphasizing how these competencies help individuals break free from dependence on &ldquo;the system.&rdquo;</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Strategies, Tactics, and Guiding Principles:</strong> Provides strategic and tactical guidance for achieving financial independence.</li>
<li><strong>Tactical Principles:</strong> Offers more specific action guidelines, such as how to identify needs and wants, how to build a modular lifestyle, and how to maximize the use of existing resources.</li>
<li><strong>Economic and Financial Foundations:</strong> Explains the cash flow cycle and how to make money work for you instead of working for money through saving and investing.</li>
<li><strong>Financial Independence and Investing:</strong> Discusses important financial ratios and investment strategies, emphasizing the importance of understanding investment principles and risk management.  (Formulas: N=log[(1)/(1- (Po)/(p)(i)/(1+i))]/log(1+i) and P = (1+0.03/12)/(0.03/12) p = 401 р)</li>
<li><strong>The Renaissance Lifestyle:</strong>  Explores how to implement the Renaissance ideal in aspects such as food, clothing, shelter, transportation, health, relationships, etc., contrasting it with the modern consumerist lifestyle. Emphasizes how reducing dependence on products and services provided by &ldquo;the system&rdquo; can lower living costs and improve quality of life. (Examples: how to replace car ownership with walking, cycling, or other methods, how to repair and maintain items oneself, and how to reduce expenses through socializing and sharing resources).</li>
<li><strong>Conclusion:</strong>  Summarizes the core ideas and encourages readers to break free from the constraints of &ldquo;the system&rdquo; to live more free and autonomous lives.</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">III. Key Quotes 
    <div id="iii-key-quotes" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii-key-quotes" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>Independence is not something you have; it&rsquo;s something you are.</p></blockquote>
<p>Insight:  Independence is a way of thinking and behaving, not a state of being.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>You cannot solve a problem with the same mindset that created it.</p></blockquote>
<p>Insight: Achieving financial independence requires a shift from a consumerist mindset to a creative problem-solving approach.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Be the change that you wish to see in the world.</p></blockquote>
<p>Insight: Instead of complaining about the system, change yourself and your actions, and influence others by example.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The best prison has invisible bars.</p></blockquote>
<p>Insight: Modern society subtly confines us through social norms, consumerism, and the education system, making us unconsciously comply.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">IV.  Guidance 
    <div id="iv--guidance" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv--guidance" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This book provides a perspective that goes beyond traditional financial advice, helping readers re-examine their lifestyles, values, and relationship with societal &ldquo;systems.&rdquo; It encourages readers to achieve financial independence and early retirement through:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Critical thinking:</strong> Question social norms and consumerism to avoid being manipulated by &ldquo;the system.&rdquo;</li>
<li><strong>Developing diverse skills:</strong> Increase self-worth and competitiveness, and reduce dependence on a single income source.</li>
<li><strong>Smart consumption:</strong> Avoid unnecessary expenses and allocate resources to more valuable areas.</li>
<li><strong>Long-term planning and investing:</strong> Prepare for the future and make money work for you.</li>
<li><strong>Building a resilient lifestyle:</strong> Reduce dependence on the external environment and &ldquo;the system&rdquo; and increase the ability to adapt to change.</li>
<li><strong>Pursuing personal growth and self-realization:</strong> Live a more meaningful, autonomous, and free life.</li>
</ul>
<p>In conclusion, this book encourages readers to undertake a profound self-reflection and lifestyle transformation to ultimately break free from the constraints of &ldquo;the system&rdquo; and achieve financial independence and true freedom.
<br/>

  



<div
  
    class="flex px-4 py-3 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900"
  >

  <span
    
      class="text-primary-400 ltr:pr-3 rtl:pl-3 flex items-center"
    >

    

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512">
<path fill="currentColor" d="M288 32c0-17.7-14.3-32-32-32s-32 14.3-32 32V274.7l-73.4-73.4c-12.5-12.5-32.8-12.5-45.3 0s-12.5 32.8 0 45.3l128 128c12.5 12.5 32.8 12.5 45.3 0l128-128c12.5-12.5 12.5-32.8 0-45.3s-32.8-12.5-45.3 0L288 274.7V32zM64 352c-35.3 0-64 28.7-64 64v32c0 35.3 28.7 64 64 64H448c35.3 0 64-28.7 64-64V416c0-35.3-28.7-64-64-64H346.5l-45.3 45.3c-25 25-65.5 25-90.5 0L165.5 352H64zM432 456c-13.3 0-24-10.7-24-24s10.7-24 24-24s24 10.7 24 24s-10.7 24-24 24z"/></svg>
  </span>


  </span>

  <span
    
      class="dark:text-neutral-300"
    ><strong>Download:</strong> <a href="https://github.com/TianmingLi/early_retirement_extreme_cn/blob/main/src/earlyretirementextreme.pdf" target="_blank">Early Retirement Extreme</a></span>
</div>

<br/>
<a id="github-ca5909c42993317bda43c57784488179" target="_blank" href="https://github.com/TianmingLi/early_retirement_extreme_cn" class="cursor-pointer">
  <div
    class="w-full md:w-auto pt-3 p-5 border border-neutral-200 dark:border-neutral-700 border rounded-md shadow-2xl">

    <div class="flex items-center">
      <span class="text-2xl text-neutral-800 dark:text-neutral" style="margin-right:10px;">
        

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 496 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M165.9 397.4c0 2-2.3 3.6-5.2 3.6-3.3.3-5.6-1.3-5.6-3.6 0-2 2.3-3.6 5.2-3.6 3-.3 5.6 1.3 5.6 3.6zm-31.1-4.5c-.7 2 1.3 4.3 4.3 4.9 2.6 1 5.6 0 6.2-2s-1.3-4.3-4.3-5.2c-2.6-.7-5.5.3-6.2 2.3zm44.2-1.7c-2.9.7-4.9 2.6-4.6 4.9.3 2 2.9 3.3 5.9 2.6 2.9-.7 4.9-2.6 4.6-4.6-.3-1.9-3-3.2-5.9-2.9zM244.8 8C106.1 8 0 113.3 0 252c0 110.9 69.8 205.8 169.5 239.2 12.8 2.3 17.3-5.6 17.3-12.1 0-6.2-.3-40.4-.3-61.4 0 0-70 15-84.7-29.8 0 0-11.4-29.1-27.8-36.6 0 0-22.9-15.7 1.6-15.4 0 0 24.9 2 38.6 25.8 21.9 38.6 58.6 27.5 72.9 20.9 2.3-16 8.8-27.1 16-33.7-55.9-6.2-112.3-14.3-112.3-110.5 0-27.5 7.6-41.3 23.6-58.9-2.6-6.5-11.1-33.3 2.6-67.9 20.9-6.5 69 27 69 27 20-5.6 41.5-8.5 62.8-8.5s42.8 2.9 62.8 8.5c0 0 48.1-33.6 69-27 13.7 34.7 5.2 61.4 2.6 67.9 16 17.7 25.8 31.5 25.8 58.9 0 96.5-58.9 104.2-114.8 110.5 9.2 7.9 17 22.9 17 46.4 0 33.7-.3 75.4-.3 83.6 0 6.5 4.6 14.4 17.3 12.1C428.2 457.8 496 362.9 496 252 496 113.3 383.5 8 244.8 8zM97.2 352.9c-1.3 1-1 3.3.7 5.2 1.6 1.6 3.9 2.3 5.2 1 1.3-1 1-3.3-.7-5.2-1.6-1.6-3.9-2.3-5.2-1zm-10.8-8.1c-.7 1.3.3 2.9 2.3 3.9 1.6 1 3.6.7 4.3-.7.7-1.3-.3-2.9-2.3-3.9-2-.6-3.6-.3-4.3.7zm32.4 35.6c-1.6 1.3-1 4.3 1.3 6.2 2.3 2.3 5.2 2.6 6.5 1 1.3-1.3.7-4.3-1.3-6.2-2.2-2.3-5.2-2.6-6.5-1zm-11.4-14.7c-1.6 1-1.6 3.6 0 5.9 1.6 2.3 4.3 3.3 5.6 2.3 1.6-1.3 1.6-3.9 0-6.2-1.4-2.3-4-3.3-5.6-2z"/></svg>

  </span>


      </span>
      <div
        id="github-ca5909c42993317bda43c57784488179-full_name"
        class="m-0 font-bold text-xl text-neutral-800 decoration-primary-500 hover:underline hover:underline-offset-2 dark:text-neutral">
        TianmingLi/early_retirement_extreme_cn
      </div>
    </div>

    <p id="github-ca5909c42993317bda43c57784488179-description" class="m-0 mt-2 text-md text-neutral-800 dark:text-neutral">
      Early Retirement Extreme 中文翻译 Renaissance &amp; Liberty
    </p>

    <div class="m-0 mt-2 flex items-center">

      <span class="mr-1 inline-block h-3 w-3 rounded-full"
        style="background-color: #e34c26"></span>
      <div class="m-0 mr-5 text-md text-neutral-800 dark:text-neutral">
         HTML 
      </div>

      <span class="text-md mr-1 text-neutral-800 dark:text-neutral">
        

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 576 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M287.9 0C297.1 0 305.5 5.25 309.5 13.52L378.1 154.8L531.4 177.5C540.4 178.8 547.8 185.1 550.7 193.7C553.5 202.4 551.2 211.9 544.8 218.2L433.6 328.4L459.9 483.9C461.4 492.9 457.7 502.1 450.2 507.4C442.8 512.7 432.1 513.4 424.9 509.1L287.9 435.9L150.1 509.1C142.9 513.4 133.1 512.7 125.6 507.4C118.2 502.1 114.5 492.9 115.1 483.9L142.2 328.4L31.11 218.2C24.65 211.9 22.36 202.4 25.2 193.7C28.03 185.1 35.5 178.8 44.49 177.5L197.7 154.8L266.3 13.52C270.4 5.249 278.7 0 287.9 0L287.9 0zM287.9 78.95L235.4 187.2C231.9 194.3 225.1 199.3 217.3 200.5L98.98 217.9L184.9 303C190.4 308.5 192.9 316.4 191.6 324.1L171.4 443.7L276.6 387.5C283.7 383.7 292.2 383.7 299.2 387.5L404.4 443.7L384.2 324.1C382.9 316.4 385.5 308.5 391 303L476.9 217.9L358.6 200.5C350.7 199.3 343.9 194.3 340.5 187.2L287.9 78.95z"/></svg>
  </span>


      </span>
      <div id="github-ca5909c42993317bda43c57784488179-stargazers" class="m-0 mr-5 text-md text-neutral-800 dark:text-neutral">
        210
      </div>

      <span class="text-md mr-1 text-neutral-800 dark:text-neutral">
        

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 448 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M80 104c13.3 0 24-10.7 24-24s-10.7-24-24-24S56 66.7 56 80s10.7 24 24 24zm80-24c0 32.8-19.7 61-48 73.3V192c0 17.7 14.3 32 32 32H304c17.7 0 32-14.3 32-32V153.3C307.7 141 288 112.8 288 80c0-44.2 35.8-80 80-80s80 35.8 80 80c0 32.8-19.7 61-48 73.3V192c0 53-43 96-96 96H256v70.7c28.3 12.3 48 40.5 48 73.3c0 44.2-35.8 80-80 80s-80-35.8-80-80c0-32.8 19.7-61 48-73.3V288H144c-53 0-96-43-96-96V153.3C19.7 141 0 112.8 0 80C0 35.8 35.8 0 80 0s80 35.8 80 80zm208 24c13.3 0 24-10.7 24-24s-10.7-24-24-24s-24 10.7-24 24s10.7 24 24 24zM248 432c0-13.3-10.7-24-24-24s-24 10.7-24 24s10.7 24 24 24s24-10.7 24-24z"/></svg>
  </span>


      </span>
      <div id="github-ca5909c42993317bda43c57784488179-forks" class="m-0 mr-5 text-md text-neutral-800 dark:text-neutral">
        46
      </div>

    </div>

  </div>
  <script>
    fetch("https://api.github.com/repos/TianmingLi/early_retirement_extreme_cn", {
      headers: new Headers({
        'User-agent': 'Mozilla/4.0 Custom User Agent'
      })
    })
      .then(response => response.json())
      .then(data => {
        document.getElementById('github-ca5909c42993317bda43c57784488179-full_name').innerHTML = data.full_name;
        document.getElementById('github-ca5909c42993317bda43c57784488179-description').innerHTML = data.description;
        document.getElementById('github-ca5909c42993317bda43c57784488179-stargazers').innerHTML = data.stargazers_count;
        document.getElementById('github-ca5909c42993317bda43c57784488179-forks').innerHTML = data.forks;
      })
      .catch(error => console.error(error))
  </script>
</a></p>
<hr>

<section class="space-y-10 w-full">
    
    
        
            






















  <a class="flex flex-wrap article " href="/en/posts/1728295490690-book-list/">
    
        
        <div class="w-full md:w-auto h-full thumbnail nozoom thumbnailshadow md:mr-7" style="background-image:url(/posts/1728295490690-book-list/featured_hu_a14921d8ab66af4e.jpg);"></div>
        
      <div class=" mt-3 md:mt-0">
      <div class="items-center text-left text-xl font-semibold">
        
        <div class="font-bold text-xl text-neutral-800 decoration-primary-500 hover:underline hover:underline-offset-2 dark:text-neutral"
          href="/en/posts/1728295490690-book-list/">Recommended Reading List</div>
        
        
        
      </div>
      <div class="text-sm text-neutral-500 dark:text-neutral-400">
        











  



















<div class="flex flex-row flex-wrap items-center">
  
  
  <time datetime="2024-10-01T00:00:00&#43;00:00">1 October 2024</time>
  

  
  
</div>





<div class="flex flex-row flex-wrap items-center">
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  <span style="margin-top:0.5rem" class="mr-2" onclick="window.open(&#34;/en/tags/recommended/&#34;,'_self');">
    <span class="flex" style="cursor: pointer;">
  <span class="rounded-md border border-primary-400 px-1 py-[1px] text-xs font-normal text-primary-700 dark:border-primary-600 dark:text-primary-400">
    Recommended
  </span>
</span>
  </span>
  
  <span style="margin-top:0.5rem" class="mr-2" onclick="window.open(&#34;/en/tags/book/&#34;,'_self');">
    <span class="flex" style="cursor: pointer;">
  <span class="rounded-md border border-primary-400 px-1 py-[1px] text-xs font-normal text-primary-700 dark:border-primary-600 dark:text-primary-400">
    Book
  </span>
</span>
  </span>
  
  
  
  
</div>




      </div>
      
    </div>
  </a>

        
    
</section>
]]></content:encoded></item></channel></rss>