<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Wealth Management on QQQ Investor</title>
    <link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/tags/wealth-management/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Wealth Management on QQQ Investor</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 26 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jomonylw.github.io/en/tags/wealth-management/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>00513 The world is evolving: choosing the top index (e.g., Nasdaq 100), a reverie of the AI age</title>
      <link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1745714790157/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1745714790157/</guid>
      <description>In this episode, James first announced the upcoming two-week Clubhouse hiatus and then emphasized that market volatility is normal and there&amp;#39;s no need to over-analyze the reasons behind it. The core arguments revolved around the importance of long-term investing and index funds (especially the Nasdaq 100), and discussed the selection of specific ETFs (such as 00864B/00865B, BRK, HXQ). He also shared his fantasies about the future development of AI, exploring its potential impact on social structures, work, and the meaning of life. The Q&amp;amp;A session covered a range of practical issues, including market predictions, asset allocation ratios (70/30 rule, Beta value), ETF selection in different countries, digital currency risks, differences in investment philosophies between spouses, and retirement cash reserves.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<lite-youtube videoid="5WJ_23Gpcg0" playlabel="5WJ_23Gpcg0" params=""></lite-youtube>



<h2 class="relative group">I. Episode Theme 
    <div id="i-episode-theme" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-episode-theme" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This episode revolves around the core concept of long-term investing, emphasizing the importance of maintaining composure amidst inevitable market fluctuations, adhering to investments in high-quality index funds (such as the Nasdaq 100), and exploring the profound impact of AI development on the future of society and personal wealth. It also provides in-depth answers to specific questions raised by students regarding investment tool selection, asset allocation strategies, and market psychology.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">II. Summary 
    <div id="ii-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Operations and Reminders 
    <div id="operations-and-reminders" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#operations-and-reminders" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Clubhouse Hiatus Announcement</strong>: Clubhouse and video uploads will be suspended for the next two weeks (May 3rd and May 10th), resuming on May 17th (Saturday).</li>
<li><strong>Clubhouse Technical Issues</strong>: Recent issues with sound being inaudible or too low. It&rsquo;s recommended to leave and re-enter the room, or completely close and reopen the app.</li>
<li><strong>Speaking Rules</strong>: Accidental stage entries are fine, just stay on stage; no need to repeatedly enter and exit.</li>
<li><strong>Disclaimer</strong>: All sharing is for reference only. Investment decisions are the individual&rsquo;s responsibility. We are not professional investment advisors or tax professionals; sharing is based on personal experience. Long-term investment has low risk, short-term investment has high risk. Those who cannot tolerate short-term losses or are worried about asset devaluation should not invest and can choose fixed deposits instead.</li>
<li><strong>Learning Resources</strong>: Lecture notes are pinned in the Clubhouse comment section or the YouTube comment section. Newcomers are advised to start with video 00451, then 398-402, and then the latest for systematic learning (although there are as many as four or five hundred videos).</li>
<li><strong>Community Groups</strong>: No official groups are established. Participation in unofficial groups requires caution. If the group information is noisy, annoying, and not beneficial to life, it is recommended to leave. Groups aimed at sharing CLEC concepts, helping each other answer questions, and providing information are welcome.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Investment Philosophy and Strategies 
    <div id="investment-philosophy-and-strategies" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#investment-philosophy-and-strategies" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Market Volatility is Normal</strong>: The market is always fluctuating; this is the unchanging rule. No need to analyze specific reasons (international situation, trade war, financial report forecasts, etc.). Many analysts themselves do not truly understand. The market is like the sea, unaffected by streams and storms.</li>
<li><strong>Long-Term Investing</strong>: True investment is buying with the intention of never selling. Intending to sell at a high point is speculation. Investment must be long-term.</li>
<li><strong>Index Investing</strong>:
<ul>
<li><strong>Core Recommendation</strong>: Nasdaq 100 Index Fund (QQQ and its global equivalents). Reason: Compared to the S&amp;P 500 (500 companies, possibly 450 &ldquo;bad companies&rdquo;), the Nasdaq 100 focuses more on high-quality technology companies, aligning with the &ldquo;the bigger, the stronger&rdquo; trend.</li>
<li><strong>Retirees/Those with Less Capital</strong>: Consider Taiwan 0056 or US SPHD (dividend yield ~3.5%, providing stable cash flow).</li>
<li><strong>Nasdaq 100 ETF List</strong>: Provides a list of relevant ETFs including various countries (Canada HXQ.t, Singapore, Malaysia, Norway, UK, Australia, etc.). HXQ.t is recommended because it does not pay dividends (tax-free).</li>
<li><strong>Historical Experience</strong>: Watching videos since 2018 can provide insights into investor sentiment and responses during market fluctuations, giving a sense of the long-term perspective.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Stay Optimistic</strong>: Investors need to be extremely optimistic, always facing the sunlight, believing that the market will be good in the long run, even if there is a world war, the market still exists and continues to rise (only rises, never falls).</li>
<li><strong>Investment Target Selection</strong>:
<ul>
<li><strong>00864B vs 00865B (Taiwan Bond ETF)</strong>:
<ul>
<li>00864B: Pays dividends, generating National Health Insurance Supplementary Premium (2.11%), requires manual reinvestment (with handling fees, easy to forget resulting in no compounding), dividends are considered overseas income (requires declaration if it exceeds the limit, but usually not a problem with annual income below NT$1 million; according to student feedback, it is exempt from the second-generation health insurance supplementary premium).</li>
<li>00865B: Does not pay dividends, avoiding the above problems, simpler and more effective in the long run. Low trading volume is not a problem (market makers provide liquidity), initial performance differences will shrink as scale increases. <strong>Strongly recommend switching to 00865B; convenience is a value.</strong> Conversion will incur a one-time transaction cost, but worth it in the long run.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Berkshire Hathaway (BRK.A/B)</strong>:
<ul>
<li><strong>Not recommended for investment</strong>. Reason: Actively managed fund, more volatile than the index; times are changing, performance has lagged behind the S&amp;P 500; uncertainty after Buffett (&ldquo;the devil will come out&rdquo;); learning Buffett should be about learning his long-term investment spirit, investment discourse (such as the definition of investment), rather than stock picking. Investing in the S&amp;P 500 may be better than investing in BRK.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Asset Allocation (Beta)</strong>:
<ul>
<li><strong>Basic Principle</strong>: It is recommended that most people allocate an investment portfolio with a Beta value of less than 1, such as 70% index funds + 30% cash/money market funds (Beta is approximately 0.7).</li>
<li><strong>Risk Tolerance</strong>: The recent 20% drop has made many people uncomfortable (even those with a Beta of 1.2 configured at 4:4:2), indicating that actual risk tolerance may be lower than expected. Do not sacrifice the comfort of holding enough cash (&ldquo;don&rsquo;t gamble with the money you need for the money you don&rsquo;t need&rdquo;) for an extra 1-2% of return.</li>
<li><strong>Adjustment</strong>: If the initial Beta is high (such as 1.2), it is recommended to review it at the end of each year. If the market rises, you can sell part of the leveraged/index position and supplement the cash to more than 30%, gradually reducing the Beta to below 1.0. Consider smart rebalancing after the Beta is below 1.0.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Platform Interaction</strong>: Please subscribe, like, and leave comments on videos on various platforms.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">AI Development Fantasies and Impact 
    <div id="ai-development-fantasies-and-impact" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ai-development-fantasies-and-impact" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>AI Optimized Future</strong>:
<ul>
<li>Productivity greatly improved, most output is completed by AI (robots), and the cost of goods approaches zero.</li>
<li>Total social wealth accelerates, basic living needs (food, clothing, housing, transportation) may be free, uniformly supplied by the state/society (AI robots complete production, construction, and maintenance).</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Social Structure Changes</strong>:
<ul>
<li><strong>Classes Still Exist</strong>:
<ul>
<li><strong>Capitalists</strong>: Earn profits by investing in and holding the means of production (AI systems) without labor; the wealthiest. Everyone can become a capitalist (just need to know how to invest).</li>
<li><strong>High-Tech Workers</strong>: Personnel who maintain and manage AI systems, with excellent income, can enjoy entertainment beyond basic needs (such as space travel), but may fall into the &ldquo;cared-for&rdquo; class if they stop working and do not become capitalists.</li>
<li><strong>Cared-For Class (approximately 80%)</strong>: No need to work, basic life is guaranteed (food, clothing, housing, transportation, medical care), but cannot enjoy additional entertainment or resources. The standard of living may be similar to the current upper-middle class, but without work.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Philosophical Challenges</strong>:
<ul>
<li>When most people do not need to contribute for livelihood (&ldquo;nothing to serve&rdquo;), what is the meaning and purpose of life? (Analogous to being idle after retirement). May lead to widespread depression or social problems.</li>
<li>Human development may enter a stage of eternal life, facing greater philosophical and existential questions.</li>
<li>The focus should shift from &ldquo;unemployment&rdquo; to &ldquo;the meaning of life.&rdquo;</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Implications for Investors</strong>:
<ul>
<li>As capitalists, there is no need to worry about job loss due to AI development; on the contrary, they will become wealthier.</li>
<li>Start investing now to become part of the capitalist class.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">III. Q&amp;A Session 
    <div id="iii-qa-session" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii-qa-session" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Jacel 
    <div id="jacel" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#jacel" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question: SPY and QQQ have risen for three days, will they continue to rise or fall next week?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo; Response: Short-term market cannot be predicted, like flipping a coin. We invest for the long term (20+ years), focusing on long-term trends. Buy when you have money, never sell. Don&rsquo;t try to predict next week&rsquo;s market; ask the temple or the &ldquo;stock god&rdquo; in Clubhouse.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Sharing: Just started learning from the teacher&rsquo;s course two months ago, introduced by a friend in the United States. Currently in the learning stage, and has invested in some QQQ (cost between 515-530). After returning to Taiwan, considering investing in 00662. In the process of canceling previous insurance and converting individual stocks to 00662.</li>
<li>Question: Should I invest in US stocks (Firstrade account, worried about political risks in Taiwan for the child) or Taiwan stocks 00662? How to allocate at the beginning?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo; Response: Recommend investing in 00662 in Taiwan, no need to use a US broker (Firstrade). It&rsquo;s better for the child to rely on themselves rather than worry about politics. When starting to learn, it is recommended to divide the total funds into three parts: 1/3 buy 00662 immediately, 1/3 buy in batches over the next 3-6 months, and 1/3 hold in cash. The ultimate goal is 70% 00662 + 30% cash. Then slowly learn whether and how to allocate leveraged funds (adjust the Beta value to 0.8-0.9).</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Nibalao 
    <div id="nibalao" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#nibalao" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question 1: Who are QQQ and SPHD suitable for in terms of capital size?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo; Response: (Points out that students should watch the videos for repeated questions) This is a consideration for retirees. Need to calculate annual expenses after retirement. If 50 times the expenses equals your total assets, you can invest in QQQ (equivalent to a 2% annual withdrawal rate). If 2% is not enough, you need 3%, you may consider the S&amp;P 500. Only consider SPHD if you need even higher (~3.5-4%). Non-retirees should prioritize the high-growth QQQ.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2: Explain Beta value. Beta=1 is synchronized with the market? Beta=1.2 is 1.2 times the volatility? Is the Beta of an 80% QQQ + 20% SGOV portfolio 0.8?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo; Response: Basic understanding is correct. Beta measures the volatility of an asset relative to the market. The Beta of an 80/20 portfolio is approximately 0.8. (Reminds again that the videos explain it)</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 3: Will the principal of SGOV (Short-Term US Treasury ETF) fall and lose money?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo; Response: The principal risk is extremely low, almost no losses (except for minor fluctuations before and after dividend payments). SGOV invests in short-term Treasury bills (T-Bills) issued by the US Treasury Department with a maturity of 0-3 months (or within one year), backed by the credit of the United States.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Rui 
    <div id="rui" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#rui" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Joined for more than a month and reviewed the market decline in 2022 and the teacher&rsquo;s videos (especially #398 graduation episode, learned investment psychology).</li>
<li>Question 1: In January 2023 (#401), the teacher used technical indicators (50/100-day moving average crossover) to judge the market bottom and predict that 2023 would be a bull market, which was also verified afterwards. However, in later videos (#491), he emphasized not to predict market cycles and not to look at macroeconomic indicators (prosperity signals, macroeconomics, inventory cycles, etc.). Why this change? Are these indicators really useless in the long run? What was the basis for judging the bottom (just because of being optimistic about the stock market)? Should we just follow discipline and rebalance once a year?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo; Response: QQQ includes many industries (semiconductors, software, AI, biotechnology, retail such as Costco, Pepsico, Amazon, Google, Apple, etc.), and indicators for a single industry or country (such as Taiwan semiconductor economy, Taiwan prosperity signals, US prosperity signals) cannot reflect the overall index. Looking at all indicators is the same as looking at the index itself, so it is better to just focus on QQQ. The judgment in early 2023 was based on 40 years of experience (calculated that the 6-month moving average would cross upward), which is difficult to convey (&ldquo;unspeakable&rdquo;), and teaching technical analysis may cause students to misuse it and be harmed (&ldquo;go crazy&rdquo;), so it is not taught. Adhering to long-term investment discipline and holding enough cash buffer (such as 30%) is a more reliable method. Even if judging the bottom at that time, all cash would not be invested (such as still maintaining Beta 0.7), still maintaining a margin of safety. No need to take too much risk for small potential gains (referring to Buffett&rsquo;s philosophy).</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2: About the currency hedging of 00670L (Taiwan Leveraged QQQ ETF). Is the impact of exchange rate fluctuations significant in the long run? If the US dollar falls sharply (such as 1:13 against the Taiwan dollar), how will 00670L perform? (The teacher mentioned before that 00670L performs poorly when the US dollar rises)
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo; Response: 00670L is usually paired with 00865B (cash/short-term bonds). Exchange rate fluctuations have a hedging effect on both (when the US dollar rises, the hedging cost of 00670L increases, but the value of US dollar assets increases; the opposite is true when the US dollar falls). In the long run, exchange rate fluctuations are normal (such as the Taiwan dollar fluctuating between 28-32), but there is no fixed trend, and the expected value is zero. Currency hedging itself has a cost (wasting funds), which may not be necessary in the long run (it is recommended that fund companies consider canceling it), but the ETF is designed that way, and it does not hurt. The key is whether 00670L can achieve approximately twice the return of 00662 in the long run.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Mike 
    <div id="mike" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#mike" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Trump mentioned that 5.6 trillion in foreign investment may be invested in the United States in the future (may be exaggerated, even if halved, 2.8 trillion is also considerable), but the direction is beneficial to AI and QQQ. Observed that QQQ rebounded more strongly than SPY, DIA, and BRK recently, confirming the teacher&rsquo;s point of view (such as Katy Wood investing in AI-related companies when she saw mobile internet access). Compare the leadership styles of Chinese and American leaders (leader vs. manager) and the direction of attracting foreign investment (Saudi Arabia/Dubai vs. Myanmar/Vietnam/Malaysia).</li>
<li>Question: Please explain the difference between CIPS (Chinese RMB Cross-Border Payment System) and SWIFT. Why is CIPS faster (completed in 6 seconds)? Why does SWIFT take days? Can SWIFT be improved? Will this affect the status of the US dollar (AI replied that the two will coexist)?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo; Response: SWIFT is based on the traditional telegram transmission model (like a relay station), and information needs to be transferred through multiple layers (local bank -&gt; regional major bank -&gt; central bank -&gt; SWIFT center (Switzerland) -&gt; the other party&rsquo;s central bank -&gt; the other party&rsquo;s head office -&gt; the other party&rsquo;s branch), involving compliance checks (anti-money laundering), time difference, manual processing, etc., so it takes a long time (2+ days). CIPS is a modern real-time gross settlement system, similar to domestic payment systems in various countries, point-to-point or directly cleared through the central bank, and the speed is fast. CIPS uses RMB and is an alternative developed to deal with SWIFT being weaponized (such as sanctions against Russia), making people distrust the US dollar system. US sanctions opened a Pandora&rsquo;s box. Currently, CIPS is small (such as shipbuilding transactions between Malaysia and China), but it represents the trend of &ldquo;currency wars&rdquo; (such as Saudi Arabia and China being linked). Trump&rsquo;s visit to Saudi Arabia may be related to maintaining the status of the US dollar. Just watch the show.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Xiu 
    <div id="xiu" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#xiu" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question: Regarding the customized version of ChatGPT (CCTeams Investment Advisor) shared by the teacher, its knowledge cutoff date seems to be June of last year. Is the teacher using an updated version? Will the link change after the update? (Previously confused HXQ/HSQ).
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo; Response: Indeed, this AI is constantly being updated and trained. The link may change with updates. The latest link (showing content updated on April 26, such as 70/30 allocation recommendations) has been shared in the chat area. New links will be provided regularly (such as weekly or monthly) in the future. The teacher himself uses a more advanced personal &ldquo;Super AI&rdquo; account (possibly GPT-4o or higher, with memory function) to process and extract information, and then &ldquo;feeds&rdquo; the essence to this publicly shared GPTs version (similar to DIPS extraction). Feedback on AI answers is welcome for improvement.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Yao 
    <div id="yao" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#yao" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Because of recent trade tensions, I re-listened to the 2022 recordings. Two points are profound: 1. The biggest risk is missing the market (leaving the market). 2. Focus on long-term returns, not short-term fluctuations/shocks. The market is full of contradictory information (repeated presidential statements, pessimistic commentators) and bad news, but it often rebounds unintentionally. Friends who wait for a clear trend (such as buying after the big trend comes back) miss the rise. No one can accurately time the market. It is extremely difficult to obtain stable and high returns in the long term (such as an annualized return of 10% or more), like the sustained performance of top athletes (such as playing ball for 20 years); it is easy to have a good shot occasionally, but difficult to be stable in the long term. It is essential to stay in the market for a long time and focus on long-term growth.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo; Response: Strongly agree. Investing is like a long-distance race, continuing to stay in the front (such as 3rd or 4th place) will eventually win, because the leaders often make mistakes. This is how index funds are, not the best in a single year, but leading in the long term. Need an investment horizon of 15+ years. The key to persistence is having sufficient cash reserves (especially for retirees, it is recommended to have living expenses for 15+ years) or a continuous work income.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Monmon 
    <div id="monmon" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#monmon" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing 1: Started following the teacher last year, investing on my own and encouraging elders (sold insurance and invested). Recently, I have experienced a market decline and am at peace, but the elders are experiencing large fluctuations for the first time (they adopted a Beta 1.2 allocation). Through repeatedly watching videos and communicating, the elders&rsquo; confidence is still stable.</li>
<li>Sharing 2: Selling a house has been tortuous: difficulty communicating with my husband (disagreed at first, had disputes), cold market (the central bank fought housing speculation in September, difficult to get loans), price reduction (applied the teacher&rsquo;s concept of &ldquo;there is no house that cannot be sold, only a price that cannot be sold&rdquo;) to complete the sale (in February this year). The process was painful (communication, management, market changes, funds stuck, high taxes), and I learned a lesson that I don&rsquo;t want to experience again.</li>
<li>Sharing 3: Currently, half of the investment portfolio is QQQ-like, half is TSMC, and there is also a mortgage line of credit (financial mortgage). My husband wants to use this line of credit to increase positions when the market falls (TSMC?), but hesitates and is afraid in the middle of the actual fall (soft-handed, unable to do it). This decline allowed him to experience his true risk tolerance. My husband did not accept the full QQQ allocation before, but now he has some experience. It verifies the stability of the teacher&rsquo;s asset allocation method.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo; Response: Appreciate Monmon&rsquo;s peaceful state of mind (a good quality for investors, &ldquo;destiny&rdquo; + &ldquo;luck&rdquo; to meet the teacher). Communicating with family requires patience (it is a 15-30 year undertaking, no rush). The funds from the financial mortgage should be invested as soon as possible (such as 00662), buy blindly, and don&rsquo;t time the market. When investing, consider the overall asset allocation, include the loan amount in the total asset calculation, and ensure that the total Beta value is within the desired range (such as about 0.7, that is, maintaining an overall ratio of about 70/30), rather than investing all the borrowed money in high-risk assets. It is recommended to keep at least 30% cash (can be 4:1:5 or 5:1:4, Beta 0.6 or 0.7). This decline is a touchstone for risk tolerance, proving the necessity of conservative allocation. Even if young and have a job, 30% cash is also recommended.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">From Taiwan 
    <div id="from-taiwan" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#from-taiwan" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: The situation is similar to Monmon&rsquo;s. Both myself and the elders invested in 00662/00670L, using Beta 1.2 (4:4:2, that is, 40% 00662, 40% 00670L, 20% cash/00865B) allocation. I can bear the recent fluctuations (the government is quite amazing), but I am not sure whether the elders (who have not watched YouTube, have no financial common sense, but believe and invest) can bear greater future declines (such as 40-80%). Continuously accompany the elders and give them confidence. The elders have a good mentality so far.</li>
<li>Question: If I want to reduce the Beta for the elders, when and how should I operate?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo; Response: It is generally recommended now that the Beta should not exceed 1.0 (such as 70/30). For an existing allocation of 1.2, it is recommended to evaluate it at the end of each year: if the market rises (such as 00662 returning to the level at the beginning of the year or higher), you can sell part of the leveraged position (00670L) and transfer the funds to cash (00865B), so that the cash ratio is adjusted to 30% or higher. If the market is down at the end of the year, then do not move. The goal is to gradually reduce the Beta to below 1.0. Before that, there is no need to consider complicated rebalancing strategies. Don&rsquo;t operate too frequently (once a year) to avoid increasing the elders&rsquo; anxiety (they may secretly look at the APP).</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Lucy 
    <div id="lucy" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#lucy" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question 1: Investing in QQQ in Canada, the teacher recommends QQC, etc., and mentions avoiding Hedged funds? It seems that most Canadian versions are Hedged? Which one should I choose? (Previously confused HXQ/HSQ).
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo; Response: Recommend HXQ.t because it does not pay dividends, making tax treatment simpler. If you already hold QQC.to or ZQQ, there is no need to sell it, and new investments can be bought in HXQ.t. It is also acceptable if only Hedged versions are available locally.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2: Please explain the asset allocation ratio (such as 70/30, 4:4:2). Time is limited (working, back problems requiring exercise, blood sugar problems), it is difficult to find specific content in videos, and listening to Clubhouse is also time-consuming.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo; Response: (Emphasizing the importance of learning, earning money from work only accounts for a small part of a lifetime of wealth, so you should spend time learning about investment) For ordinary investors working in Canada, the simplest allocation is: 70% HXQ.t + 30% cash/money market fund (Money Market). Check and adjust annually (sell the ones that have risen more to supplement cash, or use cash to buy the ones that have fallen more) to maintain this ratio.</li>
<li>(Nibalao Supplement): Canadian local stock dividends have tax advantages, while US-sourced dividends (such as QQC) are taxed (I don&rsquo;t know how much, but higher than Canadian stock taxes). I agree with the teacher&rsquo;s point of view: focus on investment returns is higher than focusing on work.</li>
<li>James&rsquo; Response: Reiterating the advantage of HXQ.t not paying dividends. Canadian funds seem to be performing well, possibly because better compounding due to not paying dividends.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Sharing (Follow-up): Listening to the teacher&rsquo;s criticism is very comfortable and helpful. I am impatient, but after listening to the teacher&rsquo;s patient answers to &ldquo;stupid questions,&rdquo; I am more patient in helping others.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo; Response: Asking questions bravely is important.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Jason 
    <div id="jason" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#jason" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Detailed comparison of the advantages and disadvantages of Bitcoin/cryptocurrencies and QQQ, based on his personal experience in the blockchain industry (entered the industry in 2017, experienced the blockchain/cryptocurrency community, ICO explosion, 2018 bear market):
<ul>
<li>Storage Security: BTC requires self-management of private keys/hardware wallets (cold wallets), which are easy to lose or damage, high risk; QQQ is托管ed by brokers, which is safe.</li>
<li>Transaction Security: BTC is vulnerable to hacker attacks, phishing, and platform crashes; QQQ is protected by regulations.</li>
<li>Staking/Liquidity: BTC lacks standardized and safe staking channels (DeFi is high risk); QQQ can be easily staked and borrowed (pledged) through brokers without selling.</li>
<li>Taxes: Selling BTC requires capital gains tax; holding QQQ for a long time and using pledges can avoid/defer taxes.</li>
<li>Legality: BTC has legal risks in China (trading and mining are illegal), and cashing out may be frozen; QQQ (and QDII 513100/513300) are legal and compliant.</li>
<li>Volatility/Risk: BTC is extremely volatile (short-term drops of 50-80% are common, such as an 85% drop in 2018), and ordinary people cannot withstand the mental stress; QQQ has a much lower frequency of large fluctuations.</li>
<li>Liquidity: The actual circulating volume of BTC is limited (locked by large holders, lost coins), which is not as high as the global liquidity of QQQ.</li>
<li>Practicality: Not detailed.</li>
<li>Future Returns: BTC has a high market value (nearly 2 trillion US dollars, comparable to top technology companies), and the possibility of super high multiple growth in the future is reduced (even if it rises to 200,000 US dollars/coin, it is only 2-3 times), and the rate of return may tend to be stable, lower than QQQ.</li>
<li>Conclusion: Cryptocurrencies are &ldquo;demons and ghosts,&rdquo; not suitable for ordinary investors, highly tempting but extremely risky.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>James&rsquo; Comment: Completely agree, cryptocurrencies should not be touched. Shared cases of others losing huge amounts of Bitcoin (equivalent to 15 million US dollars) due to unfamiliarity with cross-chain transfer rules (such as transferring between different chains or exchanges that do not support the target chain), emphasizing its complexity and risk (may be a technical problem or fraud).</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Responding to Chat Room Questions 
    <div id="responding-to-chat-room-questions" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#responding-to-chat-room-questions" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>File Access</strong>: In areas with limited Google service, you can download the files and open them with local software (such as Excel).</li>
<li><strong>00864B Taxes</strong>: According to Angela&rsquo;s feedback, it is overseas income, which is tax-free if it is less than 1 million Taiwan dollars (or other high limit such as 7.5 million) per year, and is exempt from the second-generation supplementary health insurance premium. The main problem becomes the trouble of manual reinvestment. You need a principal of 25 million to possibly exceed 1 million in interest.</li>
<li><strong>AI Link</strong>: Confirmed that the latest link has been provided.</li>
<li><strong>Buying QQQ in China</strong>: Through QDII funds, such as 513100, 513300. See page 10 of the lecture notes.</li>
<li><strong>Conflicting Ideas Between Spouses</strong>: Patience, use your own controllable funds to set an example. Sometimes even if you prove it, the other person does not recognize it (&ldquo;past performance does not represent the future&rdquo;), it depends on fate (destiny).</li>
<li><strong>Technical Analysis/Prediction</strong>: The teacher does not make predictions (when will it bottom out, will there be a recession or crash).</li>
<li><strong>Robert Kiyosaki</strong>: The teacher is critical of him (&ldquo;he will go bankrupt&rdquo;).</li>
<li><strong>Trump Policy</strong>: No need to pay attention, high uncertainty, just &ldquo;drizzle,&rdquo; impossible to have zero income tax. In the long run, US taxes may increase to deal with the deficit. Do not make decisions based on unconfirmed conclusions.</li>
<li><strong>Mean Reversion</strong>: There is no simple mean reversion in the stock market. The growth of high-tech companies (such as TSMC) will not revert to traditional industries (such as China Steel, Formosa Plastics). Those who think it will revert are &ldquo;bookworms.&rdquo; Value stocks (such as Starbucks, McDonald&rsquo;s) also perform differently.</li>
<li><strong>442 Allocation</strong>: Not recommended for office workers, it is too risky. Those who have already used it should handle it according to the MM case.</li>
<li><strong>Investment vs Speculation</strong>: The teacher does not agree with the statement that &ldquo;all investments are speculation.&rdquo;</li>
<li><strong>12-Year Certificates of Deposit vs Compounding</strong>: 00865B/VOO etc. are compounded.</li>
<li><strong>AI Asset Allocation Advice</strong>: May be &ldquo;incorrect&rdquo; due to questioning methods or AI model understanding deviations.</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">IV. Highlights 
    <div id="iv-highlights" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv-highlights" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>The market is always fluctuating, the constant in the market is fluctuation, so fluctuation is certain to happen in the market, so you don&rsquo;t need to analyze where the fluctuation comes from&hellip; You see everyone talking so eloquently, in fact, he doesn&rsquo;t even know what he is talking about&hellip;
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Context: James emphasized the normality and unpredictability of market fluctuations, advising investors not to waste time analyzing the causes of short-term fluctuations.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Investment is buying with the intention of never selling, this is investment. Buying with the intention of selling at a high point is called speculation.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Context: James clearly distinguished the core criteria of investment and speculation: whether the purpose is to hold for the long term.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Making a decision about all investment and financial life is very simple, which is long-term, simple and effective&hellip; Convenience is a value. No trouble is a value.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Context: When comparing 00864B and 00865B, James emphasized that choosing an investment method that is simpler and less troublesome in the long run has value in itself.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>You don&rsquo;t need to risk the money you need for the money you don&rsquo;t need.
&ndash; James (quoting/paraphrasing Buffett&rsquo;s idea)</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Context: Explained why even if it is judged that the market may rise, you should keep enough cash buffer (the money you need) and should not take too much risk for additional, potentially unnecessary returns (the money you don&rsquo;t need).</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Later you will find that when humans develop to the extreme, food, clothing, housing, and transportation are all free, all free&hellip; Then what does it mean to be alive?&hellip; But what is the meaning of a dog? This may be the question that the last 80% of people have to think about.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Context: When fantasizing about the future when AI is extremely developed, James raised the question of the profound crisis of existential meaning that humans (especially the majority who do not need to work) will face after material needs are completely satisfied.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The biggest risk comes from [missing] the market&hellip; Focus on long-term returns, not this short-term [fluctuation].
&ndash; Yao</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Context: Sharing the profound experience after reviewing the teacher&rsquo;s teachings when the market information is chaotic, emphasizing the importance of being in the market for a long time and focusing on long-term goals.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>We don&rsquo;t want to be the first every time, we only want to be the third or fourth every time&hellip; Over the long term, we will be the first.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Context: Using the analogy of racing to explain the logic of index investing: not pursuing short-term leadership, relying on continuous and steady performance, and ultimately winning in the long cycle.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>There is no house that cannot be sold, only a price that cannot be sold.
&ndash; Monmon</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Context: Sharing the experience of selling a house, mentioning that applying this point of view ultimately successfully sold the property.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>You should put your focus on investing, and the return is definitely much higher than if you put your focus on working.
&ndash; Nibalao</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Context: When discussing that students do not have time to learn about investment, this student emphasized that based on their own experience, the long-term return of putting energy into investment learning far exceeds that of putting it into work itself.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>[Cryptocurrencies] are one of the demons and ghosts&hellip; The future return of Bitcoin may tend to be stable, and the teacher also mentioned this issue before.
&ndash; Jason</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Context: Based on industry experience and risk analysis, the student qualified cryptocurrencies as a high-risk category unsuitable for ordinary investors, and pointed out that its future return may not be as good as index funds.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">V. Summary 
    <div id="v-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#v-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This Clubhouse episode was rich and insightful, ranging from the macro market philosophy (fluctuation is normal, long-term perspective, optimistic mentality), AI&rsquo;s disruptive vision of the future (productivity, social structure, meaning of life), to the micro investment practice (ETF selection such as 00865B vs 00864B, Canadian HXQ.t, asset allocation principles such as 70/30, Beta management, risk awareness), all detailed explanations and discussions were provided. The core information is still focused on: adhering to long-term holding of high-quality index funds (especially the Nasdaq 100), understanding and accepting market fluctuations, maintaining rationality and patience, using time compounding, and conducting sound asset allocation according to personal risk tolerance (emphasizing the importance of at least 30% cash), and being vigilant about market noise and high-risk speculative products (such as cryptocurrencies). The Q&amp;A session answered in detail the specific questions encountered by students in different countries, different stages, and different product selections, and emphasized the importance of continuous learning of investment knowledge. Finally, it was reminded again that the Clubhouse will be suspended for the next two weeks.</p>

  



<div
  
    class="flex px-4 py-3 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900"
  >

  <span
    
      class="text-primary-400 ltr:pr-3 rtl:pl-3 flex items-center"
    >

    

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M506.3 417l-213.3-364c-16.33-28-57.54-28-73.98 0l-213.2 364C-10.59 444.9 9.849 480 42.74 480h426.6C502.1 480 522.6 445 506.3 417zM232 168c0-13.25 10.75-24 24-24S280 154.8 280 168v128c0 13.25-10.75 24-23.1 24S232 309.3 232 296V168zM256 416c-17.36 0-31.44-14.08-31.44-31.44c0-17.36 14.07-31.44 31.44-31.44s31.44 14.08 31.44 31.44C287.4 401.9 273.4 416 256 416z"/></svg>

  </span>


  </span>

  <span
    
      class="dark:text-neutral-300"
    ><strong>Disclaimer:</strong> This article is only a personal learning note and does not constitute any investment advice.</span>
</div>

]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Personal Investment Bible: The Ultimate Guide to Wealth Management</title>
      <link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1731056005973/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1731056005973/</guid>
      <description>This article explores the ultimate goal of wealth management – enhancing the quality of life, rather than simply pursuing money. Using the parable of a miser, it emphasizes that the true meaning of wealth lies in how it&amp;#39;s used to live the life you desire.  It examines the unique perspectives on money held by prominent figures like Li Ka-shing, Tsai Wan-lin, and Wang Yung-ching, highlighting how many become slaves to money, unable to utilize it for happiness. Finally, it introduces the three keys to wealth management – earning, managing, and utilizing money – emphasizing the importance of setting financial goals and using wealth wisely.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[

<h2 class="relative group">The Ultimate Guide to Wealth Management: Earning Money Requires a Goal 
    <div id="the-ultimate-guide-to-wealth-management-earning-money-requires-a-goal" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#the-ultimate-guide-to-wealth-management-earning-money-requires-a-goal" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>Money is merely a means; improving the quality of life is the ultimate goal.
Success is getting what you want, then enjoying what you have.</p>
</blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">Don&rsquo;t Be a Miser 
    <div id="dont-be-a-miser" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#dont-be-a-miser" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>A miser sold all his possessions, deposited the money in a bank, and took great satisfaction in calculating his daily interest earnings. His unscrupulous son, noticing his father&rsquo;s secretive behavior, discovered the large bank deposit. He stole the passbook and seal, withdrew all the money, and replaced the original with a forgery.  The miser, unaware of the deception, continued to calculate his imaginary wealth and interest.</p>
<p><strong>Not Spending Money Is Like Having No Money</strong></p>
<p>Months later, a sudden urge led the miser to the bank, where he discovered his account was empty. Devastated, he returned home, where his son consoled him: &ldquo;Don&rsquo;t be so upset. Just pretend the passbook is real. It serves the same purpose. You can still calculate your wealth daily. Money sitting unused in a bank is the same as having no money.&rdquo; This parable satirizes the miser to emphasize the true meaning of wealth.  Hoarding money without utilizing it is no different from having none.  Wealth, in any form, has no inherent meaning. Its value comes from what we ascribe to it and how we use it to live the life we want.</p>
<p>&ldquo;My philosophy is to live a simple life, be humble, and what significance does money hold for me?&rdquo;  Li Ka-shing, despite his immense wealth, focuses on making more money and training his successors – his two sons, Victor and Richard.</p>
<p>Wealthy Taiwanese tycoons seem to follow a similar pattern, leaving all their wealth to the next generation, even surpassing Li Ka-shing in their simple lifestyles. Tsai Wan-lin, once Taiwan&rsquo;s richest man, drove a Yulon car and ate nutritionally balanced but bland meals prepared by doctors. Even in his 70s, he went to work every day, saying, &ldquo;The thought of paying NT$20 million in salaries every day compels me to come to the office.&rdquo;</p>
<p>Taiwan has many such &ldquo;miserly&rdquo; tycoons. Wang Yung-ching, the founder of Formosa Plastics Group, was known for his frugality, even combining leftover soap scraps. He said, &ldquo;Food needs only to be nutritious, not necessarily luxurious. Simple meals are good.  Constant luxury makes one forget what happiness is.&rdquo;</p>
<p>&ldquo;I can live like an emperor or a commoner,&rdquo; said Huang Shih-hui, chairman of the Chinfon Group and a consistent top taxpayer in Taiwan. &ldquo;Even if I lost a third, or even half of my wealth, I could still live well.&rdquo; Ranked Taiwan&rsquo;s sixth richest man by Fortune magazine, Huang ate NT$50 lunches and drove an ordinary car. He said, &ldquo;How much can I wear? How much can I eat? Excessive desire will kill you!&rdquo; For these wealthy individuals, the meaning of earning so much lies in the sense of accomplishment, not enjoyment.</p>
<p><strong>Be the Master of Your Money</strong></p>
<p><em>If you don&rsquo;t master your money, your money will master you.</em></p>
<p>If asked, &ldquo;What&rsquo;s the next step after earning money?&rdquo; most people would instinctively answer, &ldquo;Spending it!&rdquo;  They&rsquo;re wrong. Those who answer this way usually haven&rsquo;t earned much. Most self-made millionaires continue to earn after becoming wealthy.</p>
<p>Some might say, &ldquo;It&rsquo;s foolish to have money and not spend it!&rdquo;  True, but such misers are not uncommon. Studies show that at least 90% of people continue to accumulate wealth, becoming slaves to money.</p>
<p>By now, you should realize that achieving financial wealth is relatively easy.  Avoid keeping all your money in the bank, invest most of it in stocks or real estate, and be patient.  However, teaching you to become a billionaire only to become a miserly hoarder is not my intention.  Therefore, it&rsquo;s crucial to discuss the meaning of wealth and the reasons for pursuing it.</p>
<p>Undeniably, with today&rsquo;s opportunities and living standards, hard work can ensure a comfortable life.  This book demonstrates that with proper financial management, wealth is attainable. However, without prior reflection on the meaning of wealth, you may become complacent, give up, or, even worse, become wealthy but not know how to use your money.  This benefits no one.  Before embarking on the path to riches, ask yourself what wealth means to you, then determine the steps to achieve it.</p>
<p><em>1. Don&rsquo;t be a miser.  Learn to spend wisely after earning.</em>
<em>2. Before pursuing wealth, understand your values regarding it.</em></p>
<blockquote>
<p>Money, a double-edged sword, has corrupted countless souls throughout history.
Poverty, a solitary grave, has buried countless heroes and talents.</p>
</blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">Why Earn So Much? 
    <div id="why-earn-so-much" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#why-earn-so-much" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>Everyone desires wealth.  Isn&rsquo;t that why you bought and are reading this book? Yet, not everyone prioritizes wealth. We often hear sentiments like: &ldquo;You can&rsquo;t take it with you,&rdquo; &ldquo;Wealth is fleeting,&rdquo; or &ldquo;One can only eat three meals a day, wear one outfit, and one pair of shoes. Why earn so much?&rdquo;</p>
<p>If you say, &ldquo;Why bother with financial management if you don&rsquo;t want wealth?&rdquo; I have nothing more to say.  This book is explicitly for those seeking financial independence and wealth.</p>
<p>The desire for wealth is a personal choice, determined by one&rsquo;s values and perspective on money. Some see it as a tool, content with enough to meet their needs; others view it as the root of all evil, associating the pursuit of wealth with something ignoble.  Undeniably, the single-minded pursuit of money is wrong. Life offers many other valuable pursuits: health, knowledge, family, love, friendship – all precious.</p>
<p>Money isn&rsquo;t everything. We often hear, &ldquo;If money can solve it, it&rsquo;s a simple problem.&rdquo;  While not the most important thing in life, its importance is undeniable. As the saying goes, &ldquo;Money isn&rsquo;t everything, but without it, you can do nothing.&rdquo;  A good life requires money, as does education, a higher quality of life, improving family life, and even philanthropy. The New England Journal of Medicine points out that the wealthy live longer, healthier lives than the poor.</p>
<p>Many aspire to a happy life and giving back to society.  Both require money. Thus, money is a necessary means to achieve life goals. You can disdain money, but you can&rsquo;t deny its utility in today&rsquo;s society.</p>
<p>One&rsquo;s status and worth are often judged by wealth.  It&rsquo;s unfair, but true.  Despite the absence of social classes, money divides people into &ldquo;rich&rdquo; and &ldquo;poor.&rdquo; Greater wealth translates to greater ability to acquire desired possessions, status, and lifestyles.</p>
<p>Money undoubtedly buys the best healthcare, food, clothing, and housing. It provides security and freedom from fear, improving the quality of life and making it more vibrant.  The poor have limited options, while the rich enjoy a wider range of experiences.</p>
<p><strong>Money Can Ruin the Next Generation</strong></p>
<p>The easiest way to ruin your children? Leave them a fortune.  The saying &ldquo;Wealth doesn&rsquo;t last three generations&rdquo; reflects this truth.</p>
<p>Many educators and I share a common experience: the most challenging students lack motivation, often stemming from wealthy backgrounds.  These children, wanting for nothing, don&rsquo;t understand the need for hard work or ambition.</p>
<p>I recall a case during my tenure as director of the Graduate Institute of Business Administration at Tunghai University. A student, admitted after fierce competition, struggled academically and seemed listless. During counseling, I inquired about learning difficulties.</p>
<p>His response: &ldquo;My engineering background makes these courses easy. I don&rsquo;t understand why I need to learn this.&rdquo; I explained that business school teaches profit maximization. He replied, &ldquo;What&rsquo;s the point of making money?&rdquo; Shocked, I learned that his family&rsquo;s wealth had shielded him from financial concerns, leaving him without a drive to earn. I then emphasized the value of business management for future employment. His response: &ldquo;My father owns a factory waiting for me, but I don&rsquo;t want it.&rdquo;  He didn&rsquo;t appreciate what he already had.  I asked about his apparent preoccupation.  Reluctantly, he confessed his biggest worry: &ldquo;Why can humans kill animals, but not the other way around?&rdquo; I truly didn&rsquo;t understand the mindset of the wealthy&rsquo;s offspring.  It reminded me of the Taiwanese saying: &ldquo;Some complain of hunger after a full meal.&rdquo;</p>
<p>We should be grateful if our parents didn&rsquo;t leave us a fortune that robbed us of our drive.  This book shows how financial management can lead to wealth.  However, I caution against leaving excessive wealth to your children.</p>
<p>Ideally, set a financial goal and stop actively pursuing wealth after reaching it.  Avoid becoming a lifelong slave to money, and don&rsquo;t ruin your children&rsquo;s future.</p>
<p><strong>Warren Buffett&rsquo;s Perspective on Money</strong></p>
<p>Billionaire Warren Buffett has arranged his estate to be managed by a trust controlled by wise individuals with absolute authority and no restrictions.  He avoids preconditions, hoping to prevent it from becoming a bureaucratic, traditional fund. He said, &ldquo;If they create a lofty palace and become conservative and closed-minded, my ghost will not let them rest.&rdquo;</p>
<p>Buffett left his children $3 million each, and they now live happily as farmers. I admire his perspective: &ldquo;True happiness isn&rsquo;t living in a palace but adding a room to your house each year, because happiness is a process, not a result.&rdquo;</p>
<p>Buffett&rsquo;s estate planning is unique.  As America&rsquo;s richest man, his financial decisions draw attention. Some criticize his perceived stinginess towards philanthropy. He countered, &ldquo;When I die, societal problems will remain.  Society will benefit more from my wealth then than now.&rdquo; He remains steadfast despite public opinion.</p>
<p>Buffett essentially ensures that his wealth, acquired from society, returns to it upon his death – a remarkably detached approach compared to many Eastern tycoons.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Acquiring wealth is difficult.
Maintaining wealth is harder.
Utilizing wealth is the hardest.</p>
</blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">The Three Keys to Wealth Management: Earning, Managing, and Utilizing 
    <div id="the-three-keys-to-wealth-management-earning-managing-and-utilizing" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#the-three-keys-to-wealth-management-earning-managing-and-utilizing" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>Wealth management comprises three levels: earning, managing, and utilizing money. Technically, earning is the hardest, followed by managing, then utilizing. However, my experience as a financial advisor suggests that teaching people how to earn is difficult, teaching them to manage is harder, and teaching them to utilize is the hardest.</p>
<p><strong>Few Spend Wisely</strong></p>
<p>Some challenge this: &ldquo;Spending is easy! Give me your money, and I&rsquo;ll spend it all quickly.&rdquo;  True, spending other people&rsquo;s money is easy; spending your life&rsquo;s earnings is not. Many wealthy individuals struggle to use their money meaningfully.</p>
<p>Many lifelong savers find it incredibly difficult to change their habits and spend appropriately, even after becoming wealthy.  When asked, &ldquo;What are you saving for?&rdquo; they often reply, &ldquo;I don&rsquo;t know.&rdquo;</p>
<p>Many people tirelessly pursue wealth without clarifying their goals.  They blindly follow the mantra &ldquo;Money is important.&rdquo;  No one takes their wealth to the grave. <strong>Many become so consumed with earning that they forget their initial purpose, mistaking the means for the end.  They fail to use their wealth for greater happiness, joy, or societal good, becoming slaves to money.  Their wealth becomes meaningless, bringing more harm than benefit.</strong></p>
<p><em>1. Money is a means to achieve life goals. Don&rsquo;t mistake the means for the end and blindly chase money.</em>
<em>2.  Learn to utilize your money to become a truly happy and wealthy individual.</em>
<em>3. Save when young, manage wisely in middle age, and spend thoughtfully in old age.</em></p>
<p><strong>The Wealth Journey of Chen Ding-chuan, Chairman of Everlight Chemical</strong></p>
<p>&ldquo;Before seeking wealth, cultivate the ability to manage money and control yourself.&rdquo; Chen Ding-chuan believes that those who don&rsquo;t understand how to use money become its slaves, losing themselves in the pursuit.  Those who master the art of utilizing money become its masters, prioritizing self-growth and attracting wealth naturally.</p>
<p>Chen founded Everlight Chemical at 40, transforming it from a producer of basic dyes to a supplier of advanced specialty chemicals and pharmaceutical ingredients.  By 1995, the company&rsquo;s revenue reached over NT$2.4 billion.  A devout Christian and former director of the International Foundation Taiwan, Chen holds a unique perspective on money. He believes earning is easy, but spending wisely is not. He&rsquo;s witnessed countless wealthy individuals squander their fortunes and lose themselves, while others hoard their wealth, living like paupers and inflicting misery on those around them. He believes most people don&rsquo;t understand how to use money.</p>
<p>Deeply religious, Chen dedicates himself to God and spreading the Gospel.  Despite his success, he&rsquo;s traveled a difficult path.  He left school after elementary to work, studying diligently at night school for seven years, never missing a class except due to illness.  While others took on extra jobs, he prioritized education, graduating with a degree in international trade at 35. Who would have predicted his future as a billionaire?</p>
<p><strong>Who Paid the Highest Estate Tax?</strong></p>
<p>&ldquo;Who paid the highest estate tax in Taiwan&rsquo;s history?&rdquo;  I often ask this during lectures.  Few know the correct answer: Chen De-shen.</p>
<p>&ldquo;Chen De-shen? Who is he?&rdquo;  Audiences always murmur after the reveal.  It&rsquo;s a shame that someone who paid nearly NT$2 billion in estate tax remains relatively unknown.  How?  The only explanation is that Chen mastered earning and managing money, but not utilizing it.</p>
<p>Chen died in 1991, leaving an estate valued at NT$10 billion, resulting in a record NT$1.9 billion estate tax bill.  He lived a remarkably frugal life, using public transportation, sleeping on a cot, and living in his office to avoid buying a house. His sister recounted how he even refused to replace worn-out underwear.</p>
<p>Unmarried and childless, his vast fortune went to his siblings, sparking a highly publicized inheritance dispute. He exemplifies the saying, &ldquo;Those enslaved by wealth are pitiable even in their riches.&rdquo;</p>
<p>I often wonder, had he allocated a portion of his wealth to establish a &ldquo;De-shen College&rdquo; or &ldquo;De-shen Hospital,&rdquo; or donated even 1% (NT$100 million) to Tunghai University&rsquo;s business school, his name would be remembered for generations.  Such philanthropy would have benefited society and avoided family conflict.</p>
<p>Stanford University, a prestigious institution nestled between San Francisco and Silicon Valley, owes its existence to a generous donation from the Stanford family a century ago.  What a profound and lasting impact!  We marvel at the wisdom and foresight behind such giving.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Personal Investment Bible: Preface</title>
      <link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1731056005958/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1731056005958/</guid>
      <description>This book aims to help readers establish a correct view of wealth management, learn financial knowledge, master easy wealth management techniques, and ultimately achieve financial freedom, even becoming millionaires. Author Huang Peiyuan uses the story of the Lien Chan family&amp;#39;s wealth management as an example, explaining the importance of wealth management in a simple and profound way, and combining his rich experience and academic research, proposes the key elements of wealth accumulation: regular savings, pursuing high returns, and long-term waiting. In addition, this book also emphasizes the inadequacy of financial education and the importance of continuous learning and adaptation in a rapidly changing investment environment.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[
  



<div
  
    class="flex px-4 py-3 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900"
  >

  <span
    
      class="text-primary-400 ltr:pr-3 rtl:pl-3 flex items-center"
    >

    

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M256 0C114.6 0 0 114.6 0 256s114.6 256 256 256s256-114.6 256-256S397.4 0 256 0zM256 128c17.67 0 32 14.33 32 32c0 17.67-14.33 32-32 32S224 177.7 224 160C224 142.3 238.3 128 256 128zM296 384h-80C202.8 384 192 373.3 192 360s10.75-24 24-24h16v-64H224c-13.25 0-24-10.75-24-24S210.8 224 224 224h32c13.25 0 24 10.75 24 24v88h16c13.25 0 24 10.75 24 24S309.3 384 296 384z"/></svg>

  </span>


  </span>

  <span
    
      class="dark:text-neutral-300"
    ><strong>Synopsis</strong><br>
Written by Mr. Huang Peiyuan from Taiwan, this book&rsquo;s greatest strength lies in its departure from traditional thinking. It uses clear and easy-to-understand language to teach correct wealth management methods. The book outlines thirteen ironclad rules for effortless wealth management, guiding readers on how to establish a correct view of financial management. Many people strive to make money but don&rsquo;t know how.  Many possess the conditions for wealth but miss opportunities due to a lack of financial literacy. Even worse, some lose everything due to investment mistakes. The author draws on practical experience and extensive academic research, exploring these thirteen ironclad rules to help you &ldquo;enjoy wealth management, achieve wealth with ease,&rdquo; and confidently join the ranks of millionaires.
<br>
<br>
<strong>About the Author</strong><br>
<strong>Huang Peiyuan</strong>, Ph.D. in Business Administration from the University of California, Berkeley, General Manager of Sancai Construction and Real Estate Co., Ltd. Former Director of the Institute of Business Administration, Tunghai University, Deputy Director of the Project Business Department, China Development Trust Company, Vice President of East-West Securities, USA, Investment Manager at Merrill Lynch, USA, and financial advisor to numerous companies.</span>
</div>



<h2 class="relative group">Learning Wealth Management from the Lien Chan Family 
    <div id="learning-wealth-management-from-the-lien-chan-family" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#learning-wealth-management-from-the-lien-chan-family" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>The people of Taiwan are not only surprised by the enormous wealth of the Lien Chan family, the former chairman of the Kuomintang, but also harbor doubts. How could two generations of civil servants, with their meager salaries, accumulate wealth comparable to that of tycoon families?</p>
<p>This suspicion is deeply ingrained, but the Lien family is a prominent political family in Taiwan, and no one wants to antagonize them by probing too deeply.</p>
<p>As a journalist, the Lien family&rsquo;s wealth has always been a puzzle to me. I even made a determined effort to uncover the truth, but to no avail.  Six months ago, Professor Huang Peiyuan, then director of the Institute of Business Administration at Tunghai University, spoke about his desire to combine theory and practice and publish a &ldquo;Personal Investment Bible.&rdquo; After reading Professor Huang&rsquo;s manuscript, the mystery of the Lien family&rsquo;s wealth became clear to me.  The Lien family is a perfect example of the principles in this &ldquo;Personal Investment Bible.&rdquo; Perhaps Lien Ya-tang, in his early years, wrote not only the renowned &ldquo;General History of Taiwan,&rdquo; but also a &ldquo;Wealth Management Manual&rdquo; passed down only within the family.</p>
<p>According to Professor Huang&rsquo;s (his title at the time; now he is in business) &ldquo;Personal Investment Bible,&rdquo; the first rule is &ldquo;Don&rsquo;t keep your money in the bank.&rdquo; The second is that if you want to get rich, invest in stocks and real estate.  This gives you the opportunity, with the income of an average office worker, to become a multimillionaire after 40 years of wealth management.</p>
<p>By this standard, the Lien family is indeed the most faithful follower of the &ldquo;Personal Investment Bible.&rdquo; When they had little wealth, Lien&rsquo;s mother (Lien Chan&rsquo;s mother) invested solely in stocks and real estate.  Over the past few decades, the Lien family remained steadfast, waiting for the appreciation of their stocks and real estate, which naturally led to the vast wealth that now arouses public suspicion.</p>
<p>Several decades ago, there were many business people who possessed similar wealth to the Lien family.  These individuals also worked hard to manage their businesses and accumulate more wealth.  However, compared to the Lien family now, most of them lament their inferiority in terms of wealth. The Lien family&rsquo;s role as pure investors fully demonstrates that &ldquo;as long as the concepts and methods are correct, wealth will naturally follow.&rdquo;</p>
<p>In fact, the theories and methods in the &ldquo;Personal Investment Bible&rdquo; have been discussed by countless scholars and experts in mature Western societies, but not many have truly adhered to them and become millionaires as a result.  The reason lies not in the inadequacy of the theories and methods, but in the lack of confidence and patience of those who apply them, leading them to give up halfway.</p>
<p>Therefore, I advise all readers of this book to truly believe in the theories presented, have long-term patience, and adhere to them unwaveringly in order to succeed.</p>
<p>We wish all readers the ability to enjoy a happy retirement with sufficient financial resources, which is perhaps the greatest contribution of the &ldquo;Personal Investment Bible&rdquo; to the public! (This article is written by the president of Business Weekly Taiwan)</p>


<h2 class="relative group">The Joy of Wealth Management, Achieving Wealth with Ease 
    <div id="the-joy-of-wealth-management-achieving-wealth-with-ease" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#the-joy-of-wealth-management-achieving-wealth-with-ease" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>When I was young, I thought that money was the most important thing in life; now that I am old, I know that it is.</p>
<p>— Oscar Wilde, British playwright</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This book is written for those who are determined to become wealthy and strive for financial independence. If you have tried every possible way to get rich and your home is filled with investment books, but you still can&rsquo;t figure out how to achieve wealth in your lifetime, congratulations! You have found the book you need. The investment and financial management concepts and methods described in this book are absolutely understandable and achievable for everyone. As long as you put them into practice, becoming a millionaire is not difficult.</p>
<p>I see many people working tirelessly to make money, hoping to improve their own and their families&rsquo; financial situation, but they can&rsquo;t find the right way. Many people clearly have the conditions to become rich through financial management, but they don&rsquo;t know how to manage their finances, resulting in missed opportunities.  Others know that investment and financial management can lead to wealth, but the problem is that what they know is not true, leading them astray and suffering from financial mismanagement.  The author sees these phenomena and often feels sorry for them.</p>
<p>The biggest problem in Taiwan at present is the serious lack of financial education. The public lacks a correct concept of financial management. They either don&rsquo;t know how to manage their finances and neglect it, or they use the wrong methods. As a result, some people not only fail to achieve wealth through financial management, but even fail to achieve basic financial independence.  Insufficient or incorrect financial concepts are harmful not only to one&rsquo;s own financial situation, but also to the public. This is the main motivation for the author to write this book, and what this book offers readers is the correct basic concept of investment and financial management.</p>
<p>As a scholar and a practitioner of financial management, I feel obligated to share my years of investment research results and practical experience in financial management with everyone, helping the public to easily manage their finances and achieve wealth through investment. The message this book wants to convey is: Financial management is actually very simple. Not only can everyone do it easily, but almost all young people have the conditions to achieve wealth through financial management.</p>
<p>This book is based on 20 years of practical financial management experience in the United States and Taiwan, 6 years of investment research at Tunghai University, and 15 years of experience as a financial advisor.  In fact, the concepts and practices in this book were developed 3 years ago.  For the past 3 years, the author has given lectures on this topic in various places and received tremendous feedback.  Many listeners have continuously requested that I compile these concepts and action guidelines into a book.  I personally also feel that these financial management concepts and action guidelines are indeed beneficial to the public and there is indeed a need to publish a book.</p>
<p>However, putting these concepts into words is a difficult task for me, so I have procrastinated for 3 years. Recently, thanks to the repeated urging of Mr. He, President of Business Weekly Cultural Enterprise, and Ms. Sun Meiqing, and the examples and suggestions provided by Ms. Shen Wenci, and especially the efforts of Mr. Yang Weikai, who spent several months helping me revise and proofread, this book has finally been completed. I express my sincere gratitude here.</p>
<p>If this book can be read by the general public, and if they can accept the concepts and financial management methods described in the book, then all the author&rsquo;s efforts will have been truly worthwhile. Good ideas should be shared with everyone. I hope everyone can benefit from them and easily become millionaires through financial management.</p>
<p>Finally, I dedicate this book to my parents, Mr. Huang Minting and Ms. Huang Juzhi, who raised and nurtured me.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">Preface 
    <div id="preface" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#preface" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>In recent years, Taiwan&rsquo;s economy has grown rapidly.  While continuous economic growth is certainly gratifying, the problem of uneven wealth distribution has become increasingly serious. Some blame inappropriate government policies, while others believe it&rsquo;s due to speculation, which has caused stock and housing prices to rise, widening the gap between rich and poor. The author believes that these factors are not the main cause. The real reason for the widening wealth gap is the significant disparity in financial literacy among the public.</p>
<p>Starting in 1986, Taiwan officially entered an era of abundant capital and a focus on wealth management.  The New Taiwan dollar slowly appreciated from 40 to 27 against the US dollar, and during this period, a large amount of foreign exchange flowed into Taiwan, creating a situation where &ldquo;money overflowed in Taiwan.&rdquo;</p>
<p>Due to the excess capital, people began to shift their money towards investing in stocks and real estate. The huge influx of funds into the stock and housing markets caused stock and housing prices to soar. Between 1986 and 1989, housing prices increased by an average of two to four times, and the weighted stock market index rose from over 700 points in early 1986 to 12,680 points in February 1990, an increase of 18 times.  Investing in stocks and participating in the capital market is inherently meaningful, and rising stock prices are a natural consequence of economic growth. Unfortunately, most investors adopted the wrong approach, believing that to profit in the stock market, they must buy low and sell high, earning the difference.  In reality, short-term trading is not only time-consuming and laborious but also incurs huge transaction costs, resulting in most investors losing money. The stock market is almost equated with a casino.</p>
<p>The purpose of this book is to enlighten the public&rsquo;s financial mindset by providing new perspectives, concepts, and methods to cope with the important yet complex investment environment. The author sincerely hopes that after reading this book, readers will develop a new financial mentality and adopt correct financial management methods.</p>
<p>&ldquo;Getting rich&rdquo; is almost everyone&rsquo;s desire, and most people think that their monthly income is not much, and the amount they can save is even less. At this rate of wealth accumulation, it seems impossible to get rich. But in fact, with enough time and proper financial management, becoming a millionaire is not impossible.  Wealth accumulation through financial management requires only three basic conditions: regular savings, the pursuit of high returns, and long-term waiting.</p>
<p>The easiest way to achieve wealth through financial management is to learn from those who have done so. What are their methods? The secret of most successful wealth managers is not that they are smarter, harder working, or luckier than others, but that they have the habits and practices of wealth creation.</p>
<p>In the past, family financial management was rarely mentioned in school education.  Perhaps this is because investment and financial management involve money, and most people think that making money with money has a connotation of getting something for nothing.  In formal school education, teachers avoid mentioning it, believing that talking about money in education may corrupt people&rsquo;s minds, especially making money with money, which doesn&rsquo;t seem noble.  However, long-term avoidance of this issue has only exacerbated the problem.</p>
<p>The people of Taiwan, through years of joint efforts, have created an economic miracle and accumulated a large amount of wealth. However, most individuals and families only know how to make money but not how to manage it, let alone how to use it wisely.  After acquiring wealth, individuals, families, and even the entire society have suffered rather than benefited. For example, in recent years, money games have been prevalent.  Many people are busy speculating in stocks and real estate, and various forms of gambling such as the Mark Six lottery, futures, and foreign exchange margin trading are still popular and becoming increasingly rampant.  Many people are obsessed with money games, all for the purpose of making money and improving their family&rsquo;s financial situation.  However, if we calmly review the investment results of the past few years, it is not difficult to find that in the end, few have profited, many have lost, and even more have gone bankrupt.  Everyone has worked in vain, and the result is only a rapid redistribution of wealth and a prevalence of unhealthy speculation in society. The wealth of individuals and society as a whole does not increase. This is all due to the public&rsquo;s lack of clear understanding of financial management concepts.</p>
<p>The consequence of poor financial literacy is not only personal loss and family misfortune but also a waste of overall social resources.  Let&rsquo;s face this issue that is crucial to individuals, families, and the entire society: family financial management.</p>
<p>As the saying goes, &ldquo;When a couple is poor, everything is sad.&rdquo;  This shows that if a family&rsquo;s financial situation cannot meet the needs of family life, or if finances are not managed properly, happiness is hard to come by. Of course, there are many factors that contribute to a happy family, and wealth is only one of them, as many family problems cannot be solved with money. There is a saying: &ldquo;Money is not everything, but without money, you can do nothing.&rdquo; Although money is not the center of a family, in our real society, most good things require money. Wealthy families are not necessarily happy, but families without money are usually even less so. To make ourselves and our families happier, investment and financial management are indeed imperative. Investment and financial management can not only improve the financial situation of an individual or a family, but it is also a good way to accumulate wealth.  Using financial management to achieve wealth is achievable for everyone, and it is something everyone should do.</p>
<p>Future wealth depends on the future investment environment, and the biggest characteristic of the investment environment, in a word, is change.  The entire financial environment is ever-changing and unpredictable. This has been true in the past and will be even more so in the future. In the world of investment and financial management, there is constant change. It can be said that &ldquo;the only constant is change.&rdquo; It is foreseeable that the changes in the next 10 years will exceed those of the previous 50 years. Changes are not only becoming faster, but also more complex, diversified, and international. Whether we like it or not, we are already in a rapidly changing environment.</p>
<p>Facing change, you can remain calm, adapt, and adopt the appropriate mental attitude. However, if you know how change will affect you, you may not dare to take it lightly. Because the natural consequence of any change is redistribution, including wealth, power, markets, personnel&hellip; In terms of wealth, any change in the investment environment will naturally affect the flow of money at all levels.  Indeed, in financial markets, capital markets, commodity markets, spot or futures markets worldwide, billions of dollars are traded every day, and wealth is constantly being redistributed.  Your wealth may increase significantly during the redistribution process, or it may shrink rapidly.  After long-term redistribution, you may become a billionaire, or you may become penniless, depending on how you face and deal with the changes.</p>
<p>Any change and the resulting redistribution poses a &ldquo;crisis&rdquo; to your wealth to a greater or lesser extent. The Chinese characters for &ldquo;crisis&rdquo; are profound and often quoted in foreign books because they contain both danger and opportunity. &ldquo;Wei&rdquo; represents the threat to wealth, and &ldquo;Ji&rdquo; represents the opportunity for wealth creation.</p>
<p>We can wait for changes and redistribution to determine our future wealth level, or we can make good use of the opportunities brought about by change and try to reduce its destructive power.  In this era of accelerating change, cultivating the ability to manage and respond to change is essential to controlling our own future.</p>
<p>Looking ahead, changes in business, economy, finance, politics, society, and other aspects will accelerate. The overall financial environment will become more complex and unpredictable, and it is foreseeable that future wealth redistribution will inevitably accelerate. Therefore, for ourselves, our families, and society, everyone should play the role of a financial manager.</p>
<p>This is an era of rapid change and abundant wealth, and it is also an era that forces us to manage our finances.  Everyone desires to become rich and improve their living standards or achieve their life goals. There are many ways to get rich, but the concept the author wants to elaborate on in this book is: Investment and financial management is one of the effective methods to achieve wealth. As long as you have the correct financial management concepts and put them into practice, whether you are rich or poor now, over time, you may become a millionaire through investment and financial management.</p>
<p>In this critical era related to our future wealth, you can no longer remain indifferent to financial management or ignorant of investment.  You must adopt the correct financial concepts as early as possible, constantly acquire new knowledge, and avoid mistakes in order to win in the process of wealth redistribution.</p>
<p><strong>The Story of the Mailman Who Got Rich</strong></p>
<p>My brother-in-law has a friend in Taichung, a middle-aged man with a dark complexion and an occasional shy smile. My first impression of him wasn&rsquo;t memorable until he drove away in a new BMW. The second time we met, he arrived in a Mercedes-Benz, which made me admire him.  I realized that appearances can be deceiving and quickly asked him what kind of big business he was in. He said he wasn&rsquo;t a businessman, just an ordinary office worker.  I pressed him further, asking which big company he worked for. He said he worked at the post office. I thought he must be a senior executive to be so prestigious and own two luxury cars.  The answer, however, was surprising. He replied, &ldquo;I&rsquo;m a mailman. I deliver mail by motorcycle in the morning, with a monthly salary of NT$30,000-40,000.&rdquo; I secretly speculated that he must specialize in delivering registered mail and was pocketing some of the contents.  He then told me his story. His previous generation were poor farmers who left behind some land, which he had always regarded as ancestral property and kept without selling. No one expected that recent land consolidation would increase the value of his land by dozens of times. Now, just by renting out houses, he earns NT$500,000 in rent every month.  This 48-year-old mailman didn&rsquo;t rely on increasing income and reducing expenditure, but simply by putting his assets in the right place, he now has assets of more than NT$300 million. This is one of the examples of wealth accumulation through financial management in Taiwanese society.</p>
<p>Similar stories seem to happen frequently around us. Before I taught at the university, I worked for an investment company. Once, during the election of directors and supervisors at a shareholders&rsquo; meeting, I discovered that a major shareholder holding more than NT$200 million worth of shares was actually a clerk in the company&rsquo;s personnel department.  It turned out that 35 years ago, when she joined the company as an employee, her salary was very low and her life was insecure, so she saved her meager salary. When company employees had fractional shares to transfer, she would buy them. After many years, this woman in her 50s, although unremarkable and not looking like a rich woman, now has a net worth of more than NT$200 million, enough to enjoy her retirement. In fact, there are countless examples of such ordinary office workers who have become wealthy through investment and financial management. Many people say that office workers cannot become rich, but in reality, wealthy office workers mostly don&rsquo;t like to show off, so the way to get rich through investment and financial management is often overlooked.</p>
<p><strong>What Differentiates the Rich from the Poor?</strong></p>
<p>Many hardworking office workers who toil daily for money have had the common experience of watching rich people in expensive clothes, living in luxurious villas, and driving by in luxury cars, looking impressive and enviable. While admiring them, you may have wondered: &ldquo;What makes them rich, but not me?&rdquo;</p>
<p>Many people attribute the wealth of these rich people directly to their being born rich, their successful entrepreneurial ventures, their being smarter, harder working, or luckier than others. However, family background, entrepreneurship, intelligence, hard work, and luck cannot explain all the reasons for wealth accumulation. We have all encountered many rich people, such as &ldquo;nouveau riche&rdquo; or &ldquo;landowners.&rdquo; They were not born into wealthy families, nor are they businessmen. They are not necessarily very smart, haven&rsquo;t received much higher education, and are not more frugal than us. Some of them even idle around all day. The only thing they seem to be better at than you is that they are rich.</p>
<p>What special skills do these rich people possess that are lacking in those office workers who diligently save money and work hard every day? How can they accumulate such enormous wealth in their lifetime? This is the question the author has been eager to explore for many years.  I have tried to explain their wealth with factors such as family background, entrepreneurship, occupation, education, IQ, and effort, but all seem to have failed. After years of observation, induction, and academic research, I have discovered a very important factor that is often overlooked by most people: the ability to invest and manage finances. At the same time, I have also discovered the following three facts:</p>
<p><em>1. One of the important factors that distinguishes the rich from the poor is: the ability to invest and manage finances.</em></p>
<p><em>2. Everyone can achieve wealth through investment and financial management.</em></p>
<p><em>3. The first thing to do to improve your financial situation is: to understand the basic concepts of investment and financial management.</em>
content_copy
Use code with caution.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
