<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Reading Notes on QQQ Investor</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/tags/reading-notes/</link><description>Recent content in Reading Notes on QQQ Investor</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jomonylw.github.io/en/tags/reading-notes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Let Time Help You Slowly Get Rich: Book Notes</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1734847682781/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1734847682781/</guid><description>This book primarily explains the strategy of regular investing, emphasizing that it&amp;#39;s the best investment method for ordinary people. The author, Li Xiaolai, elaborates on the core concepts, advantages, and correct execution of regular investing, combining personal experiences and market examples to demonstrate the importance of long-term and value investing. Furthermore, he explores topics like proactivity vs. passivity, trends, and personal growth, aiming to help readers establish a sound investment philosophy and wealth outlook, ultimately achieving financial freedom.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[

<h2 class="relative group">I. Summary 
    <div id="i-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>The core argument of this book is: <strong>Regular investing is the optimal investment strategy for ordinary people.</strong> Li Xiaolai uses a unique perspective and accessible language to systematically explain the advantages, principles, and implementation of regular investing. He argues that compared to other investment methods, regular investing is more suitable for ordinary people due to its simplicity, lower risk, and ability to overcome human weaknesses.  It helps investors maintain rationality amidst market fluctuations, ultimately achieving steady wealth growth.  Beyond investment techniques, the book also touches upon personal growth, mindset, and life choices, aiming to help readers establish a sound investment philosophy and wealth outlook, ultimately achieving financial freedom and happiness.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">II. Chapter Summaries 
    <div id="ii-chapter-summaries" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii-chapter-summaries" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">1. Almost Everyone is Qualified and Capable of Regular Investing 
    <div id="1-almost-everyone-is-qualified-and-capable-of-regular-investing" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#1-almost-everyone-is-qualified-and-capable-of-regular-investing" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Most people possess the ability to invest regularly, but they often choose the wrong target (real estate).</strong> The author uses the common phenomenon of &ldquo;mortgage slaves&rdquo; to illustrate that most people are unconsciously engaged in a form of regular investing – real estate.  Their monthly mortgage payments essentially constitute a form of regular investment. However, due to high interest rates and low liquidity, real estate is not the optimal choice. He contrasts this with the example of investing regularly in Kweichow Moutai stock for 18 years, resulting in a 180-fold increase, highlighting the significant advantages of stock investing in terms of long-term returns and liquidity.  This emphasizes the crucial importance of selecting the right investment target.  Due to mortgage burdens, many become &ldquo;mortgage millionaires,&rdquo; possessing seemingly large assets but lacking cash flow and a high quality of life.</li>
<li><strong>Advantages of regular investment in stocks/index funds: low barrier to entry, high liquidity, potential for high returns.</strong> Compared to other investment methods like investing in early-stage startups or art, stocks and index funds have a low barrier to entry, making them accessible to everyone.  Moreover, they offer high liquidity, allowing investors to buy and sell at any time, facilitating adjustments to their investment strategies as needed.  More importantly, over the long term, the stock market tends to rise with economic development, giving regular investment in stocks/index funds the potential for high returns. The author believes the stock market offers ordinary people an opportunity to share in the growth dividends of excellent companies, an advantage difficult to obtain through other investment avenues.</li>
<li><strong>The importance of participating in a regular investing community.</strong>  The author points out that regular investing is not just an investment strategy but also a social activity. Due to widespread misunderstandings and biases about stock investing (such as &ldquo;investment is risky&rdquo; or &ldquo;only the rich invest&rdquo;), investing regularly alone can be easily influenced by external factors, making it difficult to persist. Participating in a regular investing community can help investors overcome these negative influences, gain support and encouragement from peers, establish a correct investment philosophy, and learn more investment knowledge and experience. Within such communities, members can exchange experiences, share insights, and create a positive feedback loop.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">2. The Stock Market is the Ninth Wonder of the World 
    <div id="2-the-stock-market-is-the-ninth-wonder-of-the-world" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#2-the-stock-market-is-the-ninth-wonder-of-the-world" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>The stock market gives ordinary people the chance to be &ldquo;bosses&rdquo; and share in the growth dividends of excellent companies.</strong> The author believes the stock market provides a unique opportunity for ordinary people to invest in well-managed, high-quality companies and share in their profits, even if they have no understanding of business operations. This is an advantage difficult to gain even by working at a company, including publicly listed ones. Through investing, ordinary people can indirectly &ldquo;own&rdquo; multiple excellent companies, achieving wealth appreciation.</li>
<li><strong>A simple method for stock selection: choose the most favored stocks or index funds in the market.</strong> The author suggests that choosing stocks doesn&rsquo;t require complex analysis and research. One can directly choose the most popular stocks or index funds in the market, such as Kweichow Moutai, Apple, or Tencent.  These represent the collective wisdom of the smartest people in the market, and choosing them is akin to leveraging their free advice.  He further notes that the advice from the smartest people in the market is often free, like Warren Buffett&rsquo;s portfolio information and popular stock choices.</li>
<li><strong>Don&rsquo;t worry about making the wrong choice; market consensus is more important than individual judgment.</strong> Even if the most favored stock in the market eventually fails, there&rsquo;s no need for excessive self-blame, as it represented the best available advice at the time.  Individual judgment rarely surpasses market consensus. In the long run, market forces will correct errors, so the key is to hold long-term and trust the power of the market.  The author believes that rather than spending significant time and energy researching individual stocks, it&rsquo;s better to trust the collective wisdom of the market and choose widely recognized, excellent companies.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">3. Are There Any Investment Targets that Only Go Up? 
    <div id="3-are-there-any-investment-targets-that-only-go-up" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#3-are-there-any-investment-targets-that-only-go-up" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Investing in a single stock is high-risk, with unlimited opportunity cost, and requires diversification.</strong> Even the best-performing single company can face significant risks due to industry decline, black swan events, or other unpredictable factors. Concentrating funds in a single stock represents high risk, and losses can be difficult to recover if problems arise.  The author cites Kodak and Nokia as examples, illustrating how even once-great companies can decline. Hence, diversification is essential to mitigate risk.</li>
<li><strong>In the long run, the only investment that only goes up is human economic development, which can be accessed through index funds.</strong> The author argues that the human economy generally trends upwards over the long term, and index funds track the overall market performance.  By investing in index funds, one can effectively diversify risk and share in the dividends of long-term economic growth.  The 40-year performance chart of the S&amp;P 500 is compelling evidence.  Investing in index funds is like betting on the national, or even global, economy, and offers better odds in the long run.</li>
<li><strong>Long-term investment is necessary to dilute risk and ultimately achieve stable returns.</strong> Short-term market fluctuations are difficult to predict and are full of noise and randomness.  Only long-term investment can effectively smooth these fluctuations and ultimately generate stable returns.  The author emphasizes that there are no investment targets that only go up, only the long-term general upward trend of the human economy.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">4. The Only Correct Way for Ordinary People to Invest 
    <div id="4-the-only-correct-way-for-ordinary-people-to-invest" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#4-the-only-correct-way-for-ordinary-people-to-invest" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Regular investing is the most reliable investment method for ordinary people.</strong> The author uses the example of Longmen Fund, comparing lump-sum investing with regular investing. The results show that regular investing achieved a significantly higher return: 74.01% vs. 10.81%.  Regular investing can effectively smooth market fluctuations and reduce investment risk.</li>
<li><strong>Regular investing helps investors overcome fear and greed, maintaining rationality during market fluctuations.</strong> Through regular, fixed-amount investments, investors can buy more shares at lower prices during market downturns, averaging down their cost.  During market upturns, it prevents investing too much at once, avoiding being trapped at high prices.  The discipline of regular investing can help investors overcome the human weakness of chasing rising markets and selling during falls.</li>
<li><strong>Regular investing is a long-term strategy that requires patience and discipline.</strong> Returns from regular investing take time to accumulate. Investors need to be patient and maintain discipline, not easily interrupting or changing their investment plan, to achieve significant returns.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">5. Why So Few People Use Regular Investing 
    <div id="5-why-so-few-people-use-regular-investing" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#5-why-so-few-people-use-regular-investing" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>&ldquo;Fear of simplicity&rdquo; hinders people from accepting regular investing.</strong> People tend to believe in complex and sophisticated methods, underestimating the power of simplicity.  This is similar to how it took a long time for people to think of adding wheels to luggage, learning English through consistent reading aloud, improving writing through effective reading, and maintaining health through regular exercise.</li>
<li><strong>Regular investing&rsquo;s simplicity makes it easier to adhere to, avoiding the risks of frequent trading.</strong> Compared to complex trading strategies, regular investing is simple and easy to follow, avoiding transaction costs and the risk of misjudgment associated with frequent trading.  The author believes that this simplicity is precisely the greatest advantage of regular investing.</li>
<li><strong>People lack understanding and patience for long-term investing.</strong> Most people crave quick riches and struggle to endure the &ldquo;loneliness&rdquo; of long-term investing. They are easily influenced by short-term market fluctuations and often give up, as seen in the Longmen Fund example, where lump-sum investors were more prone to panic selling during market declines.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">6. The Profound Mechanisms Behind the Magic of Regular Investing 
    <div id="6-the-profound-mechanisms-behind-the-magic-of-regular-investing" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#6-the-profound-mechanisms-behind-the-magic-of-regular-investing" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Proactive personality is important, but recognize the boundaries of proactivity.</strong> Be proactive within your circle of influence, but also recognize your limitations.  Don&rsquo;t try to control what you cannot, such as your children&rsquo;s future or the operations of companies you&rsquo;ve invested in.</li>
<li><strong>Factors that determine destiny often lie outside our control, such as trends.</strong> Personal effort is important, but it&rsquo;s also essential to align with the trends of the times.  Like snooker player Ronnie O&rsquo;Sullivan, even with immense effort, competitors find it challenging to defeat him at his peak.</li>
<li><strong>Active passivity is the best strategy for navigating trends.</strong> Actively choose the right trend, then passively wait for the trend to unfold. In investing, this means actively choosing promising assets or indices for the long term, then passively adhering to a regular investment schedule.</li>
<li><strong>Regular investing is the best practice of &ldquo;active passivity.&rdquo;</strong> Choosing worthy long-term investments is active; regularly buying a fixed amount and holding long-term is passive.</li>
<li><strong>The power of passivity is fully demonstrated in long-term investing.</strong> The long-term performance of passive funds often surpasses that of actively managed funds, demonstrating the limitations of &ldquo;active management&rdquo; and the strength of long-term holding.</li>
<li><strong>Ordinary people can improve their investment abilities by controlling their own behavior, such as improving their ability to earn outside of the market.</strong>  Earning power outside of the market is the cornerstone of regular investing and a key factor ordinary people can actively improve.</li>
<li><strong>Understanding &ldquo;long-term&rdquo; determines investment outcomes.</strong> &ldquo;Long-term&rdquo; doesn&rsquo;t mean forever, but &ldquo;at least two major cycles,&rdquo; which, based on market changes, is approximately seven years.</li>
<li><strong>Ordinary people&rsquo;s money has no expiration date, a significant advantage over professional fund managers.</strong> Professional fund managers are constrained by fund deadlines and investor pressure, while ordinary people can invest long-term with more composure, fully utilizing the power of time.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">7. The Difference Between Stupidity and Ignorance, and Passive Intelligence 
    <div id="7-the-difference-between-stupidity-and-ignorance-and-passive-intelligence" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#7-the-difference-between-stupidity-and-ignorance-and-passive-intelligence" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Smart people can make ignorant mistakes in unfamiliar fields.</strong> Like Archimedes and Zu Chongzhi, geniuses in their respective fields could make mistakes in the unfamiliar territory of the stock market due to a lack of specific knowledge.</li>
<li><strong>Regular investing allows ordinary people to be passively intelligent investors from the start.</strong>  The strategy&rsquo;s simplicity avoids errors associated with complex operations, allowing ordinary people to achieve reasonable returns without becoming investment experts.</li>
<li><strong>Regular investing cultivates patience, discipline, and the habit of investing within one&rsquo;s means.</strong> Long-term regular investing requires patience and discipline. The investment amount should also be within one&rsquo;s means to avoid impacting daily life. These are all good investment habits.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">8. Some People Are Always on the Right Side 
    <div id="8-some-people-are-always-on-the-right-side" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#8-some-people-are-always-on-the-right-side" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>People with great goals are more likely to make the right choices in a mirrored world.</strong>  A sense of purpose allows focus on long-term value instead of being distracted by short-term fluctuations.  The author quotes Arnold Schwarzenegger&rsquo;s speech, emphasizing the importance of goals: &ldquo;The only reason I&rsquo;m standing here today is because I had a goal.&rdquo;</li>
<li><strong>Imbuing what you do with great meaning can ignite powerful self-motivation.</strong>  A sense of meaning provides stronger motivation to persist. The author uses his own writing and teaching experience to illustrate the significance of meaning and encourages readers to find meaning in their regular investing, such as &ldquo;for the children&rsquo;s future&rdquo; or &ldquo;for early retirement.&rdquo;</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">9.  A Glimpse into the Other Side of the Mirror World 
    <div id="9--a-glimpse-into-the-other-side-of-the-mirror-world" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#9--a-glimpse-into-the-other-side-of-the-mirror-world" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Investors who don&rsquo;t adopt regular investing easily fall into various investment traps, ultimately leading to losses.</strong> These include chasing rising markets, frequent trading, blindly following the crowd, and listening to rumors, often resulting in substantial losses during market volatility.</li>
<li><strong>Many investors blame their losses on greed, but the real root cause is a lack of understanding of the investment target.</strong> The author argues that greed is human nature and not the fundamental reason for investment failures.  The true cause lies in a lack of understanding of the investment target, an inability to judge its intrinsic value, leading to blind following or emotionally driven decisions, ultimately resulting in buying high and selling low.</li>
<li><strong>Even those who use regular investing need to deeply understand its core principles to avoid becoming half-baked investors.</strong>  This includes failing to carefully select investment targets, not holding long-term, investing too little, or easily interrupting the investment plan.  The author criticizes investors who don&rsquo;t truly grasp the essence of regular investing and merely engage in mechanical operations.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">10. Regular Investing is Essential for Ordinary People 
    <div id="10-regular-investing-is-essential-for-ordinary-people" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#10-regular-investing-is-essential-for-ordinary-people" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>The insignificance of effort: Ordinary people have limited free time, making it difficult to achieve significant success solely through hard work.</strong> The author uses data and personal experiences to illustrate that even with extraordinary effort, such as working 24 years without holidays or cutting his own hair, the gains are limited. He only managed to gain 1.26 years of effective working time compared to others.</li>
<li><strong>The essence of investing is to make money work for you, compensating for limited time and energy.</strong> Investing allows money to work 24/7, amplifying returns far beyond what one can earn through personal labor. Warren Buffett&rsquo;s 78-year investing journey serves as a prime example.</li>
<li><strong>Regular investing is an effective path for ordinary people to achieve financial freedom.</strong>  The strategy is simple and easy to execute.  Long-term adherence can generate substantial returns, helping ordinary people accumulate wealth and eventually achieve financial freedom.</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">III. Key Quotes 
    <div id="iii-key-quotes" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii-key-quotes" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>Diligence in practice makes one invincible!</p></blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>Regular investing is the only reliable investment method for ordinary people.</p></blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>There are no investment targets that only rise, only those that rise in the long term.</p></blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>Be proactive when you should be, and passive when you should be.</p></blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>Your money may not be much, but it has no expiration date.</p></blockquote>


<h2 class="relative group">IV.  Guiding Significance 
    <div id="iv--guiding-significance" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv--guiding-significance" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<ul>
<li><strong>Establishing a sound investment philosophy:</strong>  Helping readers avoid investment pitfalls and recognize the importance of long-term, value, and passive investing, while avoiding mistakes like chasing rising markets and frequent trading.</li>
<li><strong>Providing practical investment methods:</strong>  The regular investing strategy is simple and easy to implement, accessible even to those with no prior investment experience.</li>
<li><strong>Promoting personal growth:</strong>  Encouraging readers to cultivate a proactive personality, recognize the boundaries of their control, and learn how to be actively passive, aligning with trends.</li>
<li><strong>Guiding life choices:</strong> Inspiring readers to reflect on the meaning and goals of life and strive towards them, ultimately achieving financial freedom and happiness.</li>
<li><strong>Cultivating a healthy mindset:</strong> Reminding readers not to be swayed by short-term fluctuations, maintaining patience and discipline, overcoming fear and greed, and believing in the power of time.</li>
</ul>
<p>In conclusion, this book not only provides practical investment techniques but, more importantly, helps readers establish a healthy wealth outlook and life philosophy, ultimately achieving financial freedom and happiness.  The book also encourages readers to join regular investing communities for mutual learning, support, and progress.</p>
<hr>
<a id="github-e02127fda5246656fa0433195f17cabe" target="_blank" href="https://github.com/xiaolai/regular-investing-in-box" class="cursor-pointer">
  <div
    class="w-full md:w-auto pt-3 p-5 border border-neutral-200 dark:border-neutral-700 border rounded-md shadow-2xl">

    <div class="flex items-center">
      <span class="text-2xl text-neutral-800 dark:text-neutral" style="margin-right:10px;">
        

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 496 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M165.9 397.4c0 2-2.3 3.6-5.2 3.6-3.3.3-5.6-1.3-5.6-3.6 0-2 2.3-3.6 5.2-3.6 3-.3 5.6 1.3 5.6 3.6zm-31.1-4.5c-.7 2 1.3 4.3 4.3 4.9 2.6 1 5.6 0 6.2-2s-1.3-4.3-4.3-5.2c-2.6-.7-5.5.3-6.2 2.3zm44.2-1.7c-2.9.7-4.9 2.6-4.6 4.9.3 2 2.9 3.3 5.9 2.6 2.9-.7 4.9-2.6 4.6-4.6-.3-1.9-3-3.2-5.9-2.9zM244.8 8C106.1 8 0 113.3 0 252c0 110.9 69.8 205.8 169.5 239.2 12.8 2.3 17.3-5.6 17.3-12.1 0-6.2-.3-40.4-.3-61.4 0 0-70 15-84.7-29.8 0 0-11.4-29.1-27.8-36.6 0 0-22.9-15.7 1.6-15.4 0 0 24.9 2 38.6 25.8 21.9 38.6 58.6 27.5 72.9 20.9 2.3-16 8.8-27.1 16-33.7-55.9-6.2-112.3-14.3-112.3-110.5 0-27.5 7.6-41.3 23.6-58.9-2.6-6.5-11.1-33.3 2.6-67.9 20.9-6.5 69 27 69 27 20-5.6 41.5-8.5 62.8-8.5s42.8 2.9 62.8 8.5c0 0 48.1-33.6 69-27 13.7 34.7 5.2 61.4 2.6 67.9 16 17.7 25.8 31.5 25.8 58.9 0 96.5-58.9 104.2-114.8 110.5 9.2 7.9 17 22.9 17 46.4 0 33.7-.3 75.4-.3 83.6 0 6.5 4.6 14.4 17.3 12.1C428.2 457.8 496 362.9 496 252 496 113.3 383.5 8 244.8 8zM97.2 352.9c-1.3 1-1 3.3.7 5.2 1.6 1.6 3.9 2.3 5.2 1 1.3-1 1-3.3-.7-5.2-1.6-1.6-3.9-2.3-5.2-1zm-10.8-8.1c-.7 1.3.3 2.9 2.3 3.9 1.6 1 3.6.7 4.3-.7.7-1.3-.3-2.9-2.3-3.9-2-.6-3.6-.3-4.3.7zm32.4 35.6c-1.6 1.3-1 4.3 1.3 6.2 2.3 2.3 5.2 2.6 6.5 1 1.3-1.3.7-4.3-1.3-6.2-2.2-2.3-5.2-2.6-6.5-1zm-11.4-14.7c-1.6 1-1.6 3.6 0 5.9 1.6 2.3 4.3 3.3 5.6 2.3 1.6-1.3 1.6-3.9 0-6.2-1.4-2.3-4-3.3-5.6-2z"/></svg>

  </span>


      </span>
      <div
        id="github-e02127fda5246656fa0433195f17cabe-full_name"
        class="m-0 font-bold text-xl text-neutral-800 decoration-primary-500 hover:underline hover:underline-offset-2 dark:text-neutral">
        xiaolai/regular-investing-in-box
      </div>
    </div>

    <p id="github-e02127fda5246656fa0433195f17cabe-description" class="m-0 mt-2 text-md text-neutral-800 dark:text-neutral">
      定投改变命运 —— 让时间陪你慢慢变富 <a href="https://onregularinvesting.com" target="_blank">https://onregularinvesting.com</a>
    </p>

    <div class="m-0 mt-2 flex items-center">

      <span class="mr-1 inline-block h-3 w-3 rounded-full"
        style="background-color: #3572A5"></span>
      <div class="m-0 mr-5 text-md text-neutral-800 dark:text-neutral">
         Python 
      </div>

      <span class="text-md mr-1 text-neutral-800 dark:text-neutral">
        

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 576 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M287.9 0C297.1 0 305.5 5.25 309.5 13.52L378.1 154.8L531.4 177.5C540.4 178.8 547.8 185.1 550.7 193.7C553.5 202.4 551.2 211.9 544.8 218.2L433.6 328.4L459.9 483.9C461.4 492.9 457.7 502.1 450.2 507.4C442.8 512.7 432.1 513.4 424.9 509.1L287.9 435.9L150.1 509.1C142.9 513.4 133.1 512.7 125.6 507.4C118.2 502.1 114.5 492.9 115.1 483.9L142.2 328.4L31.11 218.2C24.65 211.9 22.36 202.4 25.2 193.7C28.03 185.1 35.5 178.8 44.49 177.5L197.7 154.8L266.3 13.52C270.4 5.249 278.7 0 287.9 0L287.9 0zM287.9 78.95L235.4 187.2C231.9 194.3 225.1 199.3 217.3 200.5L98.98 217.9L184.9 303C190.4 308.5 192.9 316.4 191.6 324.1L171.4 443.7L276.6 387.5C283.7 383.7 292.2 383.7 299.2 387.5L404.4 443.7L384.2 324.1C382.9 316.4 385.5 308.5 391 303L476.9 217.9L358.6 200.5C350.7 199.3 343.9 194.3 340.5 187.2L287.9 78.95z"/></svg>
  </span>


      </span>
      <div id="github-e02127fda5246656fa0433195f17cabe-stargazers" class="m-0 mr-5 text-md text-neutral-800 dark:text-neutral">
        5838
      </div>

      <span class="text-md mr-1 text-neutral-800 dark:text-neutral">
        

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 448 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M80 104c13.3 0 24-10.7 24-24s-10.7-24-24-24S56 66.7 56 80s10.7 24 24 24zm80-24c0 32.8-19.7 61-48 73.3V192c0 17.7 14.3 32 32 32H304c17.7 0 32-14.3 32-32V153.3C307.7 141 288 112.8 288 80c0-44.2 35.8-80 80-80s80 35.8 80 80c0 32.8-19.7 61-48 73.3V192c0 53-43 96-96 96H256v70.7c28.3 12.3 48 40.5 48 73.3c0 44.2-35.8 80-80 80s-80-35.8-80-80c0-32.8 19.7-61 48-73.3V288H144c-53 0-96-43-96-96V153.3C19.7 141 0 112.8 0 80C0 35.8 35.8 0 80 0s80 35.8 80 80zm208 24c13.3 0 24-10.7 24-24s-10.7-24-24-24s-24 10.7-24 24s10.7 24 24 24zM248 432c0-13.3-10.7-24-24-24s-24 10.7-24 24s10.7 24 24 24s24-10.7 24-24z"/></svg>
  </span>


      </span>
      <div id="github-e02127fda5246656fa0433195f17cabe-forks" class="m-0 mr-5 text-md text-neutral-800 dark:text-neutral">
        2019
      </div>

    </div>

  </div>
  <script>
    fetch("https://api.github.com/repos/xiaolai/regular-investing-in-box", {
      headers: new Headers({
        'User-agent': 'Mozilla/4.0 Custom User Agent'
      })
    })
      .then(response => response.json())
      .then(data => {
        document.getElementById('github-e02127fda5246656fa0433195f17cabe-full_name').innerHTML = data.full_name;
        document.getElementById('github-e02127fda5246656fa0433195f17cabe-description').innerHTML = data.description;
        document.getElementById('github-e02127fda5246656fa0433195f17cabe-stargazers').innerHTML = data.stargazers_count;
        document.getElementById('github-e02127fda5246656fa0433195f17cabe-forks').innerHTML = data.forks;
      })
      .catch(error => console.error(error))
  </script>
</a>
<hr>

<section class="space-y-10 w-full">
    
    
</section>
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Personal Investment Bible: Book Notes</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1731056005976/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1731056005976/</guid><description>This book, written by Mr. Huang Peiyuan from Taiwan, uses easy-to-understand language to teach the correct methods of financial management. It elaborates on thirteen Investment Iron Laws for effortless wealth building, guiding readers on how to establish a correct perspective on financial management and ultimately achieve financial freedom.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[

<h2 class="relative group">I. Content Summary 
    <div id="i-content-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-content-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>The core concept of this book is that everyone can achieve financial freedom through investment, not just the wealthy or high-income earners. Through thirteen Investment Iron Laws, it emphasizes the importance of correct financial management concepts and long-term investment, encouraging readers to start managing their finances early, invest primarily in high-return investment tools such as stocks and real estate, and hold them for the long term, ultimately achieving financial freedom through the power of compound interest. The book uses numerous real-life examples and simple language to help readers understand and master correct financial management methods, while abandoning common financial management misunderstandings, such as short-term trading and over-reliance on bank deposits.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">II. Chapter Summaries 
    <div id="ii-chapter-summaries" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii-chapter-summaries" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Correct Concept of Personal Finance 
    <div id="correct-concept-of-personal-finance" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#correct-concept-of-personal-finance" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Personal investment can lead to wealth:</strong> The author believes that personal investment is not only a means to improve financial status but also an important path to wealth. Even if the monthly investment amount is small, as long as you persevere, you can accumulate considerable wealth by relying on the power of compound interest and ultimately realize the dream of becoming a billionaire. The book illustrates the power of compound interest with the example of investing 1200 Yuan per month with an annual return of 20%, resulting in assets exceeding 100 million Yuan after 40 years. It also cites the financial stories of the Lien Chan family and a postman to prove that even ordinary office workers can accumulate huge wealth with proper financial management.</li>
<li><strong>Increasing income and reducing expenditure treats the symptoms, not the root cause:</strong> Although diligence and frugality are traditional virtues, it is difficult to achieve financial freedom solely by relying on them in the era of rapid economic development. The author believes that financial management is more important than increasing income and reducing expenditure. The core of financial management lies in &ldquo;making money with money&rdquo; by achieving higher returns through investment, thereby enabling wealth to grow exponentially. The book uses the Lien Chan family&rsquo;s financial management methods as an example to illustrate the importance of investing in stocks and real estate. It points out that the Lien family did not start with huge wealth but accumulated astonishing wealth through long-term investment and financial management.</li>
<li><strong>Financial management methods cause the wealth gap:</strong> The author believes that the main cause of the wealth gap is not external factors such as family background, personal effort, or luck, but the difference in financial concepts and methods. The rich tend to invest their assets in high-yield investment tools such as stocks and real estate, while the poor tend to deposit money in banks, resulting in a slow rate of wealth appreciation. The book uses the example of two classmates who joined the same company after graduation to illustrate how different financial management methods eventually lead to vastly different wealth outcomes.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Investment Iron Law 1: Don&rsquo;t Save Money in the Bank 
    <div id="investment-iron-law-1-dont-save-money-in-the-bank" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#investment-iron-law-1-dont-save-money-in-the-bank" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Saving is equal to wasting resources:</strong> The author points out that keeping money in the bank seems safe but is actually a waste of resources. This is because bank deposit interest rates are low, and under the influence of inflation, the real rate of return is close to zero or even negative. This means that money deposited in the bank not only fails to appreciate but also depreciates. The book uses biblical stories and the example of the Nobel Prize Foundation to illustrate that not making good use of wealth, even without loss, is a waste.</li>
<li><strong>Deposit interest rates do not have compound interest benefits:</strong> Although bank deposits also enjoy compound interest, due to the low interest rate, the effect of compound interest is very limited and difficult to withstand the erosion of inflation. The author compares the final returns of two investment methods after 40 years, using a 5% bank interest rate and a 20% stock/real estate investment return rate as examples, illustrating the importance of the rate of return on investment.</li>
<li><strong>The invisible killer of currency value - inflation:</strong> Inflation is the &ldquo;invisible killer&rdquo; that causes money to depreciate. The author vividly illustrates the impact of inflation by comparing the price of red bean ice 30 years ago and now. He points out that in an inflationary environment, depositing money in the bank actually means &ldquo;the more you save, the less you have&rdquo;.</li>
<li><strong>The way to wealth of Zhang Pingsan, former chairman of Chang Hwa Bank:</strong> The author tells the story of Zhang Pingsan, the former chairman of Chang Hwa Bank, who achieved tremendous wealth growth by continuously borrowing money to buy Chang Hwa Bank shares and holding them for a long time. Those who sold their shares and put the money in the bank missed the opportunity to become wealthy. This once again proves the point that &ldquo;don&rsquo;t save money in the bank&rdquo;.</li>
<li><strong>The money deposited in the bank should not exceed living expenses:</strong> The author suggests that the amount of money deposited in the bank should be limited to meet two months of living expenses, and the excess should be used for investment to obtain higher returns. He also proposes a &ldquo;two large, one small&rdquo; investment portfolio suggestion: most assets are invested in stocks and real estate, and a small portion of funds is deposited in the bank for emergencies. He explains the liquidity of stocks and real estate to dispel readers&rsquo; concerns about investment liquidity.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Investment Iron Law 2: Be Patient to Get Rich Through Financial Management 
    <div id="investment-iron-law-2-be-patient-to-get-rich-through-financial-management" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#investment-iron-law-2-be-patient-to-get-rich-through-financial-management" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>How Li Ka-shing accumulated wealth:</strong> The author uses Li Ka-shing, Hong Kong&rsquo;s richest man, as an example to illustrate the importance of long-term investment. Li Ka-shing accumulated huge wealth through long-term investment in real estate. Getting rich through financial management requires time and patience; it is impossible to achieve overnight success. His success was not solely based on luck or hard work; more importantly, it was due to his long-term vision and perseverance.</li>
<li><strong>It takes a long time to see the effect of compound interest in financial management:</strong> The manifestation of the compound interest effect takes time, and it is difficult to see significant results in short-term investments. The author uses the example of investing 14,000 Yuan annually with an annual return of 20% to calculate the investment returns after 10, 20, 30, and 40 years, which are 360,000 Yuan, 2.61 million Yuan, 16.55 million Yuan, and 102.81 million Yuan, respectively. This set of data clearly demonstrates the power of compound interest and the importance of waiting patiently. Financial management is more like a marathon than a sprint.</li>
<li><strong>As long as you are patient, the money won&rsquo;t run away:</strong> Wealth accumulation is a gradual process that requires patience to wait for the compound interest effect to play out. The author uses the land investment experience of Zhang Yaohongying, Chairman of Hongjing Construction, as an example to illustrate that even if the initial investment return is not obvious, as long as you persist in holding it for a long time, you can eventually get a rich return.</li>
<li><strong>Getting rich overnight is counterproductive:</strong> The author warns readers that getting rich through financial management takes time, and they should not dream of getting rich quickly. Investment opportunities that bring rapid wealth in the short term are often accompanied by extremely high risks, which may eventually lead to losing everything. The author suggests that if you want to get rich quickly, you should choose to start a business instead of resorting to speculation.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Investment Iron Law 3: The Sooner You Start Investing, the Better 
    <div id="investment-iron-law-3-the-sooner-you-start-investing-the-better" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#investment-iron-law-3-the-sooner-you-start-investing-the-better" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Procrastination is the main reason for financial failure:</strong> The author points out that procrastination is one of the main reasons for financial failure. As age increases, the time available for investment decreases, and the space for the compound interest effect to play out also shrinks. Therefore, financial management should start as early as possible. Do not wait until you are older to realize the importance of financial management, as it is often too late.</li>
<li><strong>Start investing from today:</strong> The earlier you start investing, the longer the time for compound interest, and the higher the final return. The author calculates the monthly investment amount required under the same target amount and investment rate of return with different starting investment ages as examples. The data shows that the later you start investing, the higher the monthly investment amount required, highlighting the importance of starting financial management early.</li>
<li><strong>Jeffrey Koo Jr. is good at making money:</strong> The author uses the example of Jeffrey Koo Jr., Vice President of CTBC Financial Holding, to illustrate that even those from wealthy families should learn financial management early. Jeffrey Koo Jr. invested his savings in the stock market during his university days and obtained substantial returns, indicating that young people can also achieve success through financial management.</li>
<li><strong>Don&rsquo;t neglect financial management because of lack of money:</strong> The author emphasizes that financial management is not exclusive to the rich. Even if you don&rsquo;t have much money, you should start as early as possible and let the limited funds play the role of compound interest, accumulating little by little to eventually accumulate considerable wealth.</li>
<li><strong>Youth is the most appropriate time to take risks:</strong> When you are young, you have a lighter family burden and the cost of failure is relatively low, so it is more suitable to take certain investment risks. Moreover, young people have more time to make up for potential losses and learn from their mistakes.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Investment Iron Law 4: Make Money with Other People&rsquo;s Money 
    <div id="investment-iron-law-4-make-money-with-other-peoples-money" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#investment-iron-law-4-make-money-with-other-peoples-money" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Good use of debt investment:</strong> The author introduces the concept of &ldquo;financial leverage,&rdquo; which refers to using borrowed funds for investment to achieve a small investment with a large return, maximizing profits. He uses the examples of Chen Youhao, President of Eastern Multimedia Group, and Weng Daming of Hualon Group to illustrate how successful entrepreneurs use financial leverage for business expansion and investment. Specific examples are used to calculate the investment return rate under different leverage ratios to help readers understand the principle and role of financial leverage.</li>
<li><strong>Two major principles of borrowing:</strong> The author proposes two major principles for debt investment: 1. The expected return on investment must be greater than the loan interest rate; 2. In the worst case, cash income must be sufficient to pay the principal and interest of the loan. These two principles emphasize the risks of debt investment and remind readers to rationally evaluate the expected rate of return of the investment target and conduct risk assessment to ensure that even if the investment fails, the principal and interest of the loan can be repaid on time.</li>
<li><strong>Banks are not places to save money:</strong> The author points out that for people who are good at financial management, banks are not places to save money but sources of borrowing. He explains the operating model of banks: Banks absorb deposits from depositors and then lend these funds to investors. Investors make profits through investment and pay interest to banks. Therefore, people who are good at financial management can use bank funds for investment to magnify returns.</li>
<li><strong>Avoid improper debt:</strong> The author cautions readers to avoid improper debt. Do not borrow money to participate in high-risk activities such as futures, margin trading, and gambling because the expected return rate of these activities is negative, and long-term participation will inevitably lead to losses. Also, do not over-engage in consumer loans, such as credit card loans and car loans, as high-interest loans will seriously erode personal wealth. Mortgage loans are acceptable, but you should also live within your means and make sure that the monthly repayment pressure is within your affordable range.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Investment Iron Law 5: Relieve the Pressure of Investment Risks 
    <div id="investment-iron-law-5-relieve-the-pressure-of-investment-risks" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#investment-iron-law-5-relieve-the-pressure-of-investment-risks" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Analyze risks and reduce harm:</strong> The author points out that risks cannot be completely avoided in the investment process. The purpose of risk management is not to eliminate risk but to analyze risk and reduce the potential harm caused by risk. He emphasizes not to over-rely on forecasting because the accuracy of forecasting is difficult to guarantee, and over-reliance on forecasting may lead investors to lose their risk awareness.</li>
<li><strong>Forbes&rsquo; philosophy of distress:</strong> The author uses the example of American billionaire Forbes to illustrate that even risk-averse people can take risks through reasonable risk management. Although Forbes doesn&rsquo;t like adventure, in order to experience the beauty of life, he will participate in some high-risk activities, such as hot air ballooning and off-road motorcycles. But he will make full preparations before taking risks and take various measures to reduce risks.</li>
<li><strong>Don&rsquo;t blindly avoid risks:</strong> The author believes that in a changing environment, the biggest risk is not taking risks. In order to obtain higher returns, certain risks must be taken. Blindly avoiding risks may eventually lead to missed opportunities and even failure to achieve financial freedom.</li>
<li><strong>Overcome risks - start small:</strong> For unfamiliar investments, you should start with small investments, gradually accumulate experience, and gradually improve your risk tolerance. Just like scouts, first test the waters with a small amount to understand the situation, and then gradually increase the investment.</li>
<li><strong>There is no high-return, zero-risk investment:</strong> The author reminds readers that all high-yield investments are accompanied by high risks and not to believe in the so-called &ldquo;high-yield, risk-free&rdquo; investment scams. If someone recommends such an investment opportunity to you, it is likely that they are trying to deceive you.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Investment Iron Law 6: Solve the Crisis of Being Trapped 
    <div id="investment-iron-law-6-solve-the-crisis-of-being-trapped" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#investment-iron-law-6-solve-the-crisis-of-being-trapped" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Diversify your investments and hold them for the long term:</strong> The author proposes the investment strategy of &ldquo;diversification and long-term holding&rdquo; and believes that this is the key to avoiding being trapped and obtaining long-term stable returns. Diversified investment can reduce the risk of choosing the wrong investment target; diversifying investment timing can reduce the risk of buying at market highs; long-term holding can reduce the risk brought by short-term market fluctuations and fully enjoy the benefits brought by compound interest.</li>
<li><strong>Principle of risk diversification:</strong> The principle of diversified investment is to reduce the overall risk of the investment portfolio by increasing the types of investments so that the rise and fall of different assets in the investment portfolio can offset each other. The author points out that diversification is not the more the better and that management costs need to be considered. Too many investment types will increase management difficulty and cost, which is not conducive to improving profits.</li>
<li><strong>Diversify investment timing:</strong> In order to reduce the risk of buying at market highs, the author suggests spreading the funds over different periods. He proposes two methods: one is &ldquo;invest if you have money,&rdquo; and the other is &ldquo;regularly invest a fixed amount in mutual funds.&rdquo; &ldquo;Invest if you have money&rdquo; means that once you have idle funds, invest immediately and do not try to predict market timing; &ldquo;regular investment of a fixed amount in mutual funds&rdquo; means investing a fixed amount every month to buy mutual funds. This method can effectively smooth market fluctuations and reduce investment risks.</li>
<li><strong>Methods of diversified investment:</strong> The author introduces three methods of diversified investment in detail: 1. Diversification of investment tools, such as stocks, real estate, gold, art, etc.; 2. Diversification of investment targets, for example, when investing in stocks, do not just buy one stock, but buy multiple stocks in different industries; 3. Diversification of investment regions, for example, invest some assets in overseas markets to diversify regional risks.</li>
<li><strong>Reduce the risk of choosing the wrong selling time - long-term holding:</strong> Through research on the Taiwan stock market, the author found that the longer the holding time, the lower the probability of loss. For example, the probability of loss when holding stocks for more than 5 years is only 1%, and it is almost impossible to lose money when holding for more than 10 years. This once again proves the importance of long-term holding.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Investment Iron Law 7: Make Good Use of Stock Investment 
    <div id="investment-iron-law-7-make-good-use-of-stock-investment" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#investment-iron-law-7-make-good-use-of-stock-investment" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Liu Qiude&rsquo;s secret to wealth:</strong> The author uses the financial story of Liu Qiude, Vice President of Cathay Life Insurance, as an example to illustrate the power of long-term holding of high-quality stocks. Liu Qiude worked at Cathay Life Insurance from his twenties. He held his savings and the Cathay Life Insurance shares he acquired from his colleagues for a long time and eventually became a billionaire. This example also reflects the long-term and stable performance growth of Cathay Life Insurance from the side.</li>
<li><strong>Why stocks have high returns:</strong> The author explains the source of returns from stock investment: stocks represent ownership of a company, and shareholders can share in the company&rsquo;s profits and asset appreciation. Therefore, the returns from investing in stocks come from corporate earnings and asset appreciation, not from the losses of other investors. He pointed out that the long-term rise in stock prices is mainly due to the improvement of corporate profitability and the growth of asset value.</li>
<li><strong>Carefully select the types of stocks to invest in:</strong> The author compares the characteristics of listed stocks, over-the-counter stocks, unlisted stocks, and mutual funds and suggests that ordinary investors should give priority to investing in listed stocks or mutual funds. Listed stocks have good liquidity, transparent information disclosure, and relatively strict supervision, so the risks are relatively low. Mutual funds are managed by professionals and can effectively diversify investment risks, making them suitable for investors who do not have much time and energy to research stocks.</li>
<li><strong>Stock investment is better than real estate investment:</strong> The author compares stock and real estate investment from the aspects of investment threshold, taxation, and trading convenience. He believes that stock investment has a lower threshold, lighter taxes, and is more convenient to trade, making it more suitable for ordinary investors.</li>
<li><strong>Can stocks still maintain high returns in the future?:</strong> The author analyzes and forecasts the future return rate of the Taiwan stock market. He believes that although Taiwan&rsquo;s economic growth has slowed down, it is still higher than other countries and regions, so the Taiwan stock market still has high investment value in the future, but the return rate may be slightly lower than in the past.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Investment Iron Law 8: Make Money When You Buy and Sell 
    <div id="investment-iron-law-8-make-money-when-you-buy-and-sell" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#investment-iron-law-8-make-money-when-you-buy-and-sell" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Buy casually, buy at any time, don&rsquo;t sell:</strong> The author once again emphasizes the investment strategy of &ldquo;buy casually, buy at any time, don&rsquo;t sell&rdquo; and points out that this is the highest level of financial management. This strategy seems simple, but it actually contains profound investment wisdom: it emphasizes long-term holding, infrequent trading, and avoiding being affected by short-term market fluctuations, thereby obtaining long-term and stable returns. The author admits that most people find it difficult to do this because they cannot overcome human weaknesses such as greed and fear.</li>
<li><strong>What to buy - buy casually:</strong> The author points out that as long as diversified investment is achieved, the selection of individual stocks is not important. He uses the experiment of &ldquo;monkeys throwing darts to select stocks&rdquo; and his own experience of selecting stocks with his children as examples to illustrate the effectiveness of &ldquo;buying casually&rdquo;.</li>
<li><strong>When to buy - buy at any time:</strong> The author suggests that investors &ldquo;buy if they have money&rdquo;, and do not try to predict market timing. He emphasizes &ldquo;buying and waiting for a chance to rise&rdquo; instead of &ldquo;waiting for a chance to buy&rdquo;. Because the market is difficult to predict, and time is the key factor in compound interest, the earlier you start investing, the more you can enjoy the benefits brought by compound interest.</li>
<li><strong>When to sell - don&rsquo;t sell:</strong> The author believes that long-term holding is the key to obtaining high returns. He quotes Jesse Livermore, the author of Reminiscences of a Stock Operator, and the investment strategy of Taiwan&rsquo;s richest man, Cai Wanlin, to illustrate the importance of long-term holding.</li>
<li><strong>Random walk and efficient market theory:</strong> The author introduces the &ldquo;random walk hypothesis&rdquo; and the &ldquo;efficient market hypothesis&rdquo; to provide a theoretical basis for the strategy of &ldquo;buy casually, buy at any time, don&rsquo;t sell&rdquo;. The &ldquo;random walk hypothesis&rdquo; believes that short-term fluctuations in stock prices are random and difficult to predict; the &ldquo;efficient market hypothesis&rdquo; believes that all information in the market is already reflected in stock prices, so it is futile to predict market trends by analyzing information.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Investment Iron Law 9: Grasp the General Trend of the Stock Market 
    <div id="investment-iron-law-9-grasp-the-general-trend-of-the-stock-market" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#investment-iron-law-9-grasp-the-general-trend-of-the-stock-market" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Blind spots in prediction and analysis:</strong> The author once again emphasizes the limitations of prediction and analysis. He points out that technical analysis and market forecasting cannot guarantee investment success, and may even lead to losses due to frequent trading. Technical analysis is based on historical data, but the market environment is constantly changing, and past performance does not represent future trends.</li>
<li><strong>The only thing that can be measured is the unmeasurable:</strong> Market trends are difficult to predict. Instead of trying to predict the market, it is better to formulate a reasonable investment strategy and hold it for a long time. The author illustrates the unreliability of prediction with an example of a failed stock market prophet.</li>
<li><strong>Believe in yourself rather than experts:</strong> The author advises investors not to over-rely on expert opinions and to cultivate their own financial management capabilities and independent judgment. He pointed out that expert opinions often contradict each other, and ten experts may have eleven opinions. Besides, experts may also be influenced by various factors, such as conflicts of interest, and thus give biased opinions.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Investment Iron Law 10: Make Good Use of Stock Market Offensive and Defensive Weapons 
    <div id="investment-iron-law-10-make-good-use-of-stock-market-offensive-and-defensive-weapons" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#investment-iron-law-10-make-good-use-of-stock-market-offensive-and-defensive-weapons" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Value strategy:</strong> The core of value strategy is &ldquo;buy when the value is higher than the price, and sell when the value is lower than the price&rdquo;. The author uses the huge difference in the share price of China Development Financial at different times as an example to illustrate the impact of market sentiment on stock prices and the performance of investors&rsquo; irrational behavior. He advises investors to learn rational consumption behavior and buy stocks when the &ldquo;price is discounted&rdquo;. He also points out that the key to value investing is being able to accurately assess the intrinsic value of a company, which requires certain professional knowledge and experience.</li>
<li><strong>Growth strategy:</strong> The core of the growth strategy is to invest in companies with high growth potential in the future and hold them for the long term. The author uses Peter Lynch&rsquo;s investment strategy and the investment story of the &ldquo;Coca-Cola Grandma&rdquo; as examples to illustrate the effectiveness of the growth strategy. He advises investors to choose companies with high growth potential in the next 5-10 years and focus on choosing the right industry because the growth of the industry will drive the growth of corporate performance.</li>
<li><strong>Contrarian strategy:</strong> The core of the contrarian strategy is &ldquo;invest when most people are not investing, and sell when most people are eager to invest&rdquo;. The author uses the business philosophy of Fan Li and the investment strategy of Zheng Zhoumin as examples to illustrate the principle of contrarian operation. He pointed out that market sentiment is often wrong. When the market is excessively pessimistic, it is often a good time to buy; when the market is excessively optimistic, it is often a good time to sell. However, contrarian operation is very difficult, and it requires investors to have independent thinking ability and strong psychological quality.</li>
<li><strong>Value, growth, and contrarian strategies are suitable for experts:</strong> The author summarizes the characteristics of the three strategies and points out that these strategies are more suitable for professional investors. For ordinary investors, the strategy of &ldquo;buy casually, buy at any time, don&rsquo;t sell&rdquo; is simpler and easier to implement, and it is also easier to obtain long-term and stable returns.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Investment Iron Law 11: Don&rsquo;t Do Short-Term Operations 
    <div id="investment-iron-law-11-dont-do-short-term-operations" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#investment-iron-law-11-dont-do-short-term-operations" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Buy low and sell high is full of crises:</strong> The author pointed out that &ldquo;buying low and selling high&rdquo; seems to be the secret to making money from stock investment, but it is actually full of traps. Because no one can accurately predict the short-term fluctuations of the market, trying to make profits through &ldquo;buying low and selling high&rdquo; will often fall into the dilemma of chasing ups and downs, which will eventually lead to losses. He emphasizes that the main source of stock investment income is corporate profits and dividends, not the difference in buying and selling prices.</li>
<li><strong>Short-term operation is gambling:</strong> The author believes that the essence of short-term operation is speculation and gambling, and it is difficult to make a profit in the long run. Because short-term operations require frequent trading, and each transaction will generate transaction costs, such as commissions, stamp duty, etc. These transaction costs will eat away at investment income, and accumulate over time, will have a significant negative impact on investment returns.</li>
<li><strong>A game with no chance of winning:</strong> The author analyzes the composition of the stock market, including intermediaries (securities companies, governments, etc.), major shareholders, major players, and retail investors. He pointed out that retail investors are at a clear disadvantage in this game of short-term operations because they lack the advantages of capital, information, and resources. Therefore, retail investors should avoid participating in short-term operations and adopt a long-term investment strategy.</li>
<li><strong>Never participate in futures and margin trading:</strong> The author strongly recommends that investors not participate in futures and margin trading because these transactions are extremely risky, and the leverage effect will magnify both profits and losses. It is difficult for ordinary investors to control the risks. He uses the example of the Barings Bank collapse to illustrate the huge risks of futures and margin trading.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Investment Iron Law 12:  Land is Wealth 
    <div id="investment-iron-law-12--land-is-wealth" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#investment-iron-law-12--land-is-wealth" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Why real estate has high returns:</strong> The author analyzes the reasons for the high returns of real estate investment, mainly including three aspects: 1. Limited land supply; 2. As the economy grows and the population grows, the demand for real estate continues to increase; 3. Inflation will push up real estate prices.</li>
<li><strong>Hong Kong&rsquo;s richest man, Lee Shau Kee&rsquo;s real estate investment strategy:</strong> The author introduces the real estate investment strategy of Hong Kong&rsquo;s richest man, Lee Shau Kee: acquire old buildings at low prices, then demolish and rebuild them, or hold land for a long time and wait for appreciation.</li>
<li><strong>Cai Wanlin&rsquo;s secret to getting rich in real estate:</strong> The author uses Taiwan&rsquo;s richest man, Cai Wanlin, as an example to illustrate the real estate investment strategy of &ldquo;buy and hold for the long term.&rdquo; Cai Wanlin&rsquo;s secret is to buy real estate and hold it for a long time, only renting and not selling.</li>
<li><strong>Zheng Zhoumin&rsquo;s real estate investment technique:</strong> The author introduces the real estate investment strategy of the Philippines&rsquo; richest man, Zheng Zhoumin: buy when the market is down, and hold it for a long time, waiting for the market to recover and prices to rise.</li>
<li><strong>Real estate is suitable for debt investment:</strong> The author believes that real estate investment is suitable for debt investment because the long-term investment return rate of real estate is usually higher than the loan interest rate. Through reasonable debt investment, financial leverage can be used to magnify returns. At the same time, he also reminds readers to live within their means and avoid the risks brought by excessive debt.</li>
<li><strong>Brand concept of real estate investment:</strong> The author emphasizes the importance of choosing real estate developers with good brands, guaranteed quality, and good after-sales service. He pointed out that buying a property is a major investment decision, and choosing a reputable developer can reduce investment risks and enhance the living experience.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Investment Iron Law 13: Act Now 
    <div id="investment-iron-law-13-act-now" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#investment-iron-law-13-act-now" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>It is better to act than to sit and study:</strong> The author once again emphasizes the importance of action. He believes that having knowledge without taking action is equivalent to not having knowledge. The key to financial management is action, not fantasy. He uses the story of a farmer who does not understand stocks but dares to buy and eventually make a profit as an example to illustrate the importance of action.</li>
<li><strong>Future wealth is in your own hands:</strong> The author points out that future wealth is in your own hands, and only active actions can create wealth. He encourages readers to overcome their fear and bravely take the first step in financial management.</li>
<li><strong>Financial experience - learn from mistakes:</strong> The author believes that failure is the mother of success, and you must dare to try and learn from your mistakes. He advises readers to start with small investments, gradually accumulate experience, and gradually improve their risk tolerance.</li>
<li><strong>The first step in learning financial management:</strong> The author suggests that readers start acting immediately after reading this book. They can start by investing a small amount in stocks or mutual funds, or they can buy a self-occupied property. He believes that the best way to learn financial management is to practice, accumulate experience in practice, and continue to learn and improve.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">The Ultimate Chapter of Financial Management: Making Money Requires a Goal 
    <div id="the-ultimate-chapter-of-financial-management-making-money-requires-a-goal" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#the-ultimate-chapter-of-financial-management-making-money-requires-a-goal" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Don&rsquo;t be a miser:</strong> The author uses the story of a miser to illustrate that money is only a means, and improving the quality of life is the goal. He warns readers not to become slaves to money, to learn to enjoy life, and to use wealth for more meaningful things.</li>
<li><strong>What is the purpose of making so much money?:</strong> The author explores the meaning and values of money. He pointed out that money itself is not good or bad, the key is how to use it. Money can be used to improve lives, pursue dreams, help others, and give back to society. He encourages readers to establish correct values about money, not to blindly pursue wealth, and ignore other aspects of life.</li>
<li><strong>Three secrets of financial management - making money, managing money, and using money:</strong> The author proposes three levels of financial management: making money, managing money, and using money. He believes that making money is the foundation, managing money is the key, and using money is the purpose. These three levels are indispensable, and only by combining the three can you truly achieve financial freedom and live a happy life. He pointed out that how to use money is the most difficult because it involves personal values and life goals.</li>
<li><strong>American billionaire - Warren Buffett&rsquo;s view of money:</strong> The author introduces Warren Buffett&rsquo;s view of money and estate planning. Although Buffett is extremely wealthy, he lives a simple life and donates most of his estate to charity. He believes that happiness is a process, not a result. True happiness lies in constant pursuit and creation, not in how much wealth you have.</li>
<li><strong>Summary:</strong> The author summarizes the core viewpoints of the book: Everyone can achieve wealth through financial management. The key lies in having the correct concept of financial management, long-term investment, and positive actions. He encourages readers to set clear financial goals and formulate feasible financial plans based on their actual situations. He emphasizes that the ultimate goal of financial management is not to have unlimited wealth, but to achieve financial freedom, improve the quality of life, and ultimately realize the value of life.</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">III.  Key Quotes 
    <div id="iii--key-quotes" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii--key-quotes" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>Don&rsquo;t keep your money in the bank.</p></blockquote>
<p>Analysis: This doesn&rsquo;t literally mean not keeping any money in the bank, but emphasizes not leaving most assets in low-yield bank deposits long-term.  Invest in higher-yielding tools like stocks and real estate.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Building wealth requires patience.</p></blockquote>
<p>Analysis: The compound interest effect takes time. Financial management is a marathon, not a sprint, requiring patient waiting for ultimate success.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The earlier you invest, the better.</p></blockquote>
<p>Analysis: Youth is the greatest asset. The earlier you start managing your finances, the sooner you can enjoy the benefits of compound interest and achieve financial freedom.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Make money with other people&rsquo;s money.</p></blockquote>
<p>Analysis:  Proper use of financial leverage can magnify investment returns and accelerate wealth accumulation.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Diversify investments and hold long-term.</p></blockquote>
<p>Analysis: Diversification reduces risk. Long-term holding yields higher returns and avoids being affected by market fluctuations.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Buy casually, buy anytime, don&rsquo;t sell.</p></blockquote>
<p>Analysis:  The core of this is long-term holding and avoiding frequent trading to prevent being impacted by short-term market fluctuations.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Knowing and not doing is the same as not knowing.</p></blockquote>
<p>Analysis: Knowledge without action is equivalent to no knowledge. The key to financial management lies in action, not just thinking.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Wealth lies in land.</p></blockquote>
<p>Analysis: Real estate is a crucial long-term value-preserving and appreciating investment tool that should hold a significant place in your portfolio.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Money is only a means, improving the quality of life is the goal.</p></blockquote>
<p>Analysis: Money itself is meaningless; its value lies in how it&rsquo;s used. The ultimate goal is to improve the quality of life and realize one&rsquo;s life value.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">IV.  Guidance and Significance 
    <div id="iv--guidance-and-significance" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv--guidance-and-significance" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This book&rsquo;s significance lies in helping readers establish a correct financial management mindset, master basic financial management methods, and ultimately achieve financial freedom.  It emphasizes the importance of long-term investment, the compound effect, and risk management, encouraging readers to overcome their fear of risk and start managing their finances early, without being misled by short-term market fluctuations. By studying this book, readers can better plan their financial future, enhance their quality of life, and ultimately achieve financial freedom and realize their life value.</p>
<hr>


<h2 class="relative group">Read the Full Book 
    <div id="read-the-full-book" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#read-the-full-book" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>

<section class="space-y-10 w-full">
    
    
        
            






















  <a class="flex flex-wrap article " href="/en/posts/1731056005958/">
    
        
        <div class="w-full md:w-auto h-full thumbnail nozoom thumbnailshadow md:mr-7" style="background-image:url(/posts/1731056005958/featured_hu_a65a55d073c07bc4.png);"></div>
        
      <div class=" mt-3 md:mt-0">
      <div class="items-center text-left text-xl font-semibold">
        
        <div class="font-bold text-xl text-neutral-800 decoration-primary-500 hover:underline hover:underline-offset-2 dark:text-neutral"
          href="/en/posts/1731056005958/">Personal Investment Bible: Preface</div>
        
        
        
      </div>
      <div class="text-sm text-neutral-500 dark:text-neutral-400">
        











  



















<div class="flex flex-row flex-wrap items-center">
  
  
  <time datetime="2024-11-08T00:00:00&#43;00:00">8 November 2024</time>
  

  
  
</div>





<div class="flex flex-row flex-wrap items-center">
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  <span style="margin-top:0.5rem" class="mr-2" onclick="window.open(&#34;/en/tags/personal-investment-bible/&#34;,'_self');">
    <span class="flex" style="cursor: pointer;">
  <span class="rounded-md border border-primary-400 px-1 py-[1px] text-xs font-normal text-primary-700 dark:border-primary-600 dark:text-primary-400">
    Personal Investment Bible
  </span>
</span>
  </span>
  
  <span style="margin-top:0.5rem" class="mr-2" onclick="window.open(&#34;/en/tags/book/&#34;,'_self');">
    <span class="flex" style="cursor: pointer;">
  <span class="rounded-md border border-primary-400 px-1 py-[1px] text-xs font-normal text-primary-700 dark:border-primary-600 dark:text-primary-400">
    Book
  </span>
</span>
  </span>
  
  <span style="margin-top:0.5rem" class="mr-2" onclick="window.open(&#34;/en/tags/wealth-management/&#34;,'_self');">
    <span class="flex" style="cursor: pointer;">
  <span class="rounded-md border border-primary-400 px-1 py-[1px] text-xs font-normal text-primary-700 dark:border-primary-600 dark:text-primary-400">
    Wealth Management
  </span>
</span>
  </span>
  
  <span style="margin-top:0.5rem" class="mr-2" onclick="window.open(&#34;/en/tags/investment/&#34;,'_self');">
    <span class="flex" style="cursor: pointer;">
  <span class="rounded-md border border-primary-400 px-1 py-[1px] text-xs font-normal text-primary-700 dark:border-primary-600 dark:text-primary-400">
    Investment
  </span>
</span>
  </span>
  
  <span style="margin-top:0.5rem" class="mr-2" onclick="window.open(&#34;/en/tags/wealth-creation/&#34;,'_self');">
    <span class="flex" style="cursor: pointer;">
  <span class="rounded-md border border-primary-400 px-1 py-[1px] text-xs font-normal text-primary-700 dark:border-primary-600 dark:text-primary-400">
    Wealth Creation
  </span>
</span>
  </span>
  
  <span style="margin-top:0.5rem" class="mr-2" onclick="window.open(&#34;/en/tags/financial-freedom/&#34;,'_self');">
    <span class="flex" style="cursor: pointer;">
  <span class="rounded-md border border-primary-400 px-1 py-[1px] text-xs font-normal text-primary-700 dark:border-primary-600 dark:text-primary-400">
    Financial Freedom
  </span>
</span>
  </span>
  
  <span style="margin-top:0.5rem" class="mr-2" onclick="window.open(&#34;/en/tags/stocks/&#34;,'_self');">
    <span class="flex" style="cursor: pointer;">
  <span class="rounded-md border border-primary-400 px-1 py-[1px] text-xs font-normal text-primary-700 dark:border-primary-600 dark:text-primary-400">
    Stocks
  </span>
</span>
  </span>
  
  <span style="margin-top:0.5rem" class="mr-2" onclick="window.open(&#34;/en/tags/real-estate/&#34;,'_self');">
    <span class="flex" style="cursor: pointer;">
  <span class="rounded-md border border-primary-400 px-1 py-[1px] text-xs font-normal text-primary-700 dark:border-primary-600 dark:text-primary-400">
    Real Estate
  </span>
</span>
  </span>
  
  <span style="margin-top:0.5rem" class="mr-2" onclick="window.open(&#34;/en/tags/financial-education/&#34;,'_self');">
    <span class="flex" style="cursor: pointer;">
  <span class="rounded-md border border-primary-400 px-1 py-[1px] text-xs font-normal text-primary-700 dark:border-primary-600 dark:text-primary-400">
    Financial Education
  </span>
</span>
  </span>
  
  <span style="margin-top:0.5rem" class="mr-2" onclick="window.open(&#34;/en/tags/long-term-investment/&#34;,'_self');">
    <span class="flex" style="cursor: pointer;">
  <span class="rounded-md border border-primary-400 px-1 py-[1px] text-xs font-normal text-primary-700 dark:border-primary-600 dark:text-primary-400">
    Long-Term Investment
  </span>
</span>
  </span>
  
  
  
  
</div>




      </div>
      
    </div>
  </a>

        
    
</section>
<hr>

<section class="space-y-10 w-full">
    
    
        
            






















  <a class="flex flex-wrap article " href="/en/posts/1728295490690-book-list/">
    
        
        <div class="w-full md:w-auto h-full thumbnail nozoom thumbnailshadow md:mr-7" style="background-image:url(/posts/1728295490690-book-list/featured_hu_a14921d8ab66af4e.jpg);"></div>
        
      <div class=" mt-3 md:mt-0">
      <div class="items-center text-left text-xl font-semibold">
        
        <div class="font-bold text-xl text-neutral-800 decoration-primary-500 hover:underline hover:underline-offset-2 dark:text-neutral"
          href="/en/posts/1728295490690-book-list/">Recommended Reading List</div>
        
        
        
      </div>
      <div class="text-sm text-neutral-500 dark:text-neutral-400">
        











  



















<div class="flex flex-row flex-wrap items-center">
  
  
  <time datetime="2024-10-01T00:00:00&#43;00:00">1 October 2024</time>
  

  
  
</div>





<div class="flex flex-row flex-wrap items-center">
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  <span style="margin-top:0.5rem" class="mr-2" onclick="window.open(&#34;/en/tags/recommended/&#34;,'_self');">
    <span class="flex" style="cursor: pointer;">
  <span class="rounded-md border border-primary-400 px-1 py-[1px] text-xs font-normal text-primary-700 dark:border-primary-600 dark:text-primary-400">
    Recommended
  </span>
</span>
  </span>
  
  <span style="margin-top:0.5rem" class="mr-2" onclick="window.open(&#34;/en/tags/book/&#34;,'_self');">
    <span class="flex" style="cursor: pointer;">
  <span class="rounded-md border border-primary-400 px-1 py-[1px] text-xs font-normal text-primary-700 dark:border-primary-600 dark:text-primary-400">
    Book
  </span>
</span>
  </span>
  
  
  
  
</div>




      </div>
      
    </div>
  </a>

        
    
</section>
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>The Intelligent Investor: Book Notes</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1730598742194/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1730598742194/</guid><description>This book provides guidance on investment strategies for laymen, explores the difference between investing and speculation, different strategies for defensive and enterprising investors and the relationship between investors and investment advisors, highlighting the concept of &amp;#39;margin of safety&amp;#39; as the core of investment.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[

<h2 class="relative group">I. Summary 
    <div id="i-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>&ldquo;The Intelligent Investor&rdquo; is a seminal work in the field of investment, authored by Benjamin Graham, widely regarded as the &ldquo;father of value investing&rdquo;. The book aims to provide guidance on investment strategies for the layman, with the following core ideas:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Rational Investment:</strong> Investment decisions should be based on thorough analysis of a security&rsquo;s value, not on market sentiment or speculative behavior.</li>
<li><strong>Margin of Safety:</strong> The core of investing is the margin of safety, which means buying securities at a price significantly below their intrinsic value, thus reducing risk and enhancing potential returns.</li>
<li><strong>Defensive and Enterprising Investors:</strong> Based on risk tolerance and investment objectives, investors are classified as either defensive or enterprising, each employing different investment strategies.</li>
<li><strong>Investors and the Market:</strong> Investors should view market fluctuations rationally, seeing them as opportunities rather than sources of risk.</li>
<li><strong>Company Owner Mentality:</strong> Investors should adopt the mindset of a company owner, paying attention to corporate management and governance and safeguarding their own interests.</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">II. Chapter Summaries 
    <div id="ii-chapter-summaries" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii-chapter-summaries" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Chapter 1: What Intelligent Investors Get 
    <div id="chapter-1-what-intelligent-investors-get" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chapter-1-what-intelligent-investors-get" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>This chapter introduces fundamental concepts of investing, including:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Investing vs. Speculation:</strong>  Investing is an operation based on analysis, aiming for safety of principal and a satisfactory return; speculation is hoping for profit from market fluctuations and carries higher risk.</li>
<li><strong>Defensive Investors:</strong> Seeking safety and steady returns, they can adopt a simple portfolio strategy, allocating funds between high-grade bonds and a diversified selection of leading common stocks.</li>
<li><strong>Enterprising Investors:</strong>  Willing to take on more risk for greater returns, they can employ more aggressive strategies, such as selecting growth stocks and seeking undervalued securities.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chapter 2: The Investor and Market Fluctuations 
    <div id="chapter-2-the-investor-and-market-fluctuations" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chapter-2-the-investor-and-market-fluctuations" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>This chapter explores how investors should view market fluctuations:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Price Fluctuations as a Measure of Investment Success:</strong>  In the long run, investment success depends on the long-term returns of the portfolio, not short-term price movements.</li>
<li><strong>Market Fluctuations as a Guide for Investment Decisions:</strong> Investors can capitalize on market volatility to create opportunities for buying low and selling high, but should avoid excessive focus on short-term market trends.</li>
<li><strong>Market Fluctuations of Individual Stocks:</strong> Focusing on undervalued individual stocks is more meaningful than attempting to predict overall market movements.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chapter 3: A Review of the 1964 Market 
    <div id="chapter-3-a-review-of-the-1964-market" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chapter-3-a-review-of-the-1964-market" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>This chapter analyzes the stock market conditions at the time of writing (1964):</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Comparison with Previous Years:</strong>  The stock market was at a historical high, rendering traditional valuation methods no longer applicable.</li>
<li><strong>New Standards for a &ldquo;New Era&rdquo;:</strong> New valuation methods had not yet been tested by time, and the market was characterized by a high degree of uncertainty.</li>
<li><strong>Investment Strategy Recommendation:</strong>  Adopt a cautious investment strategy and avoid excessive risk-taking.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chapter 4: The Investor and His Advisers 
    <div id="chapter-4-the-investor-and-his-advisers" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chapter-4-the-investor-and-his-advisers" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>This chapter discusses the relationship between investors and their advisors:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sources of Investment Advice:</strong>  Investors can obtain investment guidance from various avenues, including family and friends, banks, brokerage firms, and professional investment advisors.</li>
<li><strong>Selecting Investment Advisors:</strong> Choosing the right advisor is crucial, requiring careful assessment of their expertise, experience, and ethical standards.</li>
<li><strong>Independent Thinking:</strong>  Even when seeking professional advice, investors should maintain their own independent judgment and be responsible for their investment decisions.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chapter 5: The Defensive Investor&rsquo;s Portfolio Policy 
    <div id="chapter-5-the-defensive-investors-portfolio-policy" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chapter-5-the-defensive-investors-portfolio-policy" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>This chapter details the strategies for defensive investors:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Bond and Stock Allocation:</strong> Allocate funds between high-grade bonds and a diversified selection of leading common stocks. The ratio can be adjusted based on market conditions, but generally maintain a 50:50 split.</li>
<li><strong>Bond Portfolio Composition:</strong>  Introduces characteristics of different types of bonds, such as US Savings Bonds, state and municipal bonds, and corporate bonds.</li>
<li><strong>Principles for Common Stock Selection:</strong> Choose large, prominent, and conservatively financed companies with a long history of dividend payments, and purchase them at reasonable price-earnings ratios.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chapter 6: Portfolio Policy for the Enterprising Investor: Negative Approach 
    <div id="chapter-6-portfolio-policy-for-the-enterprising-investor-negative-approach" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chapter-6-portfolio-policy-for-the-enterprising-investor-negative-approach" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>This chapter presents a &ldquo;negative list&rdquo; of what enterprising investors should avoid:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Second-Grade Bonds and Preferred Stocks:</strong> Avoid buying securities lacking sufficient safety merely for the allure of high yields.</li>
<li><strong>Foreign Government Bonds:</strong>  Higher risk and difficulty in enforcing claims in case of default.</li>
<li><strong>New Issues:</strong> Require careful evaluation and avoidance of excessive hype surrounding them.</li>
<li><strong>Convertible Issues:</strong> Their advantages often come at the expense of quality or income, and they present investors with decision-making dilemmas.</li>
<li><strong>New-Issue Mania</strong>: During bull markets, many smaller companies go public, and their stock pricing is often unattractive or even excessive. Investors should be wary of the hype surrounding new issues and avoid blindly following the crowd.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chapter 7: Portfolio Policy for the Enterprising Investor: The Positive Side 
    <div id="chapter-7-portfolio-policy-for-the-enterprising-investor-the-positive-side" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chapter-7-portfolio-policy-for-the-enterprising-investor-the-positive-side" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>This chapter discusses positive strategies enterprising investors can employ:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Market Timing Limitations:</strong>  While the strategy of buying low in depressed markets and selling high in booming markets could be profitable in the past, recent market dynamics have made this approach less viable.</li>
<li><strong>Considerations for Growth Stocks:</strong> Selecting growth stocks requires diligent assessment of future growth potential, avoiding overpaying for lofty expectations.</li>
<li><strong>Three Recommended Areas for Enterprising Investment</strong>:
<ol>
<li><strong>Investing in Large Companies during Unpopular Periods:</strong> When large companies are experiencing unpopular periods, their stock prices may be undervalued, presenting opportunities for investors.</li>
<li><strong>Bargain Issues:</strong> Seek securities whose intrinsic value is demonstrably understated and buy them at prices significantly below this value.</li>
<li><strong>Special Situations:</strong>  Focus on events like mergers, reorganizations, and liquidations where the price fluctuations can offer substantial profit opportunities.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li><strong>Broad Application of Investment Rules:</strong>  Enterprising investors should approach investing as a business endeavor, adhering to sound business principles, such as knowing their investment domain, choosing partners carefully, and managing risk.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chapter 8: Security Analysis for the Lay Investor: General Approach 
    <div id="chapter-8-security-analysis-for-the-lay-investor-general-approach" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chapter-8-security-analysis-for-the-lay-investor-general-approach" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>This chapter introduces basic methods of security analysis for non-professional investors:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Bond Analysis</strong>:
<ul>
<li>Focus on the ratio of earnings to interest expenses, ensuring it meets certain standards (4x for utilities, 5x for railroads, 7x for industrials).</li>
<li>Consider factors like company size, equity ratio, and asset value.</li>
<li>Understand the risk characteristics of different bond types, like the relatively higher risk of railroad bonds compared to the safer utility company bonds.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Common Stock Analysis</strong>:
<ul>
<li>Analyze company profitability, including projected future earnings, sales margins, and return on net worth.</li>
<li>Assess capitalization rates, considering factors like long-term prospects, management quality, financial condition, and dividend record.</li>
<li>Pay attention to the impact of non-recurring gains and losses, making adjustments to earnings data.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Industrial Stock Analysis:</strong> Focus on industry trends and individual companies&rsquo; competitive positions within their respective sectors.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chapter 9: Stock Selection for the Defensive Investor 
    <div id="chapter-9-stock-selection-for-the-defensive-investor" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chapter-9-stock-selection-for-the-defensive-investor" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>Using Dow Jones Industrial Average stocks as an example, this chapter explains how defensive investors can select securities:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Choose a Representative Sample:</strong>  For instance, buy equal amounts of all 30 Dow Jones industrial stocks.</li>
<li><strong>Exclude Stocks with Excessive Price-Earnings Ratios:</strong> Avoid overpaying for speculative growth.</li>
<li><strong>Select Relatively Unpopular Stocks with Reasonable Valuations:</strong>  Capitalize on the market&rsquo;s neglect of certain stocks, finding undervalued investment opportunities.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chapter 10: Stock Selection for the Enterprising Investor: General Approach 
    <div id="chapter-10-stock-selection-for-the-enterprising-investor-general-approach" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chapter-10-stock-selection-for-the-enterprising-investor-general-approach" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>This chapter introduces methods for enterprising investors to select securities:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>The Valuation Approach:</strong>  Estimate a company&rsquo;s future earnings and select a suitable multiplier to determine its intrinsic value.</li>
<li><strong>Factors Affecting Asset Value:</strong> Pay attention to net tangible asset value, especially net current asset value. Add half the excess of net current asset value over earnings power value to the earnings power value for a more comprehensive assessment.</li>
<li><strong>Growth Stock Valuation:</strong> Consider the expected growth rate, but be cautious in assessing its reasonableness. The author provides a simplified formula for growth stock valuation: Value = Current (normal) earnings x (8.5 + 2 x expected annual growth rate).</li>
<li><strong>First-Grade vs. Second-Grade Common Stocks:</strong> Enterprising investors can consider buying second-grade common stocks, but only at bargain prices, namely when their price is less than two-thirds of the indicated intrinsic value.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chapter 11: Security Analysis for the Lay Investor: Six Illustrative Cases 
    <div id="chapter-11-security-analysis-for-the-lay-investor-six-illustrative-cases" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chapter-11-security-analysis-for-the-lay-investor-six-illustrative-cases" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>This chapter uses six real-world cases to illustrate how to apply security analysis techniques to uncover undervalued investment opportunities:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Case 1:  Northern Pacific Railroad common stock (1947):</strong>  The company&rsquo;s stock price was undervalued due to a combination of a low dividend payout and the non-inclusion of certain earnings in its income statement.</li>
<li><strong>Case 2:  Standard Gas and Electric (SP&amp;L) $7 preferred (1947):</strong> Analyzed the complex capital structure of SP&amp;L, pointing out the undervaluation of its preferred stock.</li>
<li><strong>Case 3:  American-Hawaiian Steamship (AHS) (1947):</strong> The company held substantial cash assets that were not reflected in its market price.</li>
<li><strong>Case 4: Royal Dutch Petroleum (RDP) (1953):</strong>  Pointed out that the market value of RDP was undervalued relative to its earnings power.</li>
<li><strong>Case 5:  Hoover Company Class A (1957):</strong> The company&rsquo;s stock was undervalued because the net worth of its British subsidiary was not fully reflected.</li>
<li><strong>Case 6:  Chicago, Terre Haute &amp; Southeastern Railway (TH) bonds (1964):</strong> Analyzed the value of TH bonds, indicating their undervaluation compared to comparable bonds.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chapter 12: Stock Market Fluctuations: The Pattern of Behavior 
    <div id="chapter-12-stock-market-fluctuations-the-pattern-of-behavior" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chapter-12-stock-market-fluctuations-the-pattern-of-behavior" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>This chapter analyzes the patterns of earnings and price fluctuations for different types of stocks:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Pattern 1:  Relatively Stable Earnings, Wide Price Fluctuations:</strong> Using S.H. Kress as an example, the chapter demonstrates how even with stable earnings, market prices can fluctuate greatly, primarily driven by market sentiment.</li>
<li><strong>Pattern 2:  Earnings Fluctuate Moderately, Stock Prices Fluctuate Widely:</strong> Using General Motors as an example, it illustrates how stock price volatility often exceeds earnings volatility and advises investors to view such fluctuations rationally.</li>
<li><strong>Pattern 3:  Extreme Ups and Downs:</strong>  Taking examples like Brunswick Corporation and St. Louis Southwestern Railway, the chapter highlights the substantial uncertainties in company development and stock price movements. Investors should be wary of companies experiencing extreme volatility.</li>
<li><strong>Pattern 4:  Growth Stocks:</strong> Using examples like 3M and Philip Morris, the chapter shows that even growth stocks face risks, and investors should carefully evaluate their growth potential and avoid overpaying for lofty expectations.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chapter 13: A Comparison of Eight Pairs of Companies 
    <div id="chapter-13-a-comparison-of-eight-pairs-of-companies" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chapter-13-a-comparison-of-eight-pairs-of-companies" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>This chapter uses comparative analysis of various stock portfolios to further investigate factors impacting stock prices:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Four Groups of Randomly Selected Cases and the Dow Jones Industrial Average</strong>:  By contrasting the performance of stocks in different market standings and comparing their initial trading dates, the chapter suggests that choosing large, strong companies often yields more consistent results. New stocks of smaller companies carry higher risk.</li>
<li><strong>Secular Changes in the Quality of a Company Group</strong>:  Taking railroad stocks as an example, the chapter highlights how the standing and investment merit of companies within a group can shift significantly over time.</li>
<li><strong>The Results of a Policy of Quality Improvement:</strong>  Using the Dow Jones Industrial Average as an example, the chapter illustrates that merely replacing underperforming components with more popular ones does not necessarily lead to sustained investment gains. Stock selection should be based on a combination of company quality and price.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chapter 14: Stockholders and Management 
    <div id="chapter-14-stockholders-and-management" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chapter-14-stockholders-and-management" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>This chapter explores the relationship between stockholders and company management:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Management Efficiency:</strong>
<ul>
<li>How to assess Management efficiency: By comparing key indicators like profitability, sales margin, and return on net worth to  industry averages.</li>
<li>How to improve inefficient management: Stockholders can take actions like raising questions at shareholder meetings, hiring independent management consultants for assessment, and electing more independent board members.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>The Board of Directors:</strong>
<ul>
<li>Role in Corporate Governance: The board represents shareholder interests, oversees management, sets company strategy, and reviews and approves significant decisions.</li>
<li>Stockholder Oversight of the Board: Stockholders can exercise their influence by electing board members and voting on proposals at shareholder meetings.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Fair Treatment of the General Stockholder:</strong>
<ul>
<li>Management&rsquo;s responsibility to protect outside stockholder interests: Management should set a fair dividend policy, avoid repurchasing stock at excessively low prices, and prioritize shareholder interests.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Holding Companies:</strong>
<ul>
<li>Disadvantageous position of outside stockholders within holding companies: Holding companies often present conflicts between controlling shareholder interests and those of outside stockholders, leading to potential harm to the latter.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>The Securities and Exchange Commission and Investor Protection:</strong>
<ul>
<li>SEC&rsquo;s functions and limitations: The SEC oversees the securities market and protects investor interests. However, its powers and functions are limited and cannot fully guarantee investor rights.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chapter 15:  &ldquo;Margin of Safety&rdquo; as the Central Concept of Investment 
    <div id="chapter-15--margin-of-safety-as-the-central-concept-of-investment" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chapter-15--margin-of-safety-as-the-central-concept-of-investment" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>This chapter summarizes the core concept of the book - the Margin of Safety:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Definition of Margin of Safety:</strong>  Purchasing securities at a price significantly below their intrinsic value, thereby mitigating risk and enhancing potential returns.</li>
<li><strong>Application in Different Investment Types:</strong> Bonds, common stocks, growth stocks, bargain issues, and other asset classes.</li>
<li><strong>Margin of Safety and Diversification:</strong> Diversification can reduce the overall risk of a portfolio and therefore enhances the margin of safety.</li>
<li><strong>Distinguishing Investment from Speculation:</strong>  The margin of safety is a key criterion for differentiating investment operations from speculative ones. Investment operations should be based on a clear and demonstrably justifiable analysis of value, while speculative operations rely more heavily on subjective judgment and market sentiment.</li>
<li><strong>Generalization of the Investment Concept:</strong> The idea of margin of safety can be applied to broader investment domains, such as when purchasing real estate, art, or other assets.</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">III. Key Quotes 
    <div id="iii-key-quotes" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii-key-quotes" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;In Wall Street, if you&rsquo;re always doing what&rsquo;s obvious or what everyone else is doing, you&rsquo;re not going to make money.&rdquo;</p></blockquote>
<p>Analysis: This emphasizes that to achieve above-average returns, investors require independent thinking and must seek value that is overlooked by the market.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;For rational investment, mental attitude is more important than technique.&rdquo;</p></blockquote>
<p>Analysis:  Investment success necessitates not just skills and tools, but also the right investment philosophy and mindset, including rationality, patience, and discipline.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;Don&rsquo;t buy after a stock has surged and don&rsquo;t sell after it has plummeted.&rdquo;</p></blockquote>
<p>Analysis: Avoid chasing rising prices and panicking during market dips. Focus on rational valuation and don&rsquo;t be swayed by market emotions.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;Have the courage of your knowledge and experience. If you have formed a conclusion from the facts and if you know your judgment is sound, act on it—even though others may hesitate or differ.&rdquo;</p></blockquote>
<p>Analysis: Investment requires independent judgment. Investors need to be confident and courageous in their convictions, even when facing dissenting opinions. Stay true to your well-researched investment principles.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;Many that are first shall be last, and the last shall be first.&rdquo;</p></blockquote>
<p>Analysis:  The business landscape is dynamic. Company strength and investment merit can shift over time, requiring investors to maintain a dynamic outlook and avoid fixed biases.</p>
<blockquote>
<p><em>&ldquo;Margin of Safety&rdquo;</em></p></blockquote>
<p>Analysis:  This succinct phrase encapsulates the core of Graham&rsquo;s approach. Investing should be grounded in acquiring assets at a price that provides a buffer against uncertainty and potential errors in judgment.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">IV. Guiding Significance 
    <div id="iv-guiding-significance" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv-guiding-significance" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<ul>
<li><strong>Establish a Sound Investment Philosophy:</strong>  Investing should be based on value analysis, not on speculation.</li>
<li><strong>Emphasize Margin of Safety:</strong> Purchase securities at prices significantly below their intrinsic value to minimize risk and enhance potential returns.</li>
<li><strong>Choose a Suitable Investment Strategy:</strong> Opt for a strategy—defensive or enterprising—that aligns with your risk tolerance and investment objectives.</li>
<li><strong>View Market Fluctuations Rationally:</strong> Don&rsquo;t be swayed by emotional reactions to market volatility. Instead, view such fluctuations as potential opportunities.</li>
<li><strong>Continuously Learn and Improve Investment Knowledge:</strong> Investing requires ongoing study and practice.</li>
<li><strong>Maintain Patience and Discipline:</strong>  Investment success often requires a long-term perspective, avoiding impulsive reactions to market movements.</li>
</ul>
<hr>

<section class="space-y-10 w-full">
    
    
        
            






















  <a class="flex flex-wrap article " href="/en/posts/1728295490690-book-list/">
    
        
        <div class="w-full md:w-auto h-full thumbnail nozoom thumbnailshadow md:mr-7" style="background-image:url(/posts/1728295490690-book-list/featured_hu_a14921d8ab66af4e.jpg);"></div>
        
      <div class=" mt-3 md:mt-0">
      <div class="items-center text-left text-xl font-semibold">
        
        <div class="font-bold text-xl text-neutral-800 decoration-primary-500 hover:underline hover:underline-offset-2 dark:text-neutral"
          href="/en/posts/1728295490690-book-list/">Recommended Reading List</div>
        
        
        
      </div>
      <div class="text-sm text-neutral-500 dark:text-neutral-400">
        











  



















<div class="flex flex-row flex-wrap items-center">
  
  
  <time datetime="2024-10-01T00:00:00&#43;00:00">1 October 2024</time>
  

  
  
</div>





<div class="flex flex-row flex-wrap items-center">
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  <span style="margin-top:0.5rem" class="mr-2" onclick="window.open(&#34;/en/tags/recommended/&#34;,'_self');">
    <span class="flex" style="cursor: pointer;">
  <span class="rounded-md border border-primary-400 px-1 py-[1px] text-xs font-normal text-primary-700 dark:border-primary-600 dark:text-primary-400">
    Recommended
  </span>
</span>
  </span>
  
  <span style="margin-top:0.5rem" class="mr-2" onclick="window.open(&#34;/en/tags/book/&#34;,'_self');">
    <span class="flex" style="cursor: pointer;">
  <span class="rounded-md border border-primary-400 px-1 py-[1px] text-xs font-normal text-primary-700 dark:border-primary-600 dark:text-primary-400">
    Book
  </span>
</span>
  </span>
  
  
  
  
</div>




      </div>
      
    </div>
  </a>

        
    
</section>
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>The Most Important Thing: Book Notes</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1729341470274/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1729341470274/</guid><description>This book, by renowned investor Howard Marks, summarizes his investment experience, explaining his investment philosophy and analyzing key factors such as market environment, investor psychology, and risk control, aiming to help investors achieve above-market investment performance.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[

<h2 class="relative group">I. Summary 
    <div id="i-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>The core idea of this book is how to achieve investment returns that surpass the market average. The author argues that achieving this goal requires &ldquo;second-level thinking,&rdquo; which is deeper and more comprehensive than the thinking of ordinary investors. He emphasizes contrarian investing, being greedy when others are fearful, and fearful when others are greedy. The book elaborates on important concepts such as market efficiency, value assessment, risk identification and control, cyclical and pendulum awareness, investor psychology, and diversified investment. It also provides a wealth of practical experience and case studies, aiming to help investors establish a sound thinking framework and control the impact of emotions on investment decisions.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">II. Chapter Summaries 
    <div id="ii-chapter-summaries" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii-chapter-summaries" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<ol>
<li>
<p><strong>Second-Level Thinking:</strong> To outperform the market, one must engage in second-level thinking, which requires investors to think more deeply and comprehensively, not being satisfied with simple conclusions, but considering various possibilities, probabilities, market consensus, and their own cognitive biases. For example, first-level thinking might conclude, &ldquo;This is a good company, so I should buy it,&rdquo; while second-level thinking would consider, &ldquo;While it&rsquo;s a good company, has the market already overreacted, pushing the price too high?&rdquo;</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Understanding Market Efficiency and Its Limitations:</strong> Markets are not perfectly efficient; there are opportunities for mispricing. However, due to the large number of investors competing, beating the market remains very difficult. Markets are efficient at incorporating information, but they don&rsquo;t always interpret that information correctly. Investors should focus on relatively inefficient markets, such as those that are less followed, have opaque information, or are controversial.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Value Assessment:</strong> The foundation of value investing is accurate estimation of intrinsic value, which requires considering factors such as a company&rsquo;s financial position, management capabilities, profitability, competitive advantages, and future growth prospects. The author emphasizes that value investing focuses more on present value, while growth investing emphasizes future value, but both require considering the future.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>The Relationship Between Price and Value:</strong> Successful investing is not about &ldquo;buying good things,&rdquo; but about &ldquo;buying things well,&rdquo; which means buying at a price below intrinsic value. Price is influenced by value, psychology, and technical factors. Investors need to understand the relationship between these three to make sound investment decisions. Buying a good company at a high price can still lead to losses, while buying a lower-quality asset at a low price can yield high returns.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Understanding Risk:</strong> Risk is not volatility, but the possibility of permanent loss of capital. It&rsquo;s crucial to understand the various forms of risk, such as failing to meet objectives, underperformance, career risk, and liquidity risk. Risk is subjective and difficult to quantify, depending on the investor&rsquo;s specific circumstances and goals.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Recognizing Risk:</strong> Risk often increases when market optimism is high and prices are inflated. Be wary of the &ldquo;no risk&rdquo; narrative and recognize signs of an overheated market, such as high P/E ratios, narrow credit spreads, and loose credit conditions.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Controlling Risk:</strong> Risk control is more important than taking risks. Control risk through diversification, limiting risk exposure, adhering to a margin of safety, and avoiding excessive leverage. The results of risk control are often invisible because they manifest in losses avoided.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Focusing on Cycles:</strong> Everything is cyclical. Recognize the inevitability of cyclical fluctuations and look for opportunities at cyclical extremes. The author uses the credit cycle as an example to illustrate how cycles are self-correcting and how investors can find opportunities within them.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Pendulum Awareness:</strong> Investor psychology swings like a pendulum between optimism and pessimism, greed and fear. Recognize the patterns of this swing and act contrarianly at extremes. Market extremes often represent turning points and opportunities.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Resisting Negative Influences:</strong> Resist the influence of negative emotions such as greed, fear, herd mentality, envy, and ego on investment decisions. Recognizing the existence of these psychological factors and striving to overcome them is crucial for making rational investment decisions.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Contrarian Investing:</strong> Be greedy when others are fearful, and fearful when others are greedy. Contrarian investing is not simply doing the opposite of the crowd; it requires independent thinking and judgment, as well as a deep understanding of value. Contrarian investing can be lonely and unsettling but is key to achieving superior returns.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Finding Bargains:</strong> Bargains often appear in unpopular and unfavored assets, such as those with apparent flaws, misunderstood by the market, or overlooked.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Waiting Patiently for Opportunities:</strong> Don&rsquo;t chase opportunities; wait patiently for them to come to you. Investors should be like baseball hitters, waiting for the perfect pitch instead of swinging blindly.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Recognizing the Limitations of Forecasting:</strong> Predicting the future is very difficult. Recognize the limitations of forecasting and focus on knowable factors, such as company fundamentals and industry trends.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Understanding Your Position in the Cycle:</strong> Understand your position within the market cycle and adjust your investment strategy accordingly. Investors can assess market conditions by observing investor behavior, the credit environment, and valuation levels.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Appreciating the Role of Luck:</strong> Investment outcomes are influenced by luck. Distinguish between skill and luck, and avoid being blinded by short-term success. Investors should focus on long-term performance and analyze the sources of returns, rather than just focusing on short-term gains.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Diversification:</strong> Diversification is an important risk management tool, but understand correlations and avoid ineffective diversification. True diversification means holding assets that behave differently under different market conditions.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Avoiding Mistakes:</strong> Avoiding major mistakes is more important than pursuing great success. Identify and avoid various types of errors, such as analytical errors, psychological errors, and failure to recognize cycles and market sentiment.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>The Significance of Value Creation:</strong> Value creation requires superior investment skill. Understand alpha and beta, and strive for asymmetric investment performance, meaning achieving higher returns when the market rises and suffering fewer losses when the market falls.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Reasonable Expectations:</strong> Set reasonable return expectations and avoid being misled by unrealistic expectations. Excessively high return expectations are often accompanied by excessive risk. Understand how returns are generated and the conditions required to achieve objectives.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>The Most Important Thing:</strong> Summarizes the core ideas of the book, emphasizing the importance of value assessment, risk control, contrarian investing, and psychological factors. Successful investing requires comprehensive consideration of these factors and the development of a complete investment framework.</p>
</li>
</ol>


<h2 class="relative group">III. Key Takeaways 
    <div id="iii-key-takeaways" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii-key-takeaways" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;There&rsquo;s a certain irony in the investing world: What&rsquo;s obvious to everyone else is likely to be wrong.&rdquo;</p></blockquote>
<p>Insight:  Consensus views often lead to average results, at best.  Superior returns require non-consensus views that prove to be correct.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;Remember, your goal in investing isn&rsquo;t to earn average returns; you want to do better than average.&rdquo;</p></blockquote>
<p>Insight:  Complacency is the enemy of superior performance.  Strive to exceed benchmarks, not simply match them.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;The widespread belief that there&rsquo;s no risk is the biggest risk of all.&rdquo;</p></blockquote>
<p>Insight:  When markets are universally optimistic, risk is often at its highest because prices don&rsquo;t reflect potential problems.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;Only when the tide goes out do you discover who&rsquo;s been swimming naked.&rdquo;</p></blockquote>
<p>Insight: Adverse market conditions reveal the weaknesses in portfolios and investment strategies that were hidden during favorable periods.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;It takes greatest courage, but provides the greatest profit, to buy when others are despondently selling and to sell when others are greedily buying.&rdquo;</p></blockquote>
<p>Insight: Contrarian investing is difficult because it requires going against the crowd, but it offers the potential for the highest rewards.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;One of the great things about investing is that you don&rsquo;t have to make a lot of good decisions to do well. What&rsquo;s essential is avoiding bad decisions.&rdquo;</p></blockquote>
<p>Insight:  Preserving capital is paramount.  Avoiding significant losses has a greater impact on long-term returns than occasional big wins.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;An investor needs do very few things right as long as he avoids big mistakes.&rdquo;</p></blockquote>
<p>Insight:  Risk management and capital preservation are the cornerstones of successful investing.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">IV. Practical Application 
    <div id="iv-practical-application" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv-practical-application" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This book provides a comprehensive investment framework to help investors:</p>
<ol>
<li><strong>Establish a sound investment philosophy:</strong> Emphasizes the importance of value investing, contrarian investing, and risk control.</li>
<li><strong>Improve investment skills:</strong> Learn how to assess value, identify risks, control emotions, and construct portfolios.</li>
<li><strong>Cultivate a healthy investment mindset:</strong> Remain rational, objective, patient, and think independently, avoiding being swayed by market sentiment.</li>
<li><strong>Achieve better investment performance:</strong> By applying the methods and techniques discussed in the book, improve the quality of investment decisions and ultimately achieve above-market returns.</li>
</ol>

  



<div
  
    class="flex px-4 py-3 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900"
  >

  <span
    
      class="text-primary-400 ltr:pr-3 rtl:pl-3 flex items-center"
    >

    

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 640 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M172.5 131.1C228.1 75.51 320.5 75.51 376.1 131.1C426.1 181.1 433.5 260.8 392.4 318.3L391.3 319.9C381 334.2 361 337.6 346.7 327.3C332.3 317 328.9 297 339.2 282.7L340.3 281.1C363.2 249 359.6 205.1 331.7 177.2C300.3 145.8 249.2 145.8 217.7 177.2L105.5 289.5C73.99 320.1 73.99 372 105.5 403.5C133.3 431.4 177.3 435 209.3 412.1L210.9 410.1C225.3 400.7 245.3 404 255.5 418.4C265.8 432.8 262.5 452.8 248.1 463.1L246.5 464.2C188.1 505.3 110.2 498.7 60.21 448.8C3.741 392.3 3.741 300.7 60.21 244.3L172.5 131.1zM467.5 380C411 436.5 319.5 436.5 263 380C213 330 206.5 251.2 247.6 193.7L248.7 192.1C258.1 177.8 278.1 174.4 293.3 184.7C307.7 194.1 311.1 214.1 300.8 229.3L299.7 230.9C276.8 262.1 280.4 306.9 308.3 334.8C339.7 366.2 390.8 366.2 422.3 334.8L534.5 222.5C566 191 566 139.1 534.5 108.5C506.7 80.63 462.7 76.99 430.7 99.9L429.1 101C414.7 111.3 394.7 107.1 384.5 93.58C374.2 79.2 377.5 59.21 391.9 48.94L393.5 47.82C451 6.731 529.8 13.25 579.8 63.24C636.3 119.7 636.3 211.3 579.8 267.7L467.5 380z"/></svg>

  </span>


  </span>

  <span
    
      class="dark:text-neutral-300"
    ><strong>Related Reading:</strong>  Howard Marks&rsquo; investment memos: <a href="https://www.oaktreecapital.com/insights/memos" target="_blank"><strong>Archived Memos</strong></a></span>
</div>

<hr>

<section class="space-y-10 w-full">
    
    
</section>
]]></content:encoded></item></channel></rss>