<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Reading Notes on QQQ Investor</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/tags/reading-notes/</link><description>Recent content in Reading Notes on QQQ Investor</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 03 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jomonylw.github.io/en/tags/reading-notes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Intelligent Investor：Book Notes</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1730598742194/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1730598742194/</guid><description>This book provides guidance on investment strategies for laymen, explores the difference between investing and speculation, different strategies for defensive and enterprising investors and the relationship between investors and investment advisors, highlighting the concept of &amp;#34;margin of safety&amp;#34; as the core of investment.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[

<h2 class="relative group">I. Summary 
    <div id="i-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>&ldquo;The Intelligent Investor&rdquo; is a seminal work in the field of investment, authored by Benjamin Graham, widely regarded as the &ldquo;father of value investing&rdquo;. The book aims to provide guidance on investment strategies for the layman, with the following core ideas:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Rational Investment:</strong> Investment decisions should be based on thorough analysis of a security&rsquo;s value, not on market sentiment or speculative behavior.</li>
<li><strong>Margin of Safety:</strong> The core of investing is the margin of safety, which means buying securities at a price significantly below their intrinsic value, thus reducing risk and enhancing potential returns.</li>
<li><strong>Defensive and Enterprising Investors:</strong> Based on risk tolerance and investment objectives, investors are classified as either defensive or enterprising, each employing different investment strategies.</li>
<li><strong>Investors and the Market:</strong> Investors should view market fluctuations rationally, seeing them as opportunities rather than sources of risk.</li>
<li><strong>Company Owner Mentality:</strong> Investors should adopt the mindset of a company owner, paying attention to corporate management and governance and safeguarding their own interests.</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">II. Chapter Summaries 
    <div id="ii-chapter-summaries" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii-chapter-summaries" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Chapter 1: What Intelligent Investors Get 
    <div id="chapter-1-what-intelligent-investors-get" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chapter-1-what-intelligent-investors-get" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>This chapter introduces fundamental concepts of investing, including:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Investing vs. Speculation:</strong>  Investing is an operation based on analysis, aiming for safety of principal and a satisfactory return; speculation is hoping for profit from market fluctuations and carries higher risk.</li>
<li><strong>Defensive Investors:</strong> Seeking safety and steady returns, they can adopt a simple portfolio strategy, allocating funds between high-grade bonds and a diversified selection of leading common stocks.</li>
<li><strong>Enterprising Investors:</strong>  Willing to take on more risk for greater returns, they can employ more aggressive strategies, such as selecting growth stocks and seeking undervalued securities.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chapter 2: The Investor and Market Fluctuations 
    <div id="chapter-2-the-investor-and-market-fluctuations" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chapter-2-the-investor-and-market-fluctuations" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>This chapter explores how investors should view market fluctuations:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Price Fluctuations as a Measure of Investment Success:</strong>  In the long run, investment success depends on the long-term returns of the portfolio, not short-term price movements.</li>
<li><strong>Market Fluctuations as a Guide for Investment Decisions:</strong> Investors can capitalize on market volatility to create opportunities for buying low and selling high, but should avoid excessive focus on short-term market trends.</li>
<li><strong>Market Fluctuations of Individual Stocks:</strong> Focusing on undervalued individual stocks is more meaningful than attempting to predict overall market movements.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chapter 3: A Review of the 1964 Market 
    <div id="chapter-3-a-review-of-the-1964-market" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chapter-3-a-review-of-the-1964-market" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>This chapter analyzes the stock market conditions at the time of writing (1964):</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Comparison with Previous Years:</strong>  The stock market was at a historical high, rendering traditional valuation methods no longer applicable.</li>
<li><strong>New Standards for a &ldquo;New Era&rdquo;:</strong> New valuation methods had not yet been tested by time, and the market was characterized by a high degree of uncertainty.</li>
<li><strong>Investment Strategy Recommendation:</strong>  Adopt a cautious investment strategy and avoid excessive risk-taking.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chapter 4: The Investor and His Advisers 
    <div id="chapter-4-the-investor-and-his-advisers" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chapter-4-the-investor-and-his-advisers" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>This chapter discusses the relationship between investors and their advisors:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sources of Investment Advice:</strong>  Investors can obtain investment guidance from various avenues, including family and friends, banks, brokerage firms, and professional investment advisors.</li>
<li><strong>Selecting Investment Advisors:</strong> Choosing the right advisor is crucial, requiring careful assessment of their expertise, experience, and ethical standards.</li>
<li><strong>Independent Thinking:</strong>  Even when seeking professional advice, investors should maintain their own independent judgment and be responsible for their investment decisions.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chapter 5: The Defensive Investor&rsquo;s Portfolio Policy 
    <div id="chapter-5-the-defensive-investors-portfolio-policy" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chapter-5-the-defensive-investors-portfolio-policy" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>This chapter details the strategies for defensive investors:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Bond and Stock Allocation:</strong> Allocate funds between high-grade bonds and a diversified selection of leading common stocks. The ratio can be adjusted based on market conditions, but generally maintain a 50:50 split.</li>
<li><strong>Bond Portfolio Composition:</strong>  Introduces characteristics of different types of bonds, such as US Savings Bonds, state and municipal bonds, and corporate bonds.</li>
<li><strong>Principles for Common Stock Selection:</strong> Choose large, prominent, and conservatively financed companies with a long history of dividend payments, and purchase them at reasonable price-earnings ratios.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chapter 6: Portfolio Policy for the Enterprising Investor: Negative Approach 
    <div id="chapter-6-portfolio-policy-for-the-enterprising-investor-negative-approach" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chapter-6-portfolio-policy-for-the-enterprising-investor-negative-approach" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>This chapter presents a &ldquo;negative list&rdquo; of what enterprising investors should avoid:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Second-Grade Bonds and Preferred Stocks:</strong> Avoid buying securities lacking sufficient safety merely for the allure of high yields.</li>
<li><strong>Foreign Government Bonds:</strong>  Higher risk and difficulty in enforcing claims in case of default.</li>
<li><strong>New Issues:</strong> Require careful evaluation and avoidance of excessive hype surrounding them.</li>
<li><strong>Convertible Issues:</strong> Their advantages often come at the expense of quality or income, and they present investors with decision-making dilemmas.</li>
<li><strong>New-Issue Mania</strong>: During bull markets, many smaller companies go public, and their stock pricing is often unattractive or even excessive. Investors should be wary of the hype surrounding new issues and avoid blindly following the crowd.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chapter 7: Portfolio Policy for the Enterprising Investor: The Positive Side 
    <div id="chapter-7-portfolio-policy-for-the-enterprising-investor-the-positive-side" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chapter-7-portfolio-policy-for-the-enterprising-investor-the-positive-side" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>This chapter discusses positive strategies enterprising investors can employ:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Market Timing Limitations:</strong>  While the strategy of buying low in depressed markets and selling high in booming markets could be profitable in the past, recent market dynamics have made this approach less viable.</li>
<li><strong>Considerations for Growth Stocks:</strong> Selecting growth stocks requires diligent assessment of future growth potential, avoiding overpaying for lofty expectations.</li>
<li><strong>Three Recommended Areas for Enterprising Investment</strong>:
<ol>
<li><strong>Investing in Large Companies during Unpopular Periods:</strong> When large companies are experiencing unpopular periods, their stock prices may be undervalued, presenting opportunities for investors.</li>
<li><strong>Bargain Issues:</strong> Seek securities whose intrinsic value is demonstrably understated and buy them at prices significantly below this value.</li>
<li><strong>Special Situations:</strong>  Focus on events like mergers, reorganizations, and liquidations where the price fluctuations can offer substantial profit opportunities.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li><strong>Broad Application of Investment Rules:</strong>  Enterprising investors should approach investing as a business endeavor, adhering to sound business principles, such as knowing their investment domain, choosing partners carefully, and managing risk.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chapter 8: Security Analysis for the Lay Investor: General Approach 
    <div id="chapter-8-security-analysis-for-the-lay-investor-general-approach" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chapter-8-security-analysis-for-the-lay-investor-general-approach" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>This chapter introduces basic methods of security analysis for non-professional investors:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Bond Analysis</strong>:
<ul>
<li>Focus on the ratio of earnings to interest expenses, ensuring it meets certain standards (4x for utilities, 5x for railroads, 7x for industrials).</li>
<li>Consider factors like company size, equity ratio, and asset value.</li>
<li>Understand the risk characteristics of different bond types, like the relatively higher risk of railroad bonds compared to the safer utility company bonds.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Common Stock Analysis</strong>:
<ul>
<li>Analyze company profitability, including projected future earnings, sales margins, and return on net worth.</li>
<li>Assess capitalization rates, considering factors like long-term prospects, management quality, financial condition, and dividend record.</li>
<li>Pay attention to the impact of non-recurring gains and losses, making adjustments to earnings data.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Industrial Stock Analysis:</strong> Focus on industry trends and individual companies&rsquo; competitive positions within their respective sectors.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chapter 9: Stock Selection for the Defensive Investor 
    <div id="chapter-9-stock-selection-for-the-defensive-investor" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chapter-9-stock-selection-for-the-defensive-investor" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>Using Dow Jones Industrial Average stocks as an example, this chapter explains how defensive investors can select securities:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Choose a Representative Sample:</strong>  For instance, buy equal amounts of all 30 Dow Jones industrial stocks.</li>
<li><strong>Exclude Stocks with Excessive Price-Earnings Ratios:</strong> Avoid overpaying for speculative growth.</li>
<li><strong>Select Relatively Unpopular Stocks with Reasonable Valuations:</strong>  Capitalize on the market&rsquo;s neglect of certain stocks, finding undervalued investment opportunities.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chapter 10: Stock Selection for the Enterprising Investor: General Approach 
    <div id="chapter-10-stock-selection-for-the-enterprising-investor-general-approach" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chapter-10-stock-selection-for-the-enterprising-investor-general-approach" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>This chapter introduces methods for enterprising investors to select securities:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>The Valuation Approach:</strong>  Estimate a company&rsquo;s future earnings and select a suitable multiplier to determine its intrinsic value.</li>
<li><strong>Factors Affecting Asset Value:</strong> Pay attention to net tangible asset value, especially net current asset value. Add half the excess of net current asset value over earnings power value to the earnings power value for a more comprehensive assessment.</li>
<li><strong>Growth Stock Valuation:</strong> Consider the expected growth rate, but be cautious in assessing its reasonableness. The author provides a simplified formula for growth stock valuation: Value = Current (normal) earnings x (8.5 + 2 x expected annual growth rate).</li>
<li><strong>First-Grade vs. Second-Grade Common Stocks:</strong> Enterprising investors can consider buying second-grade common stocks, but only at bargain prices, namely when their price is less than two-thirds of the indicated intrinsic value.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chapter 11: Security Analysis for the Lay Investor: Six Illustrative Cases 
    <div id="chapter-11-security-analysis-for-the-lay-investor-six-illustrative-cases" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chapter-11-security-analysis-for-the-lay-investor-six-illustrative-cases" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>This chapter uses six real-world cases to illustrate how to apply security analysis techniques to uncover undervalued investment opportunities:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Case 1:  Northern Pacific Railroad common stock (1947):</strong>  The company&rsquo;s stock price was undervalued due to a combination of a low dividend payout and the non-inclusion of certain earnings in its income statement.</li>
<li><strong>Case 2:  Standard Gas and Electric (SP&amp;L) $7 preferred (1947):</strong> Analyzed the complex capital structure of SP&amp;L, pointing out the undervaluation of its preferred stock.</li>
<li><strong>Case 3:  American-Hawaiian Steamship (AHS) (1947):</strong> The company held substantial cash assets that were not reflected in its market price.</li>
<li><strong>Case 4: Royal Dutch Petroleum (RDP) (1953):</strong>  Pointed out that the market value of RDP was undervalued relative to its earnings power.</li>
<li><strong>Case 5:  Hoover Company Class A (1957):</strong> The company&rsquo;s stock was undervalued because the net worth of its British subsidiary was not fully reflected.</li>
<li><strong>Case 6:  Chicago, Terre Haute &amp; Southeastern Railway (TH) bonds (1964):</strong> Analyzed the value of TH bonds, indicating their undervaluation compared to comparable bonds.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chapter 12: Stock Market Fluctuations: The Pattern of Behavior 
    <div id="chapter-12-stock-market-fluctuations-the-pattern-of-behavior" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chapter-12-stock-market-fluctuations-the-pattern-of-behavior" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>This chapter analyzes the patterns of earnings and price fluctuations for different types of stocks:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Pattern 1:  Relatively Stable Earnings, Wide Price Fluctuations:</strong> Using S.H. Kress as an example, the chapter demonstrates how even with stable earnings, market prices can fluctuate greatly, primarily driven by market sentiment.</li>
<li><strong>Pattern 2:  Earnings Fluctuate Moderately, Stock Prices Fluctuate Widely:</strong> Using General Motors as an example, it illustrates how stock price volatility often exceeds earnings volatility and advises investors to view such fluctuations rationally.</li>
<li><strong>Pattern 3:  Extreme Ups and Downs:</strong>  Taking examples like Brunswick Corporation and St. Louis Southwestern Railway, the chapter highlights the substantial uncertainties in company development and stock price movements. Investors should be wary of companies experiencing extreme volatility.</li>
<li><strong>Pattern 4:  Growth Stocks:</strong> Using examples like 3M and Philip Morris, the chapter shows that even growth stocks face risks, and investors should carefully evaluate their growth potential and avoid overpaying for lofty expectations.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chapter 13: A Comparison of Eight Pairs of Companies 
    <div id="chapter-13-a-comparison-of-eight-pairs-of-companies" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chapter-13-a-comparison-of-eight-pairs-of-companies" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>This chapter uses comparative analysis of various stock portfolios to further investigate factors impacting stock prices:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Four Groups of Randomly Selected Cases and the Dow Jones Industrial Average</strong>:  By contrasting the performance of stocks in different market standings and comparing their initial trading dates, the chapter suggests that choosing large, strong companies often yields more consistent results. New stocks of smaller companies carry higher risk.</li>
<li><strong>Secular Changes in the Quality of a Company Group</strong>:  Taking railroad stocks as an example, the chapter highlights how the standing and investment merit of companies within a group can shift significantly over time.</li>
<li><strong>The Results of a Policy of Quality Improvement:</strong>  Using the Dow Jones Industrial Average as an example, the chapter illustrates that merely replacing underperforming components with more popular ones does not necessarily lead to sustained investment gains. Stock selection should be based on a combination of company quality and price.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chapter 14: Stockholders and Management 
    <div id="chapter-14-stockholders-and-management" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chapter-14-stockholders-and-management" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>This chapter explores the relationship between stockholders and company management:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Management Efficiency:</strong>
<ul>
<li>How to assess Management efficiency: By comparing key indicators like profitability, sales margin, and return on net worth to  industry averages.</li>
<li>How to improve inefficient management: Stockholders can take actions like raising questions at shareholder meetings, hiring independent management consultants for assessment, and electing more independent board members.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>The Board of Directors:</strong>
<ul>
<li>Role in Corporate Governance: The board represents shareholder interests, oversees management, sets company strategy, and reviews and approves significant decisions.</li>
<li>Stockholder Oversight of the Board: Stockholders can exercise their influence by electing board members and voting on proposals at shareholder meetings.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Fair Treatment of the General Stockholder:</strong>
<ul>
<li>Management&rsquo;s responsibility to protect outside stockholder interests: Management should set a fair dividend policy, avoid repurchasing stock at excessively low prices, and prioritize shareholder interests.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Holding Companies:</strong>
<ul>
<li>Disadvantageous position of outside stockholders within holding companies: Holding companies often present conflicts between controlling shareholder interests and those of outside stockholders, leading to potential harm to the latter.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>The Securities and Exchange Commission and Investor Protection:</strong>
<ul>
<li>SEC&rsquo;s functions and limitations: The SEC oversees the securities market and protects investor interests. However, its powers and functions are limited and cannot fully guarantee investor rights.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chapter 15:  &ldquo;Margin of Safety&rdquo; as the Central Concept of Investment 
    <div id="chapter-15--margin-of-safety-as-the-central-concept-of-investment" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chapter-15--margin-of-safety-as-the-central-concept-of-investment" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>This chapter summarizes the core concept of the book - the Margin of Safety:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Definition of Margin of Safety:</strong>  Purchasing securities at a price significantly below their intrinsic value, thereby mitigating risk and enhancing potential returns.</li>
<li><strong>Application in Different Investment Types:</strong> Bonds, common stocks, growth stocks, bargain issues, and other asset classes.</li>
<li><strong>Margin of Safety and Diversification:</strong> Diversification can reduce the overall risk of a portfolio and therefore enhances the margin of safety.</li>
<li><strong>Distinguishing Investment from Speculation:</strong>  The margin of safety is a key criterion for differentiating investment operations from speculative ones. Investment operations should be based on a clear and demonstrably justifiable analysis of value, while speculative operations rely more heavily on subjective judgment and market sentiment.</li>
<li><strong>Generalization of the Investment Concept:</strong> The idea of margin of safety can be applied to broader investment domains, such as when purchasing real estate, art, or other assets.</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">III. Key Quotes 
    <div id="iii-key-quotes" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii-key-quotes" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;In Wall Street, if you&rsquo;re always doing what&rsquo;s obvious or what everyone else is doing, you&rsquo;re not going to make money.&rdquo;</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Analysis: This emphasizes that to achieve above-average returns, investors require independent thinking and must seek value that is overlooked by the market.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;For rational investment, mental attitude is more important than technique.&rdquo;</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Analysis:  Investment success necessitates not just skills and tools, but also the right investment philosophy and mindset, including rationality, patience, and discipline.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;Don&rsquo;t buy after a stock has surged and don&rsquo;t sell after it has plummeted.&rdquo;</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Analysis: Avoid chasing rising prices and panicking during market dips. Focus on rational valuation and don&rsquo;t be swayed by market emotions.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;Have the courage of your knowledge and experience. If you have formed a conclusion from the facts and if you know your judgment is sound, act on it—even though others may hesitate or differ.&rdquo;</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Analysis: Investment requires independent judgment. Investors need to be confident and courageous in their convictions, even when facing dissenting opinions. Stay true to your well-researched investment principles.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;Many that are first shall be last, and the last shall be first.&rdquo;</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Analysis:  The business landscape is dynamic. Company strength and investment merit can shift over time, requiring investors to maintain a dynamic outlook and avoid fixed biases.</p>
<blockquote>
<p><em>&ldquo;Margin of Safety&rdquo;</em></p>
</blockquote>
<p>Analysis:  This succinct phrase encapsulates the core of Graham&rsquo;s approach. Investing should be grounded in acquiring assets at a price that provides a buffer against uncertainty and potential errors in judgment.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">IV. Guiding Significance 
    <div id="iv-guiding-significance" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv-guiding-significance" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<ul>
<li><strong>Establish a Sound Investment Philosophy:</strong>  Investing should be based on value analysis, not on speculation.</li>
<li><strong>Emphasize Margin of Safety:</strong> Purchase securities at prices significantly below their intrinsic value to minimize risk and enhance potential returns.</li>
<li><strong>Choose a Suitable Investment Strategy:</strong> Opt for a strategy—defensive or enterprising—that aligns with your risk tolerance and investment objectives.</li>
<li><strong>View Market Fluctuations Rationally:</strong> Don&rsquo;t be swayed by emotional reactions to market volatility. Instead, view such fluctuations as potential opportunities.</li>
<li><strong>Continuously Learn and Improve Investment Knowledge:</strong> Investing requires ongoing study and practice.</li>
<li><strong>Maintain Patience and Discipline:</strong>  Investment success often requires a long-term perspective, avoiding impulsive reactions to market movements.</li>
</ul>
<hr>

<section class="space-y-10 w-full">
    
    
        
            






















  <a class="flex flex-wrap article " href="/en/posts/1728295490690-book-list/">
    
        
        <div class="w-full md:w-auto h-full thumbnail nozoom thumbnailshadow md:mr-7" style="background-image:url(/posts/1728295490690-book-list/featured_hu4424409690304057825.jpg);"></div>
        
      <div class=" mt-3 md:mt-0">
      <div class="items-center text-left text-xl font-semibold">
        
        <div class="font-bold text-xl text-neutral-800 decoration-primary-500 hover:underline hover:underline-offset-2 dark:text-neutral"
          href="/en/posts/1728295490690-book-list/">Recommended Reading List</div>
        
        
        
      </div>
      <div class="text-sm text-neutral-500 dark:text-neutral-400">
        











  









  



  









<div class="flex flex-row flex-wrap items-center">
  
  
  <time datetime="2024-10-01T00:00:00&#43;00:00">1 October 2024</time><span class="px-2 text-primary-500">&middot;</span><span>
  
  
    
    
      
      
        
        
      
        
        
      
      
    
  
  <span id="views_posts/1728295490690-book-list/index.md" class="animate-pulse inline-block text-transparent max-h-3 rounded-full mt-[-2px] align-middle bg-neutral-300 dark:bg-neutral-400" title="views">loading</span>
  <span class="inline-block align-text-bottom">

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 576 512">
<path fill="currentColor" d="M288 32c-80.8 0-145.5 36.8-192.6 80.6C48.6 156 17.3 208 2.5 243.7c-3.3 7.9-3.3 16.7 0 24.6C17.3 304 48.6 356 95.4 399.4C142.5 443.2 207.2 480 288 480s145.5-36.8 192.6-80.6c46.8-43.5 78.1-95.4 93-131.1c3.3-7.9 3.3-16.7 0-24.6c-14.9-35.7-46.2-87.7-93-131.1C433.5 68.8 368.8 32 288 32zM432 256c0 79.5-64.5 144-144 144s-144-64.5-144-144s64.5-144 144-144s144 64.5 144 144zM288 192c0 35.3-28.7 64-64 64c-11.5 0-22.3-3-31.6-8.4c-.2 2.8-.4 5.5-.4 8.4c0 53 43 96 96 96s96-43 96-96s-43-96-96-96c-2.8 0-5.6 .1-8.4 .4c5.3 9.3 8.4 20.1 8.4 31.6z"/></svg>
  </span>

</span>
</span><span class="px-2 text-primary-500">&middot;</span><span>
  
  
    
    
      
      
        
        
      
        
        
      
      
    
  
  <span id="likes_posts/1728295490690-book-list/index.md"
    class="animate-pulse inline-block text-transparent max-h-3 rounded-full mt-[-2px] align-middle bg-neutral-300 dark:bg-neutral-400"
    title="likes">loading</span>
  <span class="inline-block align-text-bottom">

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512">
<path fill="currentColor" d="M47.6 300.4L228.3 469.1c7.5 7 17.4 10.9 27.7 10.9s20.2-3.9 27.7-10.9L464.4 300.4c30.4-28.3 47.6-68 47.6-109.5v-5.8c0-69.9-50.5-129.5-119.4-141C347 36.5 300.6 51.4 268 84L256 96 244 84c-32.6-32.6-79-47.5-124.6-39.9C50.5 55.6 0 115.2 0 185.1v5.8c0 41.5 17.2 81.2 47.6 109.5z"/></svg>
  </span>

</span>
</span>
  

  
  
</div>





<div class="flex flex-row flex-wrap items-center">
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  <span style="margin-top:0.5rem" class="mr-2" onclick="window.open(&#34;/en/tags/recommended/&#34;,'_self');">
    <span class="flex" style="cursor: pointer;">
  <span class="rounded-md border border-primary-400 px-1 py-[1px] text-xs font-normal text-primary-700 dark:border-primary-600 dark:text-primary-400">
    Recommended
  </span>
</span>
  </span>
  
  <span style="margin-top:0.5rem" class="mr-2" onclick="window.open(&#34;/en/tags/book/&#34;,'_self');">
    <span class="flex" style="cursor: pointer;">
  <span class="rounded-md border border-primary-400 px-1 py-[1px] text-xs font-normal text-primary-700 dark:border-primary-600 dark:text-primary-400">
    Book
  </span>
</span>
  </span>
  
  
  
  
</div>




      </div>
      
    </div>
  </a>

        
    
</section>
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>The Most Important Thing：Book Notes</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1729341470274/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1729341470274/</guid><description>This book, by renowned investor Howard Marks, summarizes his investment experience, explaining his investment philosophy and analyzing key factors such as market environment, investor psychology, and risk control, aiming to help investors achieve above-market investment performance.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[

<h2 class="relative group">I. Summary 
    <div id="i-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>The core idea of this book is how to achieve investment returns that surpass the market average. The author argues that achieving this goal requires &ldquo;second-level thinking,&rdquo; which is deeper and more comprehensive than the thinking of ordinary investors. He emphasizes contrarian investing, being greedy when others are fearful, and fearful when others are greedy. The book elaborates on important concepts such as market efficiency, value assessment, risk identification and control, cyclical and pendulum awareness, investor psychology, and diversified investment. It also provides a wealth of practical experience and case studies, aiming to help investors establish a sound thinking framework and control the impact of emotions on investment decisions.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">II. Chapter Summaries 
    <div id="ii-chapter-summaries" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii-chapter-summaries" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<ol>
<li>
<p><strong>Second-Level Thinking:</strong> To outperform the market, one must engage in second-level thinking, which requires investors to think more deeply and comprehensively, not being satisfied with simple conclusions, but considering various possibilities, probabilities, market consensus, and their own cognitive biases. For example, first-level thinking might conclude, &ldquo;This is a good company, so I should buy it,&rdquo; while second-level thinking would consider, &ldquo;While it&rsquo;s a good company, has the market already overreacted, pushing the price too high?&rdquo;</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Understanding Market Efficiency and Its Limitations:</strong> Markets are not perfectly efficient; there are opportunities for mispricing. However, due to the large number of investors competing, beating the market remains very difficult. Markets are efficient at incorporating information, but they don&rsquo;t always interpret that information correctly. Investors should focus on relatively inefficient markets, such as those that are less followed, have opaque information, or are controversial.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Value Assessment:</strong> The foundation of value investing is accurate estimation of intrinsic value, which requires considering factors such as a company&rsquo;s financial position, management capabilities, profitability, competitive advantages, and future growth prospects. The author emphasizes that value investing focuses more on present value, while growth investing emphasizes future value, but both require considering the future.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>The Relationship Between Price and Value:</strong> Successful investing is not about &ldquo;buying good things,&rdquo; but about &ldquo;buying things well,&rdquo; which means buying at a price below intrinsic value. Price is influenced by value, psychology, and technical factors. Investors need to understand the relationship between these three to make sound investment decisions. Buying a good company at a high price can still lead to losses, while buying a lower-quality asset at a low price can yield high returns.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Understanding Risk:</strong> Risk is not volatility, but the possibility of permanent loss of capital. It&rsquo;s crucial to understand the various forms of risk, such as failing to meet objectives, underperformance, career risk, and liquidity risk. Risk is subjective and difficult to quantify, depending on the investor&rsquo;s specific circumstances and goals.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Recognizing Risk:</strong> Risk often increases when market optimism is high and prices are inflated. Be wary of the &ldquo;no risk&rdquo; narrative and recognize signs of an overheated market, such as high P/E ratios, narrow credit spreads, and loose credit conditions.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Controlling Risk:</strong> Risk control is more important than taking risks. Control risk through diversification, limiting risk exposure, adhering to a margin of safety, and avoiding excessive leverage. The results of risk control are often invisible because they manifest in losses avoided.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Focusing on Cycles:</strong> Everything is cyclical. Recognize the inevitability of cyclical fluctuations and look for opportunities at cyclical extremes. The author uses the credit cycle as an example to illustrate how cycles are self-correcting and how investors can find opportunities within them.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Pendulum Awareness:</strong> Investor psychology swings like a pendulum between optimism and pessimism, greed and fear. Recognize the patterns of this swing and act contrarianly at extremes. Market extremes often represent turning points and opportunities.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Resisting Negative Influences:</strong> Resist the influence of negative emotions such as greed, fear, herd mentality, envy, and ego on investment decisions. Recognizing the existence of these psychological factors and striving to overcome them is crucial for making rational investment decisions.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Contrarian Investing:</strong> Be greedy when others are fearful, and fearful when others are greedy. Contrarian investing is not simply doing the opposite of the crowd; it requires independent thinking and judgment, as well as a deep understanding of value. Contrarian investing can be lonely and unsettling but is key to achieving superior returns.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Finding Bargains:</strong> Bargains often appear in unpopular and unfavored assets, such as those with apparent flaws, misunderstood by the market, or overlooked.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Waiting Patiently for Opportunities:</strong> Don&rsquo;t chase opportunities; wait patiently for them to come to you. Investors should be like baseball hitters, waiting for the perfect pitch instead of swinging blindly.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Recognizing the Limitations of Forecasting:</strong> Predicting the future is very difficult. Recognize the limitations of forecasting and focus on knowable factors, such as company fundamentals and industry trends.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Understanding Your Position in the Cycle:</strong> Understand your position within the market cycle and adjust your investment strategy accordingly. Investors can assess market conditions by observing investor behavior, the credit environment, and valuation levels.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Appreciating the Role of Luck:</strong> Investment outcomes are influenced by luck. Distinguish between skill and luck, and avoid being blinded by short-term success. Investors should focus on long-term performance and analyze the sources of returns, rather than just focusing on short-term gains.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Diversification:</strong> Diversification is an important risk management tool, but understand correlations and avoid ineffective diversification. True diversification means holding assets that behave differently under different market conditions.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Avoiding Mistakes:</strong> Avoiding major mistakes is more important than pursuing great success. Identify and avoid various types of errors, such as analytical errors, psychological errors, and failure to recognize cycles and market sentiment.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>The Significance of Value Creation:</strong> Value creation requires superior investment skill. Understand alpha and beta, and strive for asymmetric investment performance, meaning achieving higher returns when the market rises and suffering fewer losses when the market falls.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Reasonable Expectations:</strong> Set reasonable return expectations and avoid being misled by unrealistic expectations. Excessively high return expectations are often accompanied by excessive risk. Understand how returns are generated and the conditions required to achieve objectives.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>The Most Important Thing:</strong> Summarizes the core ideas of the book, emphasizing the importance of value assessment, risk control, contrarian investing, and psychological factors. Successful investing requires comprehensive consideration of these factors and the development of a complete investment framework.</p>
</li>
</ol>


<h2 class="relative group">III. Key Takeaways 
    <div id="iii-key-takeaways" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii-key-takeaways" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;There&rsquo;s a certain irony in the investing world: What&rsquo;s obvious to everyone else is likely to be wrong.&rdquo;</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Insight:  Consensus views often lead to average results, at best.  Superior returns require non-consensus views that prove to be correct.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;Remember, your goal in investing isn&rsquo;t to earn average returns; you want to do better than average.&rdquo;</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Insight:  Complacency is the enemy of superior performance.  Strive to exceed benchmarks, not simply match them.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;The widespread belief that there&rsquo;s no risk is the biggest risk of all.&rdquo;</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Insight:  When markets are universally optimistic, risk is often at its highest because prices don&rsquo;t reflect potential problems.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;Only when the tide goes out do you discover who&rsquo;s been swimming naked.&rdquo;</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Insight: Adverse market conditions reveal the weaknesses in portfolios and investment strategies that were hidden during favorable periods.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;It takes greatest courage, but provides the greatest profit, to buy when others are despondently selling and to sell when others are greedily buying.&rdquo;</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Insight: Contrarian investing is difficult because it requires going against the crowd, but it offers the potential for the highest rewards.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;One of the great things about investing is that you don&rsquo;t have to make a lot of good decisions to do well. What&rsquo;s essential is avoiding bad decisions.&rdquo;</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Insight:  Preserving capital is paramount.  Avoiding significant losses has a greater impact on long-term returns than occasional big wins.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;An investor needs do very few things right as long as he avoids big mistakes.&rdquo;</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Insight:  Risk management and capital preservation are the cornerstones of successful investing.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">IV. Practical Application 
    <div id="iv-practical-application" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv-practical-application" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This book provides a comprehensive investment framework to help investors:</p>
<ol>
<li><strong>Establish a sound investment philosophy:</strong> Emphasizes the importance of value investing, contrarian investing, and risk control.</li>
<li><strong>Improve investment skills:</strong> Learn how to assess value, identify risks, control emotions, and construct portfolios.</li>
<li><strong>Cultivate a healthy investment mindset:</strong> Remain rational, objective, patient, and think independently, avoiding being swayed by market sentiment.</li>
<li><strong>Achieve better investment performance:</strong> By applying the methods and techniques discussed in the book, improve the quality of investment decisions and ultimately achieve above-market returns.</li>
</ol>

  



<div
  
    class="flex px-4 py-3 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900"
  >

  <span
    
      class="text-primary-400 ltr:pr-3 rtl:pl-3 flex items-center"
    >

    

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 640 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M172.5 131.1C228.1 75.51 320.5 75.51 376.1 131.1C426.1 181.1 433.5 260.8 392.4 318.3L391.3 319.9C381 334.2 361 337.6 346.7 327.3C332.3 317 328.9 297 339.2 282.7L340.3 281.1C363.2 249 359.6 205.1 331.7 177.2C300.3 145.8 249.2 145.8 217.7 177.2L105.5 289.5C73.99 320.1 73.99 372 105.5 403.5C133.3 431.4 177.3 435 209.3 412.1L210.9 410.1C225.3 400.7 245.3 404 255.5 418.4C265.8 432.8 262.5 452.8 248.1 463.1L246.5 464.2C188.1 505.3 110.2 498.7 60.21 448.8C3.741 392.3 3.741 300.7 60.21 244.3L172.5 131.1zM467.5 380C411 436.5 319.5 436.5 263 380C213 330 206.5 251.2 247.6 193.7L248.7 192.1C258.1 177.8 278.1 174.4 293.3 184.7C307.7 194.1 311.1 214.1 300.8 229.3L299.7 230.9C276.8 262.1 280.4 306.9 308.3 334.8C339.7 366.2 390.8 366.2 422.3 334.8L534.5 222.5C566 191 566 139.1 534.5 108.5C506.7 80.63 462.7 76.99 430.7 99.9L429.1 101C414.7 111.3 394.7 107.1 384.5 93.58C374.2 79.2 377.5 59.21 391.9 48.94L393.5 47.82C451 6.731 529.8 13.25 579.8 63.24C636.3 119.7 636.3 211.3 579.8 267.7L467.5 380z"/></svg>

  </span>


  </span>

  <span
    
      class="dark:text-neutral-300"
    ><strong>Related Reading:</strong>  Howard Marks&rsquo; investment memos: <a href="https://www.oaktreecapital.com/insights/memos" target="_blank"><strong>Archived Memos</strong></a></span>
</div>

<hr>

<section class="space-y-10 w-full">
    
    
</section>
]]></content:encoded></item></channel></rss>