<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Market Fluctuation on QQQ Investor</title>
    <link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/tags/market-fluctuation/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Market Fluctuation on QQQ Investor</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 16 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jomonylw.github.io/en/tags/market-fluctuation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>00527 Rolling 60 Million into 6 Billion? The Miraculous Path of Long-Term Snowballing with a 2% Pledge</title>
      <link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1755520553470/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1755520553470/</guid>
      <description>In this session, James delves into the core philosophy of long-term investing, emphasizing that investors should adopt a &amp;#39;do nothing&amp;#39; mindset, ignoring short-term market fluctuations, macroeconomic data, and various news noise. He points out that the key to success lies in proper risk management—namely, using rational asset allocation and sufficient cash reserves to cope with market uncertainty, rather than trying to predict the market. The course also analyzes the difficulties of value investing, the currency dilemmas of emerging markets, and answers student questions on practical topics such as geographic arbitrage, family financial communication, and the rate of return on insurance products.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<lite-youtube videoid="zo3rAowExzQ" playlabel="zo3rAowExzQ" params=""></lite-youtube>



<h2 class="relative group">I. Main Topic of the Session 
    <div id="i-main-topic-of-the-session" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-main-topic-of-the-session" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This session revolves around the core concept of long-term investing—a &ldquo;do nothing&rdquo; approach. James emphasizes that investors should ignore short-term market fluctuations, macroeconomic data, financial reports, and even political news, and instead, stick to buying and holding high-quality assets (like QQQ) for the long term. The key to success is not in predicting market highs and lows, but in proper risk management, which means using sensible asset allocation and maintaining sufficient cash reserves to handle any market condition. The market has no peak; it will only go higher. Investors should focus on the future 20 years from now, rather than worrying about tomorrow&rsquo;s ups and downs.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">II. Briefing Content 
    <div id="ii-briefing-content" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii-briefing-content" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Investment Mentality and Long-Term Perspective 
    <div id="investment-mentality-and-long-term-perspective" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#investment-mentality-and-long-term-perspective" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>&ldquo;Do Nothing&rdquo; Approach</strong>: The best investment strategy is to buy and then leave it alone; the market will naturally reach new highs. Trying to manage or predict the market is more likely to lead to failure.</li>
<li><strong>Ignore Market Noise</strong>: Investors don&rsquo;t need to care about what Trump or Putin says, nor should they pay attention to economic data like PPI and CPI or company earnings reports. This short-term information is irrelevant to long-term investing.</li>
<li><strong>The Importance of Time</strong>: Investing requires a long-term view, at least a 20-year horizon. Thinking about the person you want to become in 20 years is more meaningful than worrying about tomorrow&rsquo;s market. Getting rich overnight is impossible, but going bankrupt overnight is common, which is why risk control is crucial.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Risk Management: Asset Allocation and Cash is King 
    <div id="risk-management-asset-allocation-and-cash-is-king" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#risk-management-asset-allocation-and-cash-is-king" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Core Principle</strong>: The only way to face market volatility is through proper asset allocation and having enough cash, not by trying to predict the market.</li>
<li><strong>Investing with Loans</strong>: Whether it&rsquo;s a personal loan or a mortgage, you must ensure you can repay it with your salary. For retirees with no income, taking out a wealth management mortgage is not recommended; a reverse mortgage could be considered to increase cash flow.</li>
<li><strong>Stock Pledging</strong>: When pledging stocks, you must also understand asset allocation and keep enough cash on hand to deal with market fluctuations, avoiding a margin call due to a market downturn.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Understanding the First Principles of Global Finance 
    <div id="understanding-the-first-principles-of-global-finance" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#understanding-the-first-principles-of-global-finance" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>How the Financial System Works</strong>: By understanding the roles of the central bank and the treasury department, as well as the relationship between inflation and money printing, one can grasp the essence of government policies. For example, governments need mild inflation to ensure employment.</li>
<li><strong>A Capitalist Perspective</strong>: Today&rsquo;s world operates under a capitalist system. Analyzing political and social events from a capitalist viewpoint is the only way to see the true motivations behind the issues.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Analysis of Emerging Market Currencies and Foreign Exchange Systems 
    <div id="analysis-of-emerging-market-currencies-and-foreign-exchange-systems" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#analysis-of-emerging-market-currencies-and-foreign-exchange-systems" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Limitations of Currencies</strong>: The domestic currencies of emerging countries (like the New Taiwan Dollar) are not internationally circulated and cannot be directly converted into US dollars.</li>
<li><strong>Sources of Foreign Exchange Reserves</strong>: A country&rsquo;s foreign exchange reserves mainly come from two channels:
<ol>
<li><strong>Current Account</strong>: Earning foreign currency by exporting goods and services, such as TSMC&rsquo;s export revenues. These are called &ldquo;slave dollars&rdquo; because a great deal of labor is required to earn them.</li>
<li><strong>Financial Account</strong>: Inflow of foreign capital for investment (e.g., buying stocks). This capital can come and go quickly, easily causing financial turmoil and leading to national bankruptcy.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li><strong>Risk of Bankruptcy</strong>: When a country&rsquo;s export capability is weak and it relies heavily on foreign capital from the financial account, it faces a financial crisis or even national bankruptcy if that foreign capital withdraws on a large scale and its foreign reserves are insufficient to cope.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">The Dilemma of Value Investing &amp; The Superiority of Long-Term Holding 
    <div id="the-dilemma-of-value-investing--the-superiority-of-long-term-holding" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#the-dilemma-of-value-investing--the-superiority-of-long-term-holding" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>The Difficulty of Valuation</strong>: Valuing an asset (whether a house or a stock) is extremely difficult and subjective. Like the Mona Lisa&rsquo;s smile, different people have different interpretations, and there is no standard answer.</li>
<li><strong>The Fallacy of Valuation</strong>: Many people claim stocks are too expensive, yet the market continues to rise. Munger once said he never saw Buffett pick up a pen to calculate a discounted cash flow. Therefore, don&rsquo;t be troubled by claims of &ldquo;overvaluation.&rdquo;</li>
<li><strong>Long-Term Holding is the Only Solution</strong>: Forgetting about valuation and holding high-quality assets for the long term is the most effective investment strategy that everyone can execute.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Personalization of Asset Allocation &amp; Account Selection 
    <div id="personalization-of-asset-allocation--account-selection" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#personalization-of-asset-allocation--account-selection" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Reject Blind Imitation</strong>: Do not copy someone else&rsquo;s asset allocation plan. Everyone&rsquo;s plan is tailored to their age, asset size, risk tolerance, and financial goals (like retiring in 5 or 10 years). Learn the core spirit and logic of asset allocation, rather than mimicking specific percentages like a parrot.</li>
<li><strong>Account Advice for U.S. Investors</strong>: For investors in the United States, full advantage should be taken of the tax benefits of a Roth IRA account. It is an excellent tool for tax avoidance and inheritance. It is recommended to allocate at least one-third of your funds to a Roth account, which is particularly suitable for holding leveraged funds.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">The Importance of Investing Immediately: Earning Less is a Real Loss 
    <div id="the-importance-of-investing-immediately-earning-less-is-a-real-loss" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#the-importance-of-investing-immediately-earning-less-is-a-real-loss" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>The Right Investment</strong>: As long as it&rsquo;s the &ldquo;right investment&rdquo; (like QQQ) combined with &ldquo;long-term holding,&rdquo; you will definitely make a profit.</li>
<li><strong>Opportunity Cost is a Real Loss</strong>: Short-term paper losses are temporary and non-existent. However, the gains you miss out on due to hesitation (the money you could have earned) are a permanent and tangible loss.
<ul>
<li><strong>Example</strong>: If QQQ rises from 400 to 577, and you didn&rsquo;t buy at 400, you have permanently lost that 177 in profit. This loss can never be recovered.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Act Immediately</strong>: Therefore, you should buy immediately when you have the money; this is the action with the highest expected value. The later you buy, the less you earn, the lower your wealth growth base becomes, and the wider the gap between you and others will grow.</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">III. Q&amp;A Session 
    <div id="iii-qa-session" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii-qa-session" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Guzhongli 
    <div id="guzhongli" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#guzhongli" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: He recently read discussions about how AI will change the world, which made him feel that he shouldn&rsquo;t retire in the next 10 years. He feels he should work hard as this might be his last job opportunity, and he doesn&rsquo;t want to sell his growing QQQ for living expenses.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Comment: The decision to work should not be based on fear of the future (like AI replacing jobs). You should ask yourself: Do you like your job? Are you working for money or for happiness? This is the fundamental reason that should determine whether you continue to work, regardless of the AI era or a future space age.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question: He recently saw online discussions about &ldquo;geographic arbitrage,&rdquo; which involves moving to Southeast Asian countries with lower living costs (like Thailand or Vietnam) to make savings last longer. He wants to ask if this approach is feasible and what the risks or recommendations are.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: This isn&rsquo;t &ldquo;arbitrage&rdquo;; it&rsquo;s &ldquo;having no way out.&rdquo; Moving to a place you don&rsquo;t genuinely like just to save money is a form of external diseconomy and is not advisable. We should strive to live in an environment we like and find convenient, not be forced into a choice because of a lack of money. If you move to Hualien or Taitung because they are beautiful, that&rsquo;s the right choice even if it costs more than Taipei. But if it&rsquo;s just to save money, it&rsquo;s the wrong choice.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Edwin 
    <div id="edwin" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#edwin" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: He shared his understanding of &ldquo;happiness.&rdquo; In the past, his happiness came from external recognition like good grades or promotions. After learning James&rsquo;s financial concepts, he believes true happiness is simple, like seeing an old couple quietly eating an apple at the foot of Mount Fuji. At that moment, past achievements no longer mattered.</li>
<li>Question: He understands Adler&rsquo;s principle of &ldquo;separation of tasks,&rdquo; but he still feels sad when he sees friends and family struggling in the cycle of hard work. He knows he can&rsquo;t force them to change, but he wants to ask how to adjust this feeling of &ldquo;not being able to bear it.&rdquo;
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: My view of happiness is &ldquo;whatever, it&rsquo;s all good, it doesn&rsquo;t matter&rdquo;—that is, happiness is having no burdens. The situation you described is much like a doctor&rsquo;s dilemma: seeing a patient who can&rsquo;t afford a necessary stent, the doctor is helpless. Poverty is a disease, and we can&rsquo;t save everyone; even the thousand-armed Guanyin has limits. What you can do is tell them the correct concept once, fulfilling your responsibility. Those who believe will be saved. For those who don&rsquo;t, you must learn to let go, or you won&rsquo;t be able to live your own life well.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Yaomie 
    <div id="yaomie" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#yaomie" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question: While listening to Howard Marks&rsquo;s audiobook, he understood that market cycles don&rsquo;t have a fixed length but are driven by the collective sentiment of the masses. When the market is extremely euphoric, it&rsquo;s a bubble, and vice versa. Is this understanding correct?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: Your understanding is completely correct. The only indicator of a bubble, as Howard Marks says, is that &ldquo;investors have gone crazy&rdquo;; there are no other quantitative metrics. But the difficulty with this theory is in its execution. Everyone is in a different environment and has a different perception of the market&rsquo;s &ldquo;temperature,&rdquo; so it&rsquo;s very hard to pinpoint the peak. The theory is correct, but how to apply it is the key.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Weinini 
    <div id="weinini" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#weinini" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: She introduced James&rsquo;s investment philosophy to a very conservative elder, who ultimately only agreed to invest NT$20,000 per month into 006208 (a Taiwanese ETF) on a regular basis. She feels a bit anxious about this, thinking it&rsquo;s too slow.</li>
<li>Question: This elder insists they have an insurance policy bought 30-40 years ago with an 8% return. She suspects this was just a sales pitch from the agent back then and wants to ask how to explain to the elder that the actual return on this policy is likely not that high.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: First, don&rsquo;t be anxious. If the person involved isn&rsquo;t in a hurry, we shouldn&rsquo;t be either. You don&rsquo;t know if your advice will save them or harm them. What if they invest and the market drops in the short term? They will blame you. Taking it slow is a good thing. Regarding the insurance policy, an 8% return is almost impossible. You need to calculate the actual annualized rate of return (IRR or XIRR), not a simple arithmetic average. Especially considering the funds invested early on were locked up for 20-30 years with no return, the opportunity cost during that period is enormous. A rough estimate shows that if the same money (NT$750,000 invested annually for 20 years) were put into the market (at a 10% annualized return), it would become NT$100 million after 28 years. The policy, however, only pays out NT$1 million per year, making the return not even 1%. It&rsquo;s essentially a product from a &ldquo;scam group.&rdquo;</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Jason 
    <div id="jason" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#jason" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: A follow-up on family financial communication. He realized that for large investments (like consolidating a mortgage to free up several million), he must get his wife&rsquo;s consent. His current strategy is &ldquo;slowly might be faster,&rdquo; gradually gaining his wife&rsquo;s understanding and trust through continuous communication, sharing small gains, and explaining the long-term philosophy. He believes it&rsquo;s very important for a couple to be on the same page; otherwise, even if he makes money from investments, it could cause family conflicts.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: Your approach is absolutely correct. Take it slow, and make sure your spouse feels involved and secure. For example, you can put a portion of the money from the loan into your wife&rsquo;s account for her to manage. When she sees cash in the account, she will feel more at ease. Never make decisions on your own. Even if you succeed, your partner might get angry for not being respected, which could lead to a broken marriage.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Jeff 
    <div id="jeff" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#jeff" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question: James mentioned that one of the three principles of asset allocation is to consider the extreme scenario of &ldquo;interest rates rising to infinity.&rdquo; He is worried that if a situation like the 1980s in the U.S. occurs, with interest rates as high as 20%, our current backtesting models based on the last 20 years of data might not hold up. Is he worrying too much?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: This is an excellent question. The way to deal with such an extreme situation is to hold more cash. If you are worried about a &ldquo;stagflation&rdquo; environment like the 1970s-1980s, where the stock market stagnated and interest rates were high, then your initial cash allocation should be higher, for example, increasing it from 30% to 40% or even 50%. Your cash reserve determines how much risk you can withstand.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">IAM 
    <div id="iam" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iam" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: He observed that many university students are indoctrinated with traditional financial theories like &ldquo;diversification&rdquo; and &ldquo;asset allocation.&rdquo; He believes this is a &ldquo;systemic scam&rdquo; designed by capitalism, causing ordinary people&rsquo;s already limited savings to be further diluted and unable to grow effectively.</li>
<li>Question: When he tries to &ldquo;awaken&rdquo; people around him, he finds two outcomes: one type awakens and starts taking action; the other type realizes they&rsquo;ve been wrong for decades and feels pain and despair. He doesn&rsquo;t know how to help the latter group and worries that awakening them without proper guidance might end up harming them.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: You are right about the &ldquo;systemic scam.&rdquo; Simply &ldquo;awakening&rdquo; someone is very dangerous because they might try to figure things out on their own and end up on the wrong path (like day trading), leading to bankruptcy. The correct approach is systematic education. You should guide them to watch our channel and learn the complete investment system from the beginning. Don&rsquo;t just give them a conclusion; teach them the entire thought process and methodology.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Catherine 
    <div id="catherine" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#catherine" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question: A friend asked her: &ldquo;You early investors bought QQQ at a low price, and now you encourage us to buy, pushing the price up. What benefit do you get?&rdquo; She replied that the market is huge, we can&rsquo;t influence the price, and the price increase comes from productivity growth and inflation. She wants to know how James would respond.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: When you buy in doesn&rsquo;t matter. The long-term annualized return of the market (say, over 30-40 years) is relatively constant. The rate of return I have gotten over the past 40 years and the rate of return you will get by investing for the next 40 years have the same expected value. Us encouraging you to buy doesn&rsquo;t make us more money. Everyone&rsquo;s investment is an independent event. The return you get is only related to how long you hold, it has nothing to do with us.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Quick Q&amp;A (from comments section) 
    <div id="quick-qa-from-comments-section" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#quick-qa-from-comments-section" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>On Overseas Brokers (like Futu)</strong>: James strongly advises Taiwanese investors against using overseas brokers like Futu. The main risks are: 1. Issues with the Alternative Minimum Tax. 2. High estate taxes (potentially up to 40%). 3. If the investor has an accident, their heirs may not even find this account, and the inheritance process will be extremely difficult.</li>
<li><strong>On Exchange Rates</strong>: Investing is a decades-long endeavor; don&rsquo;t pay attention to short-term currency fluctuations. In the long run, exchange rates will fluctuate within a range and eventually converge to an expected value. Worrying about exchange rates will prevent you from doing anything.</li>
<li><strong>On the Cash Portion</strong>: The &ldquo;cash&rdquo; portion of asset allocation should absolutely not be invested in high-dividend stocks. High-dividend stocks are still stocks, they will fall, and they do not have the stability of cash. Cash should be allocated to truly safe assets like a Money Market Fund or short-term government bonds.</li>
<li><strong>On Other Funds</strong>: A student asked about actively managed funds like the Franklin Technology Fund. James&rsquo;s advice is to stop investing in such funds with high fees and potential redemption restrictions, and just buy 00662 (Taiwan&rsquo;s Nasdaq ETF) directly.</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">IV. Key Quotes 
    <div id="iv-key-quotes" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv-key-quotes" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>The market has no peak, it will only go higher.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>Background: At the beginning of the session, James emphasized the long-term conviction investors should have, and not to feel fear or try to predict the top just because the market is making new highs.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The money you miss out on earning is a permanent loss for your entire life&hellip; Earning less is a tangible loss.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>Background: When explaining why one should &ldquo;buy immediately with available cash,&rdquo; James pointed out that opportunity cost is a real and permanent loss, far more terrifying than short-term paper losses.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>You could have billions and not be able to spend it all, yet you&rsquo;re thinking of moving to a backward place&hellip; (just to save money) that&rsquo;s called having no way out.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>Background: When commenting on &ldquo;geographic arbitrage,&rdquo; James sharply pointed out that sacrificing quality of life and moving to an undesirable, cheap area due to financial constraints is not a wise move.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Seeing others suffer, it&rsquo;s hard for us to save them&hellip; It&rsquo;s like Jesus, he spoke to someone&hellip; but then the person ran away because they didn&rsquo;t have enough money&hellip; and Jesus had to let go, there was nothing he could do.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>Background: In answering Edwin&rsquo;s question on how to adjust his mindset when facing friends and family he can&rsquo;t help, James used this analogy to explain that all we can do is pass on the information. Whether the other person accepts it is beyond our control, and we must learn to let go.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Slowly might be faster.
&ndash; Jason</p></blockquote>
<p>Background: Student Jason summarized this philosophical phrase when sharing his experience communicating investment concepts with his family, emphasizing the importance of patience and continuous communication.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>When a husband and wife are of one mind, they can break through metal. If they are not&hellip; even if you succeed, she might fly into a rage, &lsquo;You do everything without telling me.&rsquo;
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>Background: When commenting on family financial communication, James stressed the extreme importance of spousal consensus, otherwise even successful investments could destroy the family relationship.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>I said your [insurance policy] doesn&rsquo;t even pay out when it should, and he said, &lsquo;how much premium did you pay?&rsquo;&hellip; Wow, is that what you call insurance?
&ndash; James
Background: Recalling a debate with an insurance professional, James revealed the nature of some insurance products where the &ldquo;payout limit is tied to the premium paid,&rdquo; pointing out the limitations of their protective function.</p></blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>Don&rsquo;t take that fifteen million to buy insurance, you could have a hundred million&hellip; you only get one million a year&hellip; that&rsquo;s just taking one percent, and you&rsquo;re still smiling happily about it.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>Background: Through calculation, James revealed the extremely low rate of return on long-term savings insurance. Compared to investing in the market over the same period, the difference in returns is immense, representing a huge opportunity cost loss.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">V. Summary 
    <div id="v-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#v-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This session once again reinforced the core idea of CLEC&rsquo;s long-term investing: simplify investment decisions and embrace the market&rsquo;s long-term growth. Through the concept of a &ldquo;do nothing&rdquo; approach, James urged investors to break free from the interference of short-term market noise and to focus on building a robust, personalized asset allocation, always maintaining sufficient cash as the ultimate defense against risk. The Q&amp;A session covered multiple dimensions, from personal mindset adjustments and family financial communication to the analysis of financial products like insurance. Using vivid examples and sharp insights, James exposed many common investment fallacies. The most central takeaway is that investing is a marathon of patience and discipline; taking immediate action and persisting for the long term is far more important than trying to find the perfect timing and valuation.</p>

  



<div
  
    class="flex px-4 py-3 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900"
  >

  <span
    
      class="text-primary-400 ltr:pr-3 rtl:pl-3 flex items-center"
    >

    

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M506.3 417l-213.3-364c-16.33-28-57.54-28-73.98 0l-213.2 364C-10.59 444.9 9.849 480 42.74 480h426.6C502.1 480 522.6 445 506.3 417zM232 168c0-13.25 10.75-24 24-24S280 154.8 280 168v128c0 13.25-10.75 24-23.1 24S232 309.3 232 296V168zM256 416c-17.36 0-31.44-14.08-31.44-31.44c0-17.36 14.07-31.44 31.44-31.44s31.44 14.08 31.44 31.44C287.4 401.9 273.4 416 256 416z"/></svg>

  </span>


  </span>

  <span
    
      class="dark:text-neutral-300"
    ><strong>Disclaimer:</strong> This article is for personal study notes only and does not constitute any investment advice.</span>
</div>

]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>00490 Workers are just picking up trash; Mortgages are a risk for retirees; Buying a house won&#39;t make you rich.</title>
      <link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1730597712367/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1730597712367/</guid>
      <description>This session focuses on investment philosophy, asset allocation, lifestyle, and how to cope with market fluctuations. It emphasizes the importance of staying optimistic, continuous learning, and answers questions from the audience on Bitcoin, real estate, retirement planning, leveraged funds, and education funds.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<lite-youtube videoid="Ad9u7a-z6Ro" playlabel="Ad9u7a-z6Ro" params=""></lite-youtube>



<h2 class="relative group">I. Main Topic 
    <div id="i-main-topic" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-main-topic" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This session revolves around investment and life planning. The core ideas are: be optimistic about investment and keep learning, ignoring short-term market fluctuations; young people should focus on asset appreciation, with Nasdaq 100 index funds being the top choice; utilize leverage and allocate assets reasonably; retirees should plan carefully and avoid excessive debt; and one should stay optimistic and confident, avoid material comparisons, and pursue true freedom.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">II. Presentation Content 
    <div id="ii-presentation-content" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii-presentation-content" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Investment Philosophy and Market Analysis 
    <div id="investment-philosophy-and-market-analysis" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#investment-philosophy-and-market-analysis" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Market Fluctuations and Investment Mentality:</strong> The market is always fluctuating. Don&rsquo;t let short-term fluctuations affect your investment decisions. Stay optimistic.</li>
<li><strong>Currency Devaluation and Asset Appreciation:</strong> Money depreciates; only assets like stocks can preserve and increase in value. Currency devaluation is more severe in emerging countries, so it is advised to convert currency into assets. Taiwan&rsquo;s low wages and currency devaluation are related to the government&rsquo;s subsidy policies.</li>
<li><strong>Worker Mindset vs. Capitalist Mindset:</strong> Workers exchange labor for depreciating currency, while capitalists exchange currency for appreciating assets. Learn to invest and become a capitalist, exchanging &ldquo;trash&rdquo; (depreciating currency) for assets.</li>
<li><strong>Global Market Linkage:</strong> Global markets are highly interconnected, and diversifying investments into other regions has limited effectiveness. Focusing on the US stock market is recommended.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Asset Allocation Strategies 
    <div id="asset-allocation-strategies" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#asset-allocation-strategies" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Nasdaq 100 Index Funds:</strong> The preferred choice for young people. Long-term investment can yield substantial returns.  Global codes for purchasing Nasdaq 100 index funds were provided, and investing based on market conditions is recommended.</li>
<li><strong>The Importance of Cash:</strong> Cash reserves are crucial. 00864B and money market funds (like SWVXX, VOXX) are safeguards and should not be replaced with high-dividend products like SPHD, as principal safety is paramount.</li>
<li><strong>Smart Rebalancing:</strong> Suitable for those who use leveraged funds, are not retired, and have income.</li>
<li><strong>Risks of Real Estate Investment:</strong> Housing prices in the Bay Area are high, putting great pressure on young people to buy houses, which can easily lead to financial difficulties. Renting is recommended to maintain flexibility.</li>
<li><strong>Borrowing and Investment:</strong> Loans, mortgages, and car loans should be repaid with stable cash flow, not relying on stock market returns.</li>
<li><strong>Retirement Planning:</strong> Retirees should be cautious about borrowing and make plans based on the size of their retirement funds.  If retirement funds are 50 times the annual expenses, two options are available: 1. Keep the mortgage and car loan, using 2% of the retirement fund annually to cover all expenses; 2. Pay off the mortgage and car loan, invest 80% of the remaining funds in 00662, 20% in 00864B, and use 2% of the total funds annually for living expenses.</li>
<li><strong>Asset Allocation Case Study:</strong> A case study with 45 million Taiwan dollars illustrated asset allocation strategies when withdrawals are not needed. An 80/20 allocation or a combination of leveraged funds (60% 00662, 20% 00670L, 20% 00864B) is recommended.  For those with stable income and no need to withdraw from investments, 100% investment in QQQ can be considered.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Other Matters 
    <div id="other-matters" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#other-matters" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Class Suspension Notice:</strong> Class is suspended on November 9th and resumes on November 16th. After daylight saving time ends, the class time will be changed to 6:00 AM Pacific Time and 10:00 PM Taiwan time.</li>
<li><strong>Stay Optimistic:</strong> Maintain an optimistic mindset; the market will reward you. Like, subscribe, and leave comments on various platforms to benefit more people.</li>
<li><strong>Contact Information:</strong> Two email addresses were provided for contact.</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">III. Q&amp;A Session 
    <div id="iii-qa-session" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii-qa-session" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Brian: 
    <div id="brian" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#brian" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing 1: Read &ldquo;Investing is Asset Allocation, What You Don&rsquo;t Know,&rdquo; agreeing with the importance of accumulating the first pot of gold early; learning investment allows for more focus on work and personal improvement, spending time each day learning new skills and increasing self-worth.  Investment enables people to be more motivated to improve their professional skills rather than &ldquo;lying flat.&rdquo;</li>
<li>Sharing 2: Individuals can improve their earning potential through learning, even if their investment assets are reduced to zero, they can still rely on professional skills to make a comeback.</li>
<li>Question 1: What should I do if the Beta value is very low when the asset value plummets in the Excel sheet?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: The sheet is designed for acceleration during market rises and deceleration during falls. A low Beta value is normal and a reflection of risk control; no adjustment is needed.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2: Even knowing that investment should be mindless, I still worry when the Beta value drops. How should I cope?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: Deceleration during declines is the purpose of the investment strategy. Don&rsquo;t worry, stick to the plan, just like autopilot.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">LU: 
    <div id="lu" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#lu" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question 1: What is the impact of Trump&rsquo;s potential return to office on Bitcoin?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: The US has abandoned the gold standard and will not adopt a Bitcoin standard. Bitcoin is similar to gold and has an anti-inflationary function, but its future development is limited.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2: Can QQQ break through its previous high?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: It definitely can. The current market is bullish; there&rsquo;s no need to worry.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Wendy: 
    <div id="wendy" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#wendy" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing 1: Learned James&rsquo;s investment philosophy and successfully recouped the income lost during unemployment. Started reading recommended books such as &ldquo;The Richest Man in Babylon&rdquo; and &ldquo;The Most Important Thing.&rdquo;</li>
<li>No Questions</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Peter: 
    <div id="peter" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#peter" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing 1: Agrees with James&rsquo;s philosophy and has increased the investment proportion of QQQ, but some individual stocks have not been completely sold due to tax reasons.</li>
<li>Question 1: Advantages and disadvantages of converting 401K to Roth 401K?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: Just put new contributions into Roth 401K; don&rsquo;t convert existing funds. Convert at retirement.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2:  How to use HSA and 529 accounts?  Is there any problem with using a credit card to pay medical bills from an HSA?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply:  HSA, 529, and college fund accounts are not recommended because they lead to a loss of control over the funds. Using your own funds or loans is recommended.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 3: Are there any suggestions for increasing income and saving money besides a full-time job?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: Excessive saving is not recommended. Plan for retirement funds first, and the remaining money can be freely used and enjoyed.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Yi Jie (First Sister): 
    <div id="yi-jie-first-sister" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#yi-jie-first-sister" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing 1: Previously followed the advice of online influencers and invested in US stocks and treasury bonds, currently converting to QQQ.  Has a modest salary and one child.</li>
<li>Question 1: Can the 20% cash in the 80/20 allocation be replaced with Fubon 50 2X leverage?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply:  QQQ 2X leverage (00670L) is recommended. He explained the use of leveraged funds.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2: Is it feasible to regularly invest equal amounts in QQQ and 2X leverage?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: Feasible, but pay attention to cash reserves. A Beta of 1.1 or 1.2 allocation is recommended, adjusting according to market conditions.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 3: Can a child&rsquo;s Lunar New Year money be all-in on 2X leverage?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: If you can guarantee continuous regular investment for more than 30 years, it&rsquo;s worth considering, but be aware of the risks and be able to withstand significant asset shrinkage.  In the long run, the returns can be substantial, but psychological barriers must be overcome.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 4: Are the views of online influencers recommending treasury bonds correct? Are treasury bonds more valuable during a market crash?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: Incorrect. During market downturns, bond declines can be even greater.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">IAM: 
    <div id="iam" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iam" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing 1: Reflecting on the value of money, learning gratitude, and paying attention to community articles, realizing that spending money is spending one&rsquo;s life energy.</li>
<li>Sharing 2: Made 100 pages of notes and calculated the return on an 80,000 loan invested for 40 years; the result was shocking.</li>
<li>Question 1: Why are people not accustomed to borrowing for investment?  Confused about the phenomenon of young people being afraid to borrow for investment but willing to use installment plans for consumption.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: This is due to cultural influences.  Change your mindset and recognize that good debt can help accumulate wealth. Shared personal experiences and spending philosophy, emphasizing the freedom of spending after becoming wealthy.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">YJ Yuanlin: 
    <div id="yj-yuanlin" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#yj-yuanlin" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing 1: Investing boosts confidence, enabling focus on work and hobbies.</li>
<li>Question 1: In a down year, can TQQ replace QLD in smart rebalancing?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: Both are possible, but pay attention to risk control and avoid excessive pursuit of high risk. TQQ has greater volatility and requires a stronger psychological capacity.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">T: 
    <div id="t" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#t" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question 1: What are your thoughts on Elon Musk supporting Trump?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: Politicians&rsquo; decisions are the result of weighing pros and cons. Elon Musk&rsquo;s support for Trump stems from personal interests and positions, such as opposing certain liberal policies.  Entrepreneurs also have to choose between different political forces.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Yi Ni: 
    <div id="yi-ni" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#yi-ni" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question 1: How to invest and use Canadian education fund accounts?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: It&rsquo;s recommended to thoroughly research the specific rules of the account and consider methods like pledged loans to avoid locking up funds. Inquired about whether it&rsquo;s possible to withdraw all funds and the limitations, suggesting consulting with professionals.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Meng: 
    <div id="meng" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#meng" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing 1: In the high-tech era, privacy and freedom are difficult to have both.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Peter: 
    <div id="peter-1" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#peter-1" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing 1: It can be difficult for beginners to invest in QQQ, etc. It&rsquo;s suggested to start by buying one share and gradually build confidence.  James&rsquo;s explanations are very patient and benefit everyone.</li>
<li>Question 1: How to strengthen mental and psychological well-being?  James&rsquo;s experience sharing on meditation and hypnosis.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: Recommended Rachel&rsquo;s hypnosis channel and shared personal methods of using hypnosis and positive psychological suggestions. Suggested listening to hypnotic audios every night before sleep.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">IV. Key Takeaways 
    <div id="iv-key-takeaways" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv-key-takeaways" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>Rise faster, fall slower.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>This is one of James&rsquo;s core investment philosophies. Through smart rebalancing strategies, increase investment during market rises to accelerate profits, and reduce investment during market downturns to mitigate losses.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Money is the least valuable thing when it has no value.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>This reflects James&rsquo;s unique view on wealth. When wealth accumulates to a certain extent, the value of money itself is no longer important; what matters more is pursuing freedom and happiness.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>If you want freedom, and you want privacy, you will not have freedom. In the future world, if you want privacy, you will not have freedom.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>This shows James&rsquo;s insight into future social trends. In the high-tech era, one needs to make trade-offs between privacy and freedom.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The more daring one is to borrow money, the broader their perspective.
&ndash; YJ Yuanlin</p></blockquote>
<p>YJ Yuanlin&rsquo;s sharing led to James&rsquo;s views on borrowing: good debt can help wealth growth.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>If you want freedom, you cannot care.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>Echoing the topic of Elon Musk supporting Trump and the entrepreneurial spirit, true freedom is not caring about external opinions and focusing on one&rsquo;s goals.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>If you don&rsquo;t use ChatGPT now, you are outdated and will be eliminated.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>James advocates for new technologies and maintains an open attitude towards learning new things.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">V. Summary 
    <div id="v-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#v-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This session covered various aspects of investment philosophy, asset allocation, lifestyle, and how to cope with market fluctuations.  James answered the audience&rsquo;s questions with easy-to-understand language and rich examples, sharing his life experiences and insights, and encouraging everyone to stay optimistic, continue learning, and pursue true freedom and happiness.</p>

  



<div
  
    class="flex px-4 py-3 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900"
  >

  <span
    
      class="text-primary-400 ltr:pr-3 rtl:pl-3 flex items-center"
    >

    

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M506.3 417l-213.3-364c-16.33-28-57.54-28-73.98 0l-213.2 364C-10.59 444.9 9.849 480 42.74 480h426.6C502.1 480 522.6 445 506.3 417zM232 168c0-13.25 10.75-24 24-24S280 154.8 280 168v128c0 13.25-10.75 24-23.1 24S232 309.3 232 296V168zM256 416c-17.36 0-31.44-14.08-31.44-31.44c0-17.36 14.07-31.44 31.44-31.44s31.44 14.08 31.44 31.44C287.4 401.9 273.4 416 256 416z"/></svg>

  </span>


  </span>

  <span
    
      class="dark:text-neutral-300"
    ><strong>Disclaimer:</strong> This article is for personal learning notes only and does not constitute any investment advice.</span>
</div>

]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
