<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Fraud Prevention on QQQ Investor</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/tags/fraud-prevention/</link><description>Recent content in Fraud Prevention on QQQ Investor</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 21 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jomonylw.github.io/en/tags/fraud-prevention/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>00519 The Highest State of Investing: Getting Rich in Boredom, Staying Firm Amidst Risk</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1750558031341/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1750558031341/</guid><description>In this session, Teacher James emphasizes the importance of maintaining a long-term optimistic mindset in investing, sharing a transcendent attitude of &amp;#39;it has nothing to do with me&amp;#39; when facing market volatility. He provides a detailed interpretation of the core principles of asset allocation, especially the strategic significance of cash reserves, and discusses how to adjust investment strategies at different life stages. Additionally, he recommends books and films to improve one&amp;#39;s state of mind and answers specific questions from students about asset allocation, pledging, retirement planning, career choices, and preventing financial fraud.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<lite-youtube videoid="VTVj8Ez81OU" playlabel="VTVj8Ez81OU" params=""></lite-youtube>



<h2 class="relative group">I. Main Theme of the Session 
    <div id="i-main-theme-of-the-session" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-main-theme-of-the-session" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This session revolves around &ldquo;The Long-term Practice of Investment Mindset and Asset Allocation.&rdquo; The core message is that investors should cultivate a transcendent mindset of &ldquo;it has nothing to do with me,&rdquo; remaining calm in the face of external factors like international situations and economic data, and firmly believing that the market will trend upwards and reach new highs in the long run. It emphasizes achieving financial freedom through reasonable asset allocation (e.g., Nasdaq 100 index funds combined with ample cash) and passive management, and drawing strength for life and investment from wisdom such as &ldquo;I might be wrong&rdquo; and &ldquo;life is worthwhile.&rdquo;</p>


<h2 class="relative group">II. Briefing Content 
    <div id="ii-briefing-content" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii-briefing-content" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Investment Mindset and Market Outlook 
    <div id="investment-mindset-and-market-outlook" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#investment-mindset-and-market-outlook" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>The Market Irrelevance Theory</strong>: Macro factors like international situations, financial reports, economic data, and interest rate decisions have no direct correlation with an individual investor&rsquo;s long-term success. One should adopt a mindset of &ldquo;it all has nothing to do with me.&rdquo; Market volatility is normal and not worth worrying about, as you can&rsquo;t control it anyway.</li>
<li><strong>Always Be Extremely Optimistic</strong>: Firmly believe that the market will inevitably rise and set new historical highs in the long run. Investing requires patience, and wealth is worth the trouble and the wait.</li>
<li><strong>Recommended Books/Films for the Mind</strong>:
<ol>
<li><strong>&ldquo;I Might Be Wrong&rdquo;</strong> (The Illumination of a Forest Sage): This book recounts the life insights of a man (from Europe, as the teacher recalls) who spent over a decade (perhaps 14 or 16 years) as a monk in a Thai forest. The core takeaway is to tell yourself &ldquo;I might be wrong&rdquo; three times before arguing or getting angry, to calm your mind and self-reflect. It emphasizes practicing the state of &ldquo;no-self&rdquo; and learning to live harmoniously with all kinds of people.</li>
<li><strong>&ldquo;Life is Worthwhile&rdquo;</strong> (Audiobook): This book contains the professional insights and life experiences of an elderly female Japanese psychiatrist. Through numerous patient cases, it explores how many psychological barriers stem from &ldquo;attachment.&rdquo; Her life experiences (e.g., maintaining a less-than-perfect marriage until her husband passed away in his 70s so that both parents could stand on the stage at their children&rsquo;s weddings) are thought-provoking. The core message is to let go of attachments and appreciate life. The teacher believes that, aside from the somewhat fatalistic view on marriage, the book is very beneficial for one&rsquo;s outlook on life.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li><strong>Boredom is the Highest State</strong>: &ldquo;Hold stocks in your hand, but not their prices in your heart.&rdquo; True investing should be boring, requiring only 5 minutes of operation and review each year. If it feels exciting, you&rsquo;re likely speculating or gambling, as if you&rsquo;re in Las Vegas.</li>
<li><strong>Coping with Anxiety</strong>: Don&rsquo;t create your own troubles in life. If you can handle something, face it and get it done. If you can&rsquo;t, since it&rsquo;s beyond your control, let it go without worry.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Asset Allocation and Risk Management 
    <div id="asset-allocation-and-risk-management" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#asset-allocation-and-risk-management" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>The Importance of Cash is King</strong>:
<ul>
<li><strong>For Retirees</strong>: It&rsquo;s recommended to hold total assets equivalent to 50 times your annual expenses. Of this, 30% of your assets (equivalent to 15 years of living expenses) should be held in cash or short-term treasury bonds. With 15 years of living expenses in cash, nothing in the world concerns you.</li>
<li><strong>For Working Individuals</strong>: You usually can&rsquo;t hold 15 years&rsquo; worth of cash. You should continue to save and invest, and the world&rsquo;s affairs also have nothing to do with you.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>The Ultimate Perspective of Life</strong>: In life-or-death moments (like the last day of your life), wealth, stock losses, and asset security become irrelevant. Therefore, don&rsquo;t worry excessively about things you can&rsquo;t control in daily life.</li>
<li><strong>Initial Asset Allocation Principles (Pledged Investing)</strong>:
<ul>
<li><strong>Beta Control</strong>: The initial Beta of your asset allocation should not exceed 1.0. For example, a 40% non-leveraged fund (QQQ) + 30% leveraged fund (QLD) + 30% cash (433 allocation) is an aggressive setup. A 40% QQQ + 20% QLD + 40% cash (424 allocation, Beta 0.8) is also a solid choice. Aggressive allocations like 442, where the Beta might exceed 1.2, are not recommended at the beginning.</li>
<li><strong>Proportion Limits</strong>: The market value of the leveraged fund should not exceed that of the non-leveraged fund, nor should it exceed the cash position.</li>
<li><strong>Prudent Choices</strong>: Even without using leveraged funds, a pledged allocation like 70% QQQ + 30% cash, or 60% QQQ + 40% cash, can withstand risk tests. Prioritize stability, with returns being secondary.</li>
<li><strong>Coping with Extreme Scenarios</strong>: This allocation must be able to withstand a market downturn lasting 10 years, like the one in 2000 (in reality, it took about 13-15 years for the market to fully recover and significantly surpass its previous high).</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>The Role of Cash</strong>: Cash is key to protecting the safety of your long-term investments (the &ldquo;army&rdquo; of non-leveraged funds and the &ldquo;marines&rdquo; of leveraged funds).</li>
<li><strong>The Worst-Case Scenario Principle</strong>: Envision the worst possible situation and create a plan to deal with it. Once you have a solution, anxiety will diminish. For example, if you get laid off, the worst case is being unable to find a job for a year. Plan how to prepare funds and how to find a temporary job for cash flow. For disasters beyond your control that you can&rsquo;t prevent (like a nuclear war, as Buffett mentioned, or a meteor hitting Earth), worrying is useless, so let it go.</li>
<li><strong>A Long-Term Investor&rsquo;s Perspective</strong>: Don&rsquo;t fear market downturns; instead, fear that the market rises too quickly, preventing you from buying enough (like the market&rsquo;s rapid rebound after the tariff war). Downturns are buying opportunities. Resolutely do not sell core assets (like QQQ, 00662). It takes multiple experiences (e.g., 7 major slumps) to learn to buy the dip. You can choose not to buy, but you must never sell.</li>
<li><strong>Discipline for Leveraged Investing</strong>: A reminder that for leveraged investing, the initial cash allocation must exceed 30% (40% is also fine), with limits on the proportion of leveraged funds and a Beta not exceeding 1.0. This is emphasized because too many people ask the same questions and make allocation mistakes.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Spreading and Learning the Investment Philosophy 
    <div id="spreading-and-learning-the-investment-philosophy" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#spreading-and-learning-the-investment-philosophy" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>The Importance of Accompaniment</strong>: Investment success isn&rsquo;t just talk; it requires long-term accompaniment and guidance. Teacher James is dedicated to this, hoping to awaken more people to capitalism and that his followers will pass on the philosophy, change the world, and free themselves and those around them from financial worries.</li>
<li><strong>Learning Resources</strong>: Newcomers are advised to start with videos 00451 &ldquo;An Investment Lecture for Value Investors,&rdquo; 00398, 399, 400, 401, etc., and understand them in the context of the current market. The main recommendation is the Nasdaq 100 index fund (like QQQ), combined with cash or short-term treasury bonds. Relevant handouts and links will be provided on the Clubhouse message board and in the pinned comment on YouTube.</li>
<li><strong>Call for Promotion</strong>: We hope everyone will subscribe, leave comments, and like our content on all platforms where you find our channel. Subscriptions and likes help promote the videos to a wider audience. Although the click-through rate is not high (about 5.5%), it is still an important way to spread the word.</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">III. Q&amp;A Session 
    <div id="iii-qa-session" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii-qa-session" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Ba 
    <div id="ba" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ba" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing 1: I&rsquo;ve watched every episode this year and find that the Clubhouse platform has the most comprehensive information and links. YouTube Music is also a good experience, but finding consecutive episodes on YouTube can be a bit inconvenient. I hope there could be a central place for all handouts and links shared by the teacher.
<ul>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo;s Comment: The YouTube channel has playlists, such as the &ldquo;Weekly ClubHouse&rdquo; series which already has 39 entries and can be played in order. There is also a playlist for short videos with 595 clips. Using playlists makes it easy to listen continuously.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 1: In the smart rebalancing model you mentioned, during an uptrend, 30% of the profits from QLD are moved to SGOV, and during a downtrend, 2% of SGOV is moved to QLD. Is this 2% related to the previously mentioned &ldquo;using 2% of your assets annually for living expenses&rdquo;?
<ul>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo;s Reply: In smart rebalancing, during an up year, you move 30% of that year&rsquo;s appreciation from the leveraged fund (like QLD) into cash (like SGOV). In a down year, you move 2% of your total assets (equivalent to a portion of living expenses or a planned investment amount) from cash into the leveraged fund. For retirees, the core principle is to ensure your cash reserve can last at least 15 years, because after a market peak, it might take up to 15 years for a non-leveraged fund (QQQ) to have a high probability of doubling. For example, if you start with 50% cash and 50% QQQ, and the market falls for several years while you rebalance, you must ensure the remaining cash can still cover living expenses for (15 years - years passed). A strategy of 70% QQQ + 30% cash, without touching the cash for 15 years, is another option. The key is the &ldquo;15-year cash buffer.&rdquo;</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2: The total assets of the U.S. are about $200 trillion (200T), with the stock market being about $50T. What comprises the other $150T? Is there an index to track the flow of funds between the stock market and cash?
<ul>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo;s Reply: The remaining assets include real estate, mineral resources, various physical assets, etc. There is currently no specific public index tracking this kind of macro fund flow. The total assets of the U.S. are enormous and grow substantially each year (e.g., by $20-30T). Its debt (about $36T) is not a major issue relative to its total assets and annual growth, so the public shouldn&rsquo;t worry too much. In comparison, an individual investor&rsquo;s balance sheet risk might be higher. As for the claim that Social Security is going bankrupt, I&rsquo;ve been hearing that for 40 years. There&rsquo;s no need to worry; the U.S. can solve it. The Social Security fund itself is more like a pay-as-you-go system, where contributions from new workers pay for retirees&rsquo; benefits, rather than a massive investment fund.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Kevin 
    <div id="kevin" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#kevin" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing 1: I am an investor from mainland China and also a Christian. Last year, I sold a primary residence and invested the funds. I feel like a steward of money with a responsibility to manage it well. I originally planned to dollar-cost average into USD and have opened an account in Hong Kong. After listening to your classes recently, I&rsquo;ve been deeply moved by your selfless dedication and strongly agree with your investment philosophy. My current plan is to use my wife&rsquo;s and my annual $50,000 foreign exchange quotas to transfer funds to Longbridge Securities and gradually buy assets like QQQ. I&rsquo;ve also bought some 513100 in the domestic A-share market. Our total capital is about 3 million RMB. I plan to deploy most of it in Longbridge Securities within six months, keeping a small portion domestically. Is this a reasonable approach? I considered using HSBC for pledging, but the threshold is high (over 1 million HKD), transferring from Longbridge to HSBC has fees, and HSBC&rsquo;s management fees might be high. I plan to wait until I have enough capital to transfer it to HSBC all at once.
<ul>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo;s Comment: Your approach is reasonable. You can first accumulate assets in Longbridge Securities and then transfer them in one go when your capital reaches HSBC&rsquo;s pledging threshold or when you are ready to pledge. This is more economical. Investors in mainland China generally lack financial literacy; many get hurt after entering the market blindly and then stay away, including Kevin&rsquo;s own wife who suffered losses in the stock market in 2015 due to the wrong philosophy.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Sharing 2: I deeply resonate with your sharing on both the &ldquo;technique&rdquo; (术) of investing and the &ldquo;way&rdquo; (道) of life. I also listen to Pastor Stephen Tong&rsquo;s sermons and have many reflections. Thank you for your efforts. You&rsquo;ve mentioned Confucius and Zhuangzi; I was wondering if you&rsquo;ve come across Pastor Tong&rsquo;s sharing on these topics?
<ul>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo;s Comment: Thank you for sharing, Kevin. I haven&rsquo;t specifically listened to Pastor Stephen Tong&rsquo;s sharing, but I maintain an open and learning attitude towards various religious and philosophical thoughts (Christianity, Buddhism, etc.). If it&rsquo;s recommended to me, I&rsquo;ll listen, as I believe all great truths are interconnected. The core of investing is this: we own companies (like the 100 companies represented by QQQ), and we shouldn&rsquo;t sell them easily just because of external opinions on their stock prices (Mr. Market&rsquo;s neurotic quotes). Focus on long-term holding and accumulating shares, just like accumulating real estate, but with better liquidity. Investing should be passive and simple. You only need to spend 5 minutes at the end of the year (e.g., Dec 31st or the market open on Jan 2nd or 3rd) to rebalance once. Avoid emotional trading based on short-term market fluctuations, which will only get you into trouble, like being influenced by Mr. Market and becoming a &ldquo;lunatic&rsquo;s lunatic.&rdquo;</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Huayin 
    <div id="huayin" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#huayin" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question 1: In your Excel model for maintenance margin calculation, are leveraged funds excluded? Is this also the case in Taiwan?
<ul>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo;s Reply: Yes, in the models of U.S. brokerages, leveraged funds usually cannot be used to calculate maintenance margin because they cannot be pledged themselves. If a Taiwanese brokerage allows leveraged funds to be pledged, its risk tolerance would be better, and the calculated maintenance margin might include the leveraged portion.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2: My investment journey has been: 0056 (high-dividend) -&gt; 0050 (Taiwan 50) -&gt; 00646 (S&amp;P 500 ETF) -&gt; 00662 (Nasdaq 100 ETF). I recently re-listened to one of your earlier sessions (possibly 00451 or another early one) where you mentioned that if one doesn&rsquo;t have enough money, they could buy 0056 and live off the 4% annual dividend for retirement. Did I misunderstand? It feels like I&rsquo;ve come full circle.
<ul>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo;s Reply: You didn&rsquo;t mishear. Different strategies apply to different life stages and asset sizes. If you are still relatively young, you can use a 433 (QQQ non-leveraged, QLD leveraged, cash) allocation for aggressive growth. If you are close to retirement and your assets are not enough to support a 2% annual withdrawal (i.e., total assets 50 times your annual expenses)—for example, you need 1 million per year but have less than 50 million, maybe only 30 million—then a less volatile option like 00646 (S&amp;P 500) with a 3% annual withdrawal might be a choice. If your assets are even smaller (e.g., only 20 or 25 million), then a high-dividend ETF like 0056, withdrawing the 4% dividend to supplement your living expenses, is a reluctant but realistic option. The 0056 plan is for special cases of insufficient assets; the mainstream, ideal allocation is still centered around QQQ.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 3: If I am about to retire and the market happens to be in a major downturn, at a low point in the model, how should I reposition my assets and plan my living expense withdrawals?
<ul>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo;s Reply: You should base your 2% annual living expense calculation on the total asset value at the market&rsquo;s peak before your retirement. For example, if you had 50 million at the peak and planned to spend 1 million a year. Even if the market then drops for three years and your assets shrink to 25 million, you should still try to maintain your 1 million annual living standard (if your cash reserves allow). Because the market has already been down for several years, the risk is actually lower. You&rsquo;ve passed a three-year window, and you should trust that the market will recover in the coming cycle (15 years minus the years passed).</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 4: I am a Taiwanese investor and I buy 00662 with TWD. If the TWD appreciates significantly in the future, will my assets shrink as a result?
<ul>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo;s Reply: In the long run (e.g., 20, 30, or even over 40 years), the impact of currency fluctuations tends to approach zero. For instance, the TWD/USD exchange rate has historically fluctuated between 25 and 33. Your buying and selling (or spending) is a continuous process, not a single point in time. So, don&rsquo;t worry too much about currency issues; it&rsquo;s not within our consideration.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 5: There&rsquo;s a U.S. law (the student mentioned &ldquo;Law 899,&rdquo; possibly referring to FATCA or another tax law for foreigners), will it affect us Taiwanese investors?
<ul>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo;s Reply: That (usually referring to FATCA, etc.) has little to do with Taiwanese people, so don&rsquo;t worry. It mainly targets countries with unequal tax treaties or reciprocal relationships with the U.S., like some G7 countries in Europe (Germany, France, UK, etc.).</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Rui 
    <div id="rui" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#rui" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Thanks for your previous advice on my work issue; my mindset at work has improved a lot. I recall reading the book &ldquo;I Might Be Wrong&rdquo; (the author is Swedish) and noted down two points: 1. Secular success doesn&rsquo;t necessarily bring happiness. 2. Focusing on your breath can train your brain. I didn&rsquo;t quite understand it back then.</li>
<li>Question 1: With your rich experience and having reached your current level, what do you think ultimate happiness is? Also, there are many methods for practicing breathing now (like in yoga); do you have any specific experience with learning to breathe?
<ul>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo;s Reply:
<ul>
<li><strong>Breathing</strong>: It&rsquo;s very simple, just &ldquo;observe your breath&rdquo; (观呼吸). Notice your own inhales and exhales, know that you are breathing. This is observing the breath. Doing so will naturally clear your mind, eliminate distracting thoughts, and enter a state of &ldquo;presence,&rdquo; a relaxed state focused on the now. We often forget we are breathing during the day, which means we are in a tense state.</li>
<li><strong>Happiness</strong>: Happiness is not determined by secular success or external evaluation. The value of a stock has nothing to do with me. The only thing to focus on is yourself. True happiness comes from within. Practice methods: 1. Observe your breath. 2. Practice introspection (similar to meditation or Christian prayer), empty your mind. 3. Relax your entire body (from head to toe), you can lie down, sit in a chair, or sit cross-legged. 4. Enter a hypnotic state (possible after long practice). 5. In the hypnotic state, give yourself positive affirmations (Re-programming), for example, tell yourself &ldquo;I am happy, I am happy, I am happy,&rdquo; &ldquo;I am wealthy, I am wealthy, I am wealthy,&rdquo; &ldquo;All the money in the world is mine, all the money in the world is mine, all the money in the world is mine,&rdquo; &ldquo;All the market&rsquo;s money is mine,&rdquo; &ldquo;My stocks will always go up, up, up, up, only up and never down.&rdquo; Curve your lips upwards, practice smiling. Happiness needs practice. This is the basic skill of hypnotherapy. I recommend the &ldquo;Rachel&rsquo;s Hypnosis Channel&rdquo; on YouTube, which has many guided sessions for different needs (like improving sleep, increasing wealth, relaxation).</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2: I previously had some money in Firstrade (about 4 million TWD, 5-6% of my total assets). Recently, I&rsquo;ve heard some concerns about overseas brokerages and plan to wire this money back to Taiwan. My current asset allocation is 433. After this money comes back, should I directly convert it to TWD and buy 00670L (Taiwan&rsquo;s Nasdaq leveraged ETF), or should I use this &ldquo;small amount of money&rdquo; to invest in QLD (since the amount is not large, it won&rsquo;t exceed the 7.5 million TWD tax exemption for overseas income by much)? I want to slightly adjust my overall allocation from 433 to 424.
<ul>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo;s Reply: As long as your total cash reserve remains above 30%, the market value of your leveraged fund does not exceed your non-leveraged fund or your cash position, and the overall Beta of your portfolio does not exceed 1.0, you can proceed as you wish.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Brian 
    <div id="brian" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#brian" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: I always wanted to be a &ldquo;big shot&rdquo; (senior manager), so I left a large company for a VP role at a small Singaporean firm. My salary doubled, but my workload also doubled. I was basically working 7 days a week, 18 hours a day, with no personal time, not even on Sundays or evenings. What was worse, in my third or fourth week, during a meeting with the company&rsquo;s CTO, he was extremely rude (saying things like &ldquo;a one-year-old child could have made your presentation,&rdquo; and &ldquo;what did I hire you for?&rdquo;). I was very upset and felt verbally abused. Then I remembered your words and realized it wasn&rsquo;t worth it. I contacted my former boss at the big company (who said, &ldquo;Didn&rsquo;t you say you were going on leave?&rdquo;), and he welcomed me back. I quickly resigned and returned to my old company. Although I&rsquo;m not a &ldquo;big shot,&rdquo; I feel it was the right decision. That one month at the small company was miserable; there was no happiness. It seems more money can&rsquo;t buy happiness.
<ul>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo;s Comment: Brian, you did the absolutely right thing! Cutting your losses in time and leaving an unsuitable environment is crucial. Just as we shouldn&rsquo;t buy or sell based on stock price fluctuations, we shouldn&rsquo;t choose or leave a job solely based on salary. Happiness is priceless, &ldquo;worth a thousand pieces of gold,&rdquo; and far more important than a high salary. When considering a job, the first question to ask is &ldquo;Am I happy?&rdquo; If you&rsquo;re not, you should leave. Happiness is a human right. You shouldn&rsquo;t accept anything that makes you unhappy. First, remove external sources of unhappiness, then cultivate inner happiness. Young people should try to work for large companies. They have more resources, better systems, and you can learn more (learn systems, management, learn in a big ocean), and the career paths are broader. If you encounter a bad manager or department in a large company, consider an internal transfer (the manager might be transferred, but a good company will remain), rather than resigning hastily. I myself proactively sought an opportunity to be transferred from Acer Taiwan to the US.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">L 
    <div id="l" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#l" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question: I am an old student who started following you during the market low in 2002, and you gave me a lot of confidence back then. Recently, there&rsquo;s a trend in our group to share that if you use a large amount of cash from your pledged loan, you should prepare twice the borrowed amount in cash as a buffer. To meet this requirement, I sold some of my QLD to supplement my cash, which brought my Beta down very low. Now, I have a new sum of money coming in. Should I use it to pay back part of the loan, or to buy back the QLD I sold? Cheng Feng&rsquo;s advice was that if you use a large sum of money, you need to adjust the entire portfolio proportionally, including the non-leveraged fund (QQQ). Does this conflict with your frequent advice to &ldquo;never sell the core fund&rdquo;? Also, I think Kate said that new funds coming in shouldn&rsquo;t be used to return to a fixed ratio allocation? I&rsquo;m very confused and feel like I haven&rsquo;t grasped the core idea after following you for so long.
<ul>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo;s Reply: Cheng Feng&rsquo;s understanding is correct. When you &ldquo;borrow and spend&rdquo; a large amount of cash from your pledged account (e.g., 10% or more of your total assets, like borrowing 1 million from a 10 million total asset base), this is a special situation that requires a &ldquo;re-navigation&rdquo; or &ldquo;re-positioning&rdquo; of your entire asset allocation.
<ul>
<li><strong>Example and Adjustment Steps</strong>: Let&rsquo;s say you originally had 10 million in assets with a 433 allocation: 4 million in QQQ, 3 million in QLD, and 3 million in cash. Now, you need to borrow and spend 1 million for an emergency.
<ol>
<li>For this 1 million loan, you need to set aside an additional 2 million in cash as a risk buffer (because you borrowed 1 million, you prepare 2 million in cash).</li>
<li>So, out of your 10 million total assets, 2 million in cash is specifically designated to cover this loan risk. The remaining 8 million (10 million - 2 million) is then allocated according to your target allocation (e.g., 433, or adjusted to a more conservative Beta of 0.8, which corresponds to a certain proportion). Specifically, a 433 allocation for 8 million would be: 3.2M QQQ, 2.4M QLD, 2.4M operational cash. Add the 2M risk buffer, and your total cash is 4.4M. In this case, the leveraged fund is 2.4M, which is 24% of the 10M total assets, contributing a Beta of 0.48; the non-leveraged fund is 3.2M, contributing a Beta of 0.32. The total Beta is 0.8.</li>
<li>In this situation, selling a portion of your existing QQQ and QLD proportionally and combining it with your existing cash to create the 2 million risk buffer and the cash needed for the new allocation is a reasonable &ldquo;asset structure adjustment.&rdquo; It&rsquo;s not considered a &ldquo;sale that violates the never-sell principle.&rdquo;</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li><strong>New Capital Injection</strong>: When you have new funds coming in (like the new capital you mentioned), you can use them to restore your QLD position or to supplement the relevant parts of your &ldquo;re-navigated&rdquo; target allocation (which might be Beta 0.8). Restoring QLD to bring the Beta back to 0.8 is fine; it doesn&rsquo;t have to go back to 1.0.</li>
<li><strong>Kate&rsquo;s Viewpoint</strong>: What Kate said about &ldquo;new funds not being used to return to a fixed ratio&rdquo; usually refers to routine, small-scale additions of capital. In that case, you don&rsquo;t need to strictly follow the initial 433 ratio; you can flexibly add to the part you feel needs strengthening the most (e.g., add to cash if it&rsquo;s low, or add to the leveraged position if you want to increase it). This is a different scenario from the &ldquo;re-allocation&rdquo; after a &ldquo;large withdrawal and spending&rdquo; that you described. When a plane is on autopilot, small adjustments are fine. But if the number of passengers changes significantly or the destination changes, you need to re-plan the route and fuel.</li>
<li><strong>Conclusion</strong>: Under normal autopilot (small fund inflows/outflows or rebalancing due to market fluctuations), the core asset is not easily touched. But when a major event like a large withdrawal for spending occurs, changing the overall risk structure, you need to re-evaluate and adjust the entire allocation. Following for a long time doesn&rsquo;t guarantee you&rsquo;ve learned well; the key is to learn the core principles.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">JASON 
    <div id="jason" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#jason" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: I want to share some risk points about the direct selling (or MLM) industry, as I heard a user mention wanting to return to Taiwan to do direct selling to change their situation.
<ol>
<li><strong>High entry fees</strong>: Be wary of these.</li>
<li><strong>No substantial product or service</strong>: Or the price of the product/service is severely disconnected from its market value (e.g., selling wine from Maotai Town at an exorbitant price; something worth a few hundred sold for thousands).</li>
<li><strong>Focus on recruiting downlines, ignoring consumer experience</strong>.</li>
<li><strong>Different purchase prices for agents at different levels</strong>.</li>
<li><strong>Promises of quick riches through IPOs, dividends, or stock options</strong>: Especially with newly established companies that lure you into buying a lot of inventory at once.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li><strong>Advice for Choosing Direct Selling</strong>:
<ol>
<li><strong>Mainland China</strong>: Look for companies with a direct selling license issued by the Ministry of Commerce (a total of 88), which are relatively legitimate. There are now many new retail, social e-commerce, and micro-business models whose underlying logic may be similar.</li>
<li><strong>US or other regions</strong>: Choose companies that have been established for over 10 years, preferably publicly listed ones (financial reports are public and transparent, and can be analyzed). Only about 10% of new companies survive for three to five years; most fail within five years.</li>
<li><strong>Long-termism</strong>: Even with legitimate direct selling, it requires long-term commitment (at least 5 years). Don&rsquo;t expect to get rich quick. If it feels like a &ldquo;great opportunity&rdquo; for rapid change, there&rsquo;s a high risk of being scammed.</li>
<li><strong>Beware of &ldquo;Direct Selling + Insurance&rdquo; models</strong>: In the US, services can also be sold via direct selling. The combination of direct selling and insurance requires special caution, as it can be highly deceptive, seeming to offer both income and security. Chinese direct selling law requires physical products and a factory.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo;s Comment: JASON&rsquo;s reminder is excellent; scams are everywhere. Everyone should be wary of messages that demand urgent action (e.g., &ldquo;Your payment of $698 has been successful, please call this number if you have questions&rdquo;), or else your account will be frozen, your package will be lost, or that urge you to pay first. You can use AI tools like ChatGPT to make a preliminary judgment on the authenticity of an email (I once used ChatGPT to verify a DMV email). Remember, nothing is that urgent. Take a deep breath, think calmly, and don&rsquo;t part with your money easily. When people are eager to do something (like get rich), they are more likely to be scammed. I myself had an experience in high school with a summer job scam that cost me 300 TWD; I paid the fee and the person disappeared.</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">IV. Highlights / Key Quotes 
    <div id="iv-highlights--key-quotes" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv-highlights--key-quotes" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>The market is truly unrelated to international situations, financial reports, or the economy. Whether interest rates are cut or not doesn&rsquo;t matter, it&rsquo;s all fine, it has nothing to do with us. It all has nothing to do with me.
&ndash; Teacher James</p></blockquote>
<p>This viewpoint, woven throughout the session, emphasizes the transcendent mindset an investor should have, focusing on their own investment discipline and not being distracted by external noise.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The market will definitely go up, the market will definitely reach new highs. Investing requires patience, and wealth is worth the trouble.
&ndash; Teacher James</p></blockquote>
<p>This articulates a firm belief in the long-term trend of the market and the character required for successful investing—patience.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>I might be wrong. I might be wrong. I might be wrong.
&ndash; Teacher James (quoting from the book &ldquo;I Might Be Wrong&rdquo;)</p></blockquote>
<p>When facing disagreements or strong emotions, engaging in self-reflection first can help resolve conflicts and enhance cognition and inner peace.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Hold stocks in your hand, but not their prices in your heart. You only need to spend five minutes a year on it.
&ndash; Teacher James</p></blockquote>
<p>This describes the ideal state of investing: holding quality assets without being disturbed by short-term price fluctuations, emphasizing the simplicity and passive nature of investing.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Boredom is the highest state of investing. If you feel it&rsquo;s exciting, then you&rsquo;re speculating, you&rsquo;re gambling.
&ndash; Teacher James</p></blockquote>
<p>This reveals the true nature of long-term value investing, drawing a clear line between it and the thrill-seeking behavior of speculation.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>If you can handle something, face it and get it done. If you can&rsquo;t handle it, then forget about it, as it&rsquo;s not within your capability.
&ndash; Teacher James</p></blockquote>
<p>This offers a philosophical attitude for dealing with various problems in life and investing, reducing unnecessary worries.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Absolutely do not sell your QQQ, sell your 00662, during a downturn. You can choose not to buy, but you must never sell.
&ndash; Teacher James</p></blockquote>
<p>This emphasizes that one should not panic-sell core quality assets during a market correction, a common mistake among investors.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Don&rsquo;t leave (your current job) because your salary is low, and don&rsquo;t jump to another just because its salary is high.
&ndash; Teacher James (commenting on Brian&rsquo;s sharing)</p></blockquote>
<p>This highlights that in career choices, personal happiness and the growth environment are more important than short-term salary.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Your cash must be able to last you 15 years (during a market downturn). This is a critical key.
&ndash; Teacher James (on asset allocation for retirees)</p></blockquote>
<p>This points out the importance of having cash reserves in retirement planning that can cover a long bear market (which could last up to 15 years before the market doubles).</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Happiness is a human right. Therefore, you shouldn&rsquo;t accept anything that makes you unhappy.
&ndash; Teacher James (commenting on Brian&rsquo;s sharing)</p></blockquote>
<p>This encourages people to prioritize inner happiness and harmony in their work and life, and to have the courage to change unhappy situations.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">V. Summary 
    <div id="v-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#v-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>In this sharing session, Teacher James once again reinforced the core philosophy of long-term investing: maintain optimism, adhere to discipline, and filter out market noise with the wisdom of &ldquo;it has nothing to do with me.&rdquo; By recommending &ldquo;I Might Be Wrong&rdquo; and &ldquo;Life is Worthwhile,&rdquo; he guided students to cultivate their inner selves, focus on breathing and relaxation, and achieve harmony in both investing and life. In terms of asset allocation, the teacher detailed cash management strategies for different life stages, especially the importance of having 15 years of living expenses for retirees to safely navigate market cycles, and gave clear guidance on pledging, leverage, and Beta control. The Q&amp;A session delved into specific cases, addressing students&rsquo; confusion in practical operations, such as portfolio adjustments after large cash withdrawals, tax considerations for overseas investments, the wisdom of career choices, and preventing financial scams like direct selling. The teacher encouraged students to work and live in a relaxed, stress-free state, to simplify investing, and ultimately achieve financial freedom and life happiness. He emphasized investing in index funds like QQQ/00662 and avoiding annuities and unnecessary insurance.</p>

  



<div
  
    class="flex px-4 py-3 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900"
  >

  <span
    
      class="text-primary-400 ltr:pr-3 rtl:pl-3 flex items-center"
    >

    

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M506.3 417l-213.3-364c-16.33-28-57.54-28-73.98 0l-213.2 364C-10.59 444.9 9.849 480 42.74 480h426.6C502.1 480 522.6 445 506.3 417zM232 168c0-13.25 10.75-24 24-24S280 154.8 280 168v128c0 13.25-10.75 24-23.1 24S232 309.3 232 296V168zM256 416c-17.36 0-31.44-14.08-31.44-31.44c0-17.36 14.07-31.44 31.44-31.44s31.44 14.08 31.44 31.44C287.4 401.9 273.4 416 256 416z"/></svg>

  </span>


  </span>

  <span
    
      class="dark:text-neutral-300"
    ><strong>Disclaimer:</strong> This article is for personal study notes only and does not constitute any investment advice.</span>
</div>

]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>00514 Cash Level and Risk Tolerance: Investor's Psychological Quality and Allocation Logic; Preserving Wealth Requires Humility and Respect for the Market</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1747557009031/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1747557009031/</guid><description>In this lecture, Teacher James reiterates the core philosophy of long-term investing, pointing out that market fluctuations are irrelevant to investors; the key is to hold sufficient cash and adhere to correct asset allocation. He warns investors against impersonation scams and shares wisdom on dealing with market volatility, currency fluctuations, and personal financial planning. The lecture also delves into practical issues such as stock pledging, tax planning, and selecting investment tools in different regions.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<lite-youtube videoid="8_7Y1pN5rYk" playlabel="8_7Y1pN5rYk" params=""></lite-youtube>



<h2 class="relative group">I. Theme of the Current Session 
    <div id="i-theme-of-the-current-session" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-theme-of-the-current-session" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>The core theme of this lecture is <strong>&ldquo;What Does Market Volatility Have to Do with Me? Adhering to the Discipline and Wisdom of Long-Term Investing&rdquo;</strong>. Teacher James emphasizes that investors should ignore short-term market fluctuations and not panic-sell stocks as a result. Correct asset allocation, sufficient cash reserves, and unwavering long-term conviction are key to navigating market cycles. Teacher James also reminds everyone to be wary of financial scams and provides specific guidance on issues such as stock pledging, leverage, taxation, and personal financial planning.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">II. Briefing Content 
    <div id="ii-briefing-content" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii-briefing-content" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Fraud Prevention and Official Contact Channels 
    <div id="fraud-prevention-and-official-contact-channels" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#fraud-prevention-and-official-contact-channels" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Beware of Impersonation</strong>: Recently, someone has been using Teacher James&rsquo;s logo and name, claiming to be Teacher James&rsquo;s alternate account on platforms like Clubhouse to make private contact. Everyone must be vigilant and not be deceived. Teacher James has only one Clubhouse account, ID: <code>CLECchairman</code>.</li>
<li><strong>Official Contact Methods</strong>:
<ul>
<li>Clubhouse: Participate directly in lectures (Teacher James&rsquo;s ID is <code>CLECchairman</code>, please verify).</li>
<li>Email: <code>changeismoney@gmail.com</code> and <code>CRCdirectorgmail.com</code>. Provided at the end of the briefing.</li>
<li>YouTube comments.</li>
<li>Facebook comments.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Teacher James will not proactively contact students</strong>. Any proactive contact requesting information or offering investment guidance is a scam.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Core Investment Philosophy: Market Volatility Has Nothing to Do with Me 
    <div id="core-investment-philosophy-market-volatility-has-nothing-to-do-with-me" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#core-investment-philosophy-market-volatility-has-nothing-to-do-with-me" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Don&rsquo;t Sell Stocks</strong>: Market volatility is normal and irrelevant to the goals of long-term investors; do not sell stocks because of it. &ldquo;Don&rsquo;t sell stocks, don&rsquo;t sell stocks, don&rsquo;t sell stocks&rdquo; is the core discipline.</li>
<li><strong>Importance of Asset Allocation</strong>: Proper asset allocation (e.g., retirees at least 30% cash, or 10-15 years of living expenses; young people at least 1 year of living expenses in cash) ensures a worry-free life during extreme market conditions (such as the 10-year market downturn after the 2000 tech bubble), preventing panicked and reckless operations.
<ul>
<li>For example, with 2% annual living expenses, holding 15 years of cash means 30% cash. If holding 40% cash, then there are 20 years of living expenses.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Harm of Reckless Operations</strong>: Some people panic due to market declines after pledging stocks, and their reckless operations lead to difficult situations. If you have enough cash and don&rsquo;t operate recklessly, there won&rsquo;t be problems.</li>
<li><strong>Understanding Market Phenomena</strong>:
<ul>
<li><strong>Physical Phenomenon vs. Chemical Phenomenon</strong>: Events like tariff wars are physical phenomena (like blowing up a balloon, there&rsquo;s push and pull, eventually finding an equilibrium), not chemical phenomena (permanent change, irreversible). Therefore, short-term factors like international situations, market analysis, financial reports, economic conditions, and celebrity remarks (e.g., Trump&rsquo;s speeches) are irrelevant to long-term investment strategy.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Beware of Inner &ldquo;Demons and Monsters&rdquo;</strong>:
<ul>
<li>When thoughts like &ldquo;What should I do if the market drops next?&rdquo; or &ldquo;The market keeps rising, I should sell some and buy back when it falls?&rdquo; arise, these are inner &ldquo;demons and monsters&rdquo; at play, a very dangerous signal, and such thinking should stop immediately.</li>
<li>When you think, &ldquo;Wow, I&rsquo;ve made so much money, I&rsquo;ve struck it rich, I&rsquo;m wealthy!&rdquo; this is also a dangerous signal; greed has appeared.</li>
<li>When you think, &ldquo;How can it keep falling like this? What if the market drops to zero, what will I do?&rdquo; this is the emergence of the &ldquo;demon&rdquo; of fear.</li>
<li>Greed and fear stem from feelings about the market. View the market like a variety show; financial media and analysts are like hosts and guests—just laugh it off. If you can watch market fluctuations (like a 10% rise or fall in a day) without any inner turmoil, then you can pay attention to the market.</li>
<li>The goal is &ldquo;it will definitely rise in 20 years&rdquo;; short-term corrections are normal.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Investment Education and Disclaimer 
    <div id="investment-education-and-disclaimer" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#investment-education-and-disclaimer" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Educational Purpose</strong>: All videos and sharing are for educational purposes only, with no profit-making intent, and are for reference only.</li>
<li><strong>Personal Responsibility</strong>: Investing is a personal act. Teacher James is not a professional investment advisor or tax professional; all decisions are your own responsibility.</li>
<li><strong>Stress Test</strong>: Ask yourself daily, &ldquo;If the market drops to zero, is your cash sufficient? Can you still live for one, two, or three years? Can young people continue working, and can retirees still withdraw money from the ATM?&rdquo; Use this to test the robustness of your asset allocation.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">How to Learn and Access Resources 
    <div id="how-to-learn-and-access-resources" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#how-to-learn-and-access-resources" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Clubhouse Message Board</strong>: Scroll to the top for the day&rsquo;s briefing and related links.</li>
<li><strong>YouTube Comment Section</strong>: Pinned comment has related links.</li>
<li><strong>Learning Path for New Friends</strong>:
<ul>
<li>Search &ldquo;CLEC投资理财频道&rdquo; (CLEC Investment and Finance Channel) on YouTube.</li>
<li>Watch the &ldquo;One Hundred Million Dollar Investment Lecture&rdquo; playlist, starting from early videos like <code>00451</code>, <code>00398</code>, <code>00399</code>, <code>00400</code>, <code>00401</code>, <code>00402</code>, etc., to gradually understand the investment philosophy.</li>
<li>Teacher James believes the investment and financial knowledge he shares is more complete and correct than most books on the market (many are &ldquo;demons and monsters,&rdquo; good books are few and hard to distinguish) and financial programs.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Investment Discipline and Leverage Utilization 
    <div id="investment-discipline-and-leverage-utilization" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#investment-discipline-and-leverage-utilization" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Wisdom and Destiny</strong>: Those who can watch the videos and follow through have wisdom and good destiny. Others watch, think they understand, but operate recklessly.</li>
<li><strong>Stock Pledging and Repayment</strong>: Once you pledge stocks and borrow money, you should be determined not to repay (the principal) for the rest of your life before you borrow. Otherwise, you should not pledge.</li>
<li><strong>Don&rsquo;t Do What You Don&rsquo;t Understand</strong>: Those who don&rsquo;t understand financial tools like Beta, leverage, etc. (e.g., can&rsquo;t even calculate Beta), should stick to investing only in index funds (like QQQ) and keep ample cash. 70% investment, 30% cash can also lead to a good life.</li>
<li><strong>Leverage is Not Essential</strong>: Leverage and stock pledging are ways to deeply understand financial operations, but they are not necessary conditions for wealth, suitable for a few who truly understand, are not afraid, and can withstand their volatility.</li>
<li><strong>Beware of Groups and Private Chats</strong>: Teacher James has no official groups. Any group using the CLEC name may be unauthorized or a scam. Taiwan&rsquo;s <code>00662</code> (Fubon NASDAQ) study group is student-initiated and not affiliated with the official CLEC; they also won&rsquo;t use the CLEC banner. Be cautious when joining any group or engaging in private contact.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Investment Targets and Global Allocation 
    <div id="investment-targets-and-global-allocation" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#investment-targets-and-global-allocation" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Recommended Target</strong>: Nasdaq 100 Index Fund (QQQ and its corresponding ETFs in various regions, like Taiwan&rsquo;s 00662). Don&rsquo;t ask about other ETFs.</li>
<li><strong>Global Purchase Channels</strong>: A document (page 15) lists channels for purchasing Nasdaq 100 Index Funds globally (Canada, Australia, UK, Brazil, Europe, Malaysia, South Korea, etc.).</li>
<li><strong>Information Disclosure</strong>: Since entering YouTube in 2018, all information has been publicly available on YouTube, Podcasts, and other platforms. Before 2018, classes were in-person, meeting students every two weeks.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Long-Term Optimism and Market Outlook 
    <div id="long-term-optimism-and-market-outlook" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#long-term-optimism-and-market-outlook" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Always Extremely Optimistic, Always Sunny</strong>: Firmly believe the market will always rise and reach new highs. QQQ at $540 will definitely be surpassed; it might reach $50,000, $500,000 in the future (a 100-fold increase is a small case in the market). 00662 might reach NT$90,000, NT$900,000 in the future.</li>
<li><strong>Volatility is Not Risk</strong>: Market decline after buying is not a risk; not being in the market is the risk. Don&rsquo;t regret not buying QQQ at $500 when it reaches $50,000.
<ul>
<li>Looking back: In 2022, when QQQ hit a low of over $200, everyone was terrified. Now it&rsquo;s over $500. The previous high of $408 was also called a high point; it was underwater for a year, and now it&rsquo;s back and hitting new highs. So what if you buy at $540 and it drops? In a few years, you&rsquo;ll be fine again.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Investment Pace</strong>: Buy when you have money, invest in batches. Achieve the &ldquo;golden mean&rdquo; of being happy when it rises and comfortable when it falls (because you can buy cheaper shares).</li>
<li><strong>QQQ Performance Over the Past Year</strong>: Up 15.38%. If you haven&rsquo;t made over 10% in the past year, you&rsquo;re failing. You get this return even without active trading. Ignore recent volatility. During Trump&rsquo;s tariff war, it fell over 20%, institutions fled, and ended up missing out later. Investors who have calmly weathered the year-to-date volatility are doing great.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Case Analysis on Money Market Funds and Exchange Rate Fluctuations 
    <div id="case-analysis-on-money-market-funds-and-exchange-rate-fluctuations" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#case-analysis-on-money-market-funds-and-exchange-rate-fluctuations" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Student Case Background</strong>: A student (email inquiry) mentioned a short-term &ldquo;crazy 10% appreciation&rdquo; of the NTD against the USD (Teacher James pointed out it should be &ldquo;depreciation,&rdquo; but the subsequent discussion revolved around the student&rsquo;s sense of &ldquo;loss,&rdquo; suggesting the student meant NTD appreciation led to a relative drop in the NTD value of their USD assets). The student held 00864B (a USD bond ETF) and experienced a paper &ldquo;loss&rdquo; due to exchange rate changes. He also mentioned pledging over NT$30 million and borrowing NT$6.6 million (20%), which Teacher James criticized as &ldquo;courting disaster&rdquo; behavior—pledging and immediately borrowing to reinvest. A slight 10% drop in the market (referring to the value of USD assets relative to NTD) caused him to panic.</li>
<li><strong>Student&rsquo;s Questions</strong>:
<ol>
<li>Should the 00864B portion not be transferred to 00865B? (Because a transfer would mean &ldquo;immediate loss&rdquo;)</li>
<li>Will the USD continue to depreciate against the NTD? Should the money market funds remain in 00864B?</li>
<li>Can 00864B be transferred to 00662 (QQQ)?</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s Analysis and Criticism</strong>:
<ul>
<li><strong>Human Fragility and Ignorance is Bliss</strong>: The student&rsquo;s behavior exposed pretending to understand, reckless bravery born of ignorance (like pledging and immediately borrowing a large sum to reinvest), and human fragility in the face of real market volatility (even currency fund exchange rate fluctuations). Like the &ldquo;Boxers&rdquo; (义和团), not learning leads to being plundered.</li>
<li><strong>Prohibition on Borrowing to Immediately Reinvest</strong>: Repeatedly emphasized that borrowing against pledged stock, especially a large one-time sum for reinvestment, is extremely dangerous.</li>
<li><strong>Short-term Exchange Rates are Unpredictable</strong>: Even the US central bank cannot predict short-term exchange rates and interest rates; investors should not worry about this. Financial media predictions are either from charlatans or liars.</li>
<li><strong>Act Immediately, Forget Sunk Costs</strong>: If a fund switch is necessary (00864B to 00865B, assuming it&rsquo;s a similar but superior fund), act immediately. Don&rsquo;t consider so-called &ldquo;losses&rdquo; or wait to &ldquo;break even.&rdquo; This is kindergarten-level financial thinking. 00864B and 00865B (if similar assets) will move mostly in tandem; waiting for one to break even means the other will have risen too.</li>
<li><strong>Severe Misconception of Risk</strong>: Being scared by a 4% paper &ldquo;loss&rdquo; in a very low-volatility money market fund (or short-term bond ETF) due to short-term exchange rate fluctuations, to the point of wanting to switch to a highly volatile stock fund (00662), is a massive risk perception error. QQQ/00662 could fall 80% within 10 years.</li>
<li><strong>Role of Cash</strong>: Cash (held in money market funds) is like the &ldquo;air force&rdquo; in a strategy, protecting ground troops (stock investments like QQQ/00662 and leveraged funds). The air force cannot be used as infantry.</li>
<li><strong>Those Unable to Bear Volatility Should Not Invest</strong>: If one cannot even bear minor exchange rate fluctuations in a money market fund (like the 10% perceived by the student) and panics because of it, then one is not suited for investing at all and should leave the market immediately, or face bankruptcy sooner or later.</li>
<li><strong>Long-term Exchange Rate Mean Reversion</strong>: In the long run (e.g., observed over 30 years), NTD exchange rate fluctuations will tend towards a mean (e.g., within a 22%-30% range up or down). As long as USD assets are held long enough (e.g., over 10 years), the expected return on USD assets (e.g., 3% annual money market yield, 34% over 10 years) far outweighs potential losses from exchange rate fluctuations.</li>
<li><strong>Market Volatility Has Nothing to Do with Me</strong>: If this exchange rate fluctuation makes you nervous, it shows you are not suited for investing.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Asset Allocation and the Importance of Cash 
    <div id="asset-allocation-and-the-importance-of-cash" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#asset-allocation-and-the-importance-of-cash" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Cash Requirement for Pledged Loans</strong>: When taking out stock-pledged loans, the cash (or cash equivalents) held should, under certain models, especially initially or when the market hasn&rsquo;t fallen significantly, be greater than the loan amount. Teacher James mentioned his 433 model (40% QQQ, 30% leverage, 30% cash) where, after an 80% market drop, cash might be close to or slightly less than the loan, but the overall position remains safe. If this is uncomfortable, a more conservative allocation like 424 (40% QQQ, 20% leverage, 40% cash) or 505 (50% QQQ, 50% cash, smart rebalancing) can be chosen.</li>
<li><strong>Minimum 30% Cash</strong>: At least 30% of investable assets should be allocated to cash (or money market funds). This is the first step. If you don&rsquo;t understand why you need cash, you cannot invest; you will go bankrupt.</li>
<li><strong>Cash as Living Expenses Standard</strong>: For working individuals, 30% cash should cover at least one year of living expenses. If funds are insufficient to cover one year&rsquo;s living expenses, one should not invest. Young people, after starting work, should first save a one-year emergency fund; subsequent salary can then be invested.</li>
<li><strong>Investment Horizon</strong>: Investing is a plan for 10+ years. Money needed within 10 years (e.g., children&rsquo;s tuition, down payment for a house) should not be used for high-volatility investments.</li>
<li><strong>Risks and Conditions for Buying Property</strong>:
<ul>
<li>Not recommended for young people to buy property easily, unless they have sufficient cash flow or can buy two houses as easily as buying slippers (with the mentality of buying a new pair if one breaks).</li>
<li>Concentrating investment in a single property is extremely risky (e.g., earthquake risk), violating the principle of diversification (QQQ diversifies across 100 companies).</li>
<li>The financial industry generally claims one should not concentrate bets or gamble on individual stocks, yet encourages the public to buy property (concentrated investment). This is contradictory; many practitioners either don&rsquo;t understand or are &ldquo;scammers.&rdquo; Teacher James mentioned being invited by a Taiwanese TV station to talk against buying property but declined, unwilling to become a public target.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Learn Investment Philosophy, Not Mimicry</strong>: Learn from masters like Buffett, Peter Lynch their investment philosophy (e.g., don&rsquo;t fear market volatility; Buffett encountered market drops of 10%+ annually and 20%+ every five years), not their specific stock-picking methods or asset allocation ratios. You can never mimic them.</li>
<li><strong>Cash for Retirees</strong>: Cash reserves need to cover 10+ years of expenses, ensuring that even if the market (e.g., QQQ/00662) goes to zero in an extreme scenario, and leveraged funds also go to zero, you can still live comfortably and at ease.</li>
<li><strong>Where to Keep Cash</strong>: In Taiwan, it&rsquo;s 00865B; in the US, it&rsquo;s BIL or SGOV, etc. (money market funds).</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Other Important Tips 
    <div id="other-important-tips" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#other-important-tips" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Taiwan Tax Reference</strong>: Mentioned a PDF file from Cathay United Bank regarding Taiwan taxes. Tools like ChatGPT can assist in understanding, but questions need to be logical, and AI answers are for reference only, not to be fully trusted. Teacher James stated his trained ChatGPT has not yet reached AGI (Artificial General Intelligence) level.</li>
<li><strong>Proactive Learning</strong>: When encountering problems, first search for information and learn independently. Don&rsquo;t treat Teacher James as a secretary or search engine. For example, what a money market fund is, you should look it up yourself. If you still don&rsquo;t understand after researching, you can list what you found and your confusion when asking.</li>
<li><strong>Your Biggest Enemy is Yourself</strong>: The best antidote to inner fear and greed is robust asset allocation and an ample cash level. When greedy, hold onto cash; when fearful, hold onto stocks. Asset allocation itself is to mitigate risk.</li>
<li><strong>Health and Longevity are Paramount</strong>: Health and longevity are key to achieving wealth compounding. Buffett is Buffett largely because he lived into his 90s. 96% of his wealth was earned after age 60 (a 25-fold increase in 30 years, about 11% annualized, similar to SPY). If you live that long with QQQ, your asset growth will be far more than 25 times, possibly 100 times.</li>
<li><strong>Volatility is the Entry Fee</strong>: View short-term paper &ldquo;losses&rdquo; from market volatility as an entry fee to the market, or &ldquo;withholding tax&rdquo; (it will be returned to you later), not a fine. Missing out on market upswings by not being in the market is a permanent loss (e.g., missing the 10 best days in the past 20 years might yield only 25% of the total return, while staying in the market could yield 17 times).</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">III. Q&amp;A Session 
    <div id="iii-qa-session" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii-qa-session" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Lucy 
    <div id="lucy" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#lucy" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question 1: In Canada, investing in QQQ monthly, but bank (RBC/TD) transaction fees are high (approx. 9.99 CAD/trade), which is not cost-effective for small regular investments. Asks if there are low-fee platforms?
<ul>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo;s Reply: Recommends checking the message board; some students have recommended WealthSimple or Interactive Brokers (IBKR).</li>
<li>Other student (Lin) adds: Questrade, if it&rsquo;s a self-directed account and meets asset requirements (e.g., 10,000 CAD+), might offer free trading. National Bank&rsquo;s brokerage services might also offer free trading and can link to bank accounts for direct transfers.</li>
<li>Other student (unnamed male) adds: Questrade&rsquo;s mobile trading platform might offer free commissions under certain conditions and has a regular investment feature, but specific fees need confirmation.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2: When buying Canadian QQQ ETFs, some are Hedged (HG), some are Non-Hedged (NH), how to choose? QQC vs QQQ selection?
<ul>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo;s Reply: For Canadian investors, recommends buying <code>HXQ.TO</code>. It doesn&rsquo;t pay dividends (dividends are reinvested), avoiding withholding tax issues, and it&rsquo;s Hedged.</li>
<li>Other student (Lin) adds: <code>QQC.TO</code> (CAD-denominated) allows purchasing fractional shares, suitable for small regular investments (e.g., 150 CAD monthly). <code>HXQ.TO</code> (currently around 80+ CAD per share) requires whole share purchases.</li>
<li>Other student (unnamed male) adds: CAD-denominated QQC might have slightly higher gains than directly buying QQQ with USD due to currency conversion operations. Buying directly with CAD is also simpler for tax reporting.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 3: What&rsquo;s the difference between using a brokerage platform and a bank platform for trading?
<ul>
<li>Teacher James and other students reply: Brokerage platforms are specialized investment accounts; a bank&rsquo;s investment services might be an independent department or outsourced. In Canada and the US, there&rsquo;s a firewall between brokerage and commercial banking. Using brokerage platforms directly (like Questrade, IBKR, WealthSimple) is usually more professional, and fees might be lower. Be aware that banks might try to sell packaged financial products; insist on buying pure ETFs.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Watson 
    <div id="watson" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#watson" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing 1: Early on (2018), saw Teacher James&rsquo;s &ldquo;One Hundred Million Dollar Investment Lecture&rdquo; on Bilibili but didn&rsquo;t think much of it. After years of ups and downs in A-shares and overseas investments (overseas funds invested for nearly 10 years without profit, until inventory at the beginning of this year). Now almost 50, feels like time was wasted. After re-encountering Teacher James&rsquo;s investment philosophy (buy when you have money, hold to death, only buy never sell), took out a portfolio loan through HSBC Hong Kong, allocating 70% QQQ, 10% TQQQ, and 20% MME (should be META). Experienced a significant market pullback in April (TQQQ dropped from purchase price near $90 to $35), but because of belief in Teacher James&rsquo;s philosophy, felt no inner turmoil, calm and composed, firmly believing volatility is not risk, and with proper asset allocation and cash reserves, there&rsquo;s nothing to fear. Studied nearly 200 of Teacher James&rsquo;s lessons, moving from understanding to faith, believing in humanity, the US, and technology, enabling steadfast holding. Teacher James is a benefactor on his investment journey.
<ul>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo;s Comment: Thanks for sharing, excellent mentality.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Sharing 2: Information on HSBC Hong Kong portfolio loans: Currently, one-month HIBOR is about 1.2%, plus the bank&rsquo;s spread, total interest is no more than 2.4%, very low. At HSBC, BIL (should be SGOV or similar short-term Treasury ETF) and leveraged funds (TQQQ, etc.) cannot be used as collateral, but SGOV can, with a loan-to-value ratio up to 90%; QQQ&rsquo;s LTV is 70%. SGOV dividends are subject to 10% withholding tax (for mainland China residents after signing W8 form), but since it&rsquo;s US Treasury interest, it&rsquo;s theoretically tax-exempt, and HSBC will refund this 10% in March/April of the following year. This method of not selling stocks, not repaying principal, and not paying interest (referring to net interest cost) through pledging is very helpful for mainland Chinese investors to avoid taxes on overseas investment income (dividends, capital gains) being investigated (recently discussed on Xueqiu), because as long as you don&rsquo;t sell, there are no realized capital gains or dividends.
<ul>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo;s Comment: This method (not selling, pledging to borrow) is applicable to investors worldwide and can legally avoid many taxes. The key is &ldquo;buy when you have money, hold to death, never repay stock-pledged loans (principal), and borrow (through asset allocation) without paying (net) interest.&rdquo; Watson broke through the psychological barrier of &ldquo;why borrow money when I have cash,&rdquo; understanding that cash is also an asset that needs to continuously grow.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question: If one withdraws no more than 2% from pledged assets annually for living expenses, and this 2% is not fully used, should the remaining portion be left as is (not borrowed), or can the unused portion of the borrowed money be reinvested into the QQQ/TQQQ portfolio?
<ul>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo;s Reply: Either is fine. Reinvesting the unused portion is okay, not reinvesting is also fine; whatever makes you comfortable. If the market is falling, you can buy; if the market is rising, you can ignore it. The core is to buy when you have money, at the market price, immediately. Since you are already financially free, the extra funds just increase your inheritance, not a necessary operation.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Ray 
    <div id="ray" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ray" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: After rewatching Teacher James&rsquo;s videos, his investment philosophy has improved greatly. Fortunate to be able to jump directly from ignorance to a state of &ldquo;non-action&rdquo; (wu wei), skipping the intermediate stages of &ldquo;not knowing one is ignorant,&rdquo; &ldquo;cleverness,&rdquo; &ldquo;from non-action to action.&rdquo;</li>
<li>Question 1: Teacher James once said wealth has tiers (million for food freedom, ten million for financial freedom, one hundred million for housing freedom and helping family, one billion for helping the poor, ten billion for helping society/seeking longevity). The &ldquo;hold to death&rdquo; strategy might cause assets to fluctuate significantly between these tiers (e.g., from 100 million down to 30 million). How to psychologically overcome the feeling of falling from a higher freedom tier, even knowing it&rsquo;s temporary volatility? (For example, eating without looking at prices when assets are high, then reflecting on not being so complacent when assets fall back.)
<ul>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo;s Reply: The key is to focus on <strong>cash flow</strong> rather than short-term fluctuations in total assets. Whether working or retired, your annual disposable cash flow should be relatively fixed (e.g., annual income 3 million, spend 1.2 million, reinvest 1.8 million), unaffected by market ups and downs. Don&rsquo;t change your spending habits because of market fluctuations. If you want to increase living expenses due to significant asset growth (e.g., from 60 million to 120 million) (e.g., from 2% of original assets to 2% of new assets, increasing cash flow from 1.2 million to 2.4 million, spending an extra 1.2 million), you should first re-evaluate and adjust your asset allocation (e.g., reduce Beta from 1.0 to lower, increase cash proportion) to ensure the new cash flow plan is sustainable. After that, your life should no longer be affected by market volatility.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2: Why is the rebalancing frequency chosen as once a year? (Saw an author who tried different frequencies and concluded there&rsquo;s no optimum, once a year is about right.)
<ul>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo;s Reply: Once a year is based on intuition and common sense. Two years is too long, volatility might be too great, reducing rebalancing efficiency (e.g., if it rises 50% this year, annual rebalancing is efficient; over two years, volatility might be smoothed out, reducing efficiency). Daily rebalancing is theoretically most efficient but impractical (becomes short-term trading) and incurs high transaction costs and tax issues. Once a year strikes a good balance between efficiency and practicability, and also aligns well with tax reporting (e.g., in the US).</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Yao 
    <div id="yao" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#yao" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Observed that the market mostly rises slowly (e.g., 0.x% daily, leveraged funds 1.x%), but when it falls (e.g., president talks about trade war), the decline is larger (5%, 10%, 20%). This is like life, mostly mundane daily routines, but long-term accumulation (power of compounding) can lead to huge changes. Work hard, live well, and you can ultimately lead a happy life.
<ul>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo;s Comment: Well said. Plainness is a blessing, safety first, stable profits. Without safety, everything else is false; without health, everything else is false. Health and safety are prerequisites for enjoying wealth. Like the example of Bill Gates (or Steve Jobs), his high school had an expensive computer (a one-in-ten-thousand chance of luck), and he learned programming; but another equally talented classmate unfortunately died while mountain climbing (a one-in-ten-thousand chance of disaster). One must first avoid disaster for luck to be meaningful.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Lin 
    <div id="lin" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#lin" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Watched the Berkshire Hathaway shareholders meeting. Warren Buffett, though 94 years old (born 1930) and having experienced WWII and countless storms, repeatedly emphasized four or five times within three to four hours how lucky he was to be born in America as a white male. This echoes Teacher James&rsquo;s emphasis on &ldquo;always be optimistic, embrace the sunshine.&rdquo; If I hadn&rsquo;t listened to Teacher James&rsquo;s classes, I might not have understood Buffett&rsquo;s expression and would have found it insincere. Now I understand; he certainly had bad things happen in his life, but he chose optimism.
<ul>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo;s Comment: Very well said. Be grateful every day, stay optimistic, think positively (&ldquo;I am great, I am good, I am very rich, all the money in the world is mine&rdquo;), and the universe will respond to your positive energy. The world is as you perceive it.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Supplement on Canadian brokerage information: Questrade, if it&rsquo;s a self-directed account and meets asset requirements (e.g., 10,000 CAD+, annual management fee might be waived), offers zero-commission trading. National Bank&rsquo;s brokerage services might also offer free trading (mainly starting in French-speaking regions). HXQ.TO must be bought in whole shares, QQC.TO can be bought in fractional shares, suitable for small regular investments (e.g., only 150 CAD per month, HXQ.TO is over 80 CAD per share, so can only buy one share).</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Jason 
    <div id="jason" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#jason" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing 1: Before and after attending the Berkshire Hathaway shareholders meeting, encountered two groups of people: one group was value investors like Li Lu, who emphasized ignoring market volatility (Mr. Market&rsquo;s emotions), believing index investing is also a form of value investing (natural growth of the economy after removing speculation). They also emphasized community support, making an annual &ldquo;pilgrimage&rdquo; to Omaha.</li>
<li>Sharing 2: The other group was insurance agents, also using Buffett&rsquo;s theories (Berkshire Hathaway has insurance business), discussing asset management, inheritance, financial literacy education (e.g., allocating 401k, Roth IRA), but their ultimate goal was to sell life insurance.
<ul>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo;s Comment: Be wary of insurance agents. Insurance is transferring your money to the insurance company&rsquo;s pocket; it&rsquo;s essentially &ldquo;the scam group within the financial scam conglomerate.&rdquo; Buffett says insurance is a good business—for the insurance company, not for the policyholder. Insurance agents use financial literacy education as a disguise, making it highly deceptive.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Haojin 
    <div id="haojin" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#haojin" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question: Taiwanese products offer good value for money (e.g., Meet Fresh is $10 in the US, Taiwan has many cheaper options), but the NTD seems undervalued. If the NTD appreciates significantly in the future as Teacher James suggested (e.g., from 30:1 USD to 15:1 or even 10:1), for Taiwanese investors in US stock ETFs (like 00662, with an annualized return of about 12-14%), will their long-term returns denominated in NTD be eroded by exchange rates, leading to less-than-expected growth in purchasing power? (A boss&rsquo;s mentality might be to hope for NTD depreciation to benefit exports, sacrificing employee welfare).
<ul>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo;s Reply:
<ol>
<li>NTD appreciation is good for Taiwan. It will be cheaper for people to buy imported goods (e.g., iPhone from NT$30,000 to NT$10,000) and travel abroad, improving quality of life. High-pollution, uncompetitive industries (like uncompetitive steel, unless for national defense) will naturally be eliminated; they shouldn&rsquo;t be subsidized by sacrificing public welfare and the environment.</li>
<li>For Taiwanese investors already invested in USD assets, NTD appreciation will indeed affect NTD-denominated returns. However, one can consider allocating to some NTD-hedged ETFs (like Taiwan&rsquo;s 00670L Fubon NASDAQ Leveraged 2x, although it&rsquo;s a leveraged ETF, Teacher James might be referring to its hedging characteristic here or using it as an example that such tools exist).</li>
<li>In the long run, the impact of exchange rate fluctuations is far less than the growth of quality assets. Even if the annualized return drops from 14% to 7% due to exchange rates, it&rsquo;s still a good return. One shouldn&rsquo;t worry excessively about exchange rates.</li>
<li>After NTD appreciation, buying USD assets in the future will be cheaper (e.g., QQQ from NT$15,000 to NT$5,000), which is actually beneficial. An undervalued NTD deprives the entire population of welfare to benefit a few manufacturers.</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Curiosity 
    <div id="curiosity" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#curiosity" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question: Regarding Roth portions in tax-deferred retirement accounts like 403(b) and 457(b) (up to $30,500 can be contributed annually), are they also subject to Required Minimum Distribution (RMD) at age 73 or 75? If so, can they be rolled over tax-free to a personal Roth IRA account without an amount limit? What are the precautions during operation (e.g., need to sell then transfer)?
<ul>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo;s Reply: Funds in Roth 403(b)/457(b), after meeting conditions, can be rolled over tax-free to a personal Roth IRA. This avoids RMD issues because personal Roth IRAs do not have RMDs during the owner&rsquo;s lifetime. Operationally, contact the brokerage to handle it; you can choose cash transfer or in-kind transfer (assets transferred directly, if the brokerage supports it and the investment holdings are the same, like QQQ). It&rsquo;s advisable to choose the brokerage link option within 403(b)/457(b) as much as possible to invest in quality targets like QQQ, rather than being limited to a few poor-performing funds offered by the plan. If you can only choose funds, don&rsquo;t contribute; deposit directly into a Roth IRA.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Catherine 
    <div id="catherine" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#catherine" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question: Regarding Pledged Line of Credit (PLOC), a friend doesn&rsquo;t understand why one would borrow money and pay interest when having enough cash or stock gains. How to simply explain its benefits? (Friend&rsquo;s argument: I have money from stock trading, why borrow and pay interest?)
<ul>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo;s Reply:
<ol>
<li><strong>Capital Efficiency and Compounding</strong>: Using your own money for living expenses (e.g., spending $20,000 annually) means reducing the principal available for investment. Borrowing for living expenses (e.g., borrowing $20,000) allows the original principal (e.g., $1 million) to continue growing at a higher rate (e.g., 10%). Even after paying interest (e.g., 5%), there&rsquo;s still a net gain (5% arbitrage). After 30 years, the borrower&rsquo;s net worth (total assets minus debt) will be far higher than that of the investor who spends their own money (Teacher James gave an example, the former has $3 million more).</li>
<li><strong>Tax Advantages</strong>: Not selling stocks means no capital gains tax.</li>
<li><strong>Possibility of Interest Deduction</strong>: Interest on loans may be tax-deductible under specific circumstances (e.g., treating long-term capital gains as short-term, forgoing preferential tax rates) (complex operation, consult a professional accountant; many accountants don&rsquo;t understand this).</li>
<li><strong>Net Interest Cost is Zero or Negative</strong>: Through proper asset allocation (like Teacher James&rsquo;s 433 model: 40% QQQ, 30% QLD/TQQQ, 30% cash/money market fund), the interest generated by money market funds (e.g., $300,000 cash generating 4.5% or $13,500 interest) can cover or even exceed the interest expense of pledged loans (e.g., borrowing $200,000, 5% interest is $10,000), achieving &ldquo;borrowing money without paying interest&rdquo; or even making money, while the portfolio&rsquo;s Beta remains at 1.0.</li>
<li><strong>Long-term Asset Growth and Risk (Counter-intuitive)</strong>: Over the long term, the total assets of an investor who borrows will be far higher than one who spends their own money. Continuously spending principal leads to principal depletion (e.g., $1 million becomes $400,000 after 30 years, then $100,000 after another 10 years, unable to afford a bento box). Borrowing and letting the principal grow continuously, even with debt, results in better sustainability of total assets (still $1 million principal growing) and cash flow, thus lower risk.
Teacher James emphasized this is one of his core strategies, requiring students to watch the videos from the beginning to fully understand.</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">IV. Wonderful Quotes 
    <div id="iv-wonderful-quotes" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv-wonderful-quotes" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>Market volatility has nothing to do with us, so don&rsquo;t sell stocks, don&rsquo;t sell stocks, don&rsquo;t sell stocks.
&ndash; Teacher James</p></blockquote>
<p>This view is a core investment discipline repeatedly emphasized by Teacher James: maintain composure in the face of market volatility and stick to the strategy of long-term holding of quality assets.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>You only run into problems if you are afraid. If you sell your stocks, always remember one thing: keep enough cash. Retirees might need to keep 10-15 years&rsquo; worth, at least 30% or more in cash.
&ndash; Teacher James</p></blockquote>
<p>Teacher James stresses the importance of ample cash reserves for overcoming fear and avoiding erroneous operations, providing cash reserve suggestions for different groups of people.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Greed and fear are like that. Because you feel the market, it causes your greed&hellip; you find your assets have exploded&hellip; you&rsquo;re about to become a superior person, then greed has appeared, and risk will follow. When the market drops, you become very fearful, very fearful, very fearful&hellip; then this fear emerges.
&ndash; Teacher James</p></blockquote>
<p>Profoundly reveals the common extreme emotions of investors in the market and their dangers, reminding investors to remain rational.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Cash is air. You must maintain the highest level of cash to survive. In the overall strategy, cash is like the air force, protecting the ground troops from annihilation.
&ndash; Teacher James</p></blockquote>
<p>Uses a vivid metaphor to emphasize the strategic position of cash in an investment portfolio, as key to resisting risk and ensuring survival.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Our method isn&rsquo;t just for China; even if you&rsquo;re in Taiwan or the US, you don&rsquo;t need to pay taxes because we don&rsquo;t sell. No selling means no taxes. Learn this trick: stock pledge loans are never repaid (principal), and the loan (through asset allocation) incurs no (net) interest.
&ndash; Teacher James (partially echoing Watson&rsquo;s sharing)</p></blockquote>
<p>Explains the strategy of achieving tax optimization and wealth growth through long-term holding, not selling, and skillfully using stock pledge loans (combined with asset allocation to make interest costs manageable).</p>
<blockquote>
<p>You just need to be optimistic, optimistic, I am great, I am good, I am very rich, all the money in the world is mine. You need to chant this every day: I am great, I am good. I am the best person in the world. That&rsquo;s enough. All good luck will come to you.
&ndash; Teacher James</p></blockquote>
<p>Emphasizes the importance of positive psychological suggestion and an optimistic mindset for investment and even life.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>When investing, you must treat the losses brought by volatility, these temporary losses, as the entry fee for the market, not a fine.
&ndash; Teacher James (quoting an online viewpoint)</p></blockquote>
<p>Provides a positive perspective on market volatility and short-term paper losses, helping investors maintain a long-term mindset.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>We make money without paying taxes, borrow money without paying (net) interest, and we hold to death, never selling (principal). This is our highest realm.
&ndash; Teacher James</p></blockquote>
<p>Summarizes the ideal state of his investment strategy, emphasizing tax efficiency, cost control, and long-term holding.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">V. Summary 
    <div id="v-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#v-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>In this lecture, Teacher James once again systematically emphasized his core investment philosophy: long-term holding of quality assets (like the Nasdaq 100 Index Fund), ignoring short-term market volatility and noise, maintaining sufficient cash reserves, and applying a reasonable asset allocation strategy. Teacher James sternly refuted panic and erroneous operations arising from short-term market or exchange rate fluctuations and detailed the correct use of stock pledge loans where &ldquo;principal is never repaid, and (net) interest is controllable.&rdquo; Through questions and sharing from multiple students, the lecture covered specific concerns of investors from different regions including Canada, Mainland China, Taiwan, and the US, touching upon brokerage selection, fees, tax planning, retirement account management, and overcoming psychological investment barriers. Teacher James consistently conveyed an extremely optimistic investment belief and reminded investors to be wary of financial scams, focus on learning correct investment knowledge, and ultimately achieve financial freedom and life happiness.</p>

  



<div
  
    class="flex px-4 py-3 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900"
  >

  <span
    
      class="text-primary-400 ltr:pr-3 rtl:pl-3 flex items-center"
    >

    

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M506.3 417l-213.3-364c-16.33-28-57.54-28-73.98 0l-213.2 364C-10.59 444.9 9.849 480 42.74 480h426.6C502.1 480 522.6 445 506.3 417zM232 168c0-13.25 10.75-24 24-24S280 154.8 280 168v128c0 13.25-10.75 24-23.1 24S232 309.3 232 296V168zM256 416c-17.36 0-31.44-14.08-31.44-31.44c0-17.36 14.07-31.44 31.44-31.44s31.44 14.08 31.44 31.44C287.4 401.9 273.4 416 256 416z"/></svg>

  </span>


  </span>

  <span
    
      class="dark:text-neutral-300"
    ><strong>Disclaimer:</strong> This article is for personal learning notes only and does not constitute any investment advice.</span>
</div>

]]></content:encoded></item></channel></rss>