<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Book on QQQ Investor</title>
    <link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/tags/book/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Book on QQQ Investor</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jomonylw.github.io/en/tags/book/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Personal Investment Bible: Investment Iron Law X</title>
      <link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1731056005969/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1731056005969/</guid>
      <description>This article introduces three stock investment strategies: value investing, growth investing, and contrarian investing. Value investing emphasizes buying stocks when the price is below their intrinsic value and selling when the price is above. Growth investing focuses on the future earnings growth potential of companies, selecting companies with sustained high growth for investment. Contrarian investing suggests going against the general market sentiment, being greedy when others are fearful, and fearful when others are greedy.  The article analyzes the advantages, disadvantages, and suitability of each strategy, pointing out that although these three strategies are theoretically effective, they are difficult to implement in practice.  Ordinary investors are more suited to adopt a long-term buy-and-hold strategy of &amp;#34;buy any stock, buy at any time, and don&amp;#39;t sell.&amp;#34;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[

<h2 class="relative group">Investment Iron Law X: Mastering the Tools of Stock Market Offense and Defense 
    <div id="investment-iron-law-x-mastering-the-tools-of-stock-market-offense-and-defense" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#investment-iron-law-x-mastering-the-tools-of-stock-market-offense-and-defense" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>Buy when Value is higher than Price.
Sell when Value is lower than Price.</p>
</blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">Value Investing 
    <div id="value-investing" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#value-investing" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>The strategy of &ldquo;buy any stock, buy at any time, and don&rsquo;t sell&rdquo; sounds simple, but most people can&rsquo;t follow it. Even if they acknowledge its potential for wealth creation, they lack the courage to implement it because it seems to contradict common investment beliefs and principles. Therefore, the author presents three superior investment strategies: value investing, growth investing, and contrarian investing. Before investing, using these strategies, you must ask yourself: Does the investment target hold this value? What is its future growth potential? Is everyone investing in it? These three investment strategies can help you make better decisions.</p>
<p><strong>Verifying Value Ensures Profitability</strong></p>
<p>During the 1920s, Florida&rsquo;s real estate prices skyrocketed daily, triggering a buying frenzy. One fortunate investor managed to secure a plot of land. Most buyers didn&rsquo;t care about the land&rsquo;s quality, but this investor prudently asked a real estate agent to show him the purchased land. He was shocked to discover it was swampland.  &ldquo;Can anyone live here?&rdquo; he exclaimed. The agent calmly replied, &ldquo;Why worry about that? As long as the price goes up.&rdquo;</p>
<p>&ldquo;Human behavior and decision-making are perfectly rational&rdquo; is a fundamental assumption in academic research and theoretical development. Generally, consumers won&rsquo;t rush to buy unless a product offers exceptional value. For instance, no one would pay $5 million for a car worth $500,000 unless they were foolish. Investment decisions, involving money and future wealth, are even more critical than buying a car. Logically, people should be more rational and cautious, making decisions only after careful calculations.</p>
<p>However, are investors truly rational?  In July 1985, China Development Corporation&rsquo;s stock price was NT$14 per share. Four years later, in September 1989, it reached NT$1075, a nearly 80-fold increase.  Remarkably, in 1985, when the price was low, investors shunned the stock, resulting in low trading volume. Conversely, in 1989, when the price soared to over NT$1000, investors rushed in, fearing they would miss out, driving trading volume to its peak.</p>
<p>Are these investment behaviors rational?  Consider the difference between China Development Corporation at NT$14 in 1985, at over NT$1000 in 1989, or even at NT$50 in 1983.  Essentially, the difference was minimal; it was the same company, managed by practically the same people, with similar assets. Why such a drastic price difference? The answer lies not in the company&rsquo;s intrinsic changes but in investors&rsquo; behavioral and decision-making biases.</p>
<p>Between 1989 and 1990, during the Taiwan stock market&rsquo;s peak, investors continued pouring in. The author often asked friends and family, &ldquo;Do you think the stocks you&rsquo;re buying are worth the price?&rdquo;  Most found the question perplexing and avoided answering. Some reluctantly admitted, &ldquo;Probably not.&rdquo;  The author would then ask, &ldquo;Why buy them then?&rdquo;  Their confident reply: &ldquo;They&rsquo;ll go up!&rdquo;</p>
<p>Some also questioned the author&rsquo;s lack of participation in this lucrative market.  The response: &ldquo;I&rsquo;ll wait until after 4000 points to invest.&rdquo; The author believed the Taiwan stock market&rsquo;s true value was below 4000 points (in 1989).  Those who heard this scoffed, &ldquo;Keep waiting.&rdquo;  As it turned out, overvalued assets cannot rise indefinitely. In August 1990, the Taiwan stock index plummeted to around 2000 points, proving the author&rsquo;s point.  No investment&rsquo;s price can remain perpetually above or below its true value.</p>
<p><strong>Buy When Value Exceeds Price</strong></p>
<p>Value investing, introduced by Benjamin Graham in his 1933 book <em>Security Analysis</em>, was later championed by his students, including Warren Buffett and John Templeton.  In the 1980s, value investing gained prominence in the US, becoming the strategy of choice for many successful long-term investors.</p>
<p>Value investing posits that every stock has an intrinsic value.  Price fluctuations arise from investor trading.  Prices exceeding intrinsic value will eventually revert, and prices falling below will eventually recover.</p>
<p>The principle is simple: buy when the value is higher than the price, regardless of market fluctuations.  If it&rsquo;s cheap, buy it. Conversely, sell when the value is lower than the price.  In short, buy low, sell high.  Sell when prices significantly exceed value amidst widespread buying, minimizing holdings. Buy when prices fall drastically below value amidst widespread fear, increasing holdings.</p>
<p>Typically, investors focus solely on price appreciation, neglecting value.  People meticulously research cars, refrigerators, or stereos for months, comparing models, reading reviews, and seeking advice, constantly evaluating value for money.  They&rsquo;ll wait for a sale if the price is too high.  Yet, when buying stocks, often on a whim based on a tip or hearsay, they overlook value, making hasty decisions involving sums far exceeding appliance purchases.</p>
<p><strong>Invest with an Owner&rsquo;s Mindset</strong></p>
<p>Warren Buffett&rsquo;s investment philosophy emphasizes investing with an owner&rsquo;s mindset and a long-term perspective. This involves buying stocks of companies with stable earnings growth, positive prospects, high asset value, or simply when the intrinsic value exceeds the price.</p>
<p>Crowds flock to department stores during sales and clearances. The steeper the discounts, the larger the crowds.  Conversely, shopping is most pleasant when there are no sales, as stores are less crowded.  This is because consumers are motivated by value, buying when prices are below perceived worth.</p>
<p>However, in stock markets, the opposite occurs. Brokerage houses are deserted when stock prices are at their lowest.  Conversely, they are packed when prices are soaring. Investors are motivated by rising prices.  A stock falling from $100 to $50 attracts little interest, while rapid price increases fuel buying frenzy.</p>
<p>The assumption of rational economic behavior applies well to consumer choices but not to investment behavior.  As illustrated, investment decisions are often driven by irrational emotions, impulses, and intuition.</p>
<p>Value investing advises emulating consumer behavior: buy when stocks are &ldquo;on sale,&rdquo; and avoid the herd when prices are inflated.</p>
<p><strong>Developing the Ability to Calculate Asset and Earnings Value</strong></p>
<p>The key to successful value investing is the ability to calculate a company&rsquo;s intrinsic value, encompassing asset value and earnings value.  Asset value represents the liquidation value of the company&rsquo;s assets per share. Earnings value represents the present value of the company&rsquo;s projected future earnings.  Estimating future earnings is challenging, requiring the development of forecasting skills.</p>
<p>Calculating intrinsic value is not easy.  Investing in familiar companies simplifies this process.  Taiwanese businesswoman Shirley Wang, CEO of FIC Global, primarily invested in FIC and related IT and semiconductor companies.  Her familiarity with the industry allowed her to better grasp its dynamics.</p>
<p>Many successful investors adhere to Buffett&rsquo;s philosophy, investing only in familiar companies.  Li-Ching Hsu, former Taiwan head of ING Group, frequently advised investors to focus on companies in their own industry or related sectors.</p>
<p>Investment decisions should always involve value analysis. Buy when the value is present or the price is attractive; sell otherwise.  Value investing encourages adopting consumer-like behavior in the stock market, buying low and selling high.</p>
<p><em>1. When investing in stocks, ask &ldquo;Is it worth buying?&rdquo; not just &ldquo;Will it go up?&rdquo;</em></p>
<p><em>2.  Learn from consumer behavior: buy when prices are discounted.</em></p>
<blockquote>
<p>Choose a great company, and if it keeps growing, you&rsquo;ll almost never have to sell.</p>
</blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">Growth Investing 
    <div id="growth-investing" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#growth-investing" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>Valuing a company is challenging.  Some professional investors therefore focus on earnings growth rate, a primary driver of value, as their investment criterion. Growth investing has been successfully employed by renowned investors, notably Peter Lynch, former manager of Fidelity&rsquo;s Magellan Fund, who achieved the highest 15-year return among hundreds of US mutual funds.</p>
<p><strong>Investing in High-Growth Potential Stocks</strong></p>
<p>Simply put, growth investing involves buying stocks of companies with high future growth potential and selling when that potential diminishes.  A key characteristic is maintaining full investment, ideally diversified.  Growth investors acknowledge their inability to predict short-term market movements but believe in the long-term upward trend of stocks, especially those with high growth potential.</p>
<p>They invest all their capital in high-growth stocks.  Peter Lynch maintained a nearly 100% invested portfolio during his tenure at Magellan Fund, keeping minimal cash reserves for redemptions.</p>
<p>The key to successful growth investing lies in identifying companies with high growth potential.  This is the challenge: finding high-growth stocks.  Investing in IBM 30 years ago, Microsoft 15 years ago, or Cathay Life Insurance in Taiwan would have yielded multifold returns.</p>
<p>However, countless seemingly high-growth companies fizzle out. No one can predict the future with certainty. Even Peter Lynch admitted that only half of his stock picks were truly successful, but that was enough.  Therefore, diversification is crucial for mitigating the higher risks of growth investing.</p>
<p>Growth investing believes that a company&rsquo;s real growth drives stock price appreciation.  Investment returns depend on the earnings over the next few years. For high returns, choose investments with 5-10 year growth potential. Invest in companies in high-growth industries with excellent performance and a sustainable growth outlook. Their stock prices are likely to rise with the company&rsquo;s growth, offering substantial long-term gains.</p>
<p><strong>Choosing the Right Industry is More Important Than Choosing the Right Company</strong></p>
<p>Growth investors prioritize future earnings growth potential.  Industry growth is crucial for a company&rsquo;s earnings.  Choosing the right industry is therefore more important than choosing the right company.  Consider the future 5-10 year demand for the company&rsquo;s products, focusing on the industry&rsquo;s growth potential. Peter Lynch advised against selling good stocks prematurely for small profits and recommended selling stocks of companies with deteriorating growth prospects, even at a loss.  This approach allows gains from successful picks to offset losses from unsuccessful ones, resulting in overall profit.</p>
<p>Peter Lynch advocated for a &ldquo;common sense&rdquo; approach to investing, illustrated in his book <em>One Up On Wall Street</em>. He profited from observing his wife&rsquo;s preference for certain hosiery and dish soap brands, and his children&rsquo;s preference for certain sneakers, leading him to invest in those companies.  This approach can be explained by market efficiency theory.  Retailers and observant consumers are often the first to notice a product&rsquo;s popularity, before analysts.  By adopting a consumer perspective and noticing trends overlooked by experts, investors can gain an edge.</p>
<p>In early 1996, after a frugal, retired court clerk passed away, her family discovered her substantial wealth. She had consistently invested small amounts in Coca-Cola stock for decades, capitalizing on its growth and share price appreciation. This illustrates the power of long-term investment in growing companies.</p>
<p><strong>Don&rsquo;t Just Focus on Price Fluctuations</strong></p>
<p>Many investors are unclear about their investment rationale.  If you can&rsquo;t explain your investment&rsquo;s business and growth potential in five minutes, you shouldn&rsquo;t own it.  Focus on monitoring the validity of your investment thesis, not daily price fluctuations.</p>
<p>Many investors prefer startups or pre-IPO companies. However, established, profitable companies with growth potential are often better investments. Peter Lynch suggested capturing the middle five years of a company&rsquo;s 15-year growth trajectory, rather than the initial or mature phases.  If a stock has the potential to rise from $2 to $200, wait until it reaches $8 before buying. The potential gains are still substantial, and the risk is lower.  Losing money in the stock market is quick, but making money takes time. Most stocks take 3-5 years to rise significantly.</p>
<p>Regarding industry growth potential, in Taiwan, IT, communications, and semiconductors within the electronics industry are promising. Pharmaceuticals and biotechnology are also attractive due to increasing health consciousness. Taiwan&rsquo;s ten emerging industries (specialty chemicals, environmental protection, aerospace, telecommunications, semiconductors, IT, pharmaceuticals, precision machinery, etc.) offer future growth opportunities.  In the service sector, securities and investment trust, construction, and shipping also have good prospects.  <strong>Savvy investors should anticipate future trends, popular products, internet-driven products, and leverage their own consumer insights to identify investment opportunities.</strong></p>
<p>Growth investing is suitable for non-professional investors.  It requires no specialized training or constant monitoring.  To identify growth stocks, consider a company&rsquo;s potential performance over the next 5-10 years. Invest in companies with strong growth potential and hold them long-term, selling only when they transition from growth to maturity.  This strategy allows even amateur investors with limited time and expertise to achieve good results.</p>
<p><em>1. Real earnings growth drives stock price appreciation.</em></p>
<p><em>2. Diversify investments in companies with sustainable 5-10 year growth potential, patiently awaiting substantial returns.</em></p>
<blockquote>
<p>Don&rsquo;t follow the crowd; be rational. Figure out what most people are doing, then don&rsquo;t do it.</p>
</blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">Contrarian Investing 
    <div id="contrarian-investing" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#contrarian-investing" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>Many ask, &ldquo;Is there a better time to buy than &lsquo;any time&rsquo;?&rdquo; Research suggests there is: contrarian investing, a time-tested and remarkably effective strategy.</p>
<p><strong>Buy Straw Hats in Winter, Boats in a Drought</strong></p>
<p>A 19th-century American tycoon, when asked about his wealth-building secret, replied, &ldquo;Buy straw hats in winter.&rdquo;  Similarly, Fan Li, a wealthy merchant in ancient China, followed the principle of &ldquo;buying fur coats in summer, selling in winter; buying boats in a drought, selling when it rains.&rdquo;  These are examples of contrarian investing.</p>
<p>This investment concept originated in ancient China. According to <em>Records of the Grand Historian</em>, Ji Ran, an economist during the Warring States period, proposed the contrarian strategy of &ldquo;invest in boats during drought, invest in carts during floods.&rdquo;  He argued that during droughts, when everyone invests in cart production, one should invest in boats.  The oversupply of carts would lower prices and profits.  When the rains return, boat demand would surge, raising prices and profits.  Conversely, during floods, when everyone invests in boats, one should invest in carts.</p>
<p>Contrarian investing means investing when most people aren&rsquo;t and selling when everyone is eager to buy.  The concept is simple: go against the crowd.  However, implementing it is challenging. It requires overcoming human nature, resisting herd mentality, cultivating independent judgment, and enduring loneliness. Most investors follow the crowd, while contrarian investors look for opportunities when others are fearful.  This strategy relies on the belief that widespread consensus is often wrong and that reversals can be powerful.</p>
<p><strong>Don&rsquo;t Be Deceived by Net Buying or Selling</strong></p>
<p>Contrarian investing works because when most people are bullish, available capital is already invested, leading to overinflated prices.  With everyone already in the market, poised to sell, potential supply outweighs demand. Any negative news can trigger a sharp decline.</p>
<p>Conversely, when most people are bearish, selling pressure is minimal as most have already sold.  With potential buyers waiting on the sidelines, demand outweighs supply.  Any positive news can trigger a sharp rise.</p>
<p>Investors tend to extrapolate past trends, especially when reinforced by market sentiment. During initial market declines, most see it as temporary, while a few predict further declines. As the market continues falling, bears are rewarded, and bulls suffer.  At severely oversold levels, widespread pessimism creates buying opportunities.  Conversely, during initial market rallies, most see it as temporary, while a few predict further gains. As the market continues rising, bulls are rewarded, and bears suffer. At severely overbought levels, widespread optimism leads to overvaluation.</p>
<p><strong>Bullish When Rising, Bearish When Falling</strong></p>
<p>People tend to become more optimistic during optimistic periods and more pessimistic during pessimistic periods.  They rely on memory to predict the future.  A rising market breeds bullishness, and a falling market breeds bearishness.</p>
<p>At the peak of the Taiwan stock market in late 1989, the author taught an investment course. During one lecture, a student requested the author refrain from discussing stocks.  Surprised, the author asked why. The student explained that every class, from political science to calculus, included discussions about stocks.</p>
<p>Another anecdote from that period involves a professor asking his class the time. A student instinctively replied, &ldquo;9865 points, up 65 points.&rdquo;  Students were constantly monitoring stock prices during lectures. This illustrates the pervasive stock market mania at the time.  As it turned out, this widespread obsession was a harbinger of the impending crash.</p>
<p><strong>Great investments often involve defying conventional wisdom, selling when others are buying, and buying when others are selling.  Be bearish before others when everyone is bullish, and be bullish before others when everyone is bearish. As a Wall Street adage goes, &ldquo;Markets are born in despair, grow in skepticism, mature in optimism, and die in euphoria.&rdquo;</strong></p>
<p>Contrarian investing doesn&rsquo;t require constantly opposing the majority. It encourages resisting herd mentality and cultivating independent thinking.  The best buying opportunities may arise when most are afraid to buy, but buying solely for that reason is as foolish as following the crowd. The crowd isn&rsquo;t always wrong.  Develop independent judgment.  True contrarians don&rsquo;t blindly oppose the majority but wait for the dust to settle and buy when no one is paying attention.</p>
<p>Contrarian investing applies to stock selection. David Dreman, in his book <em>Contrarian Investment Strategies</em>, argued that unpopular companies often outperform expectations, while popular companies are susceptible to minor setbacks.</p>
<p>Timing the market is difficult. Mastering the principles of contrarian investing can be highly rewarding.</p>
<p><em>1. Invest when others aren&rsquo;t; sell when everyone is eager to invest.</em></p>
<p><em>2. Don&rsquo;t follow the crowd; buy when investor sentiment has cooled and no one is paying attention.</em></p>
<p><strong>Value, Growth, and Contrarian Strategies are Best Suited for Experts</strong></p>
<p>These seemingly disparate strategies are not mutually exclusive. Investors can choose or combine strategies based on their individual characteristics.  The most effective strategy is subjective and depends on individual circumstances. The author recommends value investing for those skilled in financial analysis, growth investing for those with foresight, and contrarian investing for independent, emotionally disciplined individuals.</p>
<p>Value investing is considered the most sophisticated technique, requiring strong financial knowledge and valuation skills. Most investors lack this expertise. Even among analysts, few truly understand valuation.  Growth investing requires foresight to identify high-growth industries and companies, which is also challenging.  Contrarian investing requires no specialized knowledge but is the hardest to implement due to its counterintuitive nature.  Most people are trend followers. Few can buy when everyone is selling or sell when everyone is buying.</p>
<p>These three strategies can enhance returns if mastered and applied correctly.  Countless self-proclaimed &ldquo;investment experts&rdquo; populate the market, but few consistently outperform using these strategies.  Misapplied, these strategies can lead to short-term speculation and losses.  Therefore, the author still recommends the simple, yet effective, long-term buy-and-hold strategy of &ldquo;buy any stock, buy at any time, and don&rsquo;t sell&rdquo; for most investors.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Personal Investment Bible: Investment Iron Law XI</title>
      <link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1731056005970/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1731056005970/</guid>
      <description>This article explains why short-term stock trading should be avoided. The core argument is that long-term holding is the key to gaining returns from the stock market.  It analyzes the disadvantages of short-term trading, including high transaction costs, profits being taken by market makers and large investors, and investment failures caused by human weaknesses. The article emphasizes that the primary source of profit from stock investment is the company&amp;#39;s earnings, not price fluctuations. It advises investors to adopt a buy-and-hold strategy of “buy any stock, buy anytime, don&amp;#39;t sell” to truly benefit from the stock market.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[

<h2 class="relative group">Investment Iron Law 11: Avoid Short-Term Trading 
    <div id="investment-iron-law-11-avoid-short-term-trading" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#investment-iron-law-11-avoid-short-term-trading" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>The greatest enemy of investment activity is human weakness: greed, fear, and herd mentality.</p>
</blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">The Pitfalls of Buying Low and Selling High 
    <div id="the-pitfalls-of-buying-low-and-selling-high" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#the-pitfalls-of-buying-low-and-selling-high" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>Stock prices fluctuate in the short term, leading many investors to intuitively believe that profits can be made by simply &ldquo;buying low and selling high.&rdquo; Undeniably, the allure of price differences is strong. A limit-up day can bring thousands of dollars in profit, and buying ten lots could cover a month&rsquo;s salary. However, once captivated by this temptation and engaging in the game of short-term trading, you unknowingly enter a losing battle. While luck might bring short-term gains, long-term losses are inevitable.</p>
<p><strong>Stock Profits Are More Than Just Price Differences</strong></p>
<p>Many stock investors hold the misconception that profits come solely from price fluctuations. In reality, the primary source of profit lies in sharing the company&rsquo;s earnings, not capitalizing on short-term price swings. Stock investments generate returns because the invested companies&rsquo; earnings are ultimately distributed to investors.  The immense time and effort spent researching entry and exit points, diligently watching the market, and constantly chasing trends contribute nothing to the company&rsquo;s earnings.</p>
<p>The Taiwan Weighted Stock Index rose from 100 points in early 1967 to 6200 points at the end of August 1996, a 62-fold increase.  Using the end of 1986 as a base period, when the index was around 700 points, the rise to 6200 points by the end of August 1996 represents an increase of over 8 times. The Taiwan stock market&rsquo;s astonishing growth and substantial returns should have made every investor wealthy.  However, the reality is quite the opposite. Few Taiwanese investors have profited from stocks, while countless have suffered losses. According to a 1988 survey by Professor Lin Quanyuan, 27% of investors experienced losses, and 78% earned returns below the market average.  Private surveys suggest even higher loss rates.  The question arises: &ldquo;Where did the substantial stock market profits go?&rdquo;</p>
<p><strong>Short-Term Trading is Gambling</strong></p>
<p>Short-term stock trading is speculation and gambling, both characterized by a high probability of loss. We often see short-term traders boastful after successful speculations but disappear or remain silent after losses. This creates the false impression that short-term trading is profitable. In truth, these traders usually end up losing money.</p>
<p>Long-term stock holding yields an average annual return of over 15%, but only if the stocks are held and not sold. The biggest problem with short-term trading is the transaction costs incurred with each trade.  Investors often overlook these costs, believing they are insignificant compared to potential price differences. In the Taiwanese securities market, the transaction cost for each round trip (buy and sell) is approximately 0.6% of the transaction amount. While a single transaction cost seems small, the cumulative effect is substantial. Imagine trading more than 25 times a year, or every two weeks. The 15% annual return would be almost entirely eroded, making it worse than keeping the money in a bank.  Moreover, short-term traders often exceed 25 trades per year.  Factor in a few losses, and the return becomes negative.  Frequent trading inevitably diminishes returns, and negative returns are no different from gambling.</p>
<p>Therefore, if you cannot resist the urge to chase short-term price differences, it&rsquo;s best to avoid stock investment altogether and keep your money in the bank.  While you may not become rich, it&rsquo;s better than losing it all in the stock market.</p>
<p>In 1989, the total after-tax earnings of all listed companies in Taiwan were 110.3 billion NTD.  In the same year, securities transaction taxes were 152.4 billion NTD, and transaction fees totaled 76.2 billion NTD. This means the combined earnings of listed companies were insufficient to cover these costs, leaving investors with an additional 118.3 billion NTD in transaction costs. It&rsquo;s no wonder most stock investors suffer losses. The solution is simple: adopt a long-term holding strategy and minimize unnecessary trading. Long-term stock market investment offers high returns and lower risk. By holding long term, there&rsquo;s no need for worry or fear, and wealth can be accumulated over one or two decades.</p>
<p><strong>Short-Term Trading Creates Wealth for Intermediaries</strong></p>
<p>To achieve investment success, one must overcome &ldquo;greed during market upswings and fear during downswings.&rdquo;</p>
<p>A book from the 1940s in the US, titled <em>Where Are the Customer&rsquo;s Yachts?</em>, tells the story of a stockbroker taking a major client to a marina. Pointing at the luxurious yachts, the broker says, &ldquo;These yachts belong to our firm&rsquo;s brokers.&rdquo; The client then asks, &ldquo;Are any of them owned by your clients?&rdquo; The broker is speechless, as none of the yachts belonged to clients. (Note: yachts were a status symbol of wealth in American society at that time).</p>
<p>It seems unlikely that valuable clients of brokerage firms would be wealthy. This story illustrates that while stock market profits are substantial, most are earned by intermediaries.  Those who frequently trade and generate significant profits for brokerage firms rarely become yacht owners themselves.</p>
<p>Merrill Lynch annually has a dozen or so brokers earning over a million dollars.  However, their truly valuable clients are not exceptionally wealthy individuals. Wealthy people are usually busy making money and don&rsquo;t have the time for frequent trading.  They wouldn&rsquo;t be considered valuable clients. Only those who constantly engage in short-term trading are the major contributors to transaction fees and the most loyal customers of brokerage firms.</p>
<p>In 1990, a scholar wrote a bestselling book on securities investment, earning about 1 million NTD.  He was overjoyed, as it was a considerable sum for a writer.  However, his friend at a brokerage firm mocked him, saying, &ldquo;Your three years of hard work only earned you the equivalent of one month&rsquo;s salary for a broker in our company.&rdquo;</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Retail investors, your name is weakness.</p>
</blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">A Losing Game 
    <div id="a-losing-game" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#a-losing-game" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>The stock market comprises four main participants: intermediaries, major shareholders, large investors, and retail investors. Intermediaries include brokerage firms, the government, and information providers like newspapers, magazines, financial channels, and software companies.  Regardless of market outcomes, intermediaries always profit, and their profits increase with trading volume and frequency. Major shareholders are company management or those with significant equity stakes.  They have ample capital, resources, and information, giving them a winning edge. Large investors have more capital than retail investors, affording them a higher probability of success.</p>
<p><strong>Intermediaries and Large Investors Are the Winners</strong></p>
<p>The original purpose of financial markets was to channel funds from the public to businesses, which then invest and share profits with investors.  However, based on the analysis above, listed companies&rsquo; earnings are insufficient to cover the costs of intermediaries, let alone distribute profits to retail investors. For retail investors to profit, they must outperform the other three players.  In short-term trading, retail investors face intermediaries who always win, major shareholders who are guaranteed to win, and large investors with a higher probability of winning.  In this game, retail investors have no chance.</p>
<p>Most short-term trading failures are attributed to lack of skill or bad luck. In reality, a calm analysis reveals a guaranteed losing game.</p>
<p><strong>How to Win Without Fighting</strong></p>
<p>As a retail investor, how can you navigate this game against major shareholders, intermediaries, and large investors? The simplest solution: &ldquo;Don&rsquo;t play!&rdquo;</p>
<p>Listed companies, on average, generate profits annually, and successful companies grow increasingly profitable.  Therefore, not investing idle funds means missing out on long-term gains. The &ldquo;don&rsquo;t play&rdquo; strategy doesn&rsquo;t advocate avoiding the stock market altogether. Instead, it encourages investing and then leaving it alone, minimizing short-term trading.</p>
<p>By consistently investing available funds and holding long-term, investors can benefit from both company earnings and overall economic growth. This long-term holding strategy, avoiding the trading game played by intermediaries and large investors, can dramatically shift the investment landscape.  If investors buy and hold, intermediaries and major shareholders lose their advantage.  Even with substantial capital and insider information, their attempts to manipulate prices won&rsquo;t lure disciplined retail investors into their traps, eliminating the disadvantage faced by smaller investors.  Major shareholders, large investors, and retail investors would then stand on equal footing, sharing the benefits of long-term market growth.</p>
<p>This &ldquo;immovable mountain&rdquo; strategy transforms retail investors&rsquo; disadvantage into an advantage, shifting the disadvantage to the other players, particularly intermediaries. If investors stop trading frequently, brokerage firms lose transaction fees, the government loses taxes, and financial information providers lose business.  With no one to &ldquo;feed&rdquo; them, they might be forced to become buy-and-hold investors themselves.</p>
<p><strong>The correct investment philosophy is to profit together, not to defeat others.</strong>  The truly intelligent strategy is to avoid the competition.  As Sun Tzu&rsquo;s <em>Art of War</em> states, &ldquo;The supreme art of war is to subdue the enemy without fighting.&rdquo;  The primary consideration in investment strategy should not be defeating others but maximizing profits.</p>
<p>How can everyone win? If every investor adopts the strategy presented in this book—&ldquo;buy any stock, buy anytime, don&rsquo;t sell&rdquo;—and adheres to this simple principle, a win-win situation for all can be achieved.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Futures markets make casinos pale in comparison.</p>
</blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">Avoid Futures and Margin Trading 
    <div id="avoid-futures-and-margin-trading" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#avoid-futures-and-margin-trading" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>In 1995, a single trader&rsquo;s mismanagement of futures trading resulted in a $1.1 billion loss, causing the collapse of Barings Bank, one of Britain&rsquo;s oldest banks. This is not an isolated incident. With the rise of derivative financial products like futures and margin trading (forex, bond margin trading, etc.), such incidents of company collapses or personal bankruptcies due to mismanagement have become increasingly common.  Several high-performing listed companies in Taiwan have also faced near-bankruptcy due to losses in futures or margin trading.</p>
<p><strong>Either Big Wins or Big Losses</strong></p>
<p>What makes futures and margin trading so dangerous?  The core issue is the margin trading system itself, which has a high degree of leverage, leading to either significant gains or devastating losses in the short term. The high risk also encourages frequent trading, often multiple times a day. These transaction costs, relative to the margin, are extremely high.  The combined effect of frequent trading and high transaction costs pushes the returns from futures and margin trading into significant negative territory.</p>
<p>A saying circulates in the US securities market: &ldquo;Futures markets make casinos pale in comparison.&rdquo;  In other words, futures markets are even more of a gamble than casinos. After paying substantial transaction costs to intermediaries, what profits are left for investors?  The author has extensively studied investment history across various countries and has personally participated in the securities market for over a decade.  I have never heard of any investor consistently profiting from long-term participation in futures or margin trading.  On the contrary, almost everyone I know involved in such activities has ultimately lost money.</p>
<p>The purpose of futures and margin trading markets is to provide hedging tools for businesses.  Individual investors rarely have such hedging needs.  For them, these markets become &ldquo;even more of a gamble than casinos&rdquo; due to the temptation of short-term trading. The author strongly advises readers to avoid futures and margin trading entirely. If reading this book leads you to stay away from these activities, then the book&rsquo;s price has already been repaid, and the author&rsquo;s efforts have been worthwhile.</p>
<p><strong>Often a Waste of Effort</strong></p>
<p>The biggest obstacle to successful financial management is not the difficulty of understanding but the difficulty of implementing what is understood.  The principles discussed above are easy to grasp, but understanding doesn&rsquo;t guarantee implementation.  In the volatile investment world, faced with fluctuating prices, investors are often tempted by greed to chase short-term gains or driven by fear to react to price swings. They unknowingly fall into the trap of short-term trading. While the process can be thrilling, it often ends in wasted effort. The true beneficiaries of this game are usually the brokerage firms and the major shareholders manipulating the stocks, leaving retail investors with losses.</p>
<p><strong>Many people invest in stocks not to build wealth but to prove their intelligence, knowledge, and predictive abilities to others.</strong> They constantly analyze and research, overemphasizing market trends and predictions. This leads to impatience, chasing rising prices and selling during dips, attempting to profit from short-term fluctuations.  However, this constant buying and selling consumes time, energy, and money in the form of hefty transaction costs, while also creating opportunities for major shareholders and large investors to manipulate stocks.  The ultimate result is often a waste of time and money. While knowledge and experience might increase, wealth does not.</p>
<p><strong>To succeed in the fast-paced and lucrative investment world, you must cultivate self-discipline.</strong> The secret to investment success lies not in knowledge or skill, nor in intelligence or luck, but in self-control. Your investment acumen allows your assets to generate returns, and your patience in long-term holding allows the power of compounding to take you to new levels of wealth. Before succumbing to the temptation of short-term trading, ask yourself: &ldquo;Which wealthy person achieved their fortune through continuous short-term trading?&rdquo; and &ldquo;Which successful stock market investor didn&rsquo;t rely on long-term holding?&rdquo;</p>
<p><strong>Temporary Glory Leads to Crushing Debt</strong></p>
<p>In the history of the Taiwan stock market, it&rsquo;s difficult to find examples of individuals who built wealth through short-term trading. There are many who gained fame through short-term speculation, like Lei Bolong, but they often ended up heavily in debt and even faced imprisonment.  This is not unique to Taiwan; the same holds true for the US stock market.  The author has studied renowned American investors and has never found a prominent figure whose strategy primarily involved short-term trading.  Long-term wealth accumulation through short-term trading is virtually unheard of.</p>
<p>Stock investment is a vital path to personal wealth creation and a crucial source of long-term capital for businesses. However, using the wrong approach can lead to financial ruin instead of prosperity. Listed companies issue stocks to raise capital, and if these funds are then misused in speculative games, it can be detrimental to individuals, society, and the nation.</p>
<p>Stockholders are company owners with the inherent rights to profit sharing and residual asset distribution.  Therefore, the company&rsquo;s profits will eventually be distributed to shareholders as dividends. With patience, the wealth generated by the company ultimately belongs to the investors.</p>
<p>Therefore, I urge all readers to avoid the game of short-term trading.  Throughout history, no renowned investor has achieved wealth through short-term speculation. Based on the author&rsquo;s observations, the vast majority of those who engage in short-term trading lose money, and many face financial ruin.</p>
<p><em>1. True profits come not from short-term trading skills but from the discipline of long-term holding.</em></p>
<p><em>2. In the long run, short-term traders inevitably lose. There are no exceptions.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Personal Investment Bible: Investment Iron Law Ⅸ</title>
      <link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1731056005968/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1731056005968/</guid>
      <description>This article explores common misconceptions in investment and financial management, particularly the reliance on forecasting and technical analysis. The author argues that technical analysis cannot consistently help investors achieve excess returns and instead often leads to the trap of short-term trading.  The article advocates a long-term investment strategy of &amp;#39;buy any stock, buy anytime, and don&amp;#39;t sell,&amp;#39; emphasizing that the key to successful investing lies in selecting the right investment targets and holding them for the long term, rather than attempting to predict short-term market fluctuations.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[

<h2 class="relative group">Investment Iron Law 9: Grasping the General Market Trend 
    <div id="investment-iron-law-9-grasping-the-general-market-trend" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#investment-iron-law-9-grasping-the-general-market-trend" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>Basing investment decisions on technical analysis<br>
often indicates a lack of experience.<br>
In most cases, it won&rsquo;t make you money.</p>
</blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">The Blind Spots of Forecasting and Analysis 
    <div id="the-blind-spots-of-forecasting-and-analysis" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#the-blind-spots-of-forecasting-and-analysis" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>The reason many investors engage in frequent short-term trading, besides being attracted by price fluctuations, is mainly due to the so-called &ldquo;experts&rdquo; who flood the investment market with constant analysis and forecasts, providing investors with specious advice. This leads investors to frantically chase the &ldquo;buy low, sell high&rdquo; principle.  Let&rsquo;s discuss whether forecasting and analysis are truly effective. Can they genuinely help investors make a fortune?</p>
<p><strong>Is Technical Analysis Effective?</strong></p>
<p>In April 1993, the Taiwan <em>Economic Daily</em> published an article titled, &ldquo;Success in Stocks Depends on Entry and Exit Timing.&rdquo; This led many to believe that the most crucial task in investment analysis is determining the right moments to buy and sell.</p>
<p>The average investor believes the golden rule for wealth in the stock market is &ldquo;buy low, sell high.&rdquo;  They also believe the key to success lies in accurately grasping these timing opportunities. Consequently, countless investors try every means to predict future stock price trends to determine optimal buying and selling points.  In their quest for the Midas touch, various methods, from the scientific to the absurd, and even the supernatural, such as astrology and market horoscopes, have emerged.  Currently, the most widely used method is &ldquo;technical analysis.&rdquo;</p>
<p>In the author&rsquo;s humble opinion, technical analysis&rsquo;s popularity in the global investment market, and its continued prevalence among Taiwanese investors, stems from the fact that it appears sophisticated yet not overwhelmingly complex, thus attracting many novice investors.  These beginners often believe they must possess some secret technique to navigate the stock market, leading them to prioritize learning technical analysis upon entering the market.</p>
<p>Technical analysis originated from the Dow Theory in the 1930s, after which various technical analysis methods sprung up like mushrooms.  From the 1940s to the 1960s, technical analysis was highly popular in the US stock market.  However, with the advent of the Random Walk Theory, and the observation that most users of technical analysis ended up worse off, its popularity began to wane.  By the 1980s, when the author was studying investment analysis in the US stock market, established investment analysts rarely mentioned technical analysis.  At the time, if an investor claimed to use technical analysis for investment decisions, it implied inexperience and a high probability of losing money.</p>
<p>Technical analysis involves studying and analyzing past price trends and volume data to determine buying and selling timings. Its fundamental assumption is that history repeats itself. Therefore, by identifying the patterns of stock price movements, one can accurately predict future trends.</p>
<p><strong>Beating the Market is a Pipe Dream</strong></p>
<p>Numerous empirical studies by scholars have revealed many problems and controversies surrounding technical analysis.  Briefly summarized:</p>
<ul>
<li>
<ol>
<li>Historical patterns don&rsquo;t always repeat. Even if technical analysis has been effective for decades, it doesn&rsquo;t guarantee future success.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol start="2">
<li>If a particular technical analysis method consistently succeeds, its widespread adoption will eliminate its potential profits.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol start="3">
<li>The collective actions of technical analysts can create price patterns.  This means the price isn&rsquo;t reflecting a correct prediction but rather the analysts&rsquo; actions.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol start="4">
<li>Some technical indicators rely on comparisons with past data.  These values can change due to time and environment, making past standards inapplicable to the present.</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ul>
<p>If you were given a past stock chart and asked to devise a profitable investment strategy, everyone would understand &ldquo;buy low, sell high.&rdquo;  Profiting from trading in such a scenario would be easy.  However, investing is about the future. Future price movements are complex and unpredictable; no one possesses a future stock chart.  So, is &ldquo;buy low, sell high&rdquo; still a suitable investment strategy?  The answer is no.  The reason is simple: no one can predict market highs and lows in advance.</p>
<p>Using previously successful technical analysis methods doesn&rsquo;t guarantee future success in beating the market, as excess returns can be random.  Furthermore, concluding that technical analysis is effective based on occasional or random excess returns is misleading. While technical analysis might yield short-term gains, it cannot consistently outperform the market in the long run.</p>
<p>A student once asked me, if the market follows a random walk and technical analysis is ineffective, why are some technical analysis methods accurate at times?  Claiming technical analysis is ineffective means it can&rsquo;t generate long-term excess profits, not that its predictions are always wrong.  Technical analysis can sometimes be accurate, just like random guesses can be accurate.  Therefore, technical analysis isn&rsquo;t necessarily inaccurate; its accuracy is comparable to guessing.</p>
<p><strong>The Trap of Short-Term Trading</strong></p>
<p>Another significant drawback of technical analysis is that its methods focus on identifying buy and sell points.  These points constantly emerge, forcing investors to frequently buy and sell, trapping them in short-term trading and eroding returns through transaction costs. The ineffectiveness of technical analysis means that, on average, it doesn&rsquo;t generate excess returns over the long term. In other words, while sometimes accurate, it ultimately underperforms the market&rsquo;s average return (buy-and-hold strategy).</p>
<p>You might have used technical analysis methods with seemingly good results.  I admit some methods can be effective, but investors often overlook transaction costs.  Considering these costs, returns from technical analysis are unlikely to be high.  Furthermore, the effectiveness of any technical analysis method is inconsistent, making long-term high returns improbable.</p>
<p>Technical analysis exhausts investors, leading to significant losses.  Investors should abandon it and adopt a long-term &ldquo;buy-and-hold&rdquo; strategy to benefit from long-term market growth.  It&rsquo;s crucial to understand that market risk is inherent in any investment strategy.  Investors should be mentally prepared and avoid excessive optimism about short-term returns.  Profitable investing relies on correctly judging the overall market direction.  Obsessively seeking investment rules from past data, even if profitable, will likely incur time and effort costs exceeding the returns.</p>
<p>If you still believe technical analysis can lead to riches, ask yourself: who has become wealthy solely through technical analysis?</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Blind faith in predictions is worse than no prediction at all.
Prediction is more art than science.</p>
</blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">The Only Certainty is Uncertainty 
    <div id="the-only-certainty-is-uncertainty" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#the-only-certainty-is-uncertainty" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>The biggest mistake in investment strategies is overconfidence in prediction. If you&rsquo;ve tirelessly searched for prediction methods without success, or your developed methods are unreliable and unprofitable, don&rsquo;t be discouraged. All predictions face the same challenges.</p>
<p>Like you, forecasting experts cannot predict the future.  If they possessed a crystal ball, they would be wealthy, not making a living from predictions.  If this logic isn&rsquo;t convincing, ask yourself: &ldquo;Which self-made millionaire or consistently successful long-term investor has relied solely on prediction?&rdquo;  The answer is none.</p>
<p><strong>Investment Performance is Unrelated to Predictive Ability</strong></p>
<p>People often assume investment success hinges on predictive ability.  Those who predict better supposedly perform better, while investment failures are attributed to poor prediction. However, this isn&rsquo;t true. Most successful investors admit their inability to predict the future. They have no preconceived notions, and their success stems from sound strategies, not accurate predictions.</p>
<p>During my studies in the US, when I first dabbled in the US stock market, I shared the common belief that Wall Street analysts were remarkable and highly skilled at predicting market trends. After graduating from UC Berkeley in 1987, I left academia for a position at a major US brokerage firm, largely driven by the desire to learn from renowned analysts at Merrill Lynch.</p>
<p>At Merrill Lynch, I witnessed these analysts firsthand. After numerous interactions, I realized they couldn&rsquo;t accurately predict future stock prices. Some didn&rsquo;t even invest in stocks themselves. I often called analysts, asking which stocks to buy and when the market would rise. One analyst, perhaps tired of my persistent inquiries, frankly told me, &ldquo;Think about it. If I knew which stocks would rise and when the market would go up, would I be stuck working as an analyst?&rdquo;  It was then I understood that analysts don&rsquo;t possess predictive powers.</p>
<p>Upon returning to Taiwan, I observed that local newspapers and magazines were filled with &ldquo;Expert Predictions&rdquo; or &ldquo;Analyst Market Forecasts.&rdquo;  I interacted with several well-known analysts, studying their predictions carefully. My conclusion: there were no superior predictions in the Taiwan stock market.  These analysts and experts couldn&rsquo;t accurately grasp the market&rsquo;s future direction.</p>
<p><strong>Analysts Rely on Hype</strong></p>
<p>Why do so many analysts and experts constantly make predictions in the media? The reason is simple: supply follows demand. Readers crave these predictions, prompting newspapers and magazines to create dedicated columns.  Experts often publish predictions not because they possess foresight but because readers believe experts have superior knowledge of the future and eagerly seek their opinions.  Newspapers cater to this demand by soliciting expert articles.  Similarly, why do brokerage firms employ so many analysts to interpret market trends for clients? To meet customer needs.  In a competitive environment, analyst insights are considered a crucial service. Brokerage firms readily provide this service because research indicates that investors guided by experts tend towards short-term trading, generating higher commissions for the firms.</p>
<p>This demonstrates investors&rsquo; heavy reliance on expert predictions, which arise from investor demand. The problem is that the stock market is unpredictable.  No one can make accurate predictions, a widely acknowledged fact.  Yet, most investors still believe in expert forecasts.</p>
<p>A US poll once asked, &ldquo;Who lies to the public the most?&rdquo; The results: weather forecasters, stock analysts, and economic commentators.  This reveals not that expert predictions are always inaccurate but the public&rsquo;s unwavering faith in them, leading to heightened expectations.  These professions often require making future predictions under the assumption that &ldquo;experts must be able to predict; those who can&rsquo;t predict aren&rsquo;t experts.&rdquo;  This pressure compels many researchers and analysts to publish future predictions, despite the inherent uncertainty.  Being wrong is inevitable, and being perceived as liars arises from the public&rsquo;s initial belief in their predictions, leading to feelings of deception when they prove incorrect.</p>
<p>You might question this, citing instances of analysts who made remarkably accurate predictions, causing stocks to surge upon their recommendations.  However, have you noticed that these seemingly prophetic &ldquo;experts&rdquo; are rarely the same person and often disappear after a while?  In reality, these experts, unless backed by market manipulators who profit from deceiving retail investors, are simply experiencing probability at play.  Occasional streaks of accuracy are possible but not sustainable.</p>
<p><strong>Strategies to Lure Retail Investors</strong></p>
<p>Market manipulators aiming to pump and dump a stock, besides securing cooperation from major shareholders, must create a forecasting &ldquo;expert&rdquo; who, through media appearances, convinces retail investors to buy in.  As major shareholders lock up their shares and more investors join, it creates the illusion that the &ldquo;expert&rsquo;s&rdquo; predictions are coming true, causing the stock price to surge.</p>
<p>Joseph Granville was a popular technical analyst in the early 1980s.  His remarkably accurate market predictions in the late 1970s made him famous.  His large following gave him considerable market influence; his words could move the market by tens of points.  However, in early 1982, he predicted a major market crash, advising his followers to sell all their stocks.  Instead, the market surged from around 700 to over 1200 points within five months.  Those who heeded his advice missed a significant bull market, and Granville faded into obscurity.</p>
<p>I advise investors to avoid stocks being manipulated. Even if you make small profits initially, one loss could wipe out all gains and more.  Another reason: manipulated stocks involve major shareholder intervention.  These shareholders, instead of focusing on business operations and profits, are interested in quick gains through market manipulation, indicating poor management.  Such companies aren&rsquo;t worth investing in. Their scheme relies on retail investors&rsquo; money; retail investors have little chance of winning.  If retail investors could profit from this game, what would be the point for the major shareholders?</p>
<p>Another possibility for accurate predictions is simply probability.  Predictions are often diverse and contradictory, with some bullish, some bearish, and some expecting consolidation.  Inevitably, someone will be right, purely due to luck or higher guessing probability.</p>
<p><strong>More Wrong Guesses Than Right</strong></p>
<p>However, most people don&rsquo;t think this way.  When experts make several consecutive correct predictions, they gain credibility and are hailed as &ldquo;prophets.&rdquo;  People easily forget past incorrect predictions, treating the &ldquo;prophet&rsquo;s&rdquo; words as gospel.  This is extremely dangerous. Investors overlook the possibility of future incorrect predictions.</p>
<p>I&rsquo;m not entirely dismissing analysts and experts.  In the unpredictable investment world, many investors need expert guidance.  Analyst data and forecasts can be valuable reference material. My point is, regardless of your attitude towards expert predictions, remember: the future is dynamic and unpredictable.  Investment risk is an unavoidable reality and must be managed.</p>
<p>In early 1990, as the market peaked, most experts predicted continued growth. A prominent &ldquo;market prophet&rdquo; confidently proclaimed the market would reach 15,000 points within six months and 20,000 within a year.  Major media outlets reported this prediction.  The reality was starkly different.  Within six months, the market plummeted 2,000 points, shocking all experts.  Did these experts disappear?  No.  Newspapers and magazines still feature expert market forecasts.  The reason is simple: investors are &ldquo;used to&rdquo; hearing these predictions and many remain captivated by them.</p>
<p>I don&rsquo;t advocate completely ignoring predictions.  Predictions have value, and good predictions are worth considering.  However, whether you believe in predictions or not, and regardless of the predictor&rsquo;s reputation, remember: the future is fluid and unpredictable.  Investment risk is an inherent part of investing and must be managed.</p>
<p>You don&rsquo;t need predictive abilities to invest well or make money in the market. In this complex and volatile market, the only certainty is uncertainty.  In the investment world, profits come from choosing the right investments and holding them long-term, not from predicting market movements.  In summary, consider expert predictions, but remember they are just predictions.  Don&rsquo;t blindly trust them.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>There are no experts in the stock market, only winners and losers.</p>
</blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">Trust Yourself, Not the Experts 
    <div id="trust-yourself-not-the-experts" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#trust-yourself-not-the-experts" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>Some believe that lacking professional expertise makes achieving wealth through investment incredibly difficult. Yet, many who don&rsquo;t understand stocks or real estate still achieve financial success through investing.  Most successful investors aren&rsquo;t investment professionals, and investment professionals aren&rsquo;t necessarily successful investors.  This shows that expertise isn&rsquo;t a prerequisite for wealth creation through investment.</p>
<p>Investment and financial management aren&rsquo;t inherently complex.  The perceived complexity and reliance on experts stem from investors&rsquo; inability to cope with uncertainty, overcomplicating simple matters and turning financial management into a source of anxiety and confusion.  This anxiety hinders rational decision-making, leading people to constantly seek external opinions.</p>
<p><strong>10 Experts, 11 Opinions</strong></p>
<p>The inability to handle uncertainty creates the illusion that foresight or profound analytical skills are necessary for successful investing, leading to the belief that only &ldquo;experts&rdquo; can manage finances effectively. Consequently, many entrust their financial decisions to experts, who often offer conflicting &ldquo;expert opinions.&rdquo; Ten experts can have eleven different views, further complicating the investment world and adding to investor confusion.</p>
<p>Basing your financial decisions solely on expert opinions is extremely dangerous. Ultimately, investment responsibility lies with the individual. Investors should enhance their financial literacy and become their own experts.  Financial management doesn&rsquo;t require extensive professional knowledge. By following a few basic principles outlined in this book and acting accordingly, you can achieve wealth without relying on experts.  With the right investment philosophy, you might even outperform them.</p>
<p>Therefore, I urge investors to take immediate action, start investing, and stop asking questions like &ldquo;When will the market rise?&rdquo; &ldquo;Which stock should I buy?&rdquo; or &ldquo;Should I sell my xxx stock now?&rdquo;  These questions are pointless; no one knows the correct answers.</p>
<p>In 1983, when I began my doctoral studies at UC Berkeley, I started helping Taiwanese entrepreneurs invest in US stocks.  To excel at this, I dedicated immense effort to stock analysis, often neglecting sleep and meals. For one to two years, I practically lived in the Berkeley Haas School of Business library, devouring every investment book and analyzing all available stock information. I learned various technical, fundamental, and market analysis techniques.  To develop my unique investment analysis and prediction methods, I utilized Berkeley&rsquo;s advanced computers and extensive stock databases, writing programs to simulate various investment approaches.  This proved futile; I couldn&rsquo;t find a satisfactory method.  It was all for naught.</p>
<p>If anyone truly knew when the market would rise or which stock to buy, they would be wealthy enough not to need a job as an analyst or expert.  I reiterate: even without knowing &ldquo;when the market will rise&rdquo; or &ldquo;which stock to buy,&rdquo; you can still achieve wealth through investing.  Stop wasting time on these questions. Countless people have dedicated their lives to researching them since the inception of the stock market. They became stock experts but didn&rsquo;t achieve wealth through investing.</p>
<p><strong>Inaction and Effortless Gains</strong></p>
<p>Financial management doesn&rsquo;t require excessive time. Those who spend less time on it often perform better.</p>
<p>Statistics show that Taiwanese stock investors spend an average of 3.12 hours daily on stock analysis and market watching. Is stock picking difficult? Is making money in the stock market challenging?  Constantly chasing price fluctuations, what are your returns?  Those who diligently study stocks often lose the most money.</p>
<p>A common investor mistake is giving up.  They eagerly enter during bull markets and become disheartened during bear markets, abandoning the market entirely.  Lacking patience and perseverance, they rarely succeed.  Conversely, those with less financial acumen, admitting their inability to time the market, often persevere and ultimately fare better.</p>
<p>The path to investment wealth is simple: effortless gains. The investment strategy presented—&ldquo;buy any stock, buy anytime, don&rsquo;t sell&rdquo;—can be summarized as &ldquo;do nothing, gain effortlessly.&rdquo;</p>
<p>Who wouldn&rsquo;t want effortless gains? Surprisingly, most investors can&rsquo;t achieve this.  &ldquo;There&rsquo;s no such thing as a free lunch&rdquo; is a widely known principle. Applying this to investment, people assume they must master complex techniques and work harder than others to profit.  Intuitively, they believe more knowledge and effort equate to higher returns. This might hold true in other areas, but in finance, the opposite is often true. Knowledge and effort don&rsquo;t significantly contribute to investment returns.  Knowing more and constantly monitoring the market encourages impulsive trading, leading to &ldquo;effort without gain.&rdquo;</p>
<p><strong>Inaction is Superior to Action</strong></p>
<p>Even investment gurus like Warren Buffett and Peter Lynch admit they can&rsquo;t predict market movements. Admitting ignorance might seem foolish, but it&rsquo;s the beginning of financial wisdom.  Being &ldquo;foolish&rdquo; enough to &ldquo;buy any stock, buy anytime, don&rsquo;t sell&rdquo; is the starting point of wealth creation. Confucius said, &ldquo;Great wisdom appears foolish.&rdquo;  This refers to highly learned individuals who achieve mastery through natural means, without contrivance or cunning.  They appear unintelligent but are truly wise.  Lao Tzu also said, &ldquo;Great skill appears clumsy,&rdquo; and advocated for &ldquo;governing by non-interference.&rdquo;  This strategy, applied to the volatile investment environment, is a sound approach. Unless you have strong conviction about future trends, it&rsquo;s better to ignore the chaos and remain inactive.</p>
<p>Therefore, you don&rsquo;t need to be an investment expert or possess sophisticated techniques.  &ldquo;Do nothing, gain effortlessly&rdquo; is the key to financial wealth. You might think this sounds too simple, even boring.  Indeed, it is. But this simplicity is the path to riches and becoming a millionaire.  Before acting, ask yourself: &ldquo;Do I want wealth or to be a stock market expert?&rdquo;  If you want wealth through stocks, emulate the many who became rich by simply investing and then ignoring the market.  Decades later, compounding will make you wealthy. You could also dedicate yourself to becoming a stock market expert, but this rarely leads to riches.</p>
<p>My point is, even without knowing &ldquo;when the market will rise&rdquo; or &ldquo;which stock to buy,&rdquo; you can still achieve wealth through investing. Short-term market fluctuations are unpredictable, but the long-term trend is upward. Long-term investing is the key to profit.</p>
<p>&ldquo;Buy any stock, buy anytime, don&rsquo;t sell&rdquo;—so simple, effortless, and seemingly undeserved.  While it feels like unearned gain, don&rsquo;t feel guilty.  Investing in stocks contributes to economic development.  Constant trading harms individual wealth and offers no benefit to the overall economy or society.</p>
<p><strong>Easier Said Than Done</strong></p>
<p>Some worry and ask, &ldquo;You advise against saving money in banks.  If your book becomes a bestseller and this idea spreads, wouldn&rsquo;t it cause a nationwide bank run?&rdquo; This is an unnecessary concern. I&rsquo;ve been advocating against saving money in banks for three years, even before this book&rsquo;s publication. Many who hear this idea nod in agreement, as if enlightened, yet days, months, or years later, their money remains untouched in bank accounts.</p>
<p>Others question whether my &ldquo;buy any stock, buy anytime, don&rsquo;t sell&rdquo; theory, if widely adopted, would force brokerage firms to close, depriving the government of transaction taxes.  Again, there&rsquo;s no need for such concerns.  Those who frequently engage in short-term trading in stocks, futures, or margin accounts, even after understanding that it only benefits intermediaries, often can&rsquo;t resist continuing their behavior.  Like gambling, everyone knows the odds are stacked against them, yet gambling persists.</p>
<p><strong>I understand that &ldquo;don&rsquo;t save money in banks,&rdquo; &ldquo;avoid short-term trading,&rdquo; and &ldquo;diversify and hold long-term,&rdquo; are simple in theory but difficult in practice.  Nevertheless, I sincerely hope readers can integrate knowledge and action, diversifying most of their assets into stocks and real estate, holding them long-term. Achieving financial freedom is within reach.</strong></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Personal Investment Bible: Investment Iron Law VIII</title>
      <link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1731056005967/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1731056005967/</guid>
      <description>This article explores a simple long-term investment strategy: buy randomly, buy anytime, and don&amp;#39;t sell.  The author argues that due to the unpredictable nature of stock market fluctuations, it&amp;#39;s better to diversify investments and hold them long-term rather than painstakingly selecting stocks and timing the market.  The article uses the example of the Hou brothers and the Random Walk Hypothesis to support this viewpoint, emphasizing the importance of long-term holding and diversification.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[

<h2 class="relative group">Investment Iron Law VIII:  Profit When You Buy, Profit When You Sell 
    <div id="investment-iron-law-viii--profit-when-you-buy-profit-when-you-sell" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#investment-iron-law-viii--profit-when-you-buy-profit-when-you-sell" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>Some people do nothing all day,<br>
understand nothing about investing,<br>
yet become billionaires.</p>
</blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">Buy Randomly, Buy Anytime, Don&rsquo;t Sell 
    <div id="buy-randomly-buy-anytime-dont-sell" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#buy-randomly-buy-anytime-dont-sell" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>You may already understand the principle of wealth creation: invest money in high-return investment vehicles and hold them for the long term. But you might still have questions: How should you invest? When should you buy? What should you buy? When should you sell?</p>
<p><strong>The Highest Realm of Financial Management</strong></p>
<p>I propose an investment strategy here. This method is arguably the simplest, as everyone can do it; yet it is also the hardest, as few can truly follow it. This strategy is: &ldquo;<strong>Buy randomly, buy anytime, don&rsquo;t sell.</strong>&rdquo;  You might ask, &ldquo;What&rsquo;s so difficult about buying randomly, buying anytime, and not selling?&rdquo;  If you think it&rsquo;s easy, try it yourself. If you can genuinely do it, then congratulations! You have grasped the essence of investment and financial management, reaching the highest level of investing prowess.</p>
<p>The average investor&rsquo;s favorite questions are: &ldquo;What to buy?&rdquo; &ldquo;When to buy?&rdquo; &ldquo;When to sell?&rdquo; Imagine if someone knew the answers, they would surely keep it a secret and profit themselves. Would they tell you first?  Investors often assume experts know when the market will rise or fall, and which stocks to buy.  It&rsquo;s as if those who don&rsquo;t know these things are not worthy of being called experts or analysts. However, only true experts admit they don&rsquo;t know when the market will rise or fall. <strong>Precisely because no one knows future market movements, investing is worthwhile. It&rsquo;s this uncertainty that creates the potential for high returns. Otherwise, all investment profits would be taken by those with foreknowledge.</strong></p>
<p>Most people believe that to profit from investing, you must accurately predict market timing, select the right investment targets, and know when to sell.  But based on my more than ten years of experience in investment, investment management, and investment research, capturing the perfect entry point is nearly impossible. Even investment gurus like Warren Buffett and Peter Lynch admit they don&rsquo;t know when stocks will rise or when to sell.</p>
<p>You might be puzzled by how some people, seemingly doing nothing and lacking investment knowledge, become incredibly wealthy. The three principles presented in this book – &ldquo;buy randomly, buy anytime, don&rsquo;t sell&rdquo; – are the key factors to their success.</p>
<p><strong>The Wealth Creation Method of Hou Boming, Executive Director of Tainan Spinning</strong></p>
<p>The three Hou brothers, Boming, Boyu, and Boyi, are the largest shareholders of Tainan Spinning, possessing a fortune exceeding 15 billion. Despite being major tycoons in Southern Taiwan, they maintain a low profile.  Hou Boming, in his 40s, can sometimes be found playing pinball at night markets.</p>
<p>Hou Boming&rsquo;s grandfather, Hou Yuli, was a founding figure of Tainan Spinning.  After the successive deaths of his grandfather and father, Hou Yongdu, Hou Boming, his two older brothers, and his mother inherited a quarter of Tainan Spinning&rsquo;s shares. They remained passive shareholders, not participating in the company&rsquo;s management, staying completely silent. Their immense wealth only came to light when Hou Yuli&rsquo;s daughter, Hou Yingzu, sued her brothers, Hou Yongdu and Hou Yongsong, and her nephew, Hou Boming, for allegedly misappropriating family assets.</p>
<p>The Hou brothers&rsquo; investment strategy is simple: buy stocks and hold them long-term, accumulating wealth through dividends. Some criticize them for lacking business acumen and real estate development skills, but with this simple method, they became one of the top 20 richest families in Taiwan.</p>
<p>Had they heeded others&rsquo; advice and sold their stocks to pursue business ventures, they might have lost their position among the top 20 wealthiest, perhaps becoming another example of &ldquo;wealth not lasting three generations.&rdquo; If they had deposited their money in the bank, the wealth accumulated by their grandfather 40 years ago might have dwindled to almost nothing due to inflation.  With a real return rate of zero in a bank, depositing NT$500,000 annually would take 200 years to reach NT$100 million.</p>
<p>To the average person, the Hou brothers&rsquo; approach may seem unremarkable. Yet, their wealth hasn&rsquo;t diminished due to inflation; instead, it has grown year after year.  Their grandfather was a multi-millionaire 30 years ago, but their generation has become multi-billionaires. The key lies in investing in high-return vehicles – stocks – and holding them long-term.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Blindfolded, throw a dart,<br>
Buy whichever stock it hits.</p>
</blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">What to Buy - Buy Randomly 
    <div id="what-to-buy---buy-randomly" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#what-to-buy---buy-randomly" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>Everyone says choosing the right investment target is crucial for success, and I agree. But how to choose is a difficult and complex question.  The strategy I propose is exceptionally simple, so simple that you might not be able to follow it: &ldquo;Buy randomly.&rdquo;</p>
<p><strong>More Accurate than a Broker&rsquo;s Eye</strong></p>
<p>&ldquo;Buy randomly&rdquo; is so simple!  Some suggest pinning the stock market section of <em>The Wall Street Journal</em> to a wall and throwing darts at it, buying whichever stock the dart hits.  Scholars conducted an experiment where a monkey, blindfolded, threw darts at stock listings.  The resulting portfolio performed remarkably well, even outperforming portfolios managed by professional fund managers.</p>
<p>Why is &ldquo;buying randomly&rdquo; a good stock selection method? If you&rsquo;ve studied portfolio diversification theory in finance, you&rsquo;ll understand that as the number of stocks in a portfolio increases (beyond 10), the impact of individual stock factors diminishes.  In other words, <strong>as long as you diversify, stock selection ability becomes less important. Random selection works.</strong>  Especially with 30 or 40 different stocks, the overall performance will closely mirror the market.</p>
<p>Buying randomly sounds simple, even a monkey or a fool could do it. But in reality, it&rsquo;s extremely difficult, so difficult that only a fool could actually do it. I must admit, while I believe in the principle of &ldquo;buying randomly,&rdquo; I can&rsquo;t bring myself to do it when investing my own money.</p>
<p>As mentioned earlier, to help my child reach billionaire status by their 40s, I buy them stocks worth tens of thousands of dollars annually. To practice &ldquo;buying randomly,&rdquo; I spread out the stock market section of the newspaper and ask my 4-year-old to pick a stock.  However, each time they point to one, I move their hand, saying, &ldquo;Why did you pick this one?&rdquo;  Then I ask them to pick another, but I&rsquo;m still not satisfied. This is because I can&rsquo;t bring myself to buy the stocks my child randomly selects. In the end, it&rsquo;s me, the self-proclaimed &ldquo;investment expert&rdquo; dad, who selects a stock after careful analysis and research.</p>
<p>Despite this, I record the first stock my child picks each year. It&rsquo;s been five years now, and I haven&rsquo;t sold any of the five stocks.  Surprisingly, the performance of the five stocks I carefully selected is about the same as the five randomly picked by my child. This further validates that &ldquo;random selection&rdquo; is not only simple but also performs well in the long run.</p>
<p><strong>No One Can Guarantee Gains or Losses</strong></p>
<p>The purpose of suggesting &ldquo;random selection&rdquo; is not to encourage you to literally throw darts at stock listings, though it&rsquo;s not a bad method.  My real intention is to highlight that random selection is sufficient when choosing investments.  You don&rsquo;t need excessive caution or to follow expert advice that demands painstaking research.  The reason is simple: as mentioned, if you had chosen Cathay Life Insurance 20 years ago and held it, you would be a billionaire today. Conversely, if you had chosen Kuosheng 10 years ago and held it, you would have lost everything. Many experts use this to justify advising investors to be extremely cautious and meticulous in stock selection. The problem is, no matter how knowledgeable or cautious you are, you can&rsquo;t guarantee picking the next Cathay Life Insurance or avoiding the next Kuosheng.</p>
<p>A key point to consider: You don&rsquo;t need to pick the perfect stock like Cathay Life Insurance to become wealthy. <strong>As long as your investment returns are close to the overall market average, you can still become a billionaire.</strong>  To achieve this, you simply need to &ldquo;diversify and choose randomly.&rdquo;</p>
<p>Average investors often fail to understand this, leading them to be overly cautious, spending significant time, effort, and money on analysis, research, seeking hot tips, and consulting experts. This usually leads to two outcomes:</p>
<ol>
<li><strong>Confusion:</strong>  Opinions on which investments are good vary widely, leading to indecision. Unable to find a &ldquo;safe&rdquo; investment, investors often resort to the riskiest long-term move – leaving their money in the bank.</li>
<li><strong>False Sense of Security:</strong>  Sometimes, an investment appears excellent from all angles, with most experts endorsing it. This perceived safety often attracts cautious investors, but these &ldquo;safe&rdquo; investments can be the most dangerous. Remember: <strong>Investments everyone considers good are often the worst.</strong> In mid-1995, almost everyone viewed semiconductor stocks like TSMC and UMC favorably. Many cautious investors flocked to these stocks.  A year later, the market was up 30% on average, while TSMC and UMC plummeted, halving in value.</li>
</ol>
<p>While simple, buying randomly is a difficult investment philosophy to embrace.  But it teaches us a valuable lesson: <strong>Don&rsquo;t overthink stock selection.  Diversify your portfolio and choose randomly. Investing can be that simple.</strong></p>
<blockquote>
<p>The ratio of up days to down days in the stock market is approximately 55:45.</p>
</blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">When to Buy - Buy Anytime 
    <div id="when-to-buy---buy-anytime" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#when-to-buy---buy-anytime" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>Many claim that choosing the right entry point is crucial for investment success, and I agree. However, timing the market is equally difficult and complex.  My proposed strategy is simple, so simple you might find it hard to follow: &ldquo;Buy anytime.&rdquo;</p>
<p>&ldquo;Buy anytime&rdquo; means investing your money whenever you have it, regardless of the day or time.  In other words, don&rsquo;t keep your money in the bank.  Invest any surplus funds beyond your daily needs, regardless of whether you think prices will rise or fall.</p>
<p><strong>Buy and Wait for the Opportunity</strong></p>
<p>Investors often ask, &ldquo;When should I start investing?&rdquo; My answer is &ldquo;Now!&rdquo; Short-term stock prices fluctuate wildly and are unpredictable. You could say, &ldquo;The only predictable thing is unpredictability.&rdquo; Since stocks generally rise in the long term, and future price movements are uncertain, the best approach is to invest and hold long-term, regardless of short-term fluctuations, and wait for the long-term upward trend to emerge.</p>
<p>Stocks tend to have higher returns over the long term, with a higher probability of rising than falling. Statistically, the ratio of up days to down days is approximately 55:45.  Therefore, if you ask me if the market will rise or fall tomorrow, my answer is usually: &ldquo;I don&rsquo;t know, and nobody in the world knows.&rdquo; But if you insist on a guess, the statistically safer bet is that it will rise.</p>
<p>Since the guess is always for a rise, the safest approach is to buy whenever you have money.  When the probability of rising is higher than falling, and you can&rsquo;t predict tomorrow&rsquo;s movement, the best strategy is to &ldquo;buy and wait for the opportunity,&rdquo; not &ldquo;wait for the opportunity to buy.&rdquo;</p>
<p>We often hear older people lamenting, &ldquo;If only I had invested in that stock 30 years ago, I would be&hellip;&rdquo; Perhaps the best time to invest was 20 or 30 years ago, but the second-best time is now.  Act as soon as you have the funds, lest you have the same regrets in a few decades. Life is short; how many decades can we afford to waste?  How long can we allow ourselves to squander precious time?</p>
<p>Buying anytime sounds simple, but it&rsquo;s also very difficult. Try it yourself. If you can do it, you possess the basic qualities for investment success. As long as you adhere to the principles of long-term holding and diversified timing, you can buy stocks anytime.</p>
<p><strong>When to Sell - Don&rsquo;t Sell</strong></p>
<p><em>Before investing, prepare to hold for 20 years, research carefully, and after buying, put it aside and forget about it.</em></p>
<p>A common investor dilemma is: &ldquo;When should I sell?&rdquo; Some experts say, &ldquo;Choosing the right entry point is hard, choosing the right exit point is even harder.&rdquo;  Investment guru Philip Fisher famously advised, &ldquo;If the job has been correctly done when a common stock is purchased, the time to sell it is—almost never.&rdquo; Warren Buffett, who became the richest man in America in 1982 through stock investments, exemplifies this. He holds stocks for an average of 4.5 years. So, my advice on when to sell is: &ldquo;Don&rsquo;t sell.&rdquo;  Hold long-term and minimize trading.</p>
<p>Long-term holding avoids frequent trading costs that erode returns. My research shows that with high-return investments like stocks, the longer the holding period, the lower the risk of loss.  For example, with sufficient diversification, investing in the Taiwan stock market has never resulted in returns lower than bank interest rates for holding periods exceeding 11 years. This demonstrates that &ldquo;diversify and hold long-term,&rdquo; while seemingly simple, is an optimal investment strategy.</p>
<p>What&rsquo;s so hard about not selling? It seems easy enough.  But this is the most challenging of all investment rules and the most crucial factor for investment success. The difficulty lies in remaining unwavering, regardless of price fluctuations. This requires achieving the highest realm of financial management:  &ldquo;<strong>Own the stock, but not the stock price.</strong>&rdquo;</p>
<p>The typical investor&rsquo;s habit is to ignore a stock after buying it if the price falls, allowing it to continue declining and becoming a long-term loss. Conversely, if the price rises, they happily calculate their profits and readily sell after a 5% to 20% gain.  Thus, &ldquo;long-term investing&rdquo; becomes synonymous with being trapped at a high price.  There&rsquo;s nothing remarkable about holding a losing stock long-term. <strong>The real key to investment success is remaining steadfast even when you&rsquo;re profiting.</strong></p>
<p>Jesse Livermore, author of <em>Reminiscences of a Stock Operator</em>, wrote:  &ldquo;I&rsquo;ve been in Wall Street for many years, made fortunes, and lost them. My fortune-making has never depended on my forecasting ability but on my ability to hold positions firmly, unfazed by market fluctuations. You might find many people in the stock market who are incredibly accurate at predicting entry and exit points, yet they don&rsquo;t make much money. It&rsquo;s rare to find someone who can remain unmoved during a sustained market rally, and I&rsquo;ve found this to be the hardest thing to learn in stock investing.  Only by mastering this essence can investors make a fortune.&rdquo;</p>
<p><strong>Endure the Falls, Wait Out the Rises</strong></p>
<p>Traditional thinking dictates:  Buy low, sell high.  However, a new perspective redefines investing as:  <strong>selecting appropriate investment targets and holding them long-term.</strong>  Successful investing requires mastering the eight-character mantra: &ldquo;<strong>Endure the falls, wait out the rises.</strong>&rdquo;  Never be disheartened by price drops or tempted to sell at the first sign of a rally.  Maintain a long-term perspective.</p>
<p>Why do most fortunes come from real estate, while fewer are made from stocks? The key is visibility. Real estate prices are largely invisible, while stock prices are constantly displayed.  Real estate investors often achieve the &ldquo;don&rsquo;t sell&rdquo; mentality, while stock investors, influenced by price fluctuations, rarely do.  If stock investors could embrace the &ldquo;buy and hold&rdquo; approach, stock investing would be as powerful as real estate.</p>
<p>In the past 20 years, Cathay Life Insurance has consistently been among the top-performing listed companies in Taiwan. What&rsquo;s their secret?  They own real estate and stocks, and they buy and hold. This is their business philosophy, and it also applies to personal finance.</p>
<p>Look at the success stories of investors like Lien Chan, Tsai Wan-lin, and Wang Yung-ching.  They all adhered to the principle of &ldquo;don&rsquo;t sell.&rdquo; Tsai Wan-lin&rsquo;s success stemmed from treating stocks like real estate. The Lien family&rsquo;s success in stocks and real estate comes from their ability to hold long-term and remain unmoved.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The more complex the market fluctuations, the simpler the investment method.</p>
</blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">Random Walk and Efficient Market Hypothesis 
    <div id="random-walk-and-efficient-market-hypothesis" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#random-walk-and-efficient-market-hypothesis" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>I must emphasize that &ldquo;buy randomly, buy anytime, don&rsquo;t sell&rdquo; isn&rsquo;t just a catchy phrase; it has a theoretical basis. In the 1950s, the American financial and investment community developed a prominent theory: the Random Walk Hypothesis.</p>
<p><strong>Random Selection is the Best Strategy</strong></p>
<p>It&rsquo;s generally agreed that stock prices, like other commodities, fluctuate unpredictably. The Random Walk Hypothesis states that stock price movements are so complex that they resemble random changes, nearly impossible to predict.  This hypothesis highlights the unpredictable nature of stock prices and, more importantly, leads to a simple yet crucial investment method: the Buy-and-Hold strategy, which is essentially &ldquo;buy randomly, buy anytime, don&rsquo;t sell.&rdquo;</p>
<p>The Buy-and-Hold strategy means investing available funds immediately upon availability (rather than predicting market upswings), holding those investments long-term without selling (locking them away and ignoring short-term fluctuations), and selling only when funds are needed (not in anticipation of market downturns).  In short, the Buy-and-Hold strategy advocates investing consistently, holding long-term, and selling only when necessary, without trying to time the market. If stock price movements follow the Random Walk Hypothesis, the best investment strategy is random selection and long-term holding – the very essence of &ldquo;buy randomly, buy anytime, don&rsquo;t sell.&rdquo;</p>
<p>Another implication of &ldquo;buy randomly, buy anytime, don&rsquo;t sell&rdquo; is that analysis and prediction are futile. The Efficient Market Hypothesis states that in an efficient market, all information that could affect stock prices is quickly and fully reflected in those prices. By the time you receive information from analysis reports or publications, it&rsquo;s already outdated and incorporated into the price. In other words, in an efficient market, stock prices are always in equilibrium, and no investor can consistently beat the market by collecting and analyzing information to gain excess returns.</p>
<p><strong>In-depth Analysis is a Waste of Time</strong></p>
<p>The Efficient Market Hypothesis, introduced by renowned financial expert Eugene Fama in the 1970s, emphasizes that you don&rsquo;t need to be an analyst or expert to build wealth through investing.  Painstakingly researching and analyzing stocks is a waste of time because most useful information is already reflected in the price. Studying this information offers no advantage. It&rsquo;s better to invest your money and hold long-term.</p>
<p>The Efficient Market Hypothesis teaches us: <strong>Ignore the noise. Don&rsquo;t waste time, effort, and money gathering information, as it&rsquo;s mostly already priced in and thus worthless.  There&rsquo;s no need to learn complex analysis methods because most are ineffective.</strong></p>
<p>By adopting the strategy advocated in this book – diversification, buying randomly, buying anytime, and not selling – you can achieve excellent returns.</p>
<p><em>1. Short-term stock price movements are random, making it impossible to predict when prices will rise or fall.</em></p>
<p><em>2. Although short-term stock prices are unpredictable, the long-term trend is upward due to continuous economic growth.  Buying and holding stocks long-term, with the compounding effect offsetting risks over time, yields considerable average returns.</em></p>
<p><em>3. Almost all publicly available information is already reflected in stock prices, making it unhelpful for investors.</em></p>
<p><em>4. Most analytical methods used by investors are already factored into stock prices.  Using commonly employed analysis techniques will not generate excess returns, meaning you won&rsquo;t outperform the buy-and-hold strategy in the long run.</em></p>
<p>For years, facing the ever-changing investment world, I&rsquo;ve sought a method that transcends the &ldquo;busyness and blindness&rdquo; of financial management.  &ldquo;Buy randomly, buy anytime, don&rsquo;t sell&rdquo; is the principle of simplifying complex problems.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Personal Investment Bible: Investment Iron Law Ⅵ</title>
      <link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1731056005965/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1731056005965/</guid>
      <description>This article explores how to resolve the crisis of being trapped in investments, emphasizing the importance of diversification and long-term holding.  It begins with the adage, &amp;#39;Don&amp;#39;t put all your eggs in one basket,&amp;#39; explaining the principles and methods of diversification, including diversifying investment targets, timing, and regions.  The article also discusses the principles of diversification, pointing out that the number of investment targets should not be excessive, and suggesting choosing investment targets with greater negative correlation.  Furthermore, it introduces two methods for diversifying investment timing: investing whenever funds are available and regular fixed-amount investment. Finally, the article emphasizes the importance of long-term holding, arguing that it can reduce the possibility of investment losses and contribute to higher returns.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[

<h2 class="relative group">Investment Iron Law 6: Escaping the Trap of Locked-in Investments 
    <div id="investment-iron-law-6-escaping-the-trap-of-locked-in-investments" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#investment-iron-law-6-escaping-the-trap-of-locked-in-investments" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>Don&rsquo;t put all your eggs in one basket.</p>
</blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">Diversification and Long-Term Holding 
    <div id="diversification-and-long-term-holding" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#diversification-and-long-term-holding" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>Many investors often ask me: &ldquo;Even if I believe that stocks and real estate have high returns and will rise in the long run, their prices fluctuate. Some investments will make a lot of money, while others will lose a lot of money. What should I invest in? What if the company I invest in goes bankrupt?&rdquo; &ldquo;When should I invest? What if I invest at the highest price point?&rdquo; &ldquo;When should I sell? What if I sell at the wrong time?&rdquo; These questions reflect the risks inherent in investment and financial management.</p>
<p><strong>Increase Returns, Reduce Risks</strong></p>
<p>The eight-character mantra of investment and financial management is: <strong>Increase returns, reduce risks</strong>. The simplest way to increase returns is to invest assets in high-return instruments, such as stocks and real estate. However, high-return investments come with high risks. For example, stock and real estate prices fluctuate, leading to both profits and losses. Therefore, investors seeking high returns must bear the accompanying risks. However, these risks are generally undesirable for most investors. The correct financial management concept is not to avoid investment because of these risks. To achieve high returns, one should venture into investments with these risks, and then find ways to mitigate and minimize their impact.</p>
<p>Therefore, reducing risks to avoid losses and increasing returns to create wealth are equally important for successful financial management. The primary goal of risk management is to find ways to reduce the risk of loss while increasing investment returns.</p>
<p>Investing in high-return targets faces three main risks:</p>
<ol>
<li>Choosing the wrong investment target.</li>
<li>Choosing the wrong investment timing.</li>
<li>Choosing the wrong selling timing.</li>
</ol>
<p>So how can we reduce these risks?</p>
<p><em>1. Reduce the risk of choosing the wrong investment target - Diversify investment targets.</em>
<em>2. Reduce the risk of choosing the wrong investment timing - Diversify investment timing.</em>
<em>3. Reduce the risk of choosing the wrong selling timing - Long-term holding.</em></p>
<p><strong>Reduce the Risk of Choosing the Wrong Investment Target - Diversify Investment Targets</strong></p>
<p>A conglomerate that owned a private jet once required its CEO and second-in-command to attend an international conference simultaneously. The conference organizers held a cocktail party to welcome these two VIPs. Guests and media eagerly awaited their arrival.  Amidst the cheers, only the second-in-command, who had arrived on a private jet, was present. The CEO was still at the international airport going through customs. It turned out that they had taken separate planes to mitigate risk. Indeed, with frequent air disasters, if they had taken the same flight and an accident occurred, it would have severely impacted the company.</p>
<p>Three thousand years ago, the Phoenicians invested heavily in building ships for international trade, venturing across the oceans. Successful voyages brought immense wealth; shipwrecks caused by hurricanes or typhoons resulted in total loss. Thus, the risks of overseas trade were enormous. A small group became incredibly wealthy through successful trade, while a few were ruined. However, the vast majority, fearing potential disasters, hesitated and missed out on substantial profits. Because few dared to take the risk, the limited supply of ships led to higher profits in maritime trade, benefiting those who invested.</p>
<p>Someone then devised an investment method that not only generated trade profits but also mitigated risks: diversification. The approach involved dividing the capital for one ship into ten parts, investing one-tenth in each of ten ships.  This diversified the risk.</p>
<p>Despite precautions, on average, three out of ten invested ships would sink due to storms. However, the profits from the remaining seven ships not only covered the losses but also yielded substantial returns. Diversification reduced risk while maintaining the return rate. The possibility of all ten ships encountering mishaps still existed, but it was minimal, significantly lower than the risk of investing in a single ship.</p>
<p>The most effective and widely adopted method for risk reduction is &ldquo;diversification.&rdquo; Diversification simply means increasing the variety of investments. Mark Twain once said, &ldquo;Don&rsquo;t put all your eggs in one basket.&rdquo; Distributing eggs across multiple baskets ensures that even if one basket falls, the remaining eggs are safe.  This approach aims to reduce risk.</p>
<p>The investment environment is unpredictable and constantly changing.  Fortuitous investments can yield high returns in the short term, but there&rsquo;s also a high probability that chosen investments could plummet immediately after purchase. Most people avoid this risk by keeping their funds in risk-free instruments like bank deposits or government bonds. <strong>However, the correct investment perspective is to invest in &ldquo;high-risk, high-expected return&rdquo; targets to achieve high returns, while employing diversification to mitigate risks.</strong></p>
<blockquote>
<p>Invest in ten ships.
Three sink.
The remaining ones still generate profits.</p>
</blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">Principles of Diversification 
    <div id="principles-of-diversification" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#principles-of-diversification" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>The method of diversifying risk has been practiced for millennia. The principle of diversification was introduced in the &ldquo;Portfolio Theory&rdquo; published in 1950 by Dr. Harry Markowitz, the 1990 Nobel laureate in economics. Diversification means increasing the types of investments. For example, when buying stocks, don&rsquo;t buy just one; divide the investment amount and purchase multiple stocks.  With sufficient capital, diversify beyond stocks into real estate, gold, art, and other asset classes.</p>
<p><strong>Increasing Investment Types Offsets Relative Risk</strong></p>
<p>Diversification reduces risk because different investment targets don&rsquo;t rise and fall in perfect unison. Even if they do, the magnitude of change varies. When several investments form a portfolio, the portfolio&rsquo;s return is the weighted average of individual investments.  Therefore, combining several high-return investments maintains high returns, while the portfolio&rsquo;s risk is reduced as the fluctuations of individual investments offset each other. Increasing the variety of investments in a portfolio decreases the overall portfolio risk. This explains why diversification – increasing the types of investments – reduces risk.</p>
<p>Therefore, when investing in stocks, don&rsquo;t just buy one type.  Purchase several different stocks.  Adequate diversification typically involves investing in ten or more stocks.  For investors with limited funds who want diversification, mutual funds are recommended. Most mutual funds invest in 30 or more stocks, so investing $10,000 in a mutual fund is equivalent to buying more than 30 stocks, providing sufficient diversification.</p>
<p><strong>Principles of Diversification</strong></p>
<p><em>1. Choose Investment Targets with Greater Negative Correlation</em></p>
<p>The less synchronized the price movements of investments in a portfolio, or the more they move in opposite directions, the better the diversification.  Choose investments whose price trends are inversely related to the existing portfolio. For example, gold is a good tool for diversification.  Historically, gold has been a high-risk investment, but its price tends to move inversely to stock prices.  During major international events like wars, political turmoil, or inflation, stock prices often fall while gold prices rise.  Applying this principle to stock investment, choose stocks from different industries for better diversification.</p>
<p><em>2. Avoid Excessive Diversification</em></p>
<p>While working as a consultant at a securities firm, I observed a woman in the VIP room with papers scattered across the table, gesturing frantically as if commanding an army. Assuming she was a major investor, I discreetly inquired with a broker and discovered her total investment was around $300,000, spread across over 30 stocks.  While aiming for diversification, she over-diversified, increasing management costs and diminishing returns. Excessive diversification is counterproductive. Even Warren Buffett, with his vast portfolio, invests in only about a dozen stocks.</p>
<p>Generally, increasing investment types reduces portfolio risk, but the risk reduction effect diminishes with each added type.  Holding numerous investments for fun is acceptable, but if the goal is risk reduction, understand that the diversification effect diminishes with increasing variety.  The difference in risk between holding 30 stocks and 20 stocks is negligible. <strong>Beyond a certain point, risk reduction plateaus, and further diversification offers no additional benefit.</strong></p>
<p>Balance diversification against management costs.  Diversification aims to reduce risk by increasing investment types across different instruments and targets.  While increasing types reduces risk, it increases management costs as tracking multiple assets becomes complex.</p>
<p>Peter Lynch, in his book &ldquo;One Up On Wall Street,&rdquo; stated: &ldquo;Investing in stocks is like having children – if you don&rsquo;t have the ability to raise them, don&rsquo;t have too many. No one says you have to invest in five or more stocks every time.&rdquo;</p>
<p><strong>Methods of Diversification</strong></p>
<p>Diversification methods include various investment instruments, targets, and regions:</p>
<p><strong>1. Diversification of Investment Instruments:</strong> Invest in different instruments, such as stocks, real estate, overseas mutual funds, art, and gold.</p>
<p><strong>2. Diversification of Investment Targets:</strong>  Invest in various targets.  For example, when investing in stocks, don&rsquo;t focus on just one. Spread funds across four or five or more stocks. Avoid concentrating on a few industries, as stocks within the same industry tend to move together. In real estate, if funds allow, invest in different property types like apartments, offices, shops, and studios, and diversify locations.</p>
<p><strong>3. Diversification of Investment Regions:</strong> Diversify investments across different countries or regions. Some investors worry about concentrating assets in one region due to political, war, and exchange rate risks.  Distributing assets geographically mitigates these risks.</p>
<p><strong>Concentrated Investment Requires Confidence</strong></p>
<p>Diversification reduces the likelihood of worst-case scenarios, but it also eliminates the possibility of the best-case scenarios. Full diversification makes extreme outcomes unlikely, resulting in returns close to the average.</p>
<p>Some argue for concentrating investments: &ldquo;Put all your eggs in one basket and watch it carefully.&rdquo; Admittedly, many successful investors concentrate their holdings.  Few individuals are experts in both stocks and real estate. The choice between diversification and concentration depends on individual circumstances. If you&rsquo;re proficient in a specific investment area, concentration might be preferable, offering potentially higher returns.  For example, a real estate expert wouldn&rsquo;t necessarily diversify into stocks.  Over-diversification could have hindered their success.</p>
<p>If you lack confidence in most investment areas, diversification is recommended. While it might not yield exceptional returns, it protects against significant losses. Diversified returns are close to average returns. As long as the chosen investments tend to appreciate over the long term, like stocks and real estate, achieving average returns is sufficient for wealth building.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Mitigate the risk of incorrect investment timing by diversifying investment timing.</p>
</blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">Diversifying Investment Timing 
    <div id="diversifying-investment-timing" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#diversifying-investment-timing" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>Diversification applies to both investment targets and timing. To mitigate the risk of mistiming the market, distribute investments over time.  Instead of investing a lump sum at once, divide it into portions and invest at different times.</p>
<p><strong>Foolproof Method for Investment Timing</strong></p>
<p>Two methods achieve diversified investment timing. <strong>The first is to invest whenever funds are available.</strong> A friend of mine invests $10,000 in stocks whenever his bank balance reaches $15,000, keeping his balance below $5,000. He also buys different stocks each time, diversifying both target and timing.</p>
<p><strong>Another method is Dollar-Cost Averaging (DCA), which is regularly investing a fixed amount in mutual funds.</strong>  Investors contribute a set amount at regular intervals (e.g., monthly, quarterly, or annually) at the prevailing net asset value (NAV).  A specified amount is automatically deducted from a designated bank account on a specific date each month and invested in a pre-selected mutual fund.  Since the investment amount is fixed, but the NAV fluctuates, the number of units purchased varies.  This naturally leads to buying more units when prices are low and fewer when prices are high.  Over the long term, DCA offers considerable returns and mitigates price fluctuation risks.</p>
<p><strong>Reducing the Risk of Choosing the Wrong Selling Timing - Long-Term Holding</strong></p>
<blockquote>
<p>Long-term holding reduces the likelihood of losses.
Choose long-term investment instead of being forced into it after becoming trapped.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Years ago, during training at Merrill Lynch, a securities analyst stated: &ldquo;Statistically, the stock market rises 55% of the days and falls 45%.  The problem is, we don&rsquo;t know which days will be up.&rdquo; The ratio of gains and losses in the Taiwan stock market is similar.</p>
<p>Therefore, if you, like the experts, don&rsquo;t know whether the market will rise or fall tomorrow, the smartest approach is to guess it will rise.  The more you guess, the higher your probability of being correct. If you consistently predict a market rise, the best strategy is: <strong>Buy whenever you have money, and hold.</strong> This seemingly simple approach is often the most effective.  Many fortunes have been built this way.</p>
<p>Stocks and real estate are characterized by high returns and high risks. Due to their inherent risk, prices fluctuate in the short term, but their high returns generate a long-term upward trend.  The longer the holding period, the lower the probability of loss.  My research on the Taiwan stock market showed that the probability of gains and losses changes with the holding period, as shown below:</p>
<p><em>Relationship between Stock Holding Period and Probability of Gain</em></p>
<table>
  <thead>
      <tr>
          <th style="text-align: left">Holding Period</th>
          <th style="text-align: left">Probability of Gain (%)</th>
          <th style="text-align: left">Probability of Loss (%)</th>
      </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
      <tr>
          <td style="text-align: left">1 Day</td>
          <td style="text-align: left">55</td>
          <td style="text-align: left">45</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td style="text-align: left">1 Month</td>
          <td style="text-align: left">60</td>
          <td style="text-align: left">40</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td style="text-align: left">1 Year</td>
          <td style="text-align: left">66</td>
          <td style="text-align: left">34</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td style="text-align: left">5 Years</td>
          <td style="text-align: left">99</td>
          <td style="text-align: left">1</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td style="text-align: left">10 Years</td>
          <td style="text-align: left">100</td>
          <td style="text-align: left">0</td>
      </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>
<p>The table demonstrates that while stock prices fluctuate in the short term, the probability of loss decreases with longer holding periods. A one-day holding has a 45% chance of loss, which decreases to 40% for one month, 34% for one year, and a mere 1% for five years, making a loss almost impossible.  Holding for ten years or more eliminates the possibility of loss entirely. Long-term holding not only reduces the likelihood of loss but is also crucial for increasing returns.</p>
<p>How can we build wealth from small investments? The key is the power of compounding, which requires both high returns and time. Investing in high-return instruments like stocks and real estate and holding them long-term allows compounding to work its magic, accelerating wealth growth. The longer the holding period (decades), the more apparent the high return rate becomes, and the investment loss risk rapidly decreases.</p>
<p><strong>The goal of risk management isn&rsquo;t to eliminate all risk, but to acknowledge its inevitable presence, understand it, analyze it, and then mitigate it.</strong> Never wait for absolute safety; it&rsquo;s an illusion.  High-expected return investments always carry risk, and no strategy can eliminate all risks.</p>
<p>Diversification reduces individual investment fluctuations, while long-term holding neutralizes short-term price swings.  Investing in stocks and real estate requires accepting short-term and individual investment volatility. By diversifying and holding long-term, these risks are mitigated, reducing overall investment risk. In the long run, this strategy allows investors to benefit from the high returns offered by stocks and real estate.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Personal Investment Bible: Investment Iron Law IV</title>
      <link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1731056005963/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1731056005963/</guid>
      <description>This article explores the financial strategy of &amp;#34;making money with other people&amp;#39;s money,&amp;#34; also known as leveraged investing. It analyzes the principle of financial leverage, emphasizing that the return on investment must be higher than the loan interest rate to be profitable.  Case studies of entrepreneurs like Chen Youhao and Weng Damming illustrate the advantages and risks of leveraged investing.  The article further discusses borrowing principles, how to build credit, how to avoid improper borrowing, and how to determine an appropriate level of debt. Finally, it points out that banks are a source of borrowing rather than a place to save money, and emphasizes the importance of prudent borrowing.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[

<h2 class="relative group">Investment Iron Law 4: Making Money with Other People&rsquo;s Money 
    <div id="investment-iron-law-4-making-money-with-other-peoples-money" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#investment-iron-law-4-making-money-with-other-peoples-money" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>By applying the principle of financial leverage, an investment of 500 million can double your business.</p>
</blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">Utilizing Leveraged Investing 
    <div id="utilizing-leveraged-investing" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#utilizing-leveraged-investing" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>The path to wealth through investment relies on &ldquo;making money with money.&rdquo;  Therefore, the prerequisite for investment is having capital.  A common dilemma faced by individuals when investing is, &ldquo;What if I don&rsquo;t have enough money?&rdquo; This can lead to missed opportunities. This book proposes a solution: &ldquo;If you don&rsquo;t have enough money, but someone else does and is willing to lend it to you, then borrow it.&rdquo; This is the highest realm of investment management—leveraged investing.</p>
<p><strong>Chen Youhao, President of the Tuntex Group: The Money-Making Method of Borrowing and Rolling</strong></p>
<p>Starting in the textile industry, Chen Youhao used financial leverage to rapidly expand the Tuntex Group into chemical fibers, construction, cement, hotels, petrochemicals, and other fields. With over 30 affiliated companies, it became one of the top 15 largest corporate groups in Taiwan. He also planned to invest nearly 7 billion USD in Taiwan and Thailand to expand chemical fiber plants.</p>
<p>Tuntex&rsquo;s growth never stopped, and its debt continued to rise. In 1995, Tuntex Group&rsquo;s core business, Tonwin Construction, had total assets of 59.6 billion TWD, revenue of 15.7 billion TWD, and net profit after tax of 2.6 billion TWD, but its debt ratio was still as high as 60.99%.</p>
<p>A graduate of the Department of Economics at National Taiwan University, Chen Youhao always prided himself on his sophisticated money-making method of borrowing and rolling. He had full confidence in Tuntex&rsquo;s financial management. His financial principles were: 1/3 self-owned capital, the rest borrowed from financial institutions; current assets must be greater than current liabilities, with a current ratio greater than 100%; and the ratio of self-owned capital to debt must not exceed 1/2.</p>
<p>Chen Youhao emphasized that whenever the company&rsquo;s debt ratio approached its limit, he would strictly control it, so the company&rsquo;s financial situation remained normal. However, whenever the construction industry was in a downturn, Tuntex would be plagued by rumors of financial difficulties. In June 1995, due to capital needs, Chen Youhao pledged 46.5 million shares of Tonwin, setting a record for the highest number of shares pledged by directors and supervisors that month. Chen Youhao repeatedly assured the public that Tuntex&rsquo;s finances were absolutely sound.</p>
<p>Despite the rumors damaging the company&rsquo;s image, Chen Youhao firmly believed that reasonable borrowing could enable the company to earn more profits. He was also confident that businesses funded by loans would be profitable because the return on investment was higher than the interest rate on loans.</p>
<p><strong>Is Borrowing to Invest Wrong?</strong></p>
<p>Is borrowing money for investment appropriate? Shakespeare wrote in Hamlet, &ldquo;Neither a borrower nor a lender be.&rdquo; This was once considered a golden rule. Our elders often warned their children not to borrow money from others or lend money to others; borrowing was not considered respectable and should be avoided unless absolutely necessary.</p>
<p>Indeed, most stories of financial ruin are caused by debt, such as the cases of Tsai Chen-chou of the Tenth Credit Cooperative and the stock market tycoon Lei Borong. Countless examples of bankruptcy caused by debt make people fear and avoid it.</p>
<p>However, among the famous wealthy individuals we know, such as Wang Yongqing, Kao Ching-yuan, Chang Yung-fa, and Wu Ho-Su, who didn&rsquo;t rely on borrowing to invest in their journey from rags to riches? The answer is &ldquo;none.&rdquo; Moreover, the more successful people are at making money, the more they tend to borrow. Looking at the financial statements of listed companies, are there any renowned high-performing enterprises in Taiwan, such as Formosa Plastics, Uni-President, and Evergreen, that have zero debt?  The message is clear: successful tycoons, like successful businesses, rarely achieve their wealth without using other people&rsquo;s money. In business management, appropriate borrowing is not only necessary but also reasonable.</p>
<p>If Shakespeare were alive in the 21st century and understood how capitalism works and how people become wealthy, he might change his words to: &ldquo;If you have no money, but others do and are willing to lend it to you, then borrow.&rdquo;</p>
<p>After reviewing these characteristics of success, reflect on your own financial situation. What percentage of your investment funds comes from borrowing? If, like most people, 100% of your investments are made with your own funds, you are overlooking an important tool for building wealth: borrowing.</p>
<p><strong>Borrowing is a Crucial Tool for Wealth Creation</strong></p>
<p>American investment consultant Robert Allen repeatedly emphasizes in his bestselling book <em>Creating Wealth</em>: &ldquo;You cannot become rich by investing without borrowing.&rdquo; I disagree with this argument. The examples in Chapter 1 of this book clearly demonstrate that with proper financial management, one can become a billionaire without relying on borrowed investments.  The American investment master Warren Buffett does not advocate leveraged investing.  Without debt, he is a prime example of building wealth solely through his own funds. However, there is a prerequisite for accumulating wealth using only your own funds: long-term patient waiting. Warren Buffett only rose to prominence after three to four decades of investing.</p>
<p>Although Robert Allen&rsquo;s argument that &ldquo;you cannot become rich without borrowing&rdquo; is incorrect, I must admit that the &ldquo;leveraged investing&rdquo; he advocates is an important means of building wealth, especially for those who want to accelerate the speed of wealth creation.  Leveraged investing is a tool that should not be ignored.</p>
<p>In conclusion, whether you want to accelerate wealth accumulation or can tolerate the pressure of leveraged investing, you must understand the nature and impact of leveraged investing before deciding if this tool is right for you.</p>
<ul>
<li>
<ol>
<li>Leveraged investing is a powerful tool, but it must be used wisely.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol start="2">
<li>It is possible to build wealth without borrowing.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol start="3">
<li>Leveraged investing, when used correctly, can accelerate wealth accumulation.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol start="4">
<li>Don&rsquo;t be afraid of leveraged investing, but be very careful.</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>Aim high with your business goals,
Once decided, go for it and never back down.
The key to success in business lies in courage and strategy.</p>
</blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">Weng Damming&rsquo;s Revival of the Family Business 
    <div id="weng-dammings-revival-of-the-family-business" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#weng-dammings-revival-of-the-family-business" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>In Taiwan, there are quite a few entrepreneurs skilled in financial leverage. Besides Chen Youhao, the president of the Tuntex Group, Weng Damming, the head of the Hualon Group, is also a master of this art.</p>
<p>Weng Damming, the head of the Hualon Group, became a highly controversial figure due to his unconventional style. After the death of his father, Weng Mingchang, Weng Damming shouldered the heavy responsibility of reviving the family business.  Starting in textiles, the Hualon Group owned Hualon Textile, Hualon Microelectronics, Yixin Trading, Jiashin Livestock, and Kuo Hua Life Insurance, among other affiliated companies.</p>
<p>Weng Damming adopted a high-leverage approach to business management. In 1994, the Hualon Group had total assets of 130 billion TWD and debts as high as over 50 billion TWD, of which over 30 billion TWD were short-term debts.  He used the stocks or real estate of affiliated companies as collateral for bank loans, with a pledge ratio of nearly 60%. Therefore, during the stock market crash and the real estate downturn, Weng Damming was troubled by rumors of financial difficulties.  Due to the sluggish stock and real estate markets, the collateral value of the Hualon Group was insufficient, requiring him to supplement the collateral or face the pressure of being &ldquo;liquidated.&rdquo; However, the seasoned Weng Damming, with his flexible financial management, once again demonstrated that the financial crisis was just a false alarm.</p>
<p>As Hualon Textile, the parent company of the Hualon Group, enjoyed stable profits and increased earnings with the gradual recovery of the textile industry, Weng Damming was able to borrow money fearlessly and aggressively expand into new businesses.  With a gambler&rsquo;s mentality, Weng Damming can be said to have maximized the principle of financial leverage. The story of this legendary figure shows us both the rewards and risks of leveraged investing.</p>
<p><strong>The Principle of Financial Leverage</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Act within your means; don&rsquo;t over-leverage, or you risk being shaken out.</li>
</ul>
<p>In finance, borrowing is known as &ldquo;financial leverage.&rdquo; Simply put, leverage is the principle of using a small force to achieve a large effect. Humans discovered the power of leverage early on and used it to move or lift heavy objects. The ancients used the principle of leverage to create magnificent engineering marvels such as the Great Wall and the pyramids. Modern wealthy individuals use the principle of financial leverage to create immense fortunes. Archimedes once said, &ldquo;Give me a place to stand, and I shall move the earth.&rdquo;  In investment management, financial leverage implies: &ldquo;Lend me enough money, and I can make any large investment.&rdquo;</p>
<p>Leveraged investing involves borrowing other people&rsquo;s money to make larger investments, thus utilizing the leverage effect.  Proper use of leverage can turn small amounts of money into large profits. Conversely, improper use can also lead to significant losses with small amounts of money. Here&rsquo;s an example to help readers understand how financial leverage works. Suppose you buy a house with 10 million in cash. A year later, you are fortunate enough to sell it for 13 million, making a 30% profit (R1). If you only paid 3 million in cash for the house and borrowed the remaining 7 million from the bank at a 10% interest rate, and then sold it for 13 million a year later, your profit margin would increase to 77% (R2).  Conversely, if the house price unfortunately drops by 30% after a year, and you sell it for 7 million, the person who bought it entirely in cash would lose 30% (R3). The investor who borrowed 7 million would see their loss expand to 123% (R4), meaning not only is the original investment lost, but they are also in debt. The calculation of the above rates of return is as follows:</p>
<p><math xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" display="block"><mtable displaystyle="true" columnalign="right center left" columnspacing="0 thickmathspace" rowspacing="3pt"><mtr><mtd><mi>R</mi><mn>1</mn></mtd><mtd><mi></mi><mo>=</mo></mtd><mtd><mi></mi><mo stretchy="false">(</mo><mn>1300</mn><mo>−</mo><mn>1000</mn><mo stretchy="false">)</mo><mrow><mo>/</mo></mrow><mn>1000</mn></mtd><mtd><mi></mi><mo>=</mo></mtd><mtd><mn>30</mn><mi mathvariant="normal">%</mi></mtd></mtr><mtr><mtd></mtd></mtr><mtr><mtd><mi>R</mi><mn>2</mn></mtd><mtd><mi></mi><mo>=</mo></mtd><mtd><mi></mi><mo stretchy="false">(</mo><mn>1300</mn><mo>−</mo><mn>1000</mn><mo>−</mo><mn>700</mn><mo>×</mo><mn>10</mn><mi mathvariant="normal">%</mi><mo stretchy="false">)</mo><mrow><mo>/</mo></mrow><mn>300</mn></mtd><mtd><mi></mi><mo>=</mo></mtd><mtd><mn>77</mn><mi mathvariant="normal">%</mi></mtd></mtr><mtr><mtd></mtd></mtr><mtr><mtd><mi>R</mi><mn>3</mn></mtd><mtd><mi></mi><mo>=</mo></mtd><mtd><mi></mi><mo stretchy="false">(</mo><mn>700</mn><mo>−</mo><mn>1000</mn><mo stretchy="false">)</mo><mrow><mo>/</mo></mrow><mn>1000</mn></mtd><mtd><mi></mi><mo>=</mo></mtd><mtd><mi></mi><mo>−</mo><mn>30</mn><mi mathvariant="normal">%</mi></mtd></mtr><mtr><mtd></mtd></mtr><mtr><mtd><mi>R</mi><mn>4</mn></mtd><mtd><mi></mi><mo>=</mo></mtd><mtd><mi></mi><mo stretchy="false">(</mo><mn>700</mn><mo>−</mo><mn>1000</mn><mo>−</mo><mn>700</mn><mo>×</mo><mn>10</mn><mi mathvariant="normal">%</mi><mo stretchy="false">)</mo><mrow><mo>/</mo></mrow><mn>300</mn></mtd><mtd><mi></mi><mo>=</mo></mtd><mtd><mi></mi><mo>−</mo><mn>123</mn><mi mathvariant="normal">%</mi></mtd></mtr><mtr><mtd></mtd></mtr><mtr><mtd><mo stretchy="false">(</mo><mo>Calculations in units of 10,000</mo><mo stretchy="false">)</mo></mtd></mtr></mtable></math></p>
<p>From the above example, we can clearly see how debt leverage exerts the power of &ldquo;using a small force to achieve a large effect.&rdquo; <strong>When the return on investment is higher than the interest rate on the loan, leveraged investing will increase the return on investment. When the return on investment is lower than the interest rate on the loan, the return on investment will decrease due to the borrowing.</strong></p>
<p>The main reason for the leverage effect is that loan interest is a cost that must be paid under any circumstances. Regardless of the investment return, the interest cost of borrowing remains fixed. Therefore, when the investment return is greater than the loan cost, the excess profit belongs to the borrower, creating a positive leverage effect and naturally increasing the return on investment of the principal. However, when the investment return is less than the loan interest cost, the borrower must bear the difference, resulting in a negative leverage effect, which reduces the return on the principal. This is especially true when the investment incurs a loss, as the borrowing cost will magnify the loss.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Financial leverage is like a seesaw,
It can lift you very high,
It can also cause you to fall hard.</p>
</blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">Two Major Principles of Borrowing 
    <div id="two-major-principles-of-borrowing" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#two-major-principles-of-borrowing" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>Financial leverage is like a seesaw: it can lift you very high or cause you to fall hard, depending on whether the leverage effect is positive or negative.  The key factor determining the direction of the leverage effect is which is higher: the return on investment or the interest rate on the loan. If the return on investment is greater than the interest rate, the leverage effect is positive. Conversely, if the return on investment is lower than the interest rate, the leverage effect becomes detrimental.</p>
<p><strong>Return on Investment Must Be Higher Than the Interest Rate</strong></p>
<p>Therefore, when deciding whether to use leveraged investing, the first things to consider are: What is the purpose of the loan? What is the expected return on investment for the target investment? Is it higher than the loan interest rate? If the return on investment of the targeted investment is significantly lower than the borrowing rate, the idea of leveraged investing should be dismissed early on. Otherwise, the result will certainly be detrimental rather than beneficial. If you can&rsquo;t understand what the expected return on investment is or whether the return is higher than the interest rate, then I advise you to understand these issues before borrowing!</p>
<p>Debt is synonymous with risk. Increasing debt increases risk and the possibility of personal or family bankruptcy. There are two major principles of leveraged investing:</p>
<ul>
<li>
<ol>
<li>The expected return on investment must be greater than the interest rate on the loan. For example, if the loan interest rate is 11%, it&rsquo;s only worthwhile if the after-tax return on investment is above 11%.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol start="2">
<li>In the worst-case scenario, your cash income must be sufficient to cover the principal and interest payments. For instance, if the investment price falls instead of rises after a few years, you must have enough cash income to repay the principal and interest on time.</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ul>
<p>Furthermore, investors must keep in mind that leveraged investing should not be based on the expectation that the price of the investment target will definitely rise, but rather on the preparation for a price drop.  Therefore, you should only engage in leveraged investing if you can still afford the interest payments even if the price continues to fall. You must also be able to withstand the psychological pressure that comes with leveraged investing.</p>
<p><strong>Avoiding Improper Borrowing</strong></p>
<p>Some readers may feel smug after reading this section because they are already engaged in what they consider leveraged investing. Upon further inquiry, however, it turns out they are borrowing money to buy lottery tickets, futures, or other speculative products, or even taking out loans to purchase consumer goods.  I must emphasize that these actions do not constitute proper &ldquo;leveraged investing.&rdquo;</p>
<p>Futures markets, margin trading (such as foreign exchange and bonds), or any gambling activities like lotteries and horse racing all have negative expected returns.  Long-term participation will inevitably lead to financial ruin.  Coupled with the deadly effect of borrowing, the result will undoubtedly be rapid bankruptcy.  Therefore, no matter how alluring these games are, remember:  It&rsquo;s okay to indulge occasionally for recreational purposes, but never borrow money to participate, or you will accelerate your path to bankruptcy with dire consequences.</p>
<p>Another point to remind readers of is to avoid borrowing money to purchase consumer goods. Borrowing to consume is like using future money to create &ldquo;false wealth.&rdquo; Unless absolutely necessary, the concept of borrowing for consumption should be avoided. Otherwise, the family&rsquo;s financial situation will be burdened.</p>
<p>For banks, consumer loans are extremely risky and require high interest rates.  Generally, consumer loan interest rates are above 10%.  Readers should understand that high-return investments have an amazing compounding effect.  Similarly, high-interest loans also have a dramatic compounding effect.  Take car loans, for example.  Assuming a 20% loan interest rate, after three and a half years, you will have to repay double the amount. This means that if you borrow money to buy a car now, three and a half years later, not only will the original car have depreciated significantly, but you will effectively have to pay for two new cars of the same model.  My advice on car loans is: don&rsquo;t take them. Wait until you can afford to pay in cash. Car loan interest rates are usually very high, often exceeding 15%, although there are occasional promotional periods with lower rates.  Fundamentally, except for commercial vehicles, cars are consumer goods with no investment return.  From an investment perspective, borrowing for car purchases is highly inadvisable.</p>
<p><strong>Uncontrolled Consumer Lending Easily Leads to Bankruptcy</strong></p>
<p>Credit cards, now a ubiquitous form of plastic currency worldwide, are also a typical example of consumer loans.  Since the popularization of credit cards, consumer behavior has undergone significant changes. While credit cards offer great convenience, their widespread use has led to a surge in bankruptcy cases among American families, with outstanding credit card debt exceeding 700 billion USD.  Some may wonder: how can credit cards lead to bankruptcy if you only spend what you have?  In fact, from a borrowing perspective, credit cards have an irresistible allure.</p>
<p>The greatest temptation of credit card borrowing lies in its simplicity.  With just a signature, you can make purchases in advance and even borrow cash from the bank, subtly inflating your spending power.  Remember: when using credit cards, never spend more than you can afford to repay each month.  Credit card interest rates are often above 20%, so you should always pay off your credit card balance promptly.  My advice is: &ldquo;If you can&rsquo;t control your spending urges, it&rsquo;s best not to apply for a credit card. If you apply for one for convenience, never use it for the sake of credit.  Use it only when it truly offers convenience.&rdquo;</p>
<p>While using credit cards for borrowing is convenient, those who entertain this idea should first understand the destructive power of a 20% interest rate. As mentioned earlier, if you save 14,000 per year and invest it in an investment tool with a 20% annual return, after 40 years, the 560,000 invested will grow to 102.81 million due to the power of compounding. Similarly, if someone borrows 14,000 per year on a credit card for 40 years, totaling 560,000, with a 20% interest rate, they will have to repay the bank 102.81 million after 40 years. This explains why the prevalence of credit card debt in the United States has historically led to numerous bankruptcies.</p>
<p>Another common type of loan is a mortgage.  Generally, mortgages are a sound form of leveraged investing because, in the long run, the average return on real estate is above 20%, while typical mortgage interest rates are around 10%, which meets the first principle of leveraged investing: the expected return on investment is higher than the interest rate on the loan. Whether it meets the second principle depends on the purchase conditions. In recent years, with the real estate market downturn and oversupply, some pre-sale housing promotions offer &ldquo;70% financing,&rdquo; allowing you to own a 10 million house with only a 3 million down payment. This is quite appealing, but investors often overlook the fact that while borrowing 7 million sounds great, they must be able to afford the monthly principal and interest payments of over 70,000. Without considering this, there is a risk of foreclosure and being forced to sell at a low price within months of purchase, suffering losses before enjoying any benefits of leveraged investing. Therefore, when purchasing real estate with borrowed funds, careful calculations must be made beforehand to choose a suitable house price that does not jeopardize the family&rsquo;s normal living expenses.</p>
<p>Although the initial burden of a mortgage is heavy, it becomes lighter over time as work experience and salary increase.  If you wait until you have saved enough money to buy a house, you might miss the opportunity entirely due to the rapid appreciation of house prices. Therefore, <strong>young people without real estate should consider buying a house as an investment. It not only forces them to save but also effectively combats inflation. Moreover, they can utilize the principle of financial leverage, using the bank&rsquo;s money to expand their credit and accumulate wealth.</strong></p>
<p><strong>How Much Debt Should You Take On?</strong></p>
<p>If you decide to use leveraged investing, the next question is: how much debt should you take on? This is a crucial question. Too much debt carries high risks, while too little debt fails to fully utilize the potential of making money with other people&rsquo;s money.</p>
<p>How much debt should a family take on?  Like &ldquo;how much debt should a company have,&rdquo; this is a question without a precise answer. In practice, it depends on the specific circumstances of each family. However, one thing is certain: if a family has the capacity to borrow but chooses not to, it is being too conservative and not managing its finances optimally. Conversely, excessive borrowing is too dangerous.  Before taking on debt, each family should consider its actual situation and make a wise judgment about its debt level.  As for how much to borrow, I recommend considering the following factors:</p>
<ul>
<li>
<ol>
<li>Income Stability:  Loan interest must be paid on time regardless of investment performance. If your income source is unstable, you may not be able to make regular interest payments, making high-leverage investments unsuitable. Similar to companies with stable income, they have a greater capacity to utilize more debt.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol start="2">
<li>Personal Assets: Borrowing from financial institutions requires tangible assets as collateral. Therefore, owning more assets suitable as collateral allows for larger leveraged investments.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol start="3">
<li>Return on Investment: Other things being equal, the higher the return on investment, the greater the benefits of financial leverage.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol start="4">
<li>Inflation Rate: Borrowing is more advantageous during periods of high inflation, as inflation allows you to repay debt with less valuable money.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol start="5">
<li>Risk Tolerance: Everyone has a different risk tolerance, related to personality and individual circumstances. Those with low risk tolerance should not over-leverage, even if it could lead to large profits, as the stress could take a toll.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol start="6">
<li>Market Interest Rate Levels: Generally, when market interest rates fall and bank funds are ample, not only is it easier for investors to borrow money, but the benefits of financial leverage are also greater. Therefore, falling interest rates present an opportune time for investors to consider leveraged investing.</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>Keeping money in the bank makes a person poor.</p>
</blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">The Bank is Not a Place for Saving Money 
    <div id="the-bank-is-not-a-place-for-saving-money" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#the-bank-is-not-a-place-for-saving-money" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>What is the function of a bank to you? Many people believe banks are for saving money. However, for those who truly understand investment management, banks are not a place to save money, but a source of borrowing.</p>
<p><strong>The function of a bank is to provide a place for those who are not good at managing money to save, so that those who are good at it can use that money to invest and make profits.</strong> Suppose someone deposits 14,000 per year into a bank at a 5% interest rate. After 40 years, the bank will owe this depositor 1.69 million. On the other hand, if an investor borrows 14,000 per year from the same bank at the same 5% interest rate and invests that money in stocks or real estate, achieving an average annual return of 20%, after 40 years, their investment would grow to 102.81 million, while they only need to repay the bank 1.69 million. In other words, the 101.12 million gained was made by utilizing the money of bank depositors.</p>
<p><strong>How to Build Credit</strong></p>
<p>In today&rsquo;s highly developed financial markets, there are numerous financing channels for businesses. However, for individuals, banks remain the primary source of borrowing.  Maintaining a close relationship with the bank and earning their trust is crucial for building personal credit.</p>
<p>Credit is the ability to borrow.  A person with high credit not only demonstrates a strong ability to repay loans but also indicates wealth. How do you build credit?  As the saying goes, &ldquo;Loan and repay, and borrowing again is easy.&rdquo; The first rule of building credit is to borrow money and repay it on time. Some people, to establish their creditworthiness (the ability to borrow), even borrow small sums of money for seemingly frivolous reasons, just to build a good borrowing record so they can borrow larger amounts in the future.</p>
<p>Discard the outdated notion that &ldquo;borrowing is not respectable.&rdquo; In the past, only those in dire financial straits would borrow money. Nowadays, such individuals can at most borrow small amounts from relatives and friends.  They would likely be unable to borrow a cent from a bank.  Today, those who can borrow from banks are typically wealthy individuals.</p>
<p>Based on current bank loan approval standards, without sufficient assets as collateral or evidence of stable future income and repayment ability, can anyone borrow money? Therefore, when I hear about someone heavily in debt, my first question is whether the source of the debt is banks or private loans.  If the source is entirely from banks, my immediate thought is: &ldquo;This person must be wealthy.&rdquo;</p>
<p><strong>Borrowing: A Double-Edged Sword</strong></p>
<p>Those who don&rsquo;t borrow cannot go bankrupt; similarly, those who don&rsquo;t borrow can hardly become immensely wealthy in a short period.  &ldquo;Debt&rdquo; appears in the lives of both the most successful and the most unsuccessful. While many wealthy individuals utilize debt to become rich, many poor people are ruined by misusing debt. Borrowing is a double-edged sword. Used correctly, it is a significant aid to investment and wealth creation. Used improperly, its destructive power can lead to complete ruin.  Prudence is essential when using it. It&rsquo;s like a double-edged sword that can save or harm, depending on how it&rsquo;s wielded.</p>
<p>I advise against rushing into leveraged investing before fully understanding its principles.  First, understand the nature of leveraged investing and carefully consider whether to use borrowing for investment.  Before borrowing, thoroughly understand how leveraged investing works. Only then can you truly achieve the goal of making money with other people&rsquo;s money without harming yourself.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Personal Investment Bible: Investment Iron Law V</title>
      <link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1731056005964/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1731056005964/</guid>
      <description>This article explores the relationship between risk and return in investment and financial management, emphasizing the importance of risk management.  It points out that all high-return investments come with high risks, and while risk aversion is human nature, excessive risk aversion can lead to missed opportunities. Using Forbes&amp;#39; philosophy on risk as an example, the author illustrates how to assess risks and rewards, advocating for calculated risks with adequate preparation.  The article also cautions readers against being seduced by high-risk, low-return speculative activities, encouraging them to start with small investments to gain experience, gradually overcome their fear of risk, and ultimately master risk to achieve wealth growth.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[

<h2 class="relative group">Investment Iron Law V: Mitigating Investment Risk 
    <div id="investment-iron-law-v-mitigating-investment-risk" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#investment-iron-law-v-mitigating-investment-risk" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>Investment and financial management should never prioritize returns while neglecting risks.</p>
</blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">Analyzing Risk, Minimizing Damage 
    <div id="analyzing-risk-minimizing-damage" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#analyzing-risk-minimizing-damage" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>In 1987, while working at Merrill Lynch in the United States, I met a seasoned investment veteran with decades of Wall Street experience. He once said, &ldquo;I can teach you how to pick stocks in an hour, but it would take me more than five years to teach you how to manage investment risk.&rdquo;</p>
<p><strong>Risk is Unavoidable</strong></p>
<p>In the ever-changing and unpredictable world of investment, uncertainties abound. We call these uncertainties risks. How you face these risks when they materialize is a question every investor must confront. <strong>Risk is called risk precisely because future outcomes are uncertain and unavoidable.</strong> Therefore, investment and financial management should never solely focus on returns while ignoring risks. In fact, managing risk is even more crucial. <strong>The purpose of risk management is not to eliminate risk entirely, but to acknowledge its inherent existence and impossibility of complete eradication.  It&rsquo;s about analyzing risk and subsequently mitigating it.</strong></p>
<p>While engaging in risk management, investors must understand that &ldquo;you can never be fully prepared for every risk.&rdquo;  You can strive to reduce risk, but don&rsquo;t attempt to eliminate it completely. Many try to avoid risk through predictions or expert advice.  However, no matter how accurate your forecasting techniques or how insightful the expert predictions, risk can never be fully avoided. <strong>The greatest danger of predictions is not their frequent inaccuracy, but the tendency for investors to blindly trust them, losing their risk awareness. They focus solely on whether the prediction comes true, neglecting the potential magnitude of the underlying risks.</strong>  Relying solely on predictions without thorough risk analysis is extremely dangerous. Any sound investment decision inherently involves unknowns, uncertainties, and risks.  Furthermore, investments without uncertainties and a degree of risk are unlikely to be good investments.</p>
<p><strong>All High-Return Investments Carry High Risks</strong></p>
<p>The key to successful investment and financial management lies in learning to grasp high returns while effectively managing the accompanying risks.</p>
<p>The investment environment is constantly changing and unpredictable. The only constant is change. Some external factors (such as interest rates, exchange rates, economic conditions, and inflation rates) are bound to change, although the nature of these changes remains unknown.  Additionally, unforeseen events (such as wars, political events, and natural disasters) are uncontrollable variables.  To succeed in this volatile investment world, the most important thing is not to lament change but to accept it as inevitable. <strong>Prepare for various changes and even anticipate them, because only through change can wealth be redistributed.</strong> Change is both a threat and an opportunity, depending on how you respond.  Skilled investors often find profitable opportunities amidst change.</p>
<p>People often assume investors love risk.  This is not true.  Successful investors possess a unique ability to manage risk. They don&rsquo;t see &ldquo;risk-taking&rdquo; as a source of amusement, nor do they find the act of taking risks thrilling or exciting. They take risks solely for the potential of high investment returns.  Since all high-return investments inherently carry high risks, risk-taking is an unavoidable part of the journey to financial success.</p>
<p>Many perceive stock investment as extremely risky, believing stock investors to be risk-seekers. In reality, investing in stocks is not about loving the risk associated with stocks. It&rsquo;s about understanding that all high-return investments carry high risks. To build wealth, you must take the risk of investing in high-return assets and bear the associated risks.  Savvy investors understand how to take calculated risks and mitigate them.  In fact, if risk mitigation measures are implemented effectively, the actual risks of investment and financial management are relatively small.</p>
<p><strong>Stocks and real estate offer high returns precisely because of their inherent volatility and risk.</strong> Because most people are risk-averse and avoid investing in risky assets like stocks and real estate, those who can tolerate risk are better positioned to reap higher returns.</p>
<p>Many shy away from stocks and real estate primarily because they fear losses, are intimidated by future uncertainties, or can&rsquo;t handle price fluctuations. <strong>In fact, short-term price fluctuations are perfectly normal and highlight the high-risk nature of high-return investments.</strong> Therefore, to achieve high returns, one must possess a spirit of adventure and be able to withstand significant volatility.</p>
<p><em>1. Unpredictable risks allow risk-takers to earn a risk premium.</em></p>
<p><em>2. We miss opportunities because we are afraid to take risks, not because the world doesn&rsquo;t offer them.</em></p>
<p><em>3. To achieve financial success through investment, you must take risks, because high returns always come with high risks.</em></p>
<blockquote>
<p>I dislike taking unnecessary risks, so before every activity, I do my best to take necessary precautions to mitigate risk.</p>
</blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">The Forbes Philosophy on Risk 
    <div id="the-forbes-philosophy-on-risk" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#the-forbes-philosophy-on-risk" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>Malcolm Forbes was a legendary figure in the American business world.  He amassed a fortune by founding Forbes magazine, possessed a priceless collection, and was listed among the 400 wealthiest Americans. He not only ran a high-risk magazine business but was also a renowned hot air balloonist and motorcycle enthusiast.  He once rode a motorcycle across Eurasia from Paris to Beijing.  He traveled the world, flying hot air balloons across the United States, and even ventured to Turkey and China, setting multiple world records and attracting widespread media attention, making him a household name.</p>
<p><strong>Averting Danger Before it Happens, Ensuring Safety</strong></p>
<p>Some labeled him an &ldquo;adventurer.&rdquo;  He offered an insightful explanation of this label, saying, &ldquo;Many people think I&rsquo;m a risk-lover.  I&rsquo;m not. Like most people, I strongly dislike risk. The reason I take risks today, despite my aversion to them, is simple: all good things in life come with risks. I take risks purely to live a rich and fulfilling life.”  &ldquo;Riding in a hot air balloon or on a motorcycle across different lands broadens one&rsquo;s horizons and exposes one to the world&rsquo;s beauty, enriching life. However, many people, despite yearning for these experiences, hesitate to engage in them because they perceive them as high-risk activities. But, once you actually try them, you&rsquo;ll find that if you take adequate precautions beforehand, the risks involved are quite small.” &ldquo;I dislike taking unnecessary risks, so before every activity, I strive to take the necessary preventative measures to mitigate risk.&rdquo;</p>
<p>Malcolm Forbes was risk-averse, but he took risks to experience the good things in life, and after taking those risks, he sought ways to mitigate them.</p>
<p><strong>Assess the Rewards and Risks, If It&rsquo;s Worth It – Take the Risk</strong></p>
<p>Are you afraid of taking risks? If so, you are not alone.  Most people are afraid of taking risks; very few are natural risk-takers.  But why are some people so composed in the face of risk, and even achieve success through it?  It&rsquo;s because they understand the principles of &ldquo;nothing ventured, nothing gained&rdquo; and &ldquo;no high risk, no high return.&rdquo;  Indeed, the correct perspective on risk should be: take risks worth taking, and then find ways to mitigate them.</p>
<p>Successful investors are driven by the pursuit of &ldquo;wealth.&rdquo; Although they must be prepared to withstand the pressure of price fluctuations, as long as the expected return is high and there&rsquo;s a risk premium, risk-taking will ultimately lead to success.</p>
<p>Before every investment, it&rsquo;s essential to understand the potential risks and develop contingency plans for every possible scenario. Analyze the degree of blind risk-taking, estimate the probability of success, and continuously re-evaluate throughout the process. I recommend investors create a risk-reward assessment table before making any investment, weighing all factors.  Ask yourself, &ldquo;Can I bear the consequences if the worst-case scenario unfolds?&rdquo; and &ldquo;Is the potential return of this investment attractive enough?&rdquo;</p>
<p>Always plan for the worst and prepare for the best. This is especially true for investment and financial management.  <strong>Before making any investment, no matter how confident you are, you should ask yourself, &ldquo;What is the worst possible outcome?&rdquo; Then ask, &ldquo;Can I bear the consequences if the worst happens?&rdquo; If the answer to both questions is yes, and the expected return is high enough, then you should invest. If the worst-case scenario is unbearable, then no matter how alluring the potential reward, you should categorically refuse to invest.</strong></p>
<p><strong>Don&rsquo;t Take Unnecessary Risks</strong></p>
<p>If you ever visit Las Vegas or Atlantic City, observe the lavishly decorated casinos carefully. You&rsquo;ll notice the absence of clocks and windows, and the ever-present bright lights.  &ldquo;There&rsquo;s no time in the mountains, and no time in casinos.&rdquo; Why are there no clocks or windows in casinos?  It&rsquo;s because casinos leverage the law of large numbers to win your money.  The lack of clocks and windows is designed to blur the lines between day and night, encouraging gamblers to play endlessly until they lose track of time. The longer you play, the more times you play, the higher the probability of the casino winning.  As the number of games increases, the expected value gradually reveals itself.  Gambling inevitably leads to losses because its expected value is negative.  This might not be apparent in a few instances, but over time, the expected value becomes increasingly evident. Therefore, prolonged gambling inevitably leads to losses.  This explains the saying &ldquo;nine out of ten gamblers lose&rdquo; and &ldquo;long-term gambling leads to certain loss,&rdquo; which aligns perfectly with the principle of the law of large numbers. The law of large numbers states that the more times a game is played, the closer the return gets to the expected value of that game.</p>
<p>I had a classmate in the doctoral program at UC Berkeley who excelled in mathematics and frequented Las Vegas casinos on weekends.  Curious, I asked him, &ldquo;You&rsquo;re so smart and you know that gambling is designed against the players. Are you trying to win money?&rdquo;  He replied, &ldquo;I never go there to win money. I gamble to relieve stress.&rdquo;  He explained that after a heartbreak in college, he tried various methods to cope, such as drinking, speeding, and traveling, but none were effective.  He eventually found that only gambling could allow him to truly escape. Gambling can be a form of entertainment, but it&rsquo;s certainly not a way to make money. Its expected average return is lower than bank deposits, making it impossible to build wealth through such activities.</p>
<p>Many people hold the misconception that &ldquo;high risk always equates to high return.&rdquo; This misunderstanding stems from a misinterpretation of the definition of &ldquo;return.&rdquo; High risk might indeed offer high potential returns, but this represents the maximum possible return, which has a very low probability.  However, in the context of &ldquo;high risk, high return,&rdquo; the &ldquo;return&rdquo; refers to the expected return (long-term average return), not the maximum possible return.  Indeed, gambling boasts incredibly high maximum potential returns, but its average, or expected, return is negative. Taking such risks is not only unprofitable but also detrimental.</p>
<p><strong>There are No High-Return, Zero-Risk Investments</strong></p>
<p>Success requires risk-taking, but risk-taking doesn&rsquo;t guarantee success.  One must take calculated risks. A calculated risk is one that, on average, offers high returns over the long term.</p>
<p>Some people&rsquo;s problem isn&rsquo;t a lack of risk-taking spirit but a tendency to take unnecessary risks. They don&rsquo;t know what risks to take to achieve financial success. As detailed in previous chapters, the cornerstone of investment success is the power of compounding, which only works effectively with high returns.  Over the long term, stocks and real estate are asset classes that offer high expected returns.  Therefore, taking calculated risks means investing in assets with high expected returns and bravely bearing the associated risks.</p>
<p>Consider a game where participants must pay $100. There&rsquo;s a 99.9% chance of losing $100 and a 0.1% chance of winning $95,000. Would you play?  In a survey I conducted with hundreds of students, over 65% chose to play this high-risk game.  Their reasoning was simple: while the risk was high, the potential loss was capped at $100, while the potential gain was a whopping $95,000.  However, the expected return of this game is negative.  Even if you get lucky and win once, in the long run, you&rsquo;re bound to lose.  This is a classic example of a risk not worth taking.</p>
<p>Avoid risks that don&rsquo;t offer high returns. Activities like futures trading, margin trading in foreign exchange and bonds, lotteries, and short-term stock trading all carry high risks and often have negative returns.  In other words, these are high-risk, negative-return activities.  You can engage in these activities for entertainment, but never delude yourself into believing they will bring you wealth.</p>
<p><strong>There are no high-return, zero-risk investment opportunities.</strong> In a society filled with intelligent individuals, such opportunities are impossible. If someone offers you a high-return, risk-free investment opportunity, they are undoubtedly trying to scam you.</p>
<p>I remind readers again: don&rsquo;t blindly chase high returns and jump into risky ventures.  Speculative activities like those mentioned above are not truly high-return investment tools, but they are definitely high-risk endeavors.  These risks are not worth taking.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Absolute safety is a myth. The real danger is not taking any risks. In a volatile environment, the biggest risk is not taking any risks.</p>
</blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">Don&rsquo;t Shy Away from Risk Entirely 
    <div id="dont-shy-away-from-risk-entirely" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#dont-shy-away-from-risk-entirely" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>The future world is changing rapidly.  Changes will accelerate across all aspects of business, economics, finance, politics, and society, creating a more complex financial landscape.  <strong>It&rsquo;s foreseeable that wealth redistribution will also accelerate.</strong> Risk aversion is human nature.  In the past, you could live a stable life without taking risks.  However, <strong>in the face of the volatile investment environment of the future, not taking risks becomes the biggest risk of all.</strong></p>
<p><strong>Fear of Falling Will Keep You from Running Fast</strong></p>
<p>Fear of risk prevents many from investing, causing them to miss out on the opportunity to build wealth.  Keeping money in a bank seems safe and risk-free. However, as previously analyzed, inflation severely erodes the real value of money.  From a financial management perspective, keeping money in a bank carries the greatest risk.  Decades later, when those around you who invested wisely become millionaires, those who kept their money in banks may face financial hardship.  My point is: don&rsquo;t shy away from risk entirely. Risk isn&rsquo;t as terrifying as it seems.  Taking calculated risks with high potential returns is absolutely worthwhile.</p>
<p>I&rsquo;m often asked, &ldquo;Teacher, will the stock market fall again?&rdquo; My answer is, &ldquo;I don&rsquo;t know.&rdquo;  Then they ask, &ldquo;When will it start rising?&rdquo; My answer remains, &ldquo;I don&rsquo;t know.&rdquo;  They further inquire, &ldquo;Which stock should I buy?  Can you give me a hot tip?&rdquo; My answer is still, &ldquo;I don&rsquo;t know.&rdquo;  Then they question skeptically, &ldquo;How can you invest when you don&rsquo;t know anything? Isn&rsquo;t that too risky?&rdquo; My response is, &ldquo;You must invest and manage your finances without knowing the answers to these questions to succeed.&rdquo;</p>
<p>Why invest when the answers are unknown and the future is uncertain? The reason is simple: While the future is full of risks, one thing is certain: as long as the economy continues to grow and corporate profitability rises, the long-term return on investment in the stock market will inevitably surpass bank deposits, and by a significant margin.  Repeatedly avoiding worthwhile risks will prevent you from building wealth.</p>
<p><strong>How to Cultivate a Risk-Taking Spirit</strong></p>
<p><em>A courageous risk-taker is not someone without fear, but someone with the power to overcome it.</em></p>
<p>The spirit of adventure isn&rsquo;t innate; it&rsquo;s developed through practice, through taking risks, failing, taking risks again, failing again… step by step.</p>
<p>Everyone is capable of taking risks, and everyone has had the experience of taking bold risks.  As toddlers, we dared to stand and learn to walk, falling and getting back up countless times.  Learning to ride a bicycle involved numerous falls, followed by getting back up, falling again, and getting back up again, until we finally mastered it. Most life skills, such as swimming, skating, driving, public speaking, and so on, are not innate instincts.  Learning these skills requires going through a phase of risk-taking, embracing the spirit of perseverance, and trying repeatedly.  Learning investment and financial management is no exception; it requires this standard process of risk-taking.  To become a successful investor, you must first discard the habit of risk aversion, rediscover your lost instinct for adventure, and cultivate a healthy risk-taking spirit.</p>
<p>Does investing have to be extremely risky?  In reality, the risks involved in investment and financial management are no greater than the examples mentioned above.  It&rsquo;s just that as we reach an age where we believe we are qualified to manage finances, our risk-taking spirit has diminished significantly. As children, almost everyone learns to walk.  A little older, most learn to ride a bicycle.  But as we grow older, the number of people who learn more adventurous activities like swimming and skating decreases considerably.  In adulthood, the number of people comfortable with public speaking dwindles even further.</p>
<p><strong>Our risk-taking spirit seems to fade with age.  This is partly because experiencing failures and mistakes naturally leads to frustration and discouragement. Without sufficient motivation, we tend to avoid taking risks to minimize the blow of failure.  Another contributing factor is traditional education.  Out of a desire to protect children, adults often reprimand them for any risky behavior, instilling a habit of prioritizing safety and avoiding mistakes.  Children then strive to be &ldquo;good kids&rdquo; who never do anything wrong.  As we age, this risk aversion becomes ingrained. While avoiding risk isn&rsquo;t inherently bad, excessive risk aversion becomes a significant obstacle to successful investment and financial management.</strong></p>
<p><strong>The First Priority of Financial Management: Overcoming Fear</strong></p>
<p>When individuals can control their fear, they can control their thoughts and actions.  Self-control enables them to remain calm in chaotic environments, make necessary decisions without being paralyzed by the uncertainty of the outcomes, and be prepared to bear the consequences of failure when things don&rsquo;t go as planned. This courage and risk-taking spirit in the face of danger are essential qualities for investors.</p>
<p><strong>Courageous risk-takers are not fearless; they simply recognize risk and overcome their fear of it.</strong> Courage stems from controlling fear, and cultivating a risk-taking spirit begins with understanding risk.</p>
<p>To become a successful investor, you must first discard the habit of avoiding risk.  Admittedly, changing long-held risk-averse habits is no easy feat.  However, since risk-taking is an indispensable element of successful financial management, the first priority in learning to manage your finances is to overcome fear and force yourself to take risks.  Cultivate a healthy risk-taking spirit, invest bravely in assets with high expected returns, and bear the associated risks.</p>
<p><strong>Top performers in any field achieve success by bravely facing their fears and taking calculated risks.</strong> Those who achieve financial success and fulfill their dreams through investment share this same spirit of adventure. <strong>Remember: excessive caution hinders success.  Without a spirit of adventure, dreams will forever remain dreams.</strong></p>
<blockquote>
<p>Mastering risk is the foundation of successful financial management.</p>
</blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">Overcoming Risk – Start Small 
    <div id="overcoming-risk--start-small" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#overcoming-risk--start-small" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>Skilled risk-takers never test the depth of the water by stepping in with both feet. They extend one foot first, and if the situation seems unfavorable, they quickly withdraw.  An African proverb states, &ldquo;Only a fool tests the depth of the water with both feet.&rdquo;  Similarly, only a fool would go all-in without any investment experience.</p>
<p><strong>Gain Experience with Small Amounts of Money</strong></p>
<p>When faced with unfamiliar investment opportunities, don&rsquo;t put all your eggs in one basket. Start small.  Skilled generals don&rsquo;t expose their main forces to unnecessary danger.  To gather intelligence and gain an advantage, they deploy small reconnaissance units deep into enemy territory to identify low-risk, high-impact attack strategies.</p>
<p>The same principle applies to investment risk-taking strategies.  When dealing with unfamiliar investments, unclear situations, or a lack of confidence, avoid going all-in.  Start small, using small amounts of money to gain experience and familiarize yourself with the situation. Once you have sufficient experience and confidence, then you can invest larger sums.</p>
<p>As the saying goes, &ldquo;All things are difficult before they are easy.&rdquo; The best way to overcome fear is to confront what you fear head-on.  Since risk-taking is an essential part of building wealth through investment, don&rsquo;t shy away from it.  Start with small investments to build your risk tolerance.  With experience, the feeling of fear will gradually dissipate.  By progressively overcoming small fears, you can then face larger risks. You&rsquo;ll soon discover that the experience gained through risk-taking is helping you steadily approach your dreams.</p>
<p><strong>Once You&rsquo;re Used to Risk, You&rsquo;ll Find It&rsquo;s Not So Scary</strong></p>
<p>Risk aversion is human nature, but don&rsquo;t let a single investment failure shatter your confidence and prevent you from investing again, turning you into a perpetual loser.  Conversely, don&rsquo;t let a stroke of good luck make you forget the existence of risk, leading you to borrow heavily and invest recklessly, resulting in irreparable losses.  Successful and unsuccessful investors alike fear risk; they simply react to it differently.</p>
<p>Dear readers, if you haven&rsquo;t tried investing yet, take the plunge for the sake of building wealth!  If you take appropriate risk mitigation measures after investing, I can assure you from experience: &ldquo;The risks of investing are actually quite small, even smaller than the risk of riding a bicycle.  After 10 or 20 years of investing, when you see your wealth growing rapidly, the feeling will be hundreds of times better than riding a bicycle.&rdquo;</p>
<p><strong>The first element of investing is a strong adventurous spirit, seeking to generate substantial risk premiums between risk and safety.</strong> No matter what investment you choose, as long as it offers high expected returns, risk is inevitable. Investors should embrace calculated risks and accumulate financial knowledge and experience along the way. Risk naturally decreases with accumulated knowledge, and wealth grows at an increasing pace.</p>
<p>This book dedicates significant space to discussing risk because the biggest challenge people face in financial management is their inability to confront risk directly.  They don&rsquo;t know how to face or manage risk, and some are even afraid to take any risks.  They don&rsquo;t realize that the biggest obstacle to successful investment and financial management is the fear of risk. This mindset is understandable, as most investment and financial management decisions are made amidst uncertainty and change. In short, to achieve financial success through investment, you must be willing to take calculated risks. Currently, many people suffer significant losses due to blind risk-taking and involvement in high-risk speculative activities.</p>
<p>If you are unwilling to take risks and prefer a conservative approach, be prepared for a life of mediocrity, as this is unavoidable. Of course, there&rsquo;s nothing wrong with a conservative and mediocre life if it brings you happiness. The choice is yours. <strong>People usually regret the things they didn&rsquo;t do, not the things they tried.</strong> Therefore, my advice is: <strong>Take risks, but be cautious and learn how to manage them.</strong></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Personal Investment Bible: Investment Iron Law II</title>
      <link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1731056005961/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1731056005961/</guid>
      <description>This article explains that the key to wealth accumulation through personal finance is patience.  Using Li Ka-shing&amp;#39;s wealth accumulation as an example, it explains the power of compound interest and emphasizes the importance of long-term investment and time. At the same time, the article also points out the pitfalls of getting rich quickly and advises readers to choose entrepreneurship rather than speculation.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[

<h2 class="relative group">Investment Iron Law II: Patience is Key to Wealth Accumulation 
    <div id="investment-iron-law-ii-patience-is-key-to-wealth-accumulation" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#investment-iron-law-ii-patience-is-key-to-wealth-accumulation" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>Working hard is not about making more money,<br>
but about maintaining a state of mind<br>
— challenge, goals, struggle, and success.</p>
</blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">How Did Li Ka-shing Accumulate His Wealth? 
    <div id="how-did-li-ka-shing-accumulate-his-wealth" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#how-did-li-ka-shing-accumulate-his-wealth" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>Li Ka-shing, ranked among the top ten wealthiest Chinese in the world with a fortune of nearly $7 billion, is the chairman of Cheung Kong Holdings and Hutchison Whampoa Limited in Hong Kong. His legendary journey to wealth and his influence in Hong Kong&rsquo;s political and business circles have earned him another nickname — &ldquo;Superman Li.&rdquo;</p>
<p><strong>Capitalizing on the Plunging Property Market</strong></p>
<p>In 1939, 12-year-old Li Ka-shing moved to Hong Kong from his hometown of Chao&rsquo;an, Guangdong, with his father. After two years of schooling, Hong Kong fell due to the Pacific War. The following year, his father died of a serious illness, forcing Li Ka-shing, the eldest son, to drop out of school and support his family. After Hong Kong&rsquo;s liberation in 1945, he ended his odd-job career and became a salesman at a plastics factory, working over 16 hours a day. Three years later, at the age of 20, he was promoted to general manager. Two years after that, he used all his savings of HK$7,000 to start his own small plastics factory, &ldquo;Cheung Kong Industries,&rdquo; the predecessor of today&rsquo;s largest conglomerate in Hong Kong, Cheung Kong Holdings.</p>
<p>How did Li Ka-shing, without even a primary school diploma, take his first step toward becoming the richest man by producing plastic flowers? In 1958, due to a rent increase by the landlord of his factory, Li Ka-shing bought a piece of land in North Point and built his own factory. In the early 1960s, the plastic flower industry declined, and in 1967, Hong Kong property prices plummeted. Li Ka-shing seized the opportunity to acquire land at low prices. In 1972, the Hong Kong stock market soared, and Cheung Kong Industries went public, taking advantage of the opportunity to raise capital from the public to purchase more land. In the 10 years following the completion of his first factory in 1958, his real estate holdings increased 50-fold. Cheung Kong now holds approximately 1.48 million square meters of floor space. Li Ka-shing has been investing in real estate for over 40 years, and long-term investment has accumulated his enormous wealth.</p>
<p>Having strived for 50 years and achieved success in wealth accumulation, Li Ka-shing has unique insights into success. He said: &ldquo;Before the age of 20, 100% of career success comes from hard work; between 20 and 30, when a career has some foundation, 10% of success depends on good luck, and 90% still comes from diligence; after 30, the proportion of opportunity gradually increases; now, luck accounts for about 30% to 40%.&rdquo;</p>
<p>The same applies to wealth accumulation. Before 20, all money comes from hard work; between 20 and 30 is the time to work hard to earn and save money; after 30, the importance of investment and financial management gradually increases. By middle age, the money earned is less important, and how to manage money becomes more critical. Li Ka-shing has been fighting for his wealth all his life. To become rich, one must have enough patience.</p>
<p><strong>The Power of Compound Interest Takes Time</strong></p>
<p>Many people who have heard my lectures often ask the same questions: &ldquo;Saving 14,000 yuan a year to become a billionaire is indeed impressive, but according to your method, it takes 40 years, which is really discouraging!&rdquo; &ldquo;It takes 40 years to become a billionaire. By then, I might be dead. What&rsquo;s the point of having billions then?&rdquo; &ldquo;Can you teach some secrets to getting rich quickly?&rdquo;</p>
<p>Even I feel that 40 years is too long. At the repeated requests of the audience, I did spend some time studying this issue in depth. The result of the research is: <strong>Financial management requires a long time, and the effect is not visible in the short term.  It is impossible to get rich quickly through financial management.</strong></p>
<p>If someone starts now and saves 14,000 yuan at the end of each year, and if the money saved each year can be invested in stocks or real estate with an average annual return of 20%, we know that the wealth will grow to 102.81 million yuan after 40 years. Now, let&rsquo;s ask: How much wealth can he accumulate after 10 years? Most people think that with such a high return, even with a shorter time, after 10 years of compounding, it should be at least 5 million yuan, some even guess 10 million, and the most conservative guess is 1 million.  Similarly, this is a surprising answer: 360,000 yuan! The following calculation formula should be familiar to readers, but they will be surprised that the amount is so small.</p>
<p><math xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" display="block"><mtable displaystyle="true" columnalign="right center left" columnspacing="0 thickmathspace" rowspacing="3pt"><mtr><mtd><mn>14,000</mn><mo>×</mo><mfrac><mrow><msup><mrow><mo stretchy="false">(</mo><mn>1</mn><mo>+</mo><mn>0.20</mn><mo stretchy="false">)</mo></mrow><mrow><mn>10</mn></mrow></msup><mo>−</mo><mn>1</mn></mrow><mn>0.20</mn></mfrac></mtd><mtd><mi></mi><mo>=</mo></mtd><mtd><mn>360,000</mn></mtd></mtr><mtr><mtd><mn>14,000</mn><mo>×</mo><mfrac><mrow><msup><mrow><mo stretchy="false">(</mo><mn>1</mn><mo>+</mo><mn>0.20</mn><mo stretchy="false">)</mo></mrow><mrow><mn>40</mn></mrow></msup><mo>−</mo><mn>1</mn></mrow><mn>0.20</mn></mfrac></mtd><mtd><mi></mi><mo>=</mo></mtd><mtd><mn>102,810,000</mn></mtd></mtr></mtable></math></p>
<p>With the same 20% return, 14,000 yuan per year results in 102.81 million yuan after 40 years of financial management, but only 360,000 yuan after 10 years, which is unbelievable! The difference is more than 300 times! Fortunately, this concept is presented to readers in a timely manner. Otherwise, if readers use the methods mentioned in this book, save 14,000 yuan every year, and invest all of it in stocks, thinking that they can become billionaires, they would be shocked to find that after ten years of hard work, with an average annual return of 20%, they have only accumulated 360,000 yuan! They might feel cheated.  After struggling for 10 years, they can&rsquo;t even afford a car, let alone become billionaires!</p>
<p>What is 10 years? Ten years is a long time. After 10 years of struggle, there&rsquo;s only a little over 300,000 yuan. How discouraging! This is the frustration one inevitably encounters in the process of accumulating wealth through investment and financial management.  Investors must understand that financial management is a &ldquo;marathon&rdquo; rather than a &ldquo;sprint.&rdquo; It&rsquo;s about endurance, not explosive power.</p>
<p>The prerequisite for getting rich through investment and financial management is time, and a long time. You must go through a very long waiting period before you can see the results. If the invested capital is small, no results will be seen after 10 years.</p>
<p><strong>Earning Your Second 10 Million is Easier Than the First 1 Million</strong></p>
<p>Saving 14,000 yuan at the end of each year with an average investment return of 20%, even after 20 years, the assets will only accumulate to 2.61 million yuan.  At this point, one is still far from being a billionaire. It takes 30 years to accumulate 16.55 million yuan, barely reaching the millionaire level.  Only after 40 years of continuous struggle can one become a billionaire with 102.81 million yuan.</p>
<p><em>Annual Investment of 14,000 Yuan, Wealth Accumulation (20% Return, Unit/10,000 Yuan)</em></p>
<table>
  <thead>
      <tr>
          <th style="text-align: left">Year</th>
          <th style="text-align: left">Accumulated Amount at Year End</th>
          <th style="text-align: left">Amount Increased in the Last Five Years</th>
      </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
      <tr>
          <td style="text-align: left">5</td>
          <td style="text-align: left">10</td>
          <td style="text-align: left">10</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td style="text-align: left">10</td>
          <td style="text-align: left">36</td>
          <td style="text-align: left">26</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td style="text-align: left">15</td>
          <td style="text-align: left">101</td>
          <td style="text-align: left">65</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td style="text-align: left">20</td>
          <td style="text-align: left">261</td>
          <td style="text-align: left">160</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td style="text-align: left">25</td>
          <td style="text-align: left">661</td>
          <td style="text-align: left">400</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td style="text-align: left">30</td>
          <td style="text-align: left">1655</td>
          <td style="text-align: left">994</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td style="text-align: left">35</td>
          <td style="text-align: left">4128</td>
          <td style="text-align: left">2473</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td style="text-align: left">40</td>
          <td style="text-align: left">10281</td>
          <td style="text-align: left">6153</td>
      </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>
<p>From the table above, we can see: by saving 14,000 yuan annually with a 20% investment return, the wealth increased by 360,000 yuan in the first decade, 2.25 million yuan in the second decade, 13.94 million yuan in the third decade, and 86.26 million yuan in the fourth decade. This is the characteristic of geometric progression, and it is also the principle that people engaged in investment and financial management should understand.  Therefore, three important characteristics of investment and financial management can be summarized here:</p>
<ul>
<li>
<ol>
<li>Most wealth is created in the later stages. From the above example, we can see that only 41.28 million yuan was accumulated in the first 35 years, while 61.53 million yuan was created in the last 5 years.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol start="2">
<li>In terms of amount, your ability to make money through financial management increases over time. From the table above, it can be seen that doing the same thing, the amount of money earned increases, the only thing needed is patience.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol start="3">
<li>Earning the second 10 million yuan is often easier than the first 1 million yuan.</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>Wealth accumulation doesn&rsquo;t happen overnight.</p>
</blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">Patience Pays Off 
    <div id="patience-pays-off" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#patience-pays-off" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>A self-made man who got rich by investing in stocks once told me: &ldquo;Now that I&rsquo;ve made it, a stock price increase can easily bring in millions of yuan. Making money has suddenly become so easy, it&rsquo;s unstoppable. Thinking back to the days when I first entered the stock market 30 years ago, it took a lot of hard work to earn tens of thousands of yuan. I really don&rsquo;t know where the money went back then.&rdquo;</p>
<p>This experience is not unfamiliar to many who have struggled to build their fortunes from scratch.  Everything is difficult at the beginning.  During the initial struggle, money is hard to earn.  It takes a lot of effort to earn just tens of thousands of yuan. It&rsquo;s puzzling why money is so hard to earn.  Until success is achieved, and money comes rolling in, one wonders why making money has become so easy.</p>
<p><strong>Time is the Stepping Stone to Wealth Accumulation</strong></p>
<p>Everyone desires the ability to effortlessly earn their second million or ten million, reaching a state of abundant wealth.  The problem is, before earning the second million, you need to have the first million. But how can you earn the first million?  If you want to accumulate 1 million through investment and financial management, you need &ldquo;time.&rdquo; You have to go through a long period of hardship. If you can endure the difficult period of earning the first million, you can naturally enjoy the ease of earning the second million.</p>
<p>From the compound interest formula, we can see that time is an indispensable factor for compound interest to take effect.  Patient waiting is a prerequisite for investment and financial management.  Especially for wealth accumulation through financial management, the required patience is not a few months or years, but at least two or three decades, or even four or five decades.</p>
<p>The vast majority of wealthy people accumulate their huge fortunes gradually from small amounts of money over a long period. In the beginning, most people have very little capital, even negligible. However, success is woven from a series of small achievements. Great wealth is the accumulation of small wealth, coupled with the effect of compound interest.</p>
<p>The importance of time in investment and financial management is evident. Patience is essential for financial management. The more patient you are in enduring the long waiting period, the greater the power of wealth creation will be. This is the characteristic of &ldquo;compound interest.&rdquo; However, today we live in a &ldquo;fast food&rdquo; culture where everything emphasizes speed and efficiency: fast food restaurants for meals, express delivery for mail, highways for driving, one-hour photo processing, and crash courses for learning. People have become increasingly impatient and short-sighted, lacking patience.  In investment and financial management, they are also impatient and lack patience, wanting to see results immediately.  It may be more efficient to pursue speed in other matters, but investment and financial management cannot be rushed. Time is a necessary condition for financial management. The more you rush, the less you achieve.  Based on my observations, a common mistake among investors is giving up halfway. They get easily discouraged during bear markets and simply sell their stocks and real estate, completely leaving the stock and property markets, not knowing that lack of patience and perseverance makes it difficult to achieve anything.</p>
<ul>
<li>
<ol>
<li>Time is an indispensable factor in achieving wealth through financial management.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol start="2">
<li>The patience required for wealth accumulation is not a few months or years, but at least two or three decades.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol start="3">
<li>Patient waiting allows compound interest to take effect.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol start="4">
<li>How can investors achieve a state of abundant and unstoppable wealth? Long-term holding and patient waiting.</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>The Real Estate Investment Experience of Madam Chang Yao-Hung-Ying, Chairperson of Grand Pacific Construction</strong></p>
<p><em>&ldquo;Land I bought for hundreds of thousands in the past is now worth hundreds of millions.&rdquo;</em></p>
<p>Madam Chang Yao-Hung-Ying, chairperson of Grand Pacific Construction, pointed out: In the 1930s, a mainlander investing in land in Taiwan was often ridiculed. But it was with this small capital and perseverance that Madam Chang Yao-Hung-Ying, who left Shanghai for Taiwan in 1947, when her husband became disillusioned with his business, saw the development potential of Taiwan. She picked up their real estate business skills from Shanghai and started buying land.</p>
<p>After more than 40 years, her long-term investment in real estate finally paid off.  Her family&rsquo;s business is growing bigger and bigger, and they now own two listed companies: ASE Technology Holding and Grand Pacific Construction. ASE Technology Holding is now the second largest packaging factory in the world. As for Grand Pacific Construction, it launched the Earl&rsquo;s Court project in Xizhi in 1987, which boosted the real estate market in Xizhi and rapidly accumulated their family&rsquo;s wealth, making them one of the richest families in Taiwan.</p>
<p>Madam Chang Yao-Hung-Ying has now passed the baton to her son, Jason Chang. Jason Chang, chairman of ASE Technology Holding, seems to have inherited his mother&rsquo;s investment acumen. He&rsquo;s the kind of person who buys land wherever he goes, whether it&rsquo;s in Taiwan, Hong Kong, mainland China, or the United States. Perhaps in another two or three decades, Jason Chang will also say: &ldquo;I didn&rsquo;t expect that the land I bought for a few million back then would now be worth tens of billions.&rdquo;  However, Jason Chang&rsquo;s wealth accumulation speed will be much faster than his mother&rsquo;s because he has already laid a good foundation.  All he needs to do is go with the flow, and his wealth will increase geometrically, with money rolling in, unstoppable.</p>
<p><strong>Withstanding the Test of Time is the True Measure</strong></p>
<p><em>It&rsquo;s not your judgment that makes you a lot of money, but your patience.</em></p>
<p>A crucial factor in financial management is time. Without a correct understanding of it, impatience will naturally arise.  Impatience leads to taking significant risks, turning potential success into failure.</p>
<p>Whether it&rsquo;s the accumulation of wealth or experience, it&rsquo;s not something that can be accomplished overnight. It takes time. Fortunately, God is very fair in this regard. Regardless of whether one is born rich or poor, noble or humble, everyone has only 24 hours a day and an average lifespan of about 75 years. Time is the greatest wealth in life, and a person&rsquo;s honor, status, wealth, and happiness all depend on how they use this wealth.</p>
<p>To accumulate wealth through investment and financial management, time is an indispensable factor. It cannot be rushed.  Investment and financial management can lead to slow and steady wealth accumulation, but investing small amounts of money and wanting to earn billions of wealth in a short period is, I can say with certainty, &ldquo;impossible!&rdquo; Just imagine, can a mother give birth without going through ten months of pregnancy? Can a farmer shorten the growth period of rice seedlings?</p>
<p>The growth of wealth is like the growth of life.  It&rsquo;s formed bit by bit, day by day, month by month, year by year, under the effect of compound interest.  It cannot be achieved overnight. This is the law of nature, and God never changes his natural laws.</p>
<p><strong>Luck is Not a Long-Term Strategy</strong></p>
<p>Many investors make a fortune overnight and go bankrupt overnight. Their success is due to luck, and their failure is because &ldquo;you may be lucky for a while, but you cannot always be lucky.&rdquo; <strong>Any investment opportunity that promises overnight riches must hide a greater risk of overnight poverty.</strong> This is why most of those who fantasize about getting rich quickly through financial management end up losing everything.</p>
<p>As long as you are patient and invest your assets in the right investment vehicles, you don&rsquo;t need to actively manage or worry. Compound interest will naturally lead to wealth growth, and becoming a billionaire over time is almost a certainty. In investment and financial management, haste makes waste. &ldquo;Fast&rdquo; is definitely not good!</p>
<p>If you really want to get rich quickly, I suggest you try entrepreneurship instead of investment and financial management. If any of the readers want to get rich quickly, what should they do?  My sincere suggestion is to choose the path of entrepreneurship. I have studied the wealth accumulation process of many rich people throughout history and found that there are many examples of getting rich quickly through entrepreneurship. Bill Gates, the richest man in the United States, dropped out of college in his freshman year to found Microsoft and became the richest man in the United States in just 20 years.</p>
<p>However, the probability of success in getting rich through entrepreneurship is extremely low.  According to statistics from the Taiwan Entrepreneurship Association, the success rate of a person&rsquo;s first business venture is only about 7%, and entrepreneurial success does not necessarily mean getting rich. In other words, for every successful entrepreneur we see, there are at least dozens of unknown failures behind them.  Moreover, the entrepreneurial process is very arduous. Working more than ten hours a day seems to be a prerequisite for successful entrepreneurs.</p>
<p>On the contrary, as long as the method is correct, investing money in the stock market and property market, and waiting patiently for decades, the probability of getting rich through investment and financial management is very high. It&rsquo;s hard not to get rich, and the process is relatively easy and enjoyable!  Which method you choose to get rich is up to you. I must emphasize again that there is a possibility of getting rich quickly through entrepreneurship, but it is absolutely impossible to get rich quickly through financial management.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Personal Investment Bible: Investment Iron Law III</title>
      <link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1731056005962/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1731056005962/</guid>
      <description>This article explores the importance of investing and managing finances, emphasizing the principle of &amp;#39;the sooner, the better.&amp;#39; It points out that procrastination is the primary cause of financial failure and encourages young people to start managing their finances early, rather than waiting until middle or old age.  The article uses the success stories of Warren Buffett and Jeffrey Koo Jr. to illustrate the power of long-term investment and compound interest. It also emphasizes that even with limited funds, one should start managing their finances and learn how to utilize high-return investment tools to grow their wealth.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[

<h2 class="relative group">Investment Iron Law 3: Invest Sooner Rather Than Later 
    <div id="investment-iron-law-3-invest-sooner-rather-than-later" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#investment-iron-law-3-invest-sooner-rather-than-later" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>Invest first, then wait for the opportunity,<br>
rather than waiting for the opportunity to invest.</p>
</blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">Procrastination: The Primary Cause of Financial Failure 
    <div id="procrastination-the-primary-cause-of-financial-failure" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#procrastination-the-primary-cause-of-financial-failure" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>The mentality of &ldquo;things will work out&rdquo; and a passive approach to financial management is the most common obstacle to personal finance. It&rsquo;s also the main reason why many people struggle to achieve financial independence by retirement.  Many individuals adopt a passive attitude towards financial planning, believing that things will naturally fall into place. As they age and witness the rapid growth of others&rsquo; wealth, they finally realize the importance of financial management.  However, by then, time is often limited, the power of compound interest cannot be fully utilized, and it becomes too late, even if they understand the principles of financial management.</p>
<p><strong>Financial Management Is Not Just for the Middle-Aged</strong></p>
<p>Many young people believe that financial management is something for middle-aged or wealthy individuals, and that it&rsquo;s not too late to worry about it in old age.  Here, I want to remind readers that the ability to build wealth through financial management has little correlation with the amount of money one possesses, but a significant correlation with the length of time invested.  People often reach middle age, facing retirement with some savings, and only then start thinking about preparing for their financial future. However, at this point, it&rsquo;s often too late. The reason is insufficient time to allow compound interest to work its magic.  Turning small amounts of money into substantial wealth requires at least two to three decades.  Recall the previous example: 10 years is not enough time to see significant growth.  A much longer period is needed for remarkable results.</p>
<p>Since we know that building wealth through investment requires investing in high-return assets and leveraging the long-term effects of compound interest, our approach, besides enriching our investment knowledge and skills, should involve immediate action.  Financial planning should start as early as possible, cultivating patience and a long-term perspective.</p>
<p>The reason for many financial failures today is the lack of knowledge about how to utilize funds effectively to achieve the goal of making money work for you and building wealth through investment. This is a flaw in our education system. Schools dedicate significant time to teaching students how to earn a living but fail to teach them how to manage their earnings.  College students exploring financial management through stock investment are often viewed as engaging in speculative and greedy behavior. In a future dominated by finance, the lack of proper financial knowledge not only erodes the dream of wealth accumulation but also harms the financial operations of businesses and the overall prosperity of society.</p>
<p>Don&rsquo;t delay your financial plan using the excuse of uncertain future price trends.  Who can predict when real estate or stock prices will rise?  Past price surges always lead to regret for those who missed out. There are no clear signs before prices start to rise, and no one will announce it with fanfare. <strong>For investments that are unpredictable in the short term but offer high expected returns in the long term, the safest strategy is to invest first and then wait for the opportunity, not the other way around.</strong></p>
<p><strong>Warren Buffett Started Investing at Age 11</strong></p>
<p><em>I believe every business school graduate should sign a contract pledging to make no more than 20 major decisions in their lifetime. If your career spans 40 years, that&rsquo;s one decision every two years.</em></p>
<p>Warren Buffett, ranked the second richest man in America by Forbes magazine in 1996, is widely regarded as the god of stock investment. He claims that more than half of his net worth is attributed to about ten investment decisions. He believes the key to investment is to buy stocks of good companies at good prices and hold them for the long term. As long as these companies continue to perform well, don&rsquo;t sell their stocks.</p>
<p>Buffett, with a net worth of $9 billion, amassed his fortune entirely from the stock market.  At 68, he held an MBA from Columbia University and was the son of a stockbroker-turned-congressman.  Buffett made his first investment at the age of 11, putting his and his sister&rsquo;s small savings into the stock market. Initially, he lost money, and his sister criticized him, but he insisted that it would take three to four years to see profits. His sister sold her shares, while he held on, ultimately proving his point.</p>
<p>At 20, while studying at Columbia University, Buffett immersed himself in finance books and insurance industry statistics while his peers focused on leisure activities.  Lacking capital and disliking borrowing, he often sold stocks prematurely to reinvest in others. Despite the limitations of his funds, his wealth continued to grow.</p>
<p>In 1954, he joined Professor Graham&rsquo;s investment firm. Two years later, he raised $100,000 from family and friends and established his own firm. After its assets increased thirtyfold, he dissolved the company in 1969, returned the partners&rsquo; money, and focused on his own investments.</p>
<p>He is a true stock market tycoon and has been America&rsquo;s richest man for years. Other wealthy Americans, like Bill Gates and Henry Lea Hillman, built their fortunes through businesses, while Buffett focused on stock investment. As long as the US economy continues to grow, his wealth will continue to increase.</p>
<p>Buffett&rsquo;s immense wealth, accumulated through nearly 60 years of investing, is a testament to the power of compound interest.  His early experiences with trial and error played a crucial role in honing his investment acumen.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Financial management is like farming.<br>
A bountiful harvest in the future depends on diligent sowing and watering today.</p>
</blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">Start Investing Today 
    <div id="start-investing-today" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#start-investing-today" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>If time is an indispensable element of financial management, the best strategy is to act now. Start managing your finances today!</p>
<p><strong>Don&rsquo;t Wait Until Your Hair Turns White</strong></p>
<p>The earlier you start investing, the sooner you&rsquo;ll achieve your financial goals and enjoy the fruits of your labor with your family. Furthermore, starting early maximizes the time for compound interest to work, requiring smaller initial investments and making financial management easier and more enjoyable.</p>
<p>Starting later requires significantly higher monthly investments to reach the same goals. The following table is based on these assumptions: an annual return of 15%, a target amount of 100 million yuan, and a retirement age of 65. It calculates the required monthly investment for different starting ages.</p>
<p><em>Monthly Investment Required to Become a Millionaire, by Starting Age</em></p>
<table>
  <thead>
      <tr>
          <th style="text-align: left">Starting Age</th>
          <th style="text-align: left">Monthly Investment (Yuan)</th>
      </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
      <tr>
          <td style="text-align: left">20</td>
          <td style="text-align: left">2324</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td style="text-align: left">25</td>
          <td style="text-align: left">4684</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td style="text-align: left">30</td>
          <td style="text-align: left">9458</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td style="text-align: left">35</td>
          <td style="text-align: left">19863</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td style="text-align: left">40</td>
          <td style="text-align: left">39163</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td style="text-align: left">45</td>
          <td style="text-align: left">81348</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td style="text-align: left">50</td>
          <td style="text-align: left">175143</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td style="text-align: left">55</td>
          <td style="text-align: left">410428</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td style="text-align: left">60</td>
          <td style="text-align: left">1235959</td>
      </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>
<p>The table clearly demonstrates that youth is a valuable asset in wealth accumulation. The younger you are, the better positioned you are to achieve the dream of building wealth from small investments.  Starting financial planning in old age requires monthly investments that are beyond the reach of most people. In short, start saving for retirement early. Don&rsquo;t wait until your hair turns white; time waits for no one.</p>
<p>Your future financial well-being depends on your actions today. Don&rsquo;t let hesitation hold you back. Follow the principles outlined in this book, invest your funds in the stock market, real estate, or other high-return investment vehicles, and over time, you too can become wealthy.</p>
<p><em>1. The earlier you start investing, the longer the time for compound interest to work, and the sooner you&rsquo;ll achieve your wealth goals.</em></p>
<p><em>2. Only young people can dream of building wealth from small investments.</em></p>
<p><em>3. The best time to start managing your finances is as early as possible.</em></p>
<p><strong>Jeffrey Koo Jr.&rsquo;s Path to Wealth</strong></p>
<p>Jeffrey Koo Jr., the eldest son of Jeffrey Koo Sr., chairman of Chinatrust Commercial Bank in Taiwan, and current Vice President of Chinatrust, is actively uniting the third generation of Taiwanese entrepreneurs. He organized a luncheon club primarily for the third generation of prominent Taiwanese business families to network and exchange information. To expand its influence, Koo Jr. has also strengthened the luncheon club&rsquo;s connections with Southeast Asian politicians and the second and third generations of overseas Chinese business families.</p>
<p>Koo Jr. is a representative figure among Taiwan&rsquo;s third-generation entrepreneurs and the heir apparent to his father. Many assume his wealthy background afforded him a comfortable financial situation. However, Koo Sr. instilled frugal habits in his children and didn&rsquo;t provide excessive allowances.  Koo Jr. had to find his own ways to become financially independent.</p>
<p>Sent to Japan for his education by his father, Koo Jr. returned to Taiwan for university after graduating high school with only his accumulated New Year&rsquo;s money, around NT$100,000, in his bank account. In early 1987, as the weighted stock price index climbed from 1,000 points, many people invested in the stock market. Koo Jr., then a junior in college, followed suit, investing all his savings.  His grandmother&rsquo;s daily routine of asking him to recite the stock market index further influenced him.  His frequent interactions with entrepreneurs from various industries provided him with business opportunities, enabling him to grow his NT$100,000 capital to NT$10 million during the bull market.</p>
<p>When the stock market crashed from over 10,000 points in 1990, he was already pursuing his Master&rsquo;s degree at the Wharton School of Business in the US. His father, hoping for him to join the family business sooner, disapproved of his overseas studies and threatened to withhold financial support. Koo Jr. confidently assured his father that he could support himself financially. He successfully completed his studies in the US and even bought his dream car, a Porsche, with his own money.  Koo Jr.&rsquo;s knack for investment and financial management from a young age made his dreams a reality. If you aspire to be wealthy, start now!</p>
<p><strong>Youth Is the Greatest Asset for Financial Success</strong></p>
<p>Successful people have a habit: they delay, but don&rsquo;t give up, the enjoyment of the fruits of their labor.</p>
<p>In Louis Cha&rsquo;s novel <em>The Book and the Sword</em>, the Qianlong Emperor tells his sworn brother, &ldquo;I don&rsquo;t envy anything about you except your youth.&rdquo; Even the emperor envied youth.</p>
<p>Similarly, from a financial perspective, youth is the most important asset. I often tell college students, &ldquo;Young people, your name is wealth!&rdquo;  The compound interest formula clearly shows that time is money, and youth is wealth.</p>
<p>The compound interest chart provides a clear roadmap for financial planning: focus on increasing income and saving during your youth and start investing early. Money saved during youth contributes significantly to wealth in old age.  NT$10,000 saved in your youth can grow to over NT$2.3 million in 30 years.  The same amount saved in old age will only grow to NT$60,000 in 10 years. Whether the statement &ldquo;Young people, your name is wealth&rdquo; becomes a reality depends on whether young people manage their finances wisely. Poor financial management, even with the advantage of youth, will not bring wealth.</p>
<p>The prevalent notion among young people today is that it&rsquo;s fine to indulge in enjoyment while young and worry about financial planning later. This is a misguided perspective. Many young people believe retirement is far off and their funds are limited, so there&rsquo;s no need to consider investment. They often miss the opportunity to start early.</p>
<p>In reality, starting financial planning in old age, even with some savings, is often too late due to limited time. The correct approach is: <strong>investing and managing finances is the job of young people, while managing wealth is the job of old age.</strong>  However, many young people prioritize immediate gratification, spending their money on sports cars, high-end audio systems, or travel, believing they can enjoy life now and worry about finances later.</p>
<p>If you understand the role of time in financial management, it&rsquo;s easy to see why such individuals are destined for mediocrity.  Countless examples in society demonstrate how prioritizing enjoyment in youth leads to poverty in old age. The key is their neglect of the importance of early financial planning. By the time they realize it, it&rsquo;s often too late.</p>
<p>As Taiwan&rsquo;s population ages and smaller family structures become the norm, future generations will rely on their own financial resources for living expenses. Therefore, the concept of starting financial planning in youth becomes increasingly critical.</p>
<p><strong>Youth Is the Best Time for Taking Risks</strong></p>
<p>Young people possess the most valuable asset in financial management - time. Youth is also the best time to take risks because family responsibilities are generally lighter. Young people should embrace a risk-taking mindset because the cost of failure is lower.  You can recover from setbacks more easily. Moreover, with limited funds, potential losses are smaller, providing valuable learning experiences.  Most importantly, young people have ample time for compound interest to work its magic.</p>
<p>Before 50, one shouldn&rsquo;t adopt an overly conservative approach to investment and financial management. The best time to learn about financial management is as early as possible. Sound financial judgment comes from experience, and experience comes from mistakes. Since developing good judgment requires making some mistakes along the way, why not gain this experience while you&rsquo;re young and the stakes are lower?  By the time you have more capital, you can apply your honed financial judgment effectively.</p>
<p>Young people should not just spend money but also understand the importance of saving. Start saving, and once you have a few thousand or tens of thousands of yuan, consider long-term, high-return investments, even if they carry some risk.</p>
<p>Some may feel they are no longer young and their current income is low, leaving no surplus for investment. Indeed, older individuals have less time to benefit from compound interest. However, don&rsquo;t be discouraged. Money can buy time, and you might still have opportunities to catch up.  By following sound financial principles, you can achieve unexpected gains. If you are past 50, help your children by sharing these fundamental wealth-building concepts so they don&rsquo;t miss out on the opportunity to build wealth early in their lives.  Instead of giving your next generation money, teach them the knowledge of making money work for them.</p>
<p><em>1. Youth is the greatest asset for building wealth through financial management. 2. Young people should embrace risk-taking because the cost of failure is lower.</em> <em>3. Invest when you&rsquo;re young to maximize the benefits of compound interest over time.</em></p>
<blockquote>
<p>Playing a good hand well is nothing special; playing a bad hand well is what deserves admiration.</p>
</blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">Don&rsquo;t Neglect Financial Management Due to Limited Funds 
    <div id="dont-neglect-financial-management-due-to-limited-funds" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#dont-neglect-financial-management-due-to-limited-funds" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>Some believe that financial management is exclusive to the wealthy and high-income families, requiring substantial capital to even consider it.  Indeed, financial management is about making money work for you. It&rsquo;s not about turning stone into gold or creating something from nothing, so you need some initial capital. However, what many don&rsquo;t realize is that the most influential factors on future wealth, according to the compound interest formula, are the rate of return and the length of the investment period, not the current amount of capital or future contributions.</p>
<p><strong>Small Beginnings Can Lead to Great Fortunes</strong></p>
<p>With the right approach, even a small amount of money can generate significant wealth over time, as illustrated in previous examples.  Even someone with no initial capital, by investing 14,000 yuan annually, can become a millionaire in 40 years.  <strong>The principle of investment and financial management is this: understanding how to utilize high-return tools and the long-term effects of compound interest is more important than the amount of money invested.</strong></p>
<p>A common misconception is that financial planning is only necessary after accumulating a large sum of money. In reality, the key factors influencing future wealth are the rate of return and the length of investment period, not the amount of capital.  The key to successful financial management lies in maximizing returns and holding investments for the long term.  While having more capital can accelerate wealth accumulation, it&rsquo;s not the decisive factor.</p>
<p>Perhaps you&rsquo;ve considered investing but dismissed the idea due to limited funds. By doing so, you&rsquo;ve missed a valuable opportunity to enhance your investment skills.  The focus of investment should not be on &ldquo;how much money is earned&rdquo; but on &ldquo;the rate of return&rdquo; at which money is earned.  For example, earning 5,000 yuan on a principal of 100,000 yuan represents a 5% return, which is a poor investment. Earning 2,000 yuan on a principal of 10,000 yuan represents a 20% return, which is a good investment.  Over time, the latter will significantly outperform the former.  Therefore, the earlier you learn financial management, the better. It allows limited funds to leverage the power of compound interest and create substantial wealth.</p>
<p><strong>Those with Less Should Strive Harder</strong></p>
<p>Some may question how to invest with only a few thousand or tens of thousands of yuan. In today&rsquo;s developed financial markets, investment units are highly divisible. Around 10,000 yuan can buy a lower-priced stock, and a few thousand yuan can be invested in mutual funds.  Real estate is also moving towards securitization. In short, there will be more investment options for smaller amounts in the future.  Therefore, any idle funds not needed in the short term, even a few thousand yuan, should be invested.</p>
<p>Are people truly too poor to manage small amounts of money?  During the Chang Hwa Credit Cooperative bank run, many ordinary people withdrew hundreds of thousands of yuan.  Statistics also show that the average bank deposit is 600,000 yuan, which is more than enough for investment purposes.</p>
<p>Even those with no current savings or expecting limited future income shouldn&rsquo;t underestimate themselves and give up on financial planning. While wealthy or high-income individuals have a head start, those with fewer assets or lower incomes should understand the principles of financial management and leverage it to compensate for their financial disadvantages, ultimately improving their lifetime financial situation.</p>
<p>Moreover, individuals from humble beginnings and with modest incomes can achieve a greater sense of accomplishment by building wealth through diligent financial management.  As the saying goes, &ldquo;<strong>There&rsquo;s nothing remarkable about playing a good hand well; it&rsquo;s playing a bad hand well that deserves admiration.</strong>&rdquo; If you truly have no money, find ways to increase income and reduce expenses, save some money, and then start managing your finances. Remember, even a small amount of money is enough to begin. While the path to wealth may be longer and more challenging with limited initial funds, the goal is still achievable, and the journey itself is valuable.</p>
<p><em>1. Investment and financial management are not exclusive to the wealthy or high-income earners.</em></p>
<p><em>2. Those with limited assets or low incomes should leverage financial management to catch up.</em></p>
<p><em>3. The amount of money you have when you start doesn&rsquo;t matter. Less money might even be better, allowing you to experiment with smaller investments initially and gradually increase your investment as you become more comfortable with risk.</em></p>
<p><em>4. Leverage other people&rsquo;s money to accelerate wealth building.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Personal Investment Bible: Investment Iron Law I</title>
      <link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1731056005960/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1731056005960/</guid>
      <description>This article criticizes the traditional financial concept of “saving money in the bank”.  It points out that under inflation, low bank deposit interest rates struggle to withstand erosion from inflation, effectively resulting in “the more you save, the less you have”. This viewpoint is supported by examples from biblical stories, savings rate data, and the Nobel Prize Foundation&amp;#39;s case, encouraging readers to invest their funds in long-term, high-return investment tools like stocks and real estate to achieve wealth appreciation.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[

<h2 class="relative group">Investment Iron Law I: Don&rsquo;t Keep Your Money in the Bank 
    <div id="investment-iron-law-i-dont-keep-your-money-in-the-bank" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#investment-iron-law-i-dont-keep-your-money-in-the-bank" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>The vast majority of people who fail at financial management don&rsquo;t do so because they don&rsquo;t earn enough,
but because they put their assets in the wrong place.
Have you ever heard of anyone getting rich from bank savings?</p>
</blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">Saving Equals Wasting Resources 
    <div id="saving-equals-wasting-resources" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#saving-equals-wasting-resources" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>There&rsquo;s a parable in the Bible about financial stewardship. A landowner entrusted his property to three servants. He gave the first servant five units of money, the second two, and the third one. He told them to cherish and manage their wealth wisely, and he would return in a year to see how they had fared.</p>
<p><strong>Wasting Time and Money</strong></p>
<p>The first servant invested his money; the second bought raw materials and produced goods to sell; the third, for safety, buried his money under a tree. A year later, the landowner returned.  The first two servants had doubled their wealth, pleasing the landowner.  Only the third servant&rsquo;s money remained unchanged. He explained, &ldquo;Fearing loss through mismanagement, I kept the money safe. Today, I return it untouched.&rdquo;</p>
<p>The landowner was furious.  &ldquo;You lazy servant!&rdquo; he scolded. &ldquo;You didn&rsquo;t even try to utilize your wealth!&rdquo;  Wealth not utilized is wasted money and wasted potential. The third servant was rebuked not for misusing the money, nor for losing it through failed investments, but for keeping it &ldquo;safe&rdquo; and unproductive.</p>
<p>Keeping money in the bank is the most common approach to personal finance today, and also the biggest mistake people make.  Therefore, the first and most important financial rule this book offers is: <em>Don&rsquo;t keep your money in the bank.</em>  &ldquo;Bank&rdquo; here refers to post offices, commercial banks, and any other financial institution where money can be deposited.</p>
<p>Many believe that earning interest in a bank, benefiting from compound interest, constitutes sound financial planning. In reality, with inflation, the real rate of return is close to zero, meaning no real financial gain. Therefore, leaving money in the bank is equivalent to no financial management at all.</p>
<p>It&rsquo;s impossible to predict how much wealth each person will accumulate through financial management. The only certainty is that getting rich solely through bank savings is incredibly difficult.  Ask yourself, &ldquo;Have you ever heard of anyone getting rich purely from bank deposits?&rdquo;  Those who keep all their savings in the bank often find themselves not only failing to become wealthy in their old age but also struggling to maintain financial independence. Such stories are common.  Those who choose bank deposits as their primary financial management method do so primarily for safety. However, readers must understand:  <strong>&ldquo;Money in the bank is safest in the short term, but the most dangerous form of financial management in the long term.&rdquo;</strong></p>
<p><strong>Blind Spots in Personal Finance</strong></p>
<p><em>Most people manage their finances by keeping their money in the bank, so most people are not wealthy.</em></p>
<p>If accumulating immense wealth were as easy as the examples suggest, then most people over 65 today would be millionaires. However, this is far from reality.  Millionaires over 65 are few and far between, with many senior citizens facing financial hardship, relying on continued work or support from their children to make ends meet.</p>
<p>Surveys on the elderly in Taiwan reveal increasingly serious financial challenges for senior citizens.  Among approximately 1.48 million people aged 65 and above, about 13% rely on financial assistance from family and friends or social welfare.  This demonstrates a serious problem with most people&rsquo;s financial concepts and investment methods. How else could they reach old age not only without wealth but without even basic financial independence?</p>
<p>Taiwan&rsquo;s savings rate has historically been above 30%, currently hovering between 20% and 30%, consistently ranking among the highest globally. This indicates excellent performance in saving and budgeting. Consequently, we can deduce that flawed financial management is the primary reason for the lack of financial independence among ordinary people. To understand where they go wrong, we must first observe how they handle their assets. In various lectures, I often ask the audience, &ldquo;How are your assets stored?&rdquo;  The majority answer: &ldquo;In the bank.&rdquo;</p>
<p><strong>Prioritizing Security over Investment</strong></p>
<p>Surveys on Taiwanese household investment preferences reveal that the top three investment choices are demand deposits (72%), rotating savings and credit associations (53%), and time deposits (36%). Clearly, most people lean towards traditional financial methods.  Furthermore, when asked, &ldquo;If you had 10 million Taiwan dollars in savings, how would you use it?&rdquo;, about 41% of surveyed households said they would deposit it in a financial institution to earn interest. This illustrates the widespread preference for bank savings.</p>
<p>Indeed, people have high savings rates and a strong preference for depositing money in financial institutions to earn interest.  In early 1996, total deposits in Taiwanese financial institutions reached 12.6 trillion Taiwan dollars.  With a population of 21 million, this translates to an average deposit of 600,000 Taiwan dollars per person, regardless of age.  For an average family of four, this amounts to 2.4 million Taiwan dollars.  This demonstrates a strong inclination towards bank savings. However, this traditional and conservative approach is the primary reason why most people fail to achieve wealth through investment.</p>
<p>This phenomenon reveals an over-reliance on traditional bank deposits for financial management. People prioritize safety and convenience over the rate of return. However, focusing solely on earning and saving money, then depositing it in a bank, is often the first step towards financial mismanagement.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Keeping money in the bank is like having no financial plan at all.</p>
</blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">Deposit Interest Rates Lack True Compound Interest Benefits 
    <div id="deposit-interest-rates-lack-true-compound-interest-benefits" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#deposit-interest-rates-lack-true-compound-interest-benefits" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>What&rsquo;s wrong with bank deposits? The problem lies in the low interest rates (return on investment), making them unsuitable for long-term investment tools.</p>
<p>How much interest can bank deposits earn?  The salaries of average office workers are usually directly deposited into demand deposit accounts (current interest rates around 2%-4%). A portion serves as temporary funds or covers daily expenses, while the remainder is transferred to time deposits (current interest rates around 5%-8%) for investment purposes. Thus, the average interest rate earned on bank deposits is about 5%.</p>
<p><strong>5% Interest is Hardly a Path to Wealth</strong></p>
<p>Most people have a basic understanding of compound interest, believing that interest earned on bank deposits, accumulating over time, can create substantial wealth. This misconception arises from a superficial understanding of compounding.  The vast differences in final returns resulting from different rates of return on the same principal over the same period often come as a surprise.</p>
<p>Let&rsquo;s illustrate with an example. Suppose someone saves 14,000 Taiwan dollars annually at the end of each year for 40 years, depositing everything into a bank account with an average interest rate of 5%. How much will they accumulate after 40 years? Before answering, recall the similar example from the previous section, but with the money in a bank instead of invested in stocks or real estate with an average annual return of 20%.</p>
<p>You might guess 25 million, 10 million, or even a conservative 5 million Taiwan dollars.  The correct answer, however, is only 1.69 million.  This can be calculated using the future value of an annuity formula:</p>
<p><math xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" display="block"><mtable displaystyle="true" columnalign="right center left" columnspacing="0 thickmathspace" rowspacing="3pt"><mtr><mtd><mn>14,000</mn><mo>×</mo><mfrac><mrow><msup><mrow><mo stretchy="false">(</mo><mn>1</mn><mo>+</mo><mn>0.05</mn><mo stretchy="false">)</mo></mrow><mrow><mn>40</mn></mrow></msup><mo>−</mo><mn>1</mn></mrow><mn>0.05</mn></mfrac></mtd><mtd><mi></mi><mo>=</mo></mtd><mtd><mn>1,690,000</mn></mtd></mtr><mtr><mtd><mn>14,000</mn><mo>×</mo><mfrac><mrow><msup><mrow><mo stretchy="false">(</mo><mn>1</mn><mo>+</mo><mn>0.20</mn><mo stretchy="false">)</mo></mrow><mrow><mn>40</mn></mrow></msup><mo>−</mo><mn>1</mn></mrow><mn>0.20</mn></mfrac></mtd><mtd><mi></mi><mo>=</mo></mtd><mtd><mn>102,810,000</mn></mtd></mtr></mtable></math></p>
<p>Let&rsquo;s compare this with the 20% return scenario.  The only difference between the two formulas is the rate of return (5% vs. 20%). A 20% return over 40 years yields 102.81 million Taiwan dollars, while a 5% return over the same period yields only 1.69 million, less than a fraction of the former. The difference is over 60 times! This illustrates the power of compound interest.  Many assume they benefit from compound interest in a bank, but at a 5% return, even with compounding over a long period, the wealth creation effect is very limited.</p>
<p>This example demonstrates that one of the keys to successful financial management is the rate of return. The key is not just whether your assets are invested, but <em>where</em> they are invested and what the rate of return is.</p>
<ul>
<li>
<ol>
<li>The key to financial management lies in how your assets are allocated. The rate of return has a decisive impact on your future wealth.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol start="2">
<li>While bank savings provide interest income and the benefit of compounding,  you&rsquo;ll find that as you age, bank deposits contribute little to overall wealth growth.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol start="3">
<li>The first step towards building wealth through investment is to allocate assets to investments with high long-term rates of return.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol start="4">
<li>&ldquo;Financial Management&rdquo; is a significant factor contributing to wealth disparity in society.</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>Inflation makes money worth less and less.</p>
</blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">The Invisible Killer of Currency Value: Inflation 
    <div id="the-invisible-killer-of-currency-value-inflation" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#the-invisible-killer-of-currency-value-inflation" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>Forty years ago, a millionaire was truly wealthy.  Today, a millionaire might struggle to afford a house. Why?  Inflation.  Every investor must consider the impact of inflation.</p>
<p><em>Inflation reduces the purchasing power of money and lowers the real rate of return, diminishing the effect of wealth accumulation.</em></p>
<p>Over the past 30 years, the average annual inflation rate in Taiwan has been around 5%. What about the future?  Inflation and economic growth are closely linked. As Taiwan&rsquo;s economy continues to grow, inflation is expected to remain around 5% annually.</p>
<p>Inflation means continuously rising prices, which translates to decreasing purchasing power.  If you keep your money in a demand deposit account earning 4% interest with a 5% inflation rate, what happens?  Your purchasing power decreases.  The longer your money sits in a savings account, the less it&rsquo;s worth.  What used to cost 10 Taiwan dollars for a newspaper now costs 15. Your 10 dollars can now only buy two-thirds of a newspaper. With inflation, money in the bank shrinks like wool submerged in water.</p>
<p><strong>Saving Alone Won&rsquo;t Make You Rich, Not Even in Two Lifetimes</strong></p>
<p>With 5% inflation and a nominal interest rate of around 5% on bank deposits, your real rate of return is zero. In this scenario, the effect of compound interest is nullified.  Wealth accumulation relies solely on painstaking saving. Imagine someone saves 500,000 Taiwan dollars a year. How long would it take to become a billionaire?  200 years!</p>
<p>Saving 500,000 Taiwan dollars a year is difficult; living for 200 years is even harder!  Therefore, even with diligent saving and budgeting, if all the money is kept in the bank, this person won&rsquo;t become wealthy in this lifetime, and worse, not even in the next! The average lifespan is around 75 years, meaning two lifetimes total only 150 years.  It would take a third lifetime for someone relying solely on bank savings to potentially reach billionaire status.  If a family maintains the financial strategy of &ldquo;frugality and bank savings,&rdquo; it would take at least 200 years, or about seven generations, for them to potentially become wealthy.  Conversely, with proper financial management, wealth can be achieved in 40 years (half a lifetime).</p>
<p><strong>Money in the Bank Should Be Spent Sooner Rather Than Later</strong></p>
<p>I remember 30 years ago, when I was in second or third grade, a popsicle cost 20 cents, and a red bean ice cream cost 50 cents.  My parents gave me 50 cents each day for allowance, which I invariably spent on red bean ice cream after school. My parents constantly encouraged me to save, so my father opened a bank account for me. If I had been obedient and developed good saving habits from a young age, saving those 50 cents daily and earning 8% interest, it would have grown tenfold over 30 years, to 5 Taiwan dollars.  However, a red bean ice cream now costs 15 Taiwan dollars. Those 5 dollars can only buy one-third of a red bean ice cream. More importantly, for a小学生 30 years ago, a red bean ice cream was precious.  Even a dozen red bean ice creams today couldn&rsquo;t compare to the value of one back then. Had I followed my parents&rsquo; financial advice and kept my money in the bank, I would regret it now.</p>
<p>Therefore, if you&rsquo;re going to keep money in the bank, my sincere advice is: &ldquo;Spend it sooner rather than later!&rdquo; This might sound shocking, but there&rsquo;s logic to it.  From an economic perspective, money has more value and higher utility when used sooner. We save money in the bank, delaying gratification for the sake of greater enjoyment in the future.  However, with inflation, money left in the bank often leads to <em>less</em> enjoyment.</p>
<p><strong>The Value of Money Decreases with Age</strong></p>
<p>My wife and her friends developed a financial philosophy: &ldquo;Money is most valuable when spent while young.&rdquo; This makes economic sense.  Their reasoning: &ldquo;When you&rsquo;re old, delicacies might harm your health, traveling becomes difficult, and most importantly, wearing beautiful clothes attracts unwanted attention and ridicule.&rdquo;</p>
<p>Thus, everyone managing their finances must be mindful of the dual pressures of inflation and the diminishing value of money with age. Bank deposit interest rates cannot compensate for these losses. In other words, <strong>money in the bank, while nominally increasing, actually decreases in value.</strong></p>
<p>Of course, I&rsquo;m not encouraging you to spend all your savings immediately.  Rather, I&rsquo;m highlighting that if you keep money in the bank, you must consider the declining purchasing power due to inflation and the reduced economic benefit as you age.  The fundamental solution is to withdraw your money from the bank and invest it in instruments with higher returns than bank deposit rates. <strong>Therefore, the best way to combat inflation is: Don&rsquo;t keep your money in the bank. Invest in long-term, high-return assets like stocks and real estate.</strong></p>
<p>Because inflation decreases real returns and hinders wealth accumulation, even saving 14,000 Taiwan dollars annually and investing in stocks or real estate for 40 years to become a billionaire won&rsquo;t carry the same weight as being a billionaire today.  Therefore, under inflation, consider using the <em>real</em> rate of return. If the return on investment is 20% and inflation is 5%, the real return is 15%.  So how much should you save annually, investing in stocks or real estate with a nominal return of around 20% (real return of 15%), to become a billionaire in 40 years?  The answer is 57,000 Taiwan dollars per year.</p>
<p><math xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" display="block"><mn>57,000</mn><mo>×</mo><mfrac><mrow><msup><mrow><mo stretchy="false">(</mo><mn>1</mn><mo>+</mo><mn>0.15</mn><mo stretchy="false">)</mo></mrow><mrow><mn>40</mn></mrow></msup><mo>−</mo><mn>1</mn></mrow><mn>0.15</mn></mfrac><mo>=</mo><mn>101,410,000</mn><mspace linebreak="newline"></mspace></math></p>
<blockquote>
<p>A small step today makes a world of difference tomorrow.</p>
</blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">The Path to Wealth of Chang Pin-san, Former Chairman of Chang Hwa Bank 
    <div id="the-path-to-wealth-of-chang-pin-san-former-chairman-of-chang-hwa-bank" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#the-path-to-wealth-of-chang-pin-san-former-chairman-of-chang-hwa-bank" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>Chang Po-hsin, the current standing director of Chang Hwa Bank, with assets exceeding tens of billions, inherited and expanded upon the fortune of his father, Chang Pin-san, the former chairman of Chang Hwa Bank, earning him a place among Taiwan&rsquo;s wealthiest individuals.</p>
<p><strong>Trading Bank Deposits for Stock Dividends</strong></p>
<p>Forty years ago, both Chang Pin-san and my father were from Nantun District, Taichung City.  They were not only fellow townsmen but also colleagues. Back then, Chang Pin-san was just a junior manager at Chang Hwa Bank, without much wealth.  However, he borrowed money to buy Chang Hwa Bank shares from colleagues who wanted to sell them. At the time, stock dividends were far lower than bank interest. Despite this, Chang Pin-san persisted in borrowing money to acquire shares, holding onto them for the long term.  Other colleagues deposited the proceeds from their stock sales into banks. Years later, Chang Pin-san, owning the most shares, became the largest shareholder and eventually the chairman of Chang Hwa Bank, laying the foundation for his immense wealth.</p>
<p>Chang Pin-san was also friends with Lien Chen-tung, father of Lien Chan, and encouraged him to buy Chang Hwa Bank shares. The Lien family&rsquo;s fortune also originated from those hundreds of Chang Hwa Bank shares.</p>
<p>It&rsquo;s hard to believe that the path to wealth could be so simple: borrow money to buy a few Chang Hwa Bank shares, invest in some real estate, hold them long-term, and essentially forget about them.  Decades later, great wealth is attained. Those who sold their shares and deposited the money in banks are still wondering how others became rich. Some might attribute this to luck, but financial management is not about luck.  It&rsquo;s about the method chosen and the investment tools selected.  Therefore, if you don&rsquo;t want to be poor, don&rsquo;t keep your money in the bank.</p>
<p><strong>Bank Savings Shouldn&rsquo;t Exceed Living Expenses</strong></p>
<p>Someone once jokingly asked me, &ldquo;You&rsquo;re telling us not to keep money in the bank.  Are we supposed to pay with stocks or real estate certificates at the supermarket or restaurant?&rdquo; Of course not!  Advising against keeping money in the bank doesn&rsquo;t mean you can&rsquo;t have any money in the bank at all. Bank deposits offer advantages: security and convenience. They are ideal for storing funds needed for daily expenses. However, you can&rsquo;t have your cake and eat it too.  Convenience comes at the cost of high returns.</p>
<p>The wise approach is to clearly divide funds into two categories: daily expenses and investments.  Keep enough for daily needs in the bank, enjoying the security and convenience it offers. Invest the rest in higher-return assets like stocks and real estate.</p>
<p>In my opinion, keeping the equivalent of two months&rsquo; living expenses in the bank is sufficient for an individual or family. Most individuals and families receive regular income, which is deposited into their bank accounts. Therefore, one month&rsquo;s expenses for immediate use and another month&rsquo;s worth as a safety net should be ample.  The remaining funds should be invested in higher-return assets like stocks and real estate.  In other words, if your monthly expenses average 50,000 Taiwan dollars, and your bank balance consistently exceeds 100,000, you are not managing your finances effectively.  Actively seek suitable investment opportunities to make your surplus funds work for you.</p>
<p><strong>The &ldquo;Two Big, One Small&rdquo; Approach to Flexible Fund Management</strong></p>
<p>Some believe in maintaining substantial emergency funds. However, even if unforeseen circumstances drain your bank savings, there&rsquo;s no need to panic. The high-return investments mentioned earlier—stocks and real estate—are not as illiquid as some might think.  Listed stocks in Taiwan&rsquo;s active stock market can be sold almost any day of the year (excluding holidays), providing quick access to cash within a few days.  Reluctant to sell? Stocks can also be used as collateral for loans.</p>
<p>Real estate is less liquid than stocks, but many Taiwanese banks now offer &ldquo;revolving mortgage loans,&rdquo; allowing property owners to convert fixed assets into liquid assets. These loans involve mortgaging a property to secure a credit line of up to 70%-75% of the property&rsquo;s value. Borrowers can draw and repay funds as needed, with interest accruing only on the outstanding balance. For example, a 10 million Taiwan dollar property could secure a 7.5 million credit line.  Borrowing 5 million leaves 2.5 million available without interest charges, with interest accruing only on the 5 million borrowed.  Any surplus funds can be used to repay the loan, reducing interest costs.</p>
<p>Many financial experts recommend a &ldquo;three-part&rdquo; approach, dividing assets equally among bank savings, real estate, and more speculative investments. I propose a &ldquo;two big, one small&rdquo; approach: allocate most of your assets to stocks and real estate, keeping a small portion in a bank for daily expenses.  This isn&rsquo;t my invention. In fact, this is the portfolio strategy employed by many who have achieved wealth through investments.</p>
<ul>
<li>
<ol>
<li>Keeping money in the bank is the riskiest form of financial management.  Inflation erodes returns, leaving real interest rates near zero.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol start="2">
<li>Banks offer convenience, not high returns.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol start="3">
<li>Keep only two months&rsquo; worth of living expenses in the bank.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol start="4">
<li>Trying to get rich with money in the bank is like trying to win a baseball game without swinging the bat.</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ul>
<p>If all this hasn&rsquo;t convinced you to reconsider keeping most of your money in a financial institution, perhaps the story of the Nobel Prize Foundation&rsquo;s success might change your mind.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Change your asset management perspective, change your financial destiny.</p>
</blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">Lessons from the Nobel Prize Foundation 
    <div id="lessons-from-the-nobel-prize-foundation" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#lessons-from-the-nobel-prize-foundation" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>Every October, the Nobel Committee announces the Nobel laureates. The Nobel Prize attracts global attention not only for representing the highest academic honor but also because each laureate receives a substantial prize of 1 million US dollars.</p>
<p><strong>The Folly of Depleting Capital</strong></p>
<p>The Nobel Foundation awards several prizes annually, disbursing millions of dollars. This raises the question: How large is the Nobel fund to sustain such substantial payouts? The Nobel Foundation&rsquo;s success, besides the substantial initial donation by Alfred Nobel over a century ago, is largely attributed to its shrewd financial management.</p>
<p>Established in 1896 with a 9.8 million US dollar donation from Nobel, the foundation&rsquo;s purpose is to fund the prizes.  Flawless fund management was paramount.  Initially, its charter stipulated that investments be restricted to safe, fixed-income instruments like bank deposits and government bonds, explicitly excluding stocks and real estate to avoid market risks.</p>
<p>This capital preservation approach, prioritizing safety over returns, seemed prudent, preventing losses. However, sacrificing returns had consequences.  After 50 years of prize payouts and operating expenses, low returns depleted two-thirds of the Nobel fund, leaving only a little over 3 million US dollars by 1953.</p>
<p><strong>From 3 Million to 270 Million: The Secret</strong></p>
<p>Facing depletion, the Nobel Foundation&rsquo;s board recognized the importance of investment returns. In 1953, they made a groundbreaking change, amending the charter to shift from bank deposits and bonds to primarily stocks and real estate.  This shift in investment philosophy transformed the foundation&rsquo;s fate. Over the next 40 years, despite continued prize payouts and operating costs, the foundation not only recovered all previous losses but also grew its assets to 270 million US dollars by 1993.</p>
<p><em>Nobel Prize Foundation Asset Growth and Decline</em></p>
<table>
  <thead>
      <tr>
          <th style="text-align: left">Year</th>
          <th style="text-align: left">Total Assets (Million USD)</th>
          <th style="text-align: left">Remarks</th>
      </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
      <tr>
          <td style="text-align: left">1896</td>
          <td style="text-align: left">9.8</td>
          <td style="text-align: left">Foundation Established</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td style="text-align: left">1953</td>
          <td style="text-align: left">3.3</td>
          <td style="text-align: left">Investment Charter Amended</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td style="text-align: left">1993</td>
          <td style="text-align: left">270</td>
          <td style="text-align: left"></td>
      </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>
<p>Had the Nobel Foundation not changed its approach 40 years ago, clinging to bank savings, it would have vanished, unable to fund the prizes.  Perhaps other wealthy individuals would have established new foundations with larger prizes, replacing the Nobel Prize.</p>
<p>The Nobel Foundation&rsquo;s history underscores the importance of financial management.  Even a substantial initial fund, if mismanaged, can be depleted. Conversely, even with significant spending, skillful management can generate rapid growth.</p>
<p>I once heard of a Taiwanese hometown association that established a foundation with 100,000 Taiwan dollars 40 years ago to provide scholarships for children from their hometown.  Forty years later, the fund remains at 100,000 Taiwan dollars. While a significant sum back then, today it barely covers administrative costs, threatening the foundation&rsquo;s existence.  The problem? Neglecting financial management.</p>
<p>Learning from the Nobel Foundation, many US foundations, pension funds, university endowments, and even personal trusts have shifted from bank deposits and bonds to primarily stocks and real estate. In contrast, few Taiwanese foundations grasp this concept, and university endowments rarely address financial management seriously.  The fate of these foundations, if they don&rsquo;t adapt, is clear.</p>
<p>I often participate in corporate training programs, where I habitually ask companies about the size and investment strategy of their employee welfare funds.  The answers are usually similar: small funds, mostly in bank deposits, rarely exceeding a few hundred thousand or a million Taiwan dollars. However, in 1990, during my time at China Development Corporation, the employee welfare fund exceeded 200 million Taiwan dollars. Why?  Because it was primarily invested in China Development Corporation&rsquo;s own stock.</p>
<ul>
<li>
<ol>
<li>The Nobel Foundation&rsquo;s course correction 40 years ago secured its status today.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol start="2">
<li>Prioritizing security above all else leads to asset depletion.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol start="3">
<li>The growth and decline of wealth for individuals, families, businesses, or other entities depends on their investment strategy.</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ul>
<p>Will your hard-earned wealth shrink like the early Nobel fund, or grow like the later one? The key lies in <em>how</em> you invest. If, like many, you keep most of your money in the bank, it&rsquo;s not too late to change. The Nobel Foundation&rsquo;s story shows how a change in investment philosophy can transform everything.  Should you reconsider your financial habits and prioritize investments in stocks and real estate? Let the Nobel Foundation inspire your financial thinking. A single change in mindset can lead to immense wealth decades from now!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
