<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Investment Philosophy on QQQ Investor</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/tags/investment-philosophy/</link><description>Recent content in Investment Philosophy on QQQ Investor</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jomonylw.github.io/en/tags/investment-philosophy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>00522 The Outside World is Noise, Market Volatility is a Blessing: Understanding the Essence of Investing through Asset Allocation and Life Choices</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1752398791344/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1752398791344/</guid><description>In this session, Teacher James emphasizes the core investment strategy of &amp;#39;buy, hold, don&amp;#39;t sell&amp;#39; and delves deep into investment psychology and the importance of asset allocation. He specifically introduces and elaborates on the concept of an &amp;#39;anti-fragile&amp;#39; investment portfolio, explains the strategic role of cash in investing, analyzes the characteristics and risks of leveraged ETFs, and ultimately connects investment success with inner peace and life&amp;#39;s happiness.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<lite-youtube videoid="dVSU1t0Zpnk" playlabel="dVSU1t0Zpnk" params=""></lite-youtube>



<h2 class="relative group">I. Theme of the Session 
    <div id="i-theme-of-the-session" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-theme-of-the-session" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>The core of this class is to establish a simple yet firm long-term investment philosophy. Teacher James emphasizes that investors should ignore market noise and short-term fluctuations, adhering to a strategy of &ldquo;buy, hold, and never sell.&rdquo; Successful investing requires not only the right asset allocation (especially using cash to build an &ldquo;anti-fragile&rdquo; portfolio) but also a strong psychological constitution, including steadfastness, patience, and faith, to ultimately achieve financial freedom and inner peace.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">II. Briefing Content 
    <div id="ii-briefing-content" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii-briefing-content" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">The Core Concept of Investing: Simplicity is Key 
    <div id="the-core-concept-of-investing-simplicity-is-key" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#the-core-concept-of-investing-simplicity-is-key" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Ignore Market Noise</strong>: Teacher James points out that in his 40 years of investing, almost all financial and political news and market analysis have been &ldquo;demons and monsters,&rdquo; useless for long-term investing. He quotes a student&rsquo;s message, emphasizing that social opinions and market volatility are irrelevant to long-term investors; enjoying the tranquility of the present is far more important than focusing on fleeting issues.</li>
<li><strong>The Best Strategy: Buy, Hold, Don&rsquo;t Sell</strong>: This is the core principle throughout. The art of investing lies not in complex market timing or stock picking, but in persistently holding high-quality assets for a lifetime, or even for generations.</li>
<li><strong>Investing Should Be Easy and Simple</strong>: The teacher uses an analogy: investing should only take 5-10 minutes a year and should not be a burden on one&rsquo;s life. If you make investing complicated, it&rsquo;s like adding a lot of chili oil to a simple clear noodle soup, which ruins the original flavor. Investors should spend more time enjoying life and being with their families.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Asset Allocation and Risk Management 
    <div id="asset-allocation-and-risk-management" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#asset-allocation-and-risk-management" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>The &ldquo;Spicy Beef Noodle&rdquo; Theory</strong>: When asked about asset allocation ratios, the teacher uses a vivid example. He believes that asking someone else how to allocate your assets is like asking them how much chili to add to your beef noodles because everyone&rsquo;s risk tolerance (how much spice they can handle) is different.
<ul>
<li><strong>Advice for Beginners</strong>: For novices or those unsure of their risk tolerance, the teacher suggests starting with &ldquo;clear-broth beef noodles&rdquo; (a conservative allocation), for example, 50% of assets in the market and 50% in cash.</li>
<li><strong>Strategy for Large Sums of Capital</strong>: It is recommended to divide it into three parts: buy 1/3 immediately, buy 1/3 in batches, and keep 1/3 as cash.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Three Elements of Investment Psychology: Steadfastness, Patience, Faith</strong>: Once you have bought in, the next step is to cultivate a strong psychological mindset.
<ul>
<li><strong>Steadfastness</strong>: Not being affected by market fluctuations.</li>
<li><strong>Patience</strong>: Enduring painful periods of market decline is a necessary psychological quality.</li>
<li><strong>Faith</strong>: Believing in the long-term upward trend of the market is the path to reaching the highest realm of investing.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Building an &ldquo;Anti-fragile&rdquo; Investment Portfolio 
    <div id="building-an-anti-fragile-investment-portfolio" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#building-an-anti-fragile-investment-portfolio" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Cash and Market Volatility are &ldquo;Boosters&rdquo; for Assets</strong>: The teacher uses the concept of a &ldquo;boost converter&rdquo; in electronic circuits as an analogy. Market volatility is like an &ldquo;oscillator,&rdquo; and cash is like the &ldquo;electric current.&rdquo; Investing cash during a market downturn (oscillation) can effectively push asset values to new highs.</li>
<li><strong>Fragile vs. Anti-fragile</strong>:
<ul>
<li><strong>Fragile Investment</strong>: For example, investing 100% in QQQ. If the market goes to zero, your assets go to zero. This is like a flower in a greenhouse that cannot withstand a storm.</li>
<li><strong>Anti-fragile Investment</strong>: For example, holding an index fund while keeping 30% in cash. Even if the market goes to zero, you still have 30% of your assets. This is like wildflowers everywhere, tenacious and able to survive and even thrive in harsh environments.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>An Anti-fragile Life</strong>: This concept applies not only to investing but also to life. For example, an employee who serves only one company is fragile and can be laid off at any time; whereas an Uber driver is anti-fragile, earning income as long as they drive. In the AI era, a pure software engineer becomes fragile, while experts in various industries who know how to use AI become anti-fragile.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Characteristics and Risks of Leveraged ETFs (TQQQ) 
    <div id="characteristics-and-risks-of-leveraged-etfs-tqqq" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#characteristics-and-risks-of-leveraged-etfs-tqqq" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Mathematical Explanation of Volatility Decay</strong>: The teacher reveals the characteristic of volatility decay in leveraged ETFs through calculation.
<ul>
<li><strong>Example</strong>: Assume QQQ falls for 45 consecutive days (-1% each day) and then rises for 46 consecutive days (+1% each day), it will eventually hit a new high.</li>
<li><strong>Comparison</strong>: Under the same conditions, if TQQQ falls for 45 consecutive days (-3% each day) and then rises for 46 consecutive days (+3% each day), its final price will still be below the initial starting point, unable to recover its losses.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Who is Not Suitable for Leveraged Funds</strong>: Investors who are afraid of downturns and cannot withstand huge volatility should stay away from leveraged funds.</li>
<li><strong>Correct Use of Leveraged Funds</strong>:
<ul>
<li><strong>Position Size Cannot Be Too Large</strong>: Investing a large sum of money into a high proportion of leveraged funds at once is very dangerous. In a long bear market, it could lead to assets going to zero with no chance of recovery.</li>
<li><strong>Suitable for Dollar-Cost Averaging</strong>: For investors with a continuous cash flow (like a monthly salary), making small, regular investments over decades is feasible.</li>
<li><strong>Risk Warning</strong>: For retirees, a high leverage position could send you back to the workforce; for those currently employed, it could postpone your retirement plans indefinitely.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Investment and Life Philosophy 
    <div id="investment-and-life-philosophy" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#investment-and-life-philosophy" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Live in the Present, Eliminate Worry</strong>: The teacher guides everyone to ponder a question: &ldquo;If tomorrow were the end of your life, could you depart with a smile?&rdquo; He believes that true happiness comes from &ldquo;dying without regrets.&rdquo; If you have regrets in life, you should remedy them now, not spend your days worrying.</li>
<li><strong>Happiness is a Human Right</strong>: Investing should be joyful. If it causes you pain, don&rsquo;t participate. The value of life is not in its length, but in its depth and brightness.</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">III. Q&amp;A Session 
    <div id="iii-qa-session" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii-qa-session" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Line 
    <div id="line" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#line" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: A new member who has just joined is still studying hard and has no questions or sharing for now.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Bruce 
    <div id="bruce" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#bruce" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing:
<ol>
<li>A new member from last week, he is very grateful to Teacher James for his quick email response, which solved his problem with the app&rsquo;s operation.</li>
<li>He combines his insights from reading with the teacher&rsquo;s philosophy to create daily reminders for his investment principles: have capital, an investment philosophy, discipline, patience, and luck, combined with the teacher&rsquo;s &ldquo;hear, know, understand, believe, execute, firmly believe.&rdquo;</li>
<li>He quotes a conversation between Warren Buffett and Bill Gates to emphasize the principle of &ldquo;getting rich slowly,&rdquo; believing that patience is the most difficult but most crucial part of investing.</li>
<li>He shares his past principles for selling individual stocks (the reason for buying disappears, the target price is reached, the company faces irreversible difficulties), but now he has found a better option (QQQ) and is liquidating his individual stocks.</li>
<li>Regarding real estate, he believes that a house is also a financial product and proposes a view: &ldquo;Houses aren&rsquo;t bought by people, they&rsquo;re bought by money,&rdquo; with its price driven by market liquidity. He thinks the reason real estate returns are sometimes very high is due to high leverage (e.g., 5x or even 10x). His family owns a jewelry store, and he suggests that high-net-worth individuals can allocate a small amount to gold as a hedge against extreme risks.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>Question: The &ldquo;Nine Scenarios&rdquo; PDF file he downloaded shows overlapping text and numbers on his phone. He asks if he can get the link again.
<ul>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo;s Reply: This is likely a display issue with his personal phone, as there is no problem with the link itself. He suggests trying to open it on a computer or asking family or friends for help.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Zhang Le 
    <div id="zhang-le" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#zhang-le" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: He found that in the Chinese market, the management fee for the Harvest Nasdaq ETF (159501) is 0.2% lower than the 513100 recommended by the teacher, believing it will make a difference in long-term returns.
<ul>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo;s Comment: The market is very efficient; this small fee difference is unlikely to bring extra profit.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question: How to change his parents&rsquo; investment mindset? He details the painful experience of his father suffering severe losses due to high-risk investments and being deceived by relatives. This has led his parents to be extremely risk-averse, preferring to deposit tens of millions of RMB in a bank for a fixed term (with an annual interest rate of only about 1.5%) and refusing to touch any funds. They even believe that real estate is the most secure asset. He feels confused and doesn&rsquo;t know if he should continue to persuade them.
<ul>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo;s Reply: Don&rsquo;t try to change them. Everyone&rsquo;s &ldquo;psychology of money&rdquo; is shaped by their life experiences. His parents&rsquo; views are &ldquo;correct&rdquo; in their world, a way to protect themselves from further harm. What you should do is manage your own money, invest your own funds, and become a big tree yourself. When you become very wealthy, your parents might see it, but changing them is not your responsibility. The most important thing is to let them live a peaceful and happy life.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Washington 
    <div id="washington" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#washington" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Strongly agrees with the teacher&rsquo;s response to Zhang Le. Changing others, especially elders, is very difficult. Do your best, help others if you can, but whether they change is their own business.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Lu Xiaojie 
    <div id="lu-xiaojie" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#lu-xiaojie" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing:
<ol>
<li>She believes investors should first have an attitude of self-responsibility instead of just seeking answers from the teacher. She spent over a year studying the teacher&rsquo;s courses very seriously, treating investing like a startup project, so her mindset is very stable.</li>
<li>She suggests new students (like Zhang Le) need to give themselves and their investment strategy some time, using three or four years of results to prove it to their parents, rather than trying to convince their family as soon as they start.</li>
<li>She has observed that the teacher is constantly changing and growing, giving different advice based on different students&rsquo; situations, such as once advising Taiwanese investors who needed stable cash flow to allocate a portion to high-dividend ETFs.</li>
</ol>
<ul>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo;s Comment: He is in a good mood; his low tone of voice is because he is very calm inside, which is a very good state. He will not be influenced by the outside world and uses a joke about &ldquo;not wrestling with a pig&rdquo; to illustrate that for people who cannot understand, there is no need to argue, just say &ldquo;you are right.&rdquo; He emphasizes that he is growing and changing every day; otherwise, he would be stagnant.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Kai Xin 
    <div id="kai-xin" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#kai-xin" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing:
<ol>
<li>She is currently hospitalized but shares with a grateful heart. She shared the teacher&rsquo;s investment philosophy with a hospital cleaner, telling him that a regular monthly investment of 500 yuan would grow into a considerable fortune after 30 years.</li>
<li>She believes that making money is important, but not the only thing; health can also be lost. It&rsquo;s important to share good things with everyone for a perfect life. She shared her experience of entering the early childhood education field after an early retirement.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo;s Reply: Wishes her a speedy recovery. He also shares a story about a couple under immense pressure from their mortgage, who didn&rsquo;t dare to have children. The teacher&rsquo;s view is &ldquo;It&rsquo;s better to raise a child than to maintain a house.&rdquo;</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Jin Mai Jing 
    <div id="jin-mai-jing" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#jin-mai-jing" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: She confesses that during the market downturn in April, she was not only fully invested but also used a margin loan to buy more, which scared her in retrospect. After the market recovered recently, she closed her margin position and adjusted to a more stable asset allocation (retaining cash), feeling much more at ease.</li>
<li>Question: What should be done with the cash freed up after selling stocks?
<ul>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo;s Reply: Immediately, in a single transaction, at market price, buy a money market fund (like SGOV). Do not wait. He also used this case to emphasize that using margin is a very dangerous behavior and a huge risk. Making a profit this time was lucky, and everyone should not imitate it.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">IM 
    <div id="im" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#im" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: He reflected on the teacher&rsquo;s teachings, shifting his understanding from &ldquo;cash is risk&rdquo; to &ldquo;cash is life-saving money.&rdquo; He believes that besides pursuing assets, one should also explore inner needs.</li>
<li>Question: Besides external assets, what should one pursue internally in life? Is there a &ldquo;Perfect Way&rdquo;?
<ul>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo;s Reply: Pursue inner peace (&ldquo;Where my heart is at peace, that is my home&rdquo;). When a person sees through many things and their heart is not troubled by any person or event, they will reach a very peaceful state. This requires nurturing one&rsquo;s spirituality, learning to &ldquo;separate&rdquo; from certain things, and taking back control of one&rsquo;s life, daring to say &ldquo;no&rdquo; to things you don&rsquo;t want.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Si 
    <div id="si" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#si" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: He used to be confused about concepts like pledge, line of credit, and margin, always thinking they were just &ldquo;borrowing money.&rdquo; After listening to the teacher&rsquo;s explanation, he understood that the risks of different borrowing methods are vastly different, especially the difference between a line of credit and a stock pledge. He has already applied for a line of credit and paid off his previous pledge, feeling a sense of clarity.
<ul>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo;s Comment: Yes, it is crucial to understand which money is safe and which is dangerous.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Niu Fang 
    <div id="niu-fang" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#niu-fang" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question: Specific operational questions about stock pledges, such as how the interest rate is calculated, which account&rsquo;s assets it&rsquo;s based on, and whether the interest needs to be paid manually.
<ul>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo;s Reply: These questions have been explained in detail in his previous videos and Excel sheets. The interest will automatically roll into the principal and does not need to be repaid manually. The interest rate depends on the asset size of the pledged account and the total assets of the entire household account. He advises Niu Fang to watch the series of videos specifically explaining stock pledges (especially episodes 004, 005), as it&rsquo;s difficult to fully understand just through Q&amp;A.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">JF 
    <div id="jf" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#jf" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question:
<ol>
<li>His current asset allocation is 4-3-3. Would it be safer to keep an additional 10% of cash on the side?</li>
<li>If he uses a Pledge Loan for living expenses and has a surplus each year (e.g., borrows $20k but only spends $15k), what should he do with the remaining $5,000?</li>
<li>When borrowing money, should he borrow a year&rsquo;s worth at once, or borrow monthly/as needed?</li>
<li>During a ROTH conversion, can he transfer stocks (in-kind) directly from a traditional IRA to a brokerage account, instead of selling and then transferring?</li>
</ol>
<ul>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo;s Reply:</li>
</ul>
<ol>
<li>Keeping an extra 10% in cash is of course safer.</li>
<li>The remaining money can continue to be invested according to the 4-3-3 ratio.</li>
<li>Borrow as needed. For example, borrow only when you need to pay a bill this week; don&rsquo;t borrow in advance and let it sit.</li>
<li>Yes, stocks can be transferred in-kind. The brokerage will automatically adjust your cost basis based on the market value on the day of the transfer.</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Mike 
    <div id="mike" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#mike" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing:
<ol>
<li>Having followed the teacher for nearly 6 years, financial freedom has given him time for philanthropy, such as teaching indigenous communities. He noticed an interesting phenomenon: people are afraid of their health indexes (like blood sugar) going up, but they hope their wealth index (QQQ) goes up every day.</li>
<li>He mentioned hearing Howard Marks quote Warren Buffett on the &ldquo;Macro Insights&rdquo; program and then add: &ldquo;You never bet against the United States, and you never bet against China.&rdquo; He wanted to hear the teacher&rsquo;s opinion.</li>
<li>He observed the tech talent war between the US and China. Regardless of where the talent flows, it ultimately converges in the tech giants, which is a long-term positive for QQQ.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo;s Reply: What Howard Marks means is that the first choice for investment is still the US, but you shouldn&rsquo;t be bearish on China either, because its potential is huge. Therefore, you can choose not to be &ldquo;long&rdquo; China, but you should never &ldquo;short&rdquo; China. The focus of investment should remain on the United States.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Candy 
    <div id="candy" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#candy" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing:
<ol>
<li>She finds it strange when some students say their assets are still &ldquo;underwater.&rdquo; She shares her own early mistake: listening to others and buying penny stocks that didn&rsquo;t rise for years. Later, she came to her senses, decisively &ldquo;cut her losses,&rdquo; sold the bad stocks, and switched to quality assets (QQQ, 2x leveraged NVDA, etc.).</li>
<li>She uses one of her accounts as an example: it suffered severe losses during the big drop in April, but after she decisively rebalanced her portfolio, the account&rsquo;s return reached 75% within 3 months, not only recovering all losses but also earning over $50,000.</li>
<li>Her mindset is now very mature. When she hears friends spending millions on luxury homes, she feels no emotional stir, believing that investing money in the stock market will yield higher returns in the long run.</li>
</ol>
<ul>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo;s Comment: Many people listen to his class and call themselves his students, but in reality, they go and speculate on penny stocks, and then blame the investment philosophy when they lose money. True learning is the unity of knowledge and action.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Jimmy 
    <div id="jimmy" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#jimmy" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing:
<ol>
<li>The market is hitting new highs, but young people should not be afraid. Any time is a good time to buy because asset prices trend upward in the long run.</li>
<li>The key is to use the right method, such as keeping cash for rebalancing, to make the investment journey smoother. Long-term holding is the core.</li>
<li>He shares his understanding of a line from the Tao Te Ching, &ldquo;To the good, I am good. To the not-good, I am also good,&rdquo; believing that investing should be the same, accepting the market&rsquo;s ups and downs. He also mentions Zhuangzi&rsquo;s concept of &ldquo;transformation,&rdquo; explaining that both investing and life can continuously change and sublimate.</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">IV. Insightful Quotes 
    <div id="iv-insightful-quotes" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv-insightful-quotes" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>All information is a demon or a monster; in 40 years, no information has ever been useful.
&ndash; Teacher James</p></blockquote>
<p>This view emphasizes the importance of ignoring short-term market noise and sticking to a long-term investment strategy.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Asking me how to do your asset allocation is like asking me how much chili to add to your beef noodles.
&ndash; Teacher James</p></blockquote>
<p>This view vividly illustrates the personalized nature of asset allocation. Everyone&rsquo;s risk tolerance is different, and there is no one-size-fits-all answer.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>What our asset allocation needs to achieve is a state of &ldquo;anti-fragility.&rdquo;
&ndash; Teacher James</p></blockquote>
<p>This view introduces the core concept of &ldquo;anti-fragility,&rdquo; which is to build an investment portfolio that can survive and retain strength even in extreme risk scenarios (like the market going to zero).</p>
<blockquote>
<p>It&rsquo;s better to raise a child than to maintain a house.
&ndash; Teacher James</p></blockquote>
<p>This view reflects on the phenomenon in modern society where people sacrifice their quality of life, and even the desire to have children, for the sake of real estate, emphasizing the importance of life&rsquo;s happiness.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>He who can buy is a grandson, he who can sell is a father, but he who never sells is a god.
&ndash; Teacher James</p></blockquote>
<p>This view uses a colloquial analogy to highly praise the ultimate state of investing: &ldquo;hold for the long term, never sell.&rdquo;</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Houses aren&rsquo;t bought by people, they&rsquo;re bought by money.
&ndash; Bruce</p></blockquote>
<p>This view points out the essence of the real estate market, whose price fluctuations are primarily driven by monetary liquidity rather than just the housing needs of the population.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>If you can&rsquo;t even manage the little bit of money in your hands, then don&rsquo;t go selling your house, and don&rsquo;t go taking out loans.
&ndash; Teacher James</p></blockquote>
<p>This view advises investors to proceed step by step, starting with small amounts of capital and proving their ability to manage investments well before considering the use of larger-scale funds.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Investing can cultivate the mind.
&ndash; Jimmy</p></blockquote>
<p>This view highlights another dimension of investing: through the process of managing wealth and dealing with market fluctuations, investors can cultivate their character and achieve inner peace.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">V. Summary 
    <div id="v-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#v-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This session lucidly explains Teacher James&rsquo;s core investment philosophy and life wisdom. Starting from the simple principle of &ldquo;buy, hold, don&rsquo;t sell,&rdquo; it extends to the sophisticated strategy of using cash to build an &ldquo;anti-fragile&rdquo; portfolio, and then to a profound analysis of the risks of leveraged ETFs, providing investors with a clear guide to action. More importantly, the class transcends purely financial discussion, closely linking investment with personal psychological growth, family happiness, and inner peace. Through vivid analogies and real student cases, the teacher guides everyone to realize that true financial freedom is not just about numerical growth, but about breaking free from fear and anxiety, gaining the ability to control one&rsquo;s life and enjoy the present moment. At the same time, the teacher also reminds students that investment philosophy is constantly evolving and growing, requiring continuous learning and follow-up, otherwise, one becomes like a &ldquo;lost lamb,&rdquo; disconnected from the latest understanding.</p>

  



<div
  
    class="flex px-4 py-3 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900"
  >

  <span
    
      class="text-primary-400 ltr:pr-3 rtl:pl-3 flex items-center"
    >

    

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M506.3 417l-213.3-364c-16.33-28-57.54-28-73.98 0l-213.2 364C-10.59 444.9 9.849 480 42.74 480h426.6C502.1 480 522.6 445 506.3 417zM232 168c0-13.25 10.75-24 24-24S280 154.8 280 168v128c0 13.25-10.75 24-23.1 24S232 309.3 232 296V168zM256 416c-17.36 0-31.44-14.08-31.44-31.44c0-17.36 14.07-31.44 31.44-31.44s31.44 14.08 31.44 31.44C287.4 401.9 273.4 416 256 416z"/></svg>

  </span>


  </span>

  <span
    
      class="dark:text-neutral-300"
    ><strong>Disclaimer:</strong> This article is for personal study notes only and does not constitute any investment advice.</span>
</div>

]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>00515 Stock Pledging is Wisdom, Day Trading is Gambling: If You Don't Understand the System, You'll Be Eaten by the Government's System. A Preliminary Discussion on 'Stablecoins!'</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1748176430879/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1748176430879/</guid><description>In this session, Teacher James emphasizes maintaining emotional stability during market volatility, adhering to a long-term investment philosophy, and discusses the importance of cash in asset allocation, particularly the strategy of stock pledging. Additionally, he shares personal insights on the meaning of life, work value, and achieving inner peace through meditation and mindfulness. The content also includes a critique of Taiwan&amp;#39;s day trading policies and observations on current trends in digital currencies and stablecoins.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<lite-youtube videoid="KW_VQn2oops" playlabel="KW_VQn2oops" params=""></lite-youtube>



<h2 class="relative group">I. Theme of the Session 
    <div id="i-theme-of-the-session" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-theme-of-the-session" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>The core of this session is to emphasize the importance of emotional control and mental fortitude in long-term investing, proposing a life attitude of &ldquo;Whatever, it&rsquo;s all fine, it doesn&rsquo;t matter&rdquo; to cope with market fluctuations and life&rsquo;s challenges. Teacher James elaborates on asset allocation principles, especially the critical role of cash position (recommended not less than 30%) in stock pledging strategies, and critically analyzes Taiwan&rsquo;s day trading policies and their impact on investors. Furthermore, the course integrates profound insights on the meaning of work, personal growth, meditation, mindfulness, and emerging financial trends (like stablecoins).</p>


<h2 class="relative group">II. Presentation Content 
    <div id="ii-presentation-content" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii-presentation-content" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Recommended Learning Resources (Mentioned at the beginning) 
    <div id="recommended-learning-resources-mentioned-at-the-beginning" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#recommended-learning-resources-mentioned-at-the-beginning" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Facebook Page &ldquo;inrichment疾风胜&rdquo;</strong>: Teacher James mentioned this Facebook article, which covers not only investment and financial management but also psychological preparation and mindset adjustment, offering a &ldquo;mental massage&rdquo; effect.</li>
<li><strong>&ldquo;CAD贵妇理财&rdquo; (CAD Wealthy Lady Financial Management)</strong>: Also mentioned as a good sharer of financial management content.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Prerequisites for Stock Pledging (Discussed at the beginning) 
    <div id="prerequisites-for-stock-pledging-discussed-at-the-beginning" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#prerequisites-for-stock-pledging-discussed-at-the-beginning" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>HSBC (Hong Kong) Stock Pledging Threshold</strong>: Must be an &ldquo;HSBC Premier&rdquo; client or above, meaning one needs to have over 1 million HKD in assets with HSBC Hong Kong; this is a VIP service.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Market Volatility and Investment Mentality 
    <div id="market-volatility-and-investment-mentality" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#market-volatility-and-investment-mentality" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>The market is often swayed by news, causing volatility. Investors should understand the reasons but avoid letting emotions dictate their actions, which could lead to wrong decisions (like panic selling or greedy chasing of highs).</li>
<li>Controlling emotions is crucial. One can adopt methods like &ldquo;tying one&rsquo;s hands and feet,&rdquo; such as temporarily locking accounts or deleting apps to avoid impulsive operations.</li>
<li><strong>Example Strategy for Large Capital Investment</strong>: For 1 million in funds, 500,000 can be bought at market price immediately; another 250,000 can be bought in batches (e.g., 50,000 per month for 5 months), disregarding short-term fluctuations; the remaining 250,000 serves as cash reserves or for discretionary decisions. The ultimate goal is to have most of the capital (e.g., 75%) in the market.</li>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo;s investment philosophy is unrelated to short-term stock market fluctuations, emphasizing the principle of buying as soon as it&rsquo;s available.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Investment Philosophy and Life Attitude 
    <div id="investment-philosophy-and-life-attitude" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#investment-philosophy-and-life-attitude" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Risk Aversion</strong>: Life is about avoiding failure, not pursuing extreme success. The priority in investment is to &ldquo;survive&rdquo;; stable profits are more important than risking bankruptcy. Simplicity is also a form of success.</li>
<li><strong>Reduce Desires, Strengthen Inner Self</strong>: Avoid &ldquo;greed, anger, and delusion&rdquo;; adopt an attitude of &ldquo;Whatever, it&rsquo;s all fine, it doesn&rsquo;t matter&rdquo; towards material possessions and relationships. Only by not fearing loss can one truly possess.</li>
<li><strong>Dare to &ldquo;Break the Mold&rdquo; (破局)</strong>: Life, like negotiation, often favors those who dare to &ldquo;break&rdquo; (break conventions, not afraid of falling out).</li>
<li><strong>Focus on Life, Downplay the Market</strong>: Correct investing is not time-consuming; one should focus on living happily and let time make money for us.</li>
<li><strong>Meditation and Mindfulness</strong>: Can be practiced anytime, anywhere. Focus on the present moment (e.g., breathing, conversation), without dwelling on the past or future, maintaining inner peace (a mind like still water).</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Analysis of Taiwan&rsquo;s Day Trading Policy 
    <div id="analysis-of-taiwans-day-trading-policy" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#analysis-of-taiwans-day-trading-policy" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>The Taiwanese government encourages day trading by reducing transaction tax (securities transaction tax halved) to increase market liquidity.</li>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s Critique</strong>:
<ul>
<li><strong>No Capital Gains Tax</strong>: Superficially beneficial to long-term investors, but it actually doesn&rsquo;t encourage long-term holding because short-term trading also has no capital gains tax, giving no extra advantage to long-term investors.</li>
<li><strong>High Transaction Costs</strong>: The &ldquo;securities transaction tax&rdquo; (actually a transaction fee) becomes extremely high with frequent trading. For example, a transaction cost of 0.6% (0.3% for buying and 0.3% for selling), if traded 10 times a year, would erode 6.16% of the total capital as fees, far exceeding expected returns.</li>
<li><strong>Misleading &ldquo;Securities Income Tax&rdquo; (正所税)</strong>: What Taiwan calls &ldquo;securities income tax&rdquo; is not a true income tax (paid only when there&rsquo;s income) but a transaction fee (paid upon transaction, regardless of profit or loss), a misleading term for the public.</li>
<li><strong>Retail Investors&rsquo; Dilemma</strong>: This policy essentially causes retail investors to lose money due to high fees in frequent trading, while the government collects more transaction fees.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Comparison with the US: Transaction costs are very low, but there is a capital gains tax, which to some extent encourages long-term holding.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Learning and Thinking 
    <div id="learning-and-thinking" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#learning-and-thinking" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Independent Thinking</strong>: Others can provide knowledge, but thinking must be done by oneself. A life without thinking is not very meaningful (though the teacher also reflects on this, believing different lifestyles have their own meaning).</li>
<li><strong>Lwin&rsquo;s Sharing (Regarding lump-sum vs. installment investment)</strong>: Depends on individual risk tolerance. If an investment leads to panic after a market drop, it means the position is too heavy; one should increase the cash proportion until market fluctuations can be faced calmly.</li>
<li><strong>IM&rsquo;s Sharing (Young people&rsquo;s investment and primary profession)</strong>: Young people should focus on their primary profession; investment should not take up work time. Work is not just for making money, but also for serving others and realizing life&rsquo;s meaning.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Core Principles of Asset Allocation (Related to Stock Pledging) 
    <div id="core-principles-of-asset-allocation-related-to-stock-pledging" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#core-principles-of-asset-allocation-related-to-stock-pledging" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Cash is King</strong>: The initial cash position should not be less than 30% (e.g., 30% cash in a 4-3-3 allocation, or 50% cash 50% QQQ).</li>
<li><strong>Use of Leveraged Funds</strong>: Leveraged funds should not exceed the cash position, nor should they exceed the position of core funds (like QQQ).</li>
<li>Can be adjusted according to individual risk tolerance, e.g., 4-2-4 (40% QQQ, 20% leverage, 40% cash) or no leverage at all.</li>
<li>Final performance depends on the market, not the precise asset allocation ratio.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Other Important Tips 
    <div id="other-important-tips" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#other-important-tips" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>CLEC Resources</strong>: The YouTube channel has a &ldquo;Investment Lecture Worth 100 Million&rdquo; series; it&rsquo;s recommended to start learning from 00451, then watch in the order of 00398, 00399, 00400.</li>
<li><strong>Community Principles</strong>: Focus on CLEC investment philosophy, do not discuss unrelated topics (like insurance, short-term real estate, etc.).</li>
<li><strong>Recommended Tickers</strong>: Mainly recommends Nasdaq 100 index funds (QQQ and its equivalents in various regions).</li>
<li><strong>Long-term Perspective</strong>: Investing is a matter of twenty to thirty years or more; short-term fluctuations are like passing clouds. The fundamentals of the US economy and corporations remain strong.</li>
<li><strong>Disclaimer Emphasis</strong>: CLEC channel content is for reference only, for educational purposes, non-profit, and will not ask for remittances or provide private contact methods. Investment is high risk; be responsible for your own decisions.</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">III. Q&amp;A Session 
    <div id="iii-qa-session" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii-qa-session" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">CAD 
    <div id="cad" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#cad" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing:
<ol>
<li>Recently traveled with friends, overcame concerns about spending, and experienced the joy of not watching the market and focusing on the present. She emphasized that once money is invested in the market, one should let go and execute the plan (e.g., dollar-cost averaging), then go enjoy life.</li>
</ol>
<ul>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo;s comment: We will all be very wealthy in the future (adding three zeros to assets is common). Spend money wisely; you can spend when cash is ample (30% of total assets). If travel expenses would dip into core allocation cash, it&rsquo;s better to sell a small amount of stock for travel, which actually reduces risk (lowers beta). Borrowing against pledged stocks for consumption is safer because it doesn&rsquo;t touch the principal. For example, with 10 million in assets, if all in 00662, a major market crash could lead to bankruptcy; with 20 million in assets (10 million in 00662, 10 million in cash, and a 10 million loan), after an 80% drop, you&rsquo;d still have 12 million (2 million in stocks + 10 million in cash), which is safer.
CAD adds: The cash in an allocation (like the &lsquo;3&rsquo; in 4-3-3) is part of the portfolio and cannot be spent随意, or it will disrupt the ratio. Spending should be done through pledging loans or by withdrawing according to the 2% rule.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question (None)</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Overseas Loner 
    <div id="overseas-loner" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#overseas-loner" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Listener from Taiwan, 34 years old, with assets of 15 million TWD, has been investing in 00662 for about a year following the teacher&rsquo;s method.</li>
<li>Question 1: Current monthly income is about 50,000 TWD, annual income less than a million, not considered high in Taiwan. To retire early, should I switch to a higher-paying technical job (like a technician in the tech industry) to accelerate asset accumulation?
<ul>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo;s reply: Work should primarily bring joy, not just money. High-paying jobs might sacrifice health and family. 15 million TWD is already very wealthy and will grow rapidly. If changing jobs, the primary goals should be health, happiness, and joy, not purely chasing money.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2: Tried leveraged funds (like TQQQ) but found their violent fluctuations psychologically unbearable, then switched to 100% unleveraged funds (00662). The teacher previously backtested that a 4-3-3 allocation could survive the 2000 dot-com bubble (80% drop). Is it because of such extreme market conditions that the 4-3-3 allocation appears superior? If future market volatility is smaller, might other allocations (like 100% 00662) be better?
<ul>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo;s reply: The 4-3-3 is designed to seek maximum returns at the edge of risk (e.g., maintenance margin of 167%) and can barely survive extreme conditions. If backtested with the 2000 market, a 50% cash / 50% QQQ (with smart rebalancing into leverage during downturns) might perform comparably or even better than 4-3-3 because more cash means more safety. However, in a long-term bull market, 4-3-3 would outperform 50/50. Since the future market is unknown, it&rsquo;s impossible to determine which allocation is definitively optimal. The core principles are: cash not less than 30%, leveraged funds not exceeding cash, and not exceeding unleveraged funds. Leveraged funds can be zero (e.g., 70% QQQ, 30% cash).</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Watson 
    <div id="watson" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#watson" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing:
<ol>
<li>Emphasizes the importance of learning CLEC investment philosophy, especially before stock pledging.</li>
<li>This year, practically implemented the teacher&rsquo;s advice by canceling long-held savings insurance policies, deeply realizing that insurance, real estate, and long-term bonds are not quality assets.</li>
<li>Wrong decisions must be corrected immediately; correct ones should be persisted. Wealth growth is just a matter of time.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>Question 1: When calculating total assets to withdraw the annual 2% for living expenses, should funds borrowed via credit and invested in the market also be included in total assets?
<ul>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo;s reply: Yes, they should be included. The principal and interest payments for the credit are part of living expenses, and it&rsquo;s reasonable to use the 2% withdrawal to cover living expenses and loan payments.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2: If the market falls continuously for 10 years, and one still withdraws 2% for living expenses annually and performs &ldquo;smart rebalancing&rdquo; (investing the 2% cash into the market), would this deal a devastating blow to the asset allocation? Should the withdrawal percentage be reduced or rebalancing paused?
<ul>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo;s reply: Real history (e.g., 2000-2009) was not a continuous 10-year decline but had ups and downs. It fell from 2000-2003, investing about 6%; rose from 2003-2007, cash flowed out; fell in 2008, investing 2%. In total, about 4 years of investment (8%). If an extreme 10-year continuous decline truly occurred, the cash in a 4-3-3 allocation might indeed be insufficient. If &ldquo;smart rebalancing&rdquo; is not done, there would be more cash when the market rebounds.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 3: The 2% annual withdrawal benchmark: is it calculated based on total assets at the end of the previous year (e.g., December 31st), or on the initial total assets invested? Or adjust after assets have doubled?
<ul>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo;s reply: It&rsquo;s recommended to initially withdraw 2% of the initial total assets. After assets have significantly appreciated (e.g., doubled or severalfold), if one wishes to increase living expenses, a complete asset allocation replanning is needed (similar to the &ldquo;Scenario 19&rdquo; principle: first reserve enough cash to cover debts and decades of future living expenses, then allocate the remainder according to 4-3-3 or similar ratios).</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 4: Hong Kong HIBOR is very low recently (about 0.6%), total borrowing cost is about 1.5%. Can I borrow more than 20% (the teacher&rsquo;s recommended pledging loan limit) from HSBC stock pledge loans to buy SGOV or BOXX (currently yielding about 4.3%) for arbitrage?
<ul>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo;s reply: Yes. This arbitrage fund is an independent operation and does not change the allocation ratio of the original pledged portfolio. The borrowed money can only buy cash equivalents like SGOV or BOXX. The main risk is exchange rate (HKD appreciating significantly against USD, though constrained by the linked exchange rate system). HSBC does not accept leveraged funds as collateral.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 5: What are the risks of products like BOXX? HSBC does not accept BOXX as collateral.
<ul>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo;s reply: If HSBC doesn&rsquo;t accept BOXX, use SGOV (if accepted). The main risk of BOXX and SGOV is liquidity risk in extreme market conditions (difficulty selling), which all assets (including stocks) share.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Rui 
    <div id="rui" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#rui" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question 1: Regarding understanding the 2% withdrawal rule in extreme cases. If a person has 100 million in assets and spends 2 million annually. If the market drops 50% to 50 million, can they still spend 2 million? Or, if someone starts retirement with 50 million when the market has already fallen from a high (100 million), can they live by the 2 million standard corresponding to the original 100 million asset base?
<ul>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo;s reply: Yes. Having 50 million at the market bottom (e.g., March 2009) might have the purchasing power or sustainability equivalent to 100 million at the market top (e.g., 2000). So, someone retiring at a market low might achieve the same living standard with less principal.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2: Regarding career development. At 34, feeling financially free, somewhat迷茫 about work. Promotion means more responsibility but also potentially broader horizons. How did Teacher James view promotions (e.g., to VP) after achieving financial freedom?
<ul>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo;s reply: Promotion should be decided by oneself, not the company. When you feel you have the capability for a higher position, even better than the current incumbent, opportunities will naturally come. One should not accept a promotion when unprepared, as it could lead to failure. Continuously learn and improve in the current role to reach the capability for the next level. If capability is there, promotion is good, allowing one to serve more people. One should be overqualified for the position before promotion.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Brian 
    <div id="brian" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#brian" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: London prices are very high; one fish and chips costs 33 pounds.</li>
<li>Question: If the US government devalues its currency, can stock pledging somewhat hedge this risk? Because assets are bought at a fixed price, while the value of debt decreases with currency devaluation.
<ul>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo;s reply: Yes. When we borrow to invest, in a sense, we are also &ldquo;printing money,&rdquo; similar to government actions. We are borrowing future &ldquo;trash&rdquo; (potentially devalued currency) in exchange for current quality assets. If the USD devalues, the real value of our USD debt also decreases. This is a &ldquo;borrow trash for assets&rdquo; strategy.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Sharing 2: Early investments were more aggressive (e.g., 60% QQQ, 20% TQQQ, 20% cash). Now, no longer adding new investments but focusing on increasing cash reserves, letting the existing portfolio grow naturally.
<ul>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo;s reply: This is very good. Even if the initial cash ratio is high (e.g., 30%), leading to a lower overall Beta, as core assets appreciate significantly, the cash proportion will relatively shrink, and the overall portfolio&rsquo;s &ldquo;risk&rdquo; (or growth potential) remains considerable. Cash provides a huge safety net and psychological comfort. A low Beta initially is fine; eventually, the ship (assets) becomes an aircraft carrier, and the lifeboat (cash) seems insignificant.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Sharing 3: Read &ldquo;Why Do So Many Incompetent Men Become Leaders?&rdquo;, which mentions that incompetent people often manage to appear extremely confident in front of others. Engineers are typically rigorous and find it hard to make absolute guarantees, while some ignorant yet fearless managers charge ahead.
<ul>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo;s reply: This is a personality issue. He himself is an &ldquo;anomaly,&rdquo; having done many different types of work. Just be yourself.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">D 
    <div id="d" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#d" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question 1: &ldquo;Do you become capable first and then start, or start first and then become capable?&rdquo;
<ul>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo;s reply: In terms of personal learning and cultivation (practicing skills), it&rsquo;s definitely &ldquo;start first, then become capable.&rdquo; For example, learning to invest, you have to open an account first; you can&rsquo;t wait until you&rsquo;ve read all the books. But in the professional world (the &ldquo;martial arts world&rdquo;), you can&rsquo;t get promoted first and then train; that will lead to failure.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2: Following the teacher&rsquo;s advice, invested credit borrowed in Taiwan into the market (allocated proportionally to 00662, etc.). The rationale is: future inflation will decrease cash purchasing power, so it&rsquo;s better to borrow and invest now, repaying with devalued money in the future. Is this logic correct? (Friends don&rsquo;t understand.)
<ul>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo;s reply: The logic is perfectly correct. We are &ldquo;aliens,&rdquo; they are &ldquo;earthlings&rdquo;; different ways of thinking.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Yao 
    <div id="yao" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#yao" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question 1: Regarding autonomous driving technology routes: Tesla (pure vision) vs. Waymo (LiDAR) competition outlook? Waymo&rsquo;s development is steady but expansion is slow; Tesla&rsquo;s FSD V12 is about to be released.
<ul>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo;s reply: He personally uses Tesla FSD and has a good experience. Waymo&rsquo;s expansion is too slow; if Tesla&rsquo;s performance is comparable, its production and deployment scale will far exceed Waymo&rsquo;s, and costs will be lower. Waymo&rsquo;s outlook is not optimistic; it&rsquo;s like rifles against tanks and cannons.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2: Corporate innovation and leadership: It seems companies where founders are still present (like Tesla, Nvidia, Meta) are more innovative, while companies led by professional managers (like Microsoft, Google) mostly adopt follow-or-acquire strategies.
<ul>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo;s reply: Not necessarily. Microsoft under Nadella (not a founder) has performed excellently. Starbucks improved after its founder returned. The key is corporate governance and CEO capability, but the fate of large companies is complex; sometimes &ldquo;even gods can&rsquo;t save them.&rdquo; IBM revived; Kodak and BlackBerry declined. Intel&rsquo;s future is also uncertain.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Yao adds: Google&rsquo;s AI is strong, but it seems to be lagging in the AI race, and its search engine is threatened by OpenAI, etc. Apple&rsquo;s Vision Pro is expensive with low sales; a professional manager (Cook) might be less willing to take risks than a founder (Jobs).
<ul>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo;s reply: Google&rsquo;s problem is its adherence to the search engine model, failing to revolutionize its integration of AI technology. This is similar to Kodak. He hasn&rsquo;t used Google search for a long time, switching to OpenAI. OpenAI&rsquo;s search experience far surpasses Google&rsquo;s. As for various AI models, each has its pros and cons, like different tools; the key is to use them in the right place, not just compare who is &ldquo;better.&rdquo; Companies need the courage to abandon existing models and surpass themselves; otherwise, it&rsquo;s &ldquo;occupying a position without fulfilling its duties&rdquo; (尸位素餐), which is the beginning of demise.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Maochang (王茂昌) 
    <div id="maochang-%E7%8E%8B%E8%8C%82%E6%98%8C" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#maochang-%E7%8E%8B%E8%8C%82%E6%98%8C" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question: Currently using a 4-3-3 allocation, receiving 2% for living expenses monthly through pledging. Will receive a salary of 20,000 TWD mid-month. Can I spend the pledged money first, and then invest the salary into the market when it arrives mid-month?
<ul>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo;s reply: Yes. This 20,000 TWD salary can be invested proportionally (e.g., 60% 00662, 30% 00670L, 10% 00865B, or other suitable ratios). If you want to increase the living expense withdrawal amount in the future, a complete asset allocation replanning is needed.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Candy 
    <div id="candy" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#candy" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing (Detailed personal investment journey):
<ol>
<li>Inspired by &ldquo;Rich Dad Poor Dad&rdquo; in early years, started investing and exploring on her own.</li>
<li>Panic sold during the market crash at the beginning of the 2020 pandemic (sold TPTQQQ around $30+), suffered losses, missed the V-shaped recovery, deeply regretted it, and paid 50% tax.</li>
<li>During the 2022 market downturn, thanks to previous lessons and the teacher&rsquo;s philosophy, plus holding 25-30% cash, her emotions were stable, and she held on. Her husband also reminded her not to sell stocks out of fear.</li>
<li>After the market stabilized in 2023, once considered liquidating everything to invest in CDs, but after rational analysis (not worried about money, economy recovering, holding good assets), chose to continue holding quality assets.</li>
<li>During the April 2024 market pullback, remained calm, believing in economic fundamentals (employment, CPI, GDP, stable oil prices), and eventually welcomed the May rally.</li>
<li>Expresses gratitude for the teacher&rsquo;s guidance and the luck of fellow students to directly access a mature investment system.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>Sharing (Life insights): Financially free for many years (about 10 years), experienced travel, hobbies, etc., but now feels a bit lost about the second half of life, lacking clear goals. Young people having goals to strive for is a blessing.
<ul>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo;s reply: Life doesn&rsquo;t necessarily need grand meaning; &ldquo;Whatever, it&rsquo;s all fine, it doesn&rsquo;t matter&rdquo; is an important mindset. Find things that make you happy, like philosophical contemplation, observing the world (finance, politics, art, social phenomena, from minor car accidents to major wealth inequality). The entire world is a field for contemplation.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Candy adds sharing: Once managed a poorly run orchard for nearly ten years. The time spent alone in the orchard brought her inner peace. Through dialogue with nature and deep thinking, she found answers to many significant life and investment questions, and these decisions later proved correct. Emphasizes the importance of self-reflection and &ldquo;looking inward&rdquo; in tranquility. Believes that in a state of extreme calmness and emptiness, answers will naturally emerge, as if connecting with a higher power.
<ul>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo;s reply: Deeply resonates. He often talks to his garden and tomatoes, sensing their life force. The meaning of a tomato plant is to grow. A thousand-year-old sacred tree silently observes the changes of the world, indifferent to &ldquo;meaning.&rdquo; The things we cling to are insignificant on a cosmic scale; &ldquo;there is no greatest.&rdquo; Towards people and matters, including family relationships (with children, husband), maintain an attitude of &ldquo;Whatever, it&rsquo;s all fine, it doesn&rsquo;t matter.&rdquo; Love yourself, love others, but don&rsquo;t demand a response.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question: About Bitcoin. Knows it&rsquo;s digital gold, but missed it early on; now the price is high, volatility is large, and she&rsquo;s unfamiliar with it. Can she allocate a small amount to Bitcoin ETFs (like 1-2%)?
<ul>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo;s reply: Does not proactively recommend it. If one personally decides to allocate 1-2%, they bear the risk; it&rsquo;s fine even if it goes to zero. However, the overall trend of digital currencies and stablecoins is beneficial for tech indices like QQQ. The US government is gradually regulating and co-opting the stablecoin market (e.g., Circle legalized, Binance paying a huge fine to become compliant), aiming to control the dominance of digital currencies. One reason Facebook&rsquo;s Libra project failed was its peg to a basket of currencies, not just the USD, which was not in US interests. Tech companies can develop, but if they violate US interests, it&rsquo;s illegal.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Dirk 
    <div id="dirk" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#dirk" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question: News says a large amount of US Treasury bonds will mature in July. Will this have a drastic impact on US dollar short-term bond ETFs held by Taiwanese investors (like 00865B) or the New Taiwan Dollar exchange rate?
<ul>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo;s reply: Exchange rate fluctuations are &ldquo;Whatever, it&rsquo;s all fine, it doesn&rsquo;t matter.&rdquo; Behind this is a global currency war and financial revolution (digital currencies, stablecoins). The US plays a key role, strengthening the dollar&rsquo;s position through measures like the stablecoin bill (a student mentioned Graham-Cassidy, the teacher didn&rsquo;t correct but emphasized it&rsquo;s a stablecoin bill), making US Treasuries more attractive. This is positive for the overall financial system; the dollar will remain strong. No need to worry excessively about 00865B. After this bill passes, US banks other than the central bank will also be able to print money (issue stablecoins), US Treasuries will be hotter, and interest rates will fall.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Other Scattered Points Mentioned by Students or Responded to by Teacher James: 
    <div id="other-scattered-points-mentioned-by-students-or-responded-to-by-teacher-james" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#other-scattered-points-mentioned-by-students-or-responded-to-by-teacher-james" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>HSBC Premier Stock Pledging</strong>: Requires Premier level (over 1 million HKD in assets). (Early discussion)</li>
<li><strong>Young Investor Allocation</strong>: 4-3-3 or 70/30 are both fine; cash not less than 30%. 4-4-2 (40% QQQ, 40% TQQQ, 20% cash) is very volatile, not suitable for everyone.</li>
<li><strong>HSBC Hong Kong Pledge Maintenance Margin</strong>: Relatively high, so 50% stocks / 50% cash might be a safer initial allocation (cash part can also consider SGOV/BOXX). Leveraged funds cannot be pledged at HSBC.</li>
<li><strong>IBIT/FBTC</strong>: Both are Bitcoin spot ETFs. IBIT (BlackRock) currently has larger trading volume; FBTC (Fidelity) is also an option.</li>
<li><strong>Stablecoin Bill (e.g., Genius Act / Graham-Cassidy related content on stablecoins)</strong>: Expected to pass in the next month or two, will allow regulated US financial institutions to issue stablecoins, greatly invigorating the US Treasury market and dollar liquidity. This is a major positive for financial markets, an &ldquo;atomic bomb-level financial explosion.&rdquo;</li>
<li><strong>Definition of Money</strong>: JP Morgan was once asked about the money supply and retorted by asking for a definition of money first. Airline miles also count as a form of currency. Everyone writing an IOU is also printing money, as long as it circulates.</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">IV. Highlighted Quotes 
    <div id="iv-highlighted-quotes" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv-highlighted-quotes" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>The market is often quite volatile due to news. But everyone should ignore it&hellip; Don&rsquo;t let it affect your investment emotions, this is very important.
&ndash; Teacher James</p></blockquote>
<p>Context: Reminding students in an era of information overload to discern information and, more importantly, control emotions arising from short-term market fluctuations to avoid wrong investment decisions.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>One&rsquo;s life is not about pursuing how successful you want to be, but about avoiding failure. So, don&rsquo;t do risky things, don&rsquo;t take adventures.
&ndash; Teacher James</p></blockquote>
<p>Context: Explaining the core principle of investment and life, emphasizing that risk control and steady sustainability are more important than pursuing exorbitant profits.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Whatever, it&rsquo;s all fine, it doesn&rsquo;t matter&hellip; If you lower your needs, lower your desires, you become stronger. Being indifferent and unafraid of loss means you succeed; this is true wealth – not fearing loss, possessing the most.
&ndash; Teacher James</p></blockquote>
<p>Context: Sharing a philosophy of life and a method for inner cultivation, achieving inner strength and true abundance by reducing attachment to external things.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Correct investing doesn&rsquo;t take time&hellip; If you can forget the market&rsquo;s existence and let time make money for us, that&rsquo;s the most powerful.
&ndash; Teacher James</p></blockquote>
<p>Context: Emphasizing the passive and simple nature of long-term investing; investors should focus on life, not constantly watch the market.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Taiwan&rsquo;s lack of capital gains tax is encouraging, well, it means not giving long-term investors benefits, i.e., not encouraging long-term investors. &hellip;Moreover, this securities income tax and transaction fee are terrifying&hellip; Only retail investors will lose until they go bankrupt, still thinking they will win.
&ndash; Teacher James</p></blockquote>
<p>Context: Criticizing Taiwan&rsquo;s stock market tax policy, arguing that while it&rsquo;s named as a burden reduction, it actually harms retail investors through high-frequency trading fees and is not conducive to cultivating a long-term investment culture.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>It&rsquo;s good for young people to learn investing, but remember to take care of your main profession. Your main profession is not just about making money; work is also about serving others, it&rsquo;s the meaning of life.
&ndash; Teacher James</p></blockquote>
<p>Context: Responding to a young student&rsquo;s question about balancing career choice and investment, emphasizing the importance of one&rsquo;s primary job and its social value.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Borrowing against pledged stocks for consumption, without spending cash, is safer. &hellip;If you get a margin call on your loan, that other person with 10 million (all in stock) would also be wiped out, they&rsquo;d have no money either.
&ndash; Teacher James</p></blockquote>
<p>Context: Explaining why, even with cash on hand, borrowing against pledged stocks for consumption is sometimes a superior choice, as it maintains the integrity and growth potential of core assets, and comparing the safety of pure assets versus leveraged assets (with corresponding cash).</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Life can have no meaning, why must life have meaning? It doesn&rsquo;t necessarily have to have meaning, so not having meaning is the greatest goal.
&ndash; Teacher James</p></blockquote>
<p>Context: Responding to a student&rsquo;s confusion about the meaning of life, proposing a transcendent view that one need not force a grand meaning onto life; living spontaneously and finding present joy is sufficient.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>We are printing money just like the US government&hellip; Aren&rsquo;t we issuing our stablecoins using our assets when we borrow money? &hellip;This is the highest level of capitalism – aggression. Of course, it sounds harsh, but it&rsquo;s plundering.
&ndash; Teacher James</p></blockquote>
<p>Context: Responding to a student&rsquo;s discussion on currency devaluation and pledged borrowing, pointing out that in an environment of inflation and potential currency devaluation, borrowing to buy quality assets is a wealth strategy similar to how the current financial system operates.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>This (stablecoin bill) is a very important thing. The most important thing this year. Things like Trump&rsquo;s tariff wars are minor issues&hellip; If this passes, I tell you, US Treasury interest rates will fall, and the US dollar will rise.
&ndash; Teacher James</p></blockquote>
<p>Context: Discussing the stablecoin bill being promoted in the US, believing it will be a crucial move for the US to consolidate its financial hegemony and invigorate financial markets, with an impact far exceeding other short-term economic events.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">V. Summary 
    <div id="v-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#v-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>In this CLEC investment and financial management course, Teacher James once again emphasized his consistent long-term investment philosophy and emotional management techniques, encouraging students to face market ups and downs and life&rsquo;s vicissitudes with a transcendent attitude of &ldquo;Whatever, it&rsquo;s all fine, it doesn&rsquo;t matter.&rdquo; The course focused on discussing the strategic importance of the cash position (not less than 30%) in asset allocation, combined with in-depth analysis of stock pledging scenarios, aiming to help students build a more robust financial structure. The teacher also provided a profound analysis of Taiwan&rsquo;s day trading policies, revealing their potential harm to retail investors. Furthermore, the course content broadly touched upon life wisdom such as work value, personal growth, meditation, and mindfulness, and prospectively explored emerging financial trends like stablecoins and their potential impact on the future world order, offering students a broad perspective and deep thinking beyond investment itself.</p>

  



<div
  
    class="flex px-4 py-3 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900"
  >

  <span
    
      class="text-primary-400 ltr:pr-3 rtl:pl-3 flex items-center"
    >

    

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M506.3 417l-213.3-364c-16.33-28-57.54-28-73.98 0l-213.2 364C-10.59 444.9 9.849 480 42.74 480h426.6C502.1 480 522.6 445 506.3 417zM232 168c0-13.25 10.75-24 24-24S280 154.8 280 168v128c0 13.25-10.75 24-23.1 24S232 309.3 232 296V168zM256 416c-17.36 0-31.44-14.08-31.44-31.44c0-17.36 14.07-31.44 31.44-31.44s31.44 14.08 31.44 31.44C287.4 401.9 273.4 416 256 416z"/></svg>

  </span>


  </span>

  <span
    
      class="dark:text-neutral-300"
    ><strong>Disclaimer:</strong> This article is for personal learning notes only and does not constitute any investment advice.</span>
</div>

]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>00503 The Wealth Code the Market Won't Teach You: 99% of Investment Courses on the Market are Fleecing Sheep. Our Channel is Better Than Financial Advisors and MBA Investment Courses</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1740288562129/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1740288562129/</guid><description>This episode delves into the differences between CLEC Investment Education and traditional investment education and influencers, analyzing investment philosophies, asset allocation, the importance of long-term investing, and discussing issues such as the A-share NASDAQ premium, American politics, and AI regulation.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<lite-youtube videoid="eT8qj07y96E" playlabel="eT8qj07y96E" params=""></lite-youtube>



<h2 class="relative group">I. Current Topic 
    <div id="i-current-topic" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-current-topic" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This episode revolves around ChatGPT&rsquo;s analysis of CLEC Investment Education, deeply comparing CLEC investment with common investment education on the market, influencers, and common investment books. It emphasizes the uniqueness, practicality, executability, and systematic nature of CLEC investment. At the same time, James shares the growth path of investors, the necessity of asset allocation, the importance of cash flow management, and how to deal with market fluctuations, and answers questions raised by students regarding the A-share NASDAQ premium, the American political economy, and AI regulation.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">II. Briefing Content 
    <div id="ii-briefing-content" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii-briefing-content" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Investment Philosophy and Strategy 
    <div id="investment-philosophy-and-strategy" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#investment-philosophy-and-strategy" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>
<p><strong>Differences between CLEC Investment and Market Books, Influencers:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Core Strategy:</strong> CLEC uses the NASDAQ 100 Index Fund (QQQ) as its core, combined with leveraged funds (QLD) and bank pledges for asset allocation, targeting an annualized return of 12%~20%.</li>
<li><strong>Traditional Investment Education:</strong> Usually only emphasizes large-cap index investing (such as VOO, SPY) or value investing, rarely mentions leveraged funds, and even less involves specific capital operation strategies (such as stock pledges).</li>
<li><strong>Influencer Finance:</strong> Often oversimplifies investing or recommends various immature investment targets (such as newly issued ETFs), lacking systematicity and risk control.</li>
<li><strong>Financial Freedom Strategy:</strong> CLEC provides a clear path to financial freedom, including when to start stock pledges, the amount that can be safely withdrawn each year, and how to achieve financial freedom through capital operations, rather than just &ldquo;saving money + investing.&rdquo;</li>
<li><strong>Practicality and Executability:</strong> CLEC provides concrete and actionable plans, such as how much assets you need to reach to start pledging, how to adjust asset allocation according to market conditions, while many books and courses only have theory and lack practical guidance.</li>
<li><strong>Capital Operation:</strong> CLEC emphasizes capital operation through bank credit, wealth management mortgages, stock pledges, etc., to achieve the goal of &ldquo;borrowing money to invest, borrowing money to spend, and asset appreciation,&rdquo; which is rarely involved in traditional investment education and influencer finance.</li>
<li><strong>Risk Management:</strong> Emphasizes risk control and has specific coping methods in the event of a downturn.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Comparison with Common Investment Books:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>&ldquo;The Psychology of Money&rdquo;:</strong> Emphasizes long-term investing and saving, but CLEC goes a step further by accelerating wealth accumulation through leverage and capital operations.</li>
<li><strong>&ldquo;A Random Walk Down Wall Street&rdquo;:</strong> Advocates investing in the broad market index (SPY), but CLEC believes that QQQ has more growth potential and combines leveraged funds and cash for asset allocation.</li>
<li><strong>Buffett:</strong> Buffett is the representative of value investing, requiring in-depth research on companies and industries, while CLEC believes that ordinary people do not need to have professional knowledge and only need to invest in index funds.</li>
<li><strong>&ldquo;Rich Dad, Poor Dad&rdquo;:</strong> Focuses on real estate investment, while CLEC believes that stock investment and capital operations are more efficient and does not recommend investing in real estate.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Investor Growth Process:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Beginner Stage:</strong> Learn and practice long-term investing principles, and don&rsquo;t panic and sell (already in the top 20% of the market).</li>
<li><strong>Advanced Stage:</strong> Learn and use leveraged funds and stock pledges (top 20% of the market).</li>
<li><strong>Advanced Stage:</strong> Proficient in stock pledges, cash flow management, and asset allocation, and fearless of market fluctuations (top 1% of the market).</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Core Investment Philosophy:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Mission:</strong> To awaken the capital awareness of ordinary people and help them achieve financial freedom, rather than for traffic and making money.</li>
<li><strong>Investment Target:</strong> Focus on investing in QQQ, believing in the long-term development of American technology.</li>
<li><strong>Leverage Use:</strong> Reasonably use leveraged funds (QLD) to magnify returns, but strictly control risk and avoid short-term operations.</li>
<li><strong>Smart Rebalancing:</strong> According to market ups and downs, dynamically adjust between QQQ and cash (or short-term bonds) to achieve &ldquo;buy low and sell high.&rdquo;</li>
<li><strong>Stock Pledge:</strong> Obtain cash flow through stock pledge to achieve &ldquo;consuming without selling stocks&rdquo; and ensure continuous asset appreciation.</li>
<li><strong>Simple and Effective:</strong> The investment strategy is simple and easy to understand, can be executed in the long term, does not require monitoring the market, and does not require stock picking.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Asset Allocation and Risk Management 
    <div id="asset-allocation-and-risk-management" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#asset-allocation-and-risk-management" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>
<p><strong>Importance of Asset Allocation:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Survival Guarantee:</strong> When the market fluctuates violently, reasonable asset allocation is the key to survival.</li>
<li><strong>Cash is King:</strong> Always maintain at least 20% of cash (or cash equivalents) to cope with emergencies and market declines.</li>
<li><strong>Dynamic Balance:</strong> Adjust between different asset classes according to market conditions to reduce risk and increase returns.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Importance of Long-Term Investing:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Market Trends:</strong> Firmly believe that the market will move upwards in the long run and do not predict short-term fluctuations.</li>
<li><strong>Patient Holding:</strong> Investing requires time and patience, and wealth accumulation takes time.</li>
<li><strong>Emotional Control:</strong> Not affected by market sentiment and short-term information, and maintain an optimistic attitude.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Risk Management:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Risk Awareness:</strong> Recognize the high risk of investment and be mentally prepared for a possible drop of 50% or even 70%.</li>
<li><strong>Survival First:</strong> The primary goal of investing is to &ldquo;stay alive&rdquo; rather than pursuing short-term high returns.</li>
<li><strong>Cash Reserve:</strong> Adequate cash reserve is the most effective means to cope with risks.</li>
<li><strong>Smart Rebalancing:</strong> When the market falls, use cash to buy more QQQ or QLD to lower the average cost.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Stock Pledge:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Core Strategy:</strong> Obtain cash flow through stock pledge for living expenses or other investments to achieve &ldquo;spending money without selling stocks.&rdquo;</li>
<li><strong>Advantages:</strong> Avoid selling high-quality assets and enjoy the benefits of continuous asset appreciation; achieve the ideal state of &ldquo;borrowing money forever, never repaying, and no interest.&rdquo;</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Other 
    <div id="other" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#other" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>About Group Discussions:</strong>
<ul>
<li><strong>Focus on the Topic:</strong> Group discussions should revolve around CLEC investment philosophy and strategies, and not discuss content beyond the scope.</li>
<li><strong>Avoid Misleading:</strong> Do not discuss newly issued ETFs or other investment targets that do not conform to CLEC investment principles.</li>
<li><strong>Answer Questions:</strong> The group owner and senior students should help new students answer questions.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">III. Q&amp;A Session 
    <div id="iii-qa-session" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii-qa-session" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Eason 
    <div id="eason" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#eason" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>
<p><strong>Sharing:</strong></p>
<ol>
<li><strong>A-share NASDAQ ETF Premium Issue:</strong> Elaborated in detail the fundamental reasons for the premium of domestic A-share NASDAQ ETFs (such as 513100, 159941, etc.):
<ul>
<li><strong>Foreign Exchange Control:</strong> China implements foreign exchange control, and each fund company has a state-approved quota. The quotas of old fund companies are usually tight, resulting in limited off-site subscriptions (suspension or limits), and investors can only turn to buying ETFs on the market, which pushes up on-site prices and forms a premium.</li>
<li><strong>Market Sentiment:</strong> The A-share market is easily affected by policies, hot spots, and other factors, and rapid capital flows can lead to violent fluctuations in the premium of the NASDAQ ETF. For example, when the market pursues other hot sectors, funds may withdraw from the NASDAQ ETF, leading to a decrease in the premium or even a discount.</li>
<li><strong>Long-Term Trends:</strong> In the long run, due to the existence of foreign exchange controls and investors&rsquo; continued optimism about the NASDAQ, the premium will exist for a long time. However, in the short term, the premium will be affected by market sentiment and capital flows.</li>
<li><strong>On-site and Off-site Differences:</strong> The same fund has different codes and trading methods on-site (exchange-traded funds, ETFs) and off-site (subscribed and redeemed through the fund company). Off-site subscriptions are usually based on the fund&rsquo;s net value, while on-site transaction prices are affected by supply and demand, which may result in premiums or discounts.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Impact on Investors:</strong> The premium of the A-share NASDAQ ETF is unfavorable to ordinary investors, especially buying at a higher premium, which increases the investment cost.</li>
<li><strong>Investment Recommendations:</strong>
<ul>
<li><strong>Long-Term Investing:</strong> If it is a long-term investment, there is no need to worry too much about short-term premium fluctuations.</li>
<li><strong>Be Cautious When the Premium is Too High:</strong> When the premium is too high (such as exceeding 10%), you can wait appropriately or consider other investment channels.</li>
<li><strong>Pay Attention to Discount Opportunities:</strong> When a discount occurs, it is a good time to buy.</li>
<li><strong>Open an Account in Hong Kong:</strong> If conditions permit, you can consider opening an account in Hong Kong to directly purchase US stock QQQ, avoiding premium problems, and you can also allocate leveraged funds (QLD).</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ol>
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo; Comments:</strong>
<ul>
<li>Fully agrees with the doctor&rsquo;s analysis that the premium problem of A-share NASDAQ ETF is indeed caused by factors such as foreign exchange controls and market sentiment.</li>
<li>Suggests that investors who are more sensitive to premiums or want greater investment flexibility can consider opening an account in Hong Kong.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Question 1:</strong> After Trump takes office again, will his domestic and foreign policies be very different from the past (including his first term), and will these changes shake the American system?</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo; Response:</strong>
<ul>
<li><strong>American Strength:</strong> Clearly stated that the United States is very strong and Trump will make the United States stronger.</li>
<li><strong>Quality of Political Officials:</strong> American political officials are very good, they are loyal to the country, and can give up personal interests for national interests (for example, many political officials come from Goldman Sachs and other Wall Street investment banks, giving up high-paying positions).</li>
<li><strong>International Situation:</strong> Touched on international issues without commenting too much to avoid controversy.</li>
<li><strong>Ukraine Issue:</strong> Believes that the Ukraine issue was caused by Zelensky, who should be responsible for the current situation in Ukraine. Implies that Ukraine is being used by the United States.</li>
<li><strong>Summary:</strong> Overall optimistic about the United States and Trump&rsquo;s policies, believing that the United States will continue to remain strong.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Belle 
    <div id="belle" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#belle" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing:</strong>
<ol>
<li><strong>Learning Experience:</strong> Shared in detail her learning journey following James to learn CLEC investment for 4-5 years, from a &ldquo;newbie&rdquo; who knew nothing about investment to gradually understanding and practicing long-term investment, leveraged funds, stock pledges, asset allocation, and other concepts, and finally realizing a change in mentality and improvement in investment skills.</li>
<li><strong>ChatGPT Application:</strong> Introduced how she input the learning content and personal experience of CLEC investment into ChatGPT (version 4.0) and obtained ChatGPT&rsquo;s in-depth analysis and summary of CLEC investment. She found that ChatGPT can not only understand the core strategy of CLEC investment, but also analyze her psychological changes and decision-making logic in the investment process.</li>
<li><strong>Comparison with Other Investment Methods:</strong> In the learning process, Belle also read other investment books and influencer viewpoints, but she found that many investment methods are either too complex or too one-sided, lacking systematicity and operability. She believes that CLEC investment provides a complete, clear, and executable investment system, which makes her full of confidence in future financial freedom.</li>
</ol>
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo; Comments:</strong>
<ul>
<li>Highly praised Belle&rsquo;s learning achievements and summarizing ability, believing that her understanding of CLEC investment is very accurate.</li>
<li>Expressed surprise and appreciation for ChatGPT&rsquo;s analysis results, believing that ChatGPT&rsquo;s understanding of CLEC investment even exceeded his own, which gave him a deeper understanding of the potential of AI.</li>
<li>Affirmed Belle&rsquo;s questioning skills.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">IM 
    <div id="im" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#im" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>
<p><strong>Sharing:</strong></p>
<ol>
<li><strong>Learning Experience:</strong> Shared his feelings about learning CLEC investment, believing that CLEC investment not only makes him feel at ease and confident about his future financial situation, but also makes him think more deeply about life.</li>
<li><strong>Case Observation:</strong> Shared his observation of a 70-year-old retiree. This old man had devoted his whole life to his family and work, but felt confused and empty after retirement, and did not know where his life value was.</li>
</ol>
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo; Comments:</strong>
<ul>
<li><strong>Dilemma of the Working Class:</strong> Pointed out that this is a common dilemma for many working-class people, who spend their whole lives working for others but neglect their own life goals and values.</li>
<li><strong>Awakening of Life:</strong> Emphasized the importance of awakening in life, realizing that you are not living for others but for yourself. Plan your life early and don&rsquo;t feel confused until retirement.</li>
<li><strong>Significance of Financial Freedom:</strong> Financial freedom is not only the accumulation of wealth, but also to obtain more time and freedom to pursue your life goals, to accompany your family, and to experience life.</li>
<li><strong>Living in the Present:</strong> Introduced the concept of &ldquo;mindfulness,&rdquo; that is, focusing on the present, reducing thoughts, and living in every moment, so as to obtain inner peace and happiness.</li>
<li><strong>Definition of Capitalist:</strong> Redefined the concept of &ldquo;capitalist,&rdquo; pointing out that true capitalists are those who do not need to work themselves and can obtain wealth through capital operation.</li>
<li><strong>Three Levels of Investment:</strong> Divided investors into three levels:
<ul>
<li><strong>Rich People:</strong> Obtain a certain amount of wealth through investment (such as index funds).</li>
<li><strong>Wealthy People:</strong> In addition to investment, they also know how to use leverage (such as credit, wealth management mortgages) to accelerate wealth accumulation.</li>
<li><strong>Tycoons:</strong> Master advanced capital operation techniques such as stock pledge to achieve &ldquo;consuming without selling stocks&rdquo; and continuous asset appreciation.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Social Contribution:</strong> Emphasized that although CLEC investors &ldquo;do not work hard,&rdquo; they make huge contributions to society through capital allocation.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Question:</strong> How to get along with people (especially family and friends) who do not understand the CLEC investment philosophy? They may think we are &ldquo;not doing our job&rdquo; or &ldquo;fond of ease and averse to labor.&rdquo;</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo; Response:</strong>
<ul>
<li><strong>Understand the Differences:</strong> Acknowledged that there are differences between the CLEC investment philosophy and traditional concepts, and it is normal not to be understood.</li>
<li><strong>Do Your Own Thing:</strong> Do not need to force others to understand, do your own investment well, and prove it with practical results.</li>
<li><strong>Patient Communication:</strong> If the other party is willing to understand, you can patiently explain the principles and advantages of CLEC investment.</li>
<li><strong>Share Resources:</strong> You can share James&rsquo; videos, articles, handouts, and other resources to give the other party a more comprehensive understanding of CLEC investment.</li>
<li><strong>Respect Choices:</strong> Respect everyone&rsquo;s choices, do not force, and do not argue.</li>
<li><strong>Example is Better Than Precept:</strong> Put it into practice yourself and live a life of financial freedom and spiritual freedom, which is the best demonstration.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Dave 
    <div id="dave" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#dave" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing:</strong>
<ol>
<li><strong>Responding to &ldquo;National QQQ&rdquo; Concerns:</strong> Some students worry that if everyone buys QQQ, will it lead to market imbalances or a decline in QQQ&rsquo;s returns. Dave pointed out that this concern is unnecessary.</li>
<li><strong>Small Market Value of QQQ:</strong> He provided data, pointing out that the market value of QQQ (about $300 billion) is very small (about 0.5%) relative to the total market value of the entire US stock market (about $62 trillion), and even if more people buy QQQ, it will not have a big impact on the market.</li>
<li><strong>The Choice of a Few:</strong> Emphasized that CLEC investors are a minority, not a majority, and the vast majority of investors will still choose other investment methods.</li>
</ol>
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo; Comments:</strong>
<ul>
<li>Fully agrees with Dave&rsquo;s point of view, and reiterated that the market value of QQQ is very small and CLEC investors are a minority.</li>
<li>Added that even if everyone comes to buy QQQ, there will be no problem because the market will automatically adjust.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Haoqing 
    <div id="haoqing" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#haoqing" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing:</strong>
<ol>
<li><strong>Economic Comparison between Taiwan and South Korea:</strong> Compared the economic development of Taiwan and South Korea, pointing out that Taiwan&rsquo;s economic growth mainly relies on a few technology companies such as TSMC, while South Korea&rsquo;s economy is more diversified, mainly dominated by large chaebols such as Samsung and Hyundai.</li>
<li><strong>&ldquo;Individual Stocks&rdquo; and &ldquo;ETFs&rdquo;:</strong> He believes that Taiwan&rsquo;s economic model is more like &ldquo;heavy positions in individual stocks&rdquo; (TSMC), while South Korea&rsquo;s chaebol model is more like &ldquo;investing in ETFs&rdquo; (containing multiple industries and companies).</li>
<li><strong>Taiwan&rsquo;s Worries:</strong> Worried that Taiwan is overly dependent on a single industry, and once TSMC has problems, it will have a great impact on Taiwan&rsquo;s economy.</li>
<li><strong>Impressions of South Korea:</strong> South Korea is unfriendly</li>
</ol>
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo; Comments:</strong>
<ul>
<li><strong>Agree with Observations:</strong> Agreed with Haoqing&rsquo;s observations on the economic models of Taiwan and South Korea.</li>
<li><strong>Taiwan&rsquo;s Advantages:</strong> Pointed out that Taiwan&rsquo;s soft power (such as talent, innovation ability, financial environment, etc.) is very strong, but compared with the United States, there is still a big gap.</li>
<li><strong>Focus on Yourself:</strong> Emphasized that Taiwan should focus on developing its own advantageous industries and improve its overall competitiveness, rather than comparing with other countries and regions.</li>
<li><strong>Importance of Capitalists:</strong> Reiterated that both individuals and countries should learn the thinking of capital operation and become capitalists, rather than relying solely on labor and production.</li>
<li><strong>Taiwan&rsquo;s Financial Environment:</strong> Believes that Taiwan&rsquo;s financial environment is very good, even better than the United States (such as low interest rates, no capital gains tax, etc.), providing good conditions for investors.</li>
<li><strong>No Need to Compare:</strong> Taiwan doesn&rsquo;t need to compare with other Asian little dragons.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Lina 
    <div id="lina" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#lina" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Question:</strong> Regarding the issues of AI regulation and AI fraud, how should ordinary people prevent it?
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo; Response:</strong>
<ul>
<li><strong>People Vulnerable to Fraud:</strong> Pointed out that elderly people, people who lack investment knowledge, and people who covet petty gains are more vulnerable to AI fraud.</li>
<li><strong>Preventive Measures:</strong>
<ul>
<li><strong>Do Not Click on Links Randomly:</strong> Do not click on links from unknown sources, especially those that claim to provide free benefits.</li>
<li><strong>Do Not Join Unknown Groups:</strong> Do not join investment groups, financial management groups, etc. from unknown sources.</li>
<li><strong>Do Not Covet Petty Gains:</strong> Do not believe in &ldquo;pie in the sky&rdquo; good things, and do not be tempted by promises of high returns and low risks.</li>
<li><strong>Verify from Multiple Parties:</strong> If you encounter suspicious investment opportunities, verify from multiple parties and consult professional opinions.</li>
<li><strong>Protect Personal Information:</strong> Do not easily disclose personal information, especially sensitive information such as bank accounts and passwords.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>AI Regulation Issues:</strong>
<ul>
<li><strong>OpenAI is Not Open:</strong> Pointed out that OpenAI&rsquo;s &ldquo;non-openness&rdquo; is a problem. The decision-making process of AI should be transparent to humans and accept human supervision.</li>
<li><strong>Honesty of AI:</strong> Believes that AI should be honest with humans and should not deceive humans.</li>
<li><strong>Necessity of Regulation:</strong> Emphasized the necessity of AI regulation, but how to regulate it specifically still needs further discussion.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Jason 
    <div id="jason" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#jason" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing:</strong>
<ol>
<li><strong>Organizing Manuscript:</strong> Shared the progress of organizing James&rsquo; videos and articles into a manuscript, which has been organized to the fifth chapter.</li>
<li><strong>Personal Gains:</strong>
<ul>
<li><strong>Deepen Understanding:</strong> Deepened his understanding of the CLEC investment philosophy by organizing the manuscript.</li>
<li><strong>Leave Information:</strong> Reduced his attention to financial news and market information and focused more on long-term investment.</li>
<li><strong>Focus on Life:</strong> Has more time and energy to invest in his hobbies and public welfare activities.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ol>
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo; Comments:</strong>
<ul>
<li>Highly affirmed and appreciated Jason&rsquo;s organizing work and personal growth.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question:</strong> For investors in mainland China who cannot purchase leveraged funds (QLD), is it possible to keep investing in QQQ at regular intervals? Is this method feasible?
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo; Response:</strong>
<ul>
<li><strong>Completely Feasible:</strong> For investors in mainland China, since they cannot purchase leveraged funds, the following strategies can be adopted:
<ul>
<li><strong>Office Workers:</strong>
<ul>
<li>Retain six months of emergency reserve funds (cash).</li>
<li>Invest all remaining funds in A-share NASDAQ ETFs (such as 513100, 159941, etc.).</li>
<li>Hold for the long term and invest regularly.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Retirees:</strong>
<ul>
<li>Adopt an 80/20 asset allocation (80% invested in A-share NASDAQ ETFs, 20% invested in cash or short-term bonds).</li>
<li>Rebalance regularly.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Advanced Strategies:</strong>
<ul>
<li><strong>Open an Account in Hong Kong:</strong> Suggests that after investing for a period of time (such as 3-5 years), if conditions permit, investors can consider opening an account in Hong Kong to directly purchase US stock QQQ and QLD and enjoy lower transaction fees and more flexible investment options.</li>
<li><strong>Gradual Transition:</strong> Gradually transfer A-share assets to a Hong Kong account to achieve a more optimized asset allocation.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Additional Notes:</strong></li>
<li>Keep it simple when you first start investing
*   If the child&rsquo;s account is not managed by him, you can invest in QLD</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Julie 
    <div id="julie" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#julie" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Question:</strong> Worries about inflation and the Fed&rsquo;s policies. Recently, US CPI data has risen, and the market is worried that the Fed will postpone interest rate cuts or even raise interest rates, which will negatively affect the stock market?
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo; Response:</strong>
<ul>
<li><strong>Relationship between Interest Rates and the Stock Market:</strong>
<ul>
<li><strong>No Obvious Correlation:</strong> Clearly pointed out that there is no obvious correlation between the 10-year US Treasury yield (TNX) and the trend of QQQ. Suggested that students can make their own graphs for comparison to verify this conclusion.</li>
<li><strong>Do Not Pay Too Much Attention:</strong> Do not pay too much attention to interest rates and the Fed&rsquo;s policies, as these factors have little impact on the long-term trend of the stock market.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>US Economic Prospects:</strong>
<ul>
<li><strong>Very Optimistic:</strong> Very optimistic about the US economic prospects, believing that the next four years (Trump&rsquo;s second term) will be better than any of the past four years.</li>
<li><strong>Reasons:</strong>
<ul>
<li><strong>Strong System:</strong> The United States has a strong political and economic system that can self-repair and adjust.</li>
<li><strong>Excellent Political Officials:</strong> Trump&rsquo;s government officials are very good and have the ability to cope with various challenges.</li>
<li><strong>Economic Policies:</strong> Trump&rsquo;s economic policies (such as tax cuts, trade protection, etc.) are conducive to the long-term development of the US economy.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Investment Recommendations:</strong>
<ul>
<li><strong>Hold for the Long Term:</strong> Continue to hold QQQ for the long term and do not be affected by short-term market fluctuations.</li>
<li><strong>Seize Opportunities:</strong> Do not miss the opportunity for the rapid development of the US economy, now is a good time to invest in the United States.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Mike 
    <div id="mike" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#mike" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing:</strong>
<ol>
<li><strong>TSMC Premium:</strong> Discussed the issue that TSMC&rsquo;s ADR (TSM) in the United States has a premium relative to the Taiwan parent stock (2330.TW).</li>
<li><strong>US Policies:</strong> Shared his views on US policies, believing that the United States is taking a series of measures to enhance its competitiveness.</li>
</ol>
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo; Comments:</strong>
<ul>
<li><strong>Reasons for the Premium:</strong>
<ul>
<li><strong>Market Differences:</strong> Premiums and discounts are normal phenomena between different markets, just like the price of the same commodity may be different in different stores.</li>
<li><strong>Capital Flows:</strong> The US market has more funds and institutional investors, and the demand for high-quality assets is higher, leading to price increases.</li>
<li><strong>Convenience:</strong> US investors are more inclined to buy familiar stocks in the local market, even if there is a premium.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Taiwan&rsquo;s Financial Opening:</strong> Believes that whether Taiwan&rsquo;s financial market is fully open has no direct relationship with TSMC&rsquo;s premium in the United States.</li>
<li><strong>TSMC&rsquo;s Strategy:</strong> Suggests that TSMC adopt a &ldquo;cold treatment&rdquo; strategy for the investment requirements of the United States and not easily give in.</li>
<li><strong>Affirm Mike:</strong> Affirmed Mike&rsquo;s insights and analytical skills.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Becky 
    <div id="becky" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#becky" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing:</strong>
<ol>
<li><strong>California Problems:</strong> Expressed dissatisfaction with the current situation in California, including severe homelessness, inefficient government, insufficient public services, high home insurance costs, and difficulty in reconstruction.</li>
<li><strong>Medicare Issues:</strong> Shared the difficulties encountered in helping family members apply for Medicare (federal health insurance), believing that the Medicare system is very complex and difficult for ordinary people to understand.</li>
</ol>
<ul>
<li><strong>James and Mike&rsquo;s Response:</strong></li>
<li><strong>Acknowledge the Problems:</strong>
<ul>
<li>Acknowledged that there are many problems in California, and these problems are real.</li>
<li>Pointed out that these problems are mainly caused by the mismanagement of the California governor and government.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>America Needs Reform:</strong>
<ul>
<li>Emphasized that the United States needs to be reformed, especially in government efficiency, public services, and health insurance.</li>
<li>Believes that the Trump administration is working hard to solve these problems.
- <strong>Side Effects of Capitalism:</strong></li>
<li>Pointed out that problems such as homelessness and wealth inequality are inherent defects of the capitalist system and cannot be completely avoided.</li>
<li>The goal of CLEC investment is to help people achieve financial freedom under the capitalist system and reduce the impact of these problems on individuals.
-   <strong>Importance of Personal Decisions:</strong></li>
<li>Emphasized that personal decisions in investment and life are very important.</li>
<li>Pointed out that the house being burned down was a mistake in personal investment decision-making (over-reliance on real estate).</li>
<li>Suggested that everyone learn CLEC investment and reduce risks through reasonable asset allocation.
-   <strong>Taiwan&rsquo;s Experience:</strong></li>
<li>Shared Taiwan&rsquo;s experience in taxation, medical care, public services, etc., believing that Taiwan&rsquo;s system is simpler and more efficient than the United States.</li>
<li>Believes that the United States can learn from Taiwan&rsquo;s experience.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">J 
    <div id="j" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#j" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Question:</strong> How to introduce the CLEC investment philosophy to my children aged 30-40? Are there any specific videos or materials that can be recommended to them so that they can quickly understand the core ideas of CLEC investment?
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo; Response:</strong>
<ul>
<li><strong>Understand the Needs:</strong> Recognized that introducing CLEC investment to young people requires a more concise and direct approach.</li>
<li><strong>Consider Special Lectures:</strong> Considered making a special lecture on &ldquo;From Rich to Wealthy to Tycoon,&rdquo; focusing on explaining the key differences and transformation methods between these three stages.</li>
<li><strong>Emphasize &ldquo;No Income&rdquo;:</strong> Emphasized the importance of &ldquo;how to get yourself no income,&rdquo; which is a key step in achieving financial freedom.</li>
<li><strong>Follow-up Plans:</strong> Expressed that he would seriously consider this issue and launch related teaching content as soon as possible.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">IV. Wonderful Quotes 
    <div id="iv-wonderful-quotes" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv-wonderful-quotes" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>Investing is very simple, but not easy, not easy.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>Emphasizes the importance of learning and understanding investment concepts, which requires time and patience, and should not be rushed.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Happiness is a gift, wealth is a human right. Financial freedom is a right that everyone should have.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>Emphasizes the importance of financial freedom, encouraging everyone to pursue financial freedom, which is a right and an attitude towards life.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Let him be strong, the breeze caresses the mountains. Let him hate, the bright moon creates the great river. Let him be ruthless, let him be evil, I have enough true energy in one breath.
&ndash; Jin Yong</p></blockquote>
<p>When discussing the economic comparison between Taiwan and South Korea, James quoted Jin Yong&rsquo;s poems, emphasizing focusing on one&rsquo;s own development, not comparing with others, and doing one&rsquo;s own thing best.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>My destiny is determined by me, not by heaven.
&ndash; Nezha</p></blockquote>
<p>Emphasizes the autonomy of life, fate is in one&rsquo;s own hands, and should not be influenced by external factors.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>What is the final decision of the success of life? How many people love you?
&ndash; Munger
Emphasizes the importance of interpersonal relationships, money is not everything in life, love and being loved are the most important.</p></blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>Borrow money forever, never repay, no interest.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>The core concept of stock pledge, achieving financial freedom through borrowing, while assets continue to appreciate, which is an advanced strategy of CLEC investment.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>American warships have cannons, and the bullets don&rsquo;t cost money.
&ndash;James</p></blockquote>
<p>Taiwan&rsquo;s financial investment environment is better than that of the United States. The cost of borrowing is low, and the investment environment is more favorable.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>How to get yourself no income? It is a kind of wisdom and a kind of ability.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>Emphasizes the importance of reducing taxable income through legal means, which is a key step in achieving financial freedom and a kind of wisdom.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Homelessness is a side effect of capitalism.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>While capitalism brings economic development, it also leads to problems such as wealth inequality and homelessness, which cannot be completely avoided.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">V. Summary 
    <div id="v-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#v-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This episode contains a lot of information. Through ChatGPT&rsquo;s analysis, James systematically elaborated on the concepts, strategies, and advantages of CLEC investment, and compared it with traditional investment education and influencer financial management. At the same time, it also deeply discussed important topics such as investor growth paths, asset allocation, risk management, and cash flow management, and answered various questions raised by students regarding the A-share NASDAQ premium, the American political economy, AI regulation, and personal financial planning.</p>
<p>James emphasized that long-term investing, focusing on indices, reasonably using leverage, doing a good job of asset allocation, maintaining cash flow, living in the present, and pursuing financial freedom and spiritual freedom are the core ideas of CLEC investment. He encouraged everyone to learn and practice CLEC investment and achieve financial freedom and control their lives through their own efforts.</p>

  



<div
  
    class="flex px-4 py-3 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900"
  >

  <span
    
      class="text-primary-400 ltr:pr-3 rtl:pl-3 flex items-center"
    >

    

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M506.3 417l-213.3-364c-16.33-28-57.54-28-73.98 0l-213.2 364C-10.59 444.9 9.849 480 42.74 480h426.6C502.1 480 522.6 445 506.3 417zM232 168c0-13.25 10.75-24 24-24S280 154.8 280 168v128c0 13.25-10.75 24-23.1 24S232 309.3 232 296V168zM256 416c-17.36 0-31.44-14.08-31.44-31.44c0-17.36 14.07-31.44 31.44-31.44s31.44 14.08 31.44 31.44C287.4 401.9 273.4 416 256 416z"/></svg>

  </span>


  </span>

  <span
    
      class="dark:text-neutral-300"
    ><strong>Disclaimer:</strong> This article is only a personal study note and does not constitute any investment advice.</span>
</div>

]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>00502 Financial Leverage: How to Maximize Asset Allocation Returns? The Market Has No Lows, Only Highs: How to Escape Wrong Timing Strategies?</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1739684105629/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1739684105629/</guid><description>This episode mainly revolves around topics such as investment philosophy, asset allocation, insurance selection, and retirement planning, emphasizing long-term investment and overcoming human nature.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<lite-youtube videoid="dv2AJ4sVgfQ" playlabel="dv2AJ4sVgfQ" params=""></lite-youtube>



<h2 class="relative group">I. Current Theme 
    <div id="i-current-theme" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-current-theme" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This episode mainly discusses the following core themes:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Investing in Humanity for the Long Term:</strong> Emphasizing that the essence of investment is investing in the development of the entire human society, rather than short-term market fluctuations or individual company financial reports.</li>
<li><strong>Overcoming Human Weaknesses:</strong> Investors need to overcome human weaknesses such as fear and greed, and maintain extreme optimism and a long-term perspective.</li>
<li><strong>Importance of Asset Allocation:</strong> Recommend different asset allocation strategies for different age groups and financial situations, such as the 442, 433, or 80/20 principles.</li>
<li><strong>Avoiding Financial Scams:</strong> Exposing financial scams and insurance traps under the capitalist system, reminding investors to be vigilant.</li>
<li><strong>Cancel Insurance Early:</strong> Strongly recommend canceling all insurance policies, unless it is term life insurance for the family&rsquo;s primary income earner with minor children.</li>
<li><strong>Sell Property Early:</strong> Suggest selling property and investing the funds in index funds for higher returns.</li>
<li><strong>Asset Pledging:</strong> Discussing how to obtain funds through asset pledging and use them for investment to improve overall returns.</li>
<li><strong>Attitude Towards Evangelists:</strong> Like Christian missionaries, convey investment ideas without forcing others to accept them.</li>
<li><strong>Importance of Cash:</strong> Asset allocation should include at least 20% cash.</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">II. Briefing Content 
    <div id="ii-briefing-content" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii-briefing-content" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">1. Investment Philosophy 
    <div id="1-investment-philosophy" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#1-investment-philosophy" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Investing in Humanity&rsquo;s Financial Reports:</strong> Instead of looking at individual company financial reports and short-term economic situations, focus on the development trend of the entire human race over thousands of years. Invest in indexes, looking at the performance of all of humanity.</li>
<li><strong>Investors Are Always Extremely Optimistic:</strong> Investment requires long-term optimism, believing that the market will eventually rise.</li>
<li><strong>Overcoming Human Nature, Looking at the Market with a Cold Eye:</strong> Investors must overcome human weaknesses and not be affected by short-term market fluctuations. Need to practice remaining calm in the face of a tiger, believing there is glass in front of you, believing there is a safety net, no matter how the market falls.</li>
<li><strong>Understanding the Demons and Monsters of Capitalism:</strong> Recognize financial scams, insurance traps, and the government&rsquo;s wrong policies under the capitalist system, and avoid being exploited. Capitalism is efficient, but has side effects, coupled with financial industry scams, deception, and government collusion or wrong policies.</li>
<li><strong>Wealth is a Talent, and It Can Come True:</strong> The capitalist system allows everyone to have the opportunity to get rich, but requires correct knowledge and strategies. The education system is cultivating slave labor, while the financial industry is exploiting human weaknesses to sell fear. You can listen to Li Lu&rsquo;s speech to understand the difference between investment and speculation.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">2. Asset Allocation 
    <div id="2-asset-allocation" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#2-asset-allocation" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Young People:</strong> Young people who are still working should directly invest in the Nasdaq 100 index fund (QQQ) and consider using leveraged funds to increase returns. Young people must increase returns, there is no other choice, try to buy leveraged funds.</li>
<li><strong>Retirees:</strong>
<ul>
<li>Insufficient Assets: Take other strategies.</li>
<li>Sufficient Assets: Choose different asset allocation strategies depending on whether there is stock pledging and whether there are other income sources.
<ul>
<li><strong>No Pledging, Need to Withdraw Money from Assets:</strong> 80/20 principle (80% index funds, 20% cash).</li>
<li><strong>With Pledging, No Need to Withdraw Money from Stock Assets:</strong> 442 principle (40% index funds, 40% leveraged funds, 20% cash).</li>
<li><strong>No Pledging, No Other Income:</strong> 433 principle. If there is no other income, and you need to withdraw money from assets, only 80/20. Have stock pledging, do not need to withdraw money from assets to use 442.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Emergency Fund:</strong> Use 00864B as an emergency fund to cope with unexpected situations.</li>
<li><strong>About Loans:</strong>
<ul>
<li>All loans must be able to be repaid from salary or stable cash flow.</li>
<li>Try to pay off loans before retirement.</li>
<li>If there is a mortgage that has not been paid off after retirement, part of the funds can be invested in high-dividend ETFs (such as 0056), and the dividends used to pay the mortgage interest, with the remaining funds used for investment. For example, borrow NT$10 million, with an interest rate of 2.78%, and no repayment is required for 20 years. The annual interest is NT$278,000, requiring NT$4.5 million to be placed in 0056, because 0056 has a 6% dividend yield, and the remaining NT$5.5 million is added to the 433 or 442 allocation. If there is also rental income, you can use 442.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">3. Insurance 
    <div id="3-insurance" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#3-insurance" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Strongly Recommend Canceling All Insurance:</strong> Most insurance policies are scams, exploiting human weaknesses to sell fear.</li>
<li><strong>Term Life Insurance:</strong> If you are the family&rsquo;s primary income earner and have minor children, you can purchase term life insurance to protect the family&rsquo;s financial security in the event of an accident. Only buy term life insurance that is purchased once a year, which is cheaper. If your assets reach 20-30 million, you don&rsquo;t need to insure anymore.</li>
<li><strong>Funds from Redeeming Insurance:</strong> Invest in index funds to obtain higher returns.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">4. Property 
    <div id="4-property" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#4-property" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Not Recommended to Purchase Property:</strong> Houses are fixed assets, lack liquidity, and have high risks. Taichung Shin Kong Mitsukoshi will close down, and real estate will too. If you buy a house to live in for 60 years, and are forced to live in the same house for 60 years, that&rsquo;s strange.</li>
<li><strong>Sell Property:</strong> Suggest selling property and investing the funds in index funds to obtain higher returns.</li>
<li><strong>Rich People Buy Houses:</strong> Only after becoming rich can you buy houses as casually as buying slippers.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">5. Other 
    <div id="5-other" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#5-other" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Convert Roth IRA:</strong> Don&rsquo;t wait for the market to fall before converting to a Roth IRA, do what needs to be done as soon as possible. January 1st and 2nd may be the lowest points of this year.</li>
<li><strong>Overcoming Human Nature:</strong> In the face of market fluctuations, stay optimistic, eat well, sleep well, and have no worries.</li>
<li><strong>AI and Tech Development:</strong> The development of AI may promote exponential growth in U.S. stocks, with long-term returns expected.</li>
<li><strong>Longevity Risk:</strong> Need to consider the financial risks brought about by longevity and plan ahead. Need to plan to live to 120 years old.</li>
<li><strong>Children&rsquo;s Education:</strong> The focus should be on letting children learn happily and explore life goals, not just to make money.</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">III. Q&amp;A Session 
    <div id="iii-qa-session" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii-qa-session" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Xiaoxia 
    <div id="xiaoxia" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#xiaoxia" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question 1: The family income is divided between husband and wife. Is the 433 or 442 asset allocation based on the husband or the family income?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Response: It depends on each family&rsquo;s situation. If it is centrally managed or centrally thought out, you can think in the thinking mode of the whole family, depending on whether you understand the financial situation of the whole family. If the husband is more conservative and mostly in cash, the wife can be more aggressive and buy leveraged funds to balance it.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2: My son is studying abroad, and the monthly expenses are NT$40,000. How should I include this in the expenses?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Response: Treat this expense as a fixed deposit asset, deduct it directly from 00864B, and separate it from investment assets. This part will be spent this year and cannot be regarded as an investment asset. Transfer it directly to 00864B so that it will not be affected by market fluctuations for at least one year.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Feida 
    <div id="feida" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#feida" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question: Currently holding 00662 and 00670L, allocated in an 80/20 ratio, and not withdrawing money from stock assets, do I need to adjust to 442?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Response: If you need money, you can consider using credit, and then use the extra money you borrowed to allocate to 442. Borrow money, buy stocks with NT$1 million borrowed, and put NT$1 million in cash. Switching to 442 immediately will increase your return through two-tenths of the cash. Ask how much you can borrow. If the bank dares to lend, don&rsquo;t be afraid.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question: If gradually adjusting to 442, how to arrange the buying order?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Response: Sell 00662 and convert to 00670L, as long as the total asset beta value is 1.2, the rate of return will remain unchanged. If you can take out a loan, take out the loan as soon as possible and adjust to 442 immediately. Hurry up and borrow, change it immediately.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Grace 
    <div id="grace" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#grace" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question: Trump may carry out tax reform. Should I suspend converting to a Roth IRA?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Response: Do what needs to be done first, don&rsquo;t wait. Trump&rsquo;s policies will not have a big impact in the short term, and you can change your strategy after he signs it. Trump has a lot of things to do, and the tax exemption for Social Security isn&rsquo;t signed yet.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Sara 
    <div id="sara" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#sara" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question 1: How did you come to the conclusion that you may live to 120 years old in the future?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Response: Now technology is developing rapidly, many diseases can be treated, and parents&rsquo; genes also have an impact, so living to 120 years old is expected.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2: How do you view the possibility of exponential growth in U.S. stocks after the AI breakout?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Response: U.S. stocks have always had exponential growth, and now because of AI, the annualized return may be higher in the future. It used to be 6%, then it jumped to 8% when the steam engine and electricity appeared, then it jumped to 12-14% when the Internet appeared, and now it may jump to 25% because of AI.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Summer 
    <div id="summer" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#summer" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question: I bought an investment property in the Bay Area. Should I sell it now?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Response: Sell it immediately. The later you wait, the greater the loss. Non-Americans who buy American houses pay very high taxes, and the estate tax is also very high, which is not cost-effective. If your child plans to study in the United States in the future, then wait until you need it. If you buy it, you will earn money in the future, and your taxes will be very high, and 1/3 will be taken away first. The asset estate tax is 40%, and the tax exemption is only 60,000.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Jia 
    <div id="jia" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#jia" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question 1: Is it possible to borrow Japanese yen through Interactive Brokers to spend?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Response: It&rsquo;s better to borrow Japanese yen to invest in U.S. stocks, just like Buffett, so there is no exchange rate risk. Just spend the money you can afford to spend now.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2: Is it worth it for a 15-year-old child to work at McDonald&rsquo;s to open a Roth IRA?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Response: A 15-year-old child should study hard and live a happy life. Making money is not what they should be doing now. They should be taught how to manage money.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Jenny 
    <div id="jenny" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#jenny" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question 1: If the bank wants to liquidate debts after asset pledging, will the stocks be sold?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Response: The bank will not ask you to repay the money. The debt can be divided. The heirs inherit the assets and inherit the debts at the same time. Putting the account in a trust can also avoid a certification. After putting it in the trust, you can save on probate, just follow the trust. Trust just avoids probation.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2: Recent retirees have property and savings. Do they need to open a Rollover IRA?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Response: If they refuse to sell the property, there is no way to help them with financial planning. Sell the property, put it in a brokerage account, and live on 80/20 borrowing is fine.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 3: Children&rsquo;s company stocks are doing well. Should they be sold to buy QQQ?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Response: If you sell employee stocks now and earn 50,000 tax-free, you can slowly transfer them; otherwise, exchange for QQQ when you have income.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 4: How can I get the kids to take the money they earn to buy QQQ?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Response: This guy is already addicted to drugs, it&rsquo;s very difficult to quit. Encourage him to invest more money, match as much as you can in the brokerage account, and see if they are willing to do what you say. You can encourage children to invest more money into the brokerage account.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Max 
    <div id="max" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#max" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question: How to prevent elders in the countryside from being tempted by insurance agents and keep holding stocks?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Response: Keep in touch, accompany him, and cheer him up. Join the group, and everyone can help him analyze and answer his questions. You can transfer the stocks to a Yuanta Securities pledging account, but don&rsquo;t pledge them, so you can&rsquo;t buy or sell them, and there is an emergency available amount. Tell him that it has been pledged and there is no cash.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Christina 
    <div id="christina" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#christina" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question 1: How to open a Roth IRA account for a child who works part-time in high school?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Response: Find Lisa to open an account, either online or in the office, and open an account in the child&rsquo;s name. If you want to see the account online, you need to sign for power of attorney.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2: How to join Chen Feng and Naixin&rsquo;s group?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Response: There is a link on the message board. You can only join with a LINE registered with a Taiwanese mobile phone number. You can also add Peter&rsquo;s and the doctor&rsquo;s WeChat.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Shufen (Sharing) 
    <div id="shufen-sharing" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#shufen-sharing" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Because insurance was cancelled and entered QQQ (525), I wasn&rsquo;t too worried even after the price dropped.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Response: Thumbs up</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Grace (Sharing) 
    <div id="grace-sharing" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#grace-sharing" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: After listening to James, I bought QQQ and have a large sum of money now. Now I&rsquo;ve started asking my son to buy QQQ, and a masseuse who heard her sharing also wants to learn about investing.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Comment: Very happy to have helped more people.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chen Feng (Sharing) 
    <div id="chen-feng-sharing" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chen-feng-sharing" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Relatives and friends have become interested in investing due to continuous persuasion. Investment itself is psychology, and if the 80/20 allocation doesn&rsquo;t work, the mental account doesn&rsquo;t work.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Response: The 20% cash in asset allocation is very important, to preach, whether or not someone understands is their business.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">IV. Wonderful Views 
    <div id="iv-wonderful-views" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv-wonderful-views" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>Investors can only be extremely optimistic, there is no other way. Investors always influence the sunshine, the market will eventually rise, investment requires patience, and wealth is worth waiting for.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p><em>Background: This is a summary of investor mentality, emphasizing the confidence and patience of long-term investment.</em></p>
<blockquote>
<p>The world is unfair. I always say that one day, two lives, three lucks, heaven is your DNA, this is impossible, life is which country you were born in, this is life.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p><em>Background: When discussing his feelings about traveling to Egypt, he expressed his feelings about the unfairness of the world, and that fate is different when you are born in different places.</em></p>
<blockquote>
<p>Correct you immediately if you are wrong, the later you wait, the greater your loss.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p><em>Background: Emphasized that in investment decisions, if you find an error, correct it in time, do not hesitate, and cause greater losses.</em></p>
<blockquote>
<p>Young people who are still working should directly invest in the Nasdaq 100 index fund, there is no other choice, because you must increase your returns, right?
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p><em>Background: Aiming at young investors, it is recommended to invest heavily in the Nasdaq 100 index fund to obtain higher returns.</em></p>
<blockquote>
<p>Now in the United States, the leader is the Joint Group will speak a possible place where it is possible to have to expand all the full amount to buy a house, because you can&rsquo;t buy insurance, the United States if you can&rsquo;t buy insurance that can only buy a full amount of housing.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p><em>Background: Shared the potential risks of the US real estate market. In some areas, houses may be difficult to sell due to insurance issues.</em></p>
<blockquote>
<p>Capitalism itself is a fair, just, and open system, but everyone is using this system to say things that are seemingly true.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p><em>Background: Pointed out the problems of the capitalist system, which is that it is used by some people for financial scams and transfer of benefits.</em></p>
<blockquote>
<p>Financial management is a scam to me, and insurance is also a scam.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p><em>Background: He bluntly expressed his views on financial management products and insurance, believing that many of them use human weaknesses to commit fraud.</em></p>
<blockquote>
<p>If you are tormented by the market for a long time, then you need to think about whether your position is too heavy? Or are you not suitable for investing at all?
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p><em>Background: Reminded investors that if they are affected by market fluctuations for a long time, they should reflect on whether their positions are too heavy, or whether they are suitable for investing.</em></p>
<blockquote>
<p>Redeem all insurance, and then unless your children are very small, buy term life insurance, which is to buy it once a year, buy one every year.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p><em>Background: Re-emphasized the choice of insurance, and that term life insurance is only needed in special circumstances.</em></p>


<h2 class="relative group">V. Summary 
    <div id="v-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#v-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>In this episode, James emphasized the importance of long-term investment, overcoming human weaknesses, avoiding financial scams and unnecessary risks, and adopting appropriate asset allocation strategies to achieve wealth growth. At the same time, he reminded everyone that investment is a process that requires continuous learning and companionship.</p>

  



<div
  
    class="flex px-4 py-3 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900"
  >

  <span
    
      class="text-primary-400 ltr:pr-3 rtl:pl-3 flex items-center"
    >

    

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M506.3 417l-213.3-364c-16.33-28-57.54-28-73.98 0l-213.2 364C-10.59 444.9 9.849 480 42.74 480h426.6C502.1 480 522.6 445 506.3 417zM232 168c0-13.25 10.75-24 24-24S280 154.8 280 168v128c0 13.25-10.75 24-23.1 24S232 309.3 232 296V168zM256 416c-17.36 0-31.44-14.08-31.44-31.44c0-17.36 14.07-31.44 31.44-31.44s31.44 14.08 31.44 31.44C287.4 401.9 273.4 416 256 416z"/></svg>

  </span>


  </span>

  <span
    
      class="dark:text-neutral-300"
    ><strong>Disclaimer:</strong> This article is only a personal study note and does not constitute any investment advice.</span>
</div>

]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>00494 Leveraging Debt for Wealth: A New Approach to Retirement Planning; Unlocking Family Assets: Combining Equity-Release Mortgages with Index Funds</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1733617616782/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1733617616782/</guid><description>In this session, James discusses the utilization of revolving line of credit home loans, investment philosophy, how to overcome the psychological pressure brought on by market fluctuations, and how to extract wisdom from life experiences. He emphasizes the importance of long-term and value investing, reiterating the investment philosophy of &amp;#39;buy when you have money, never sell.&amp;#39; He also addresses questions from students regarding leveraged funds, price-to-earnings ratios, and newly issued ETFs.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<lite-youtube videoid="g4KoDgPDNjs" playlabel="g4KoDgPDNjs" params=""></lite-youtube>



<h2 class="relative group">I. Main Topic 
    <div id="i-main-topic" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-main-topic" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This session revolves around investment and life wisdom. The core idea is to maintain a long-term perspective on investments, avoid being influenced by short-term market fluctuations, and continuously learn from life experiences to form one&rsquo;s own investment philosophy and life wisdom.  Just like life, investment also requires continuous learning and reflection.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">II. Presentation Content 
    <div id="ii-presentation-content" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii-presentation-content" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Utilizing Revolving Line of Credit Home Loans 
    <div id="utilizing-revolving-line-of-credit-home-loans" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#utilizing-revolving-line-of-credit-home-loans" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>People nearing retirement can consider using a revolving line of credit home loan (HELOC), treating the credit line as a part of their cash reserves for living expenses without touching the principal investment, thereby increasing overall asset returns.  For example, if someone has $40 million in retirement funds and obtains a $10 million HELOC, the total assets become $50 million, and the annual disposable funds increase from $800,000 to $1 million.</li>
<li>The HELOC credit line can supplement the 20% cash portion of asset allocation.</li>
<li>Note: It&rsquo;s easier to obtain a HELOC before retirement; it becomes more difficult afterward. The loan term typically doesn&rsquo;t exceed age 90.</li>
<li>It&rsquo;s not recommended to take out a loan after retirement to repay the HELOC.</li>
<li>A listener shared a strategy of using a HELOC for living expenses, which James considers a good option.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Investment Philosophy and Market Analysis 
    <div id="investment-philosophy-and-market-analysis" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#investment-philosophy-and-market-analysis" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>The market, like life, requires a long-term perspective to see the big picture. Avoid being misled by short-term fluctuations.</li>
<li>In the age of AI, human development will accelerate, and the market will continue to rise. The next two to three decades will be a period of prosperity. QQQ might reach $500,000.</li>
<li>Focus on long-term trends in investing. Don&rsquo;t be swayed by short-term market analysts or news.  Focus on long-term growth, not short-term gains.</li>
<li>If you can&rsquo;t withstand a 50% loss, it&rsquo;s not recommended to enter the market.</li>
<li>Invest in Nasdaq 100 index funds (QQQ), unless retirement funds are insufficient.</li>
<li>Short-term declines are inevitable. Be mentally prepared and maintain sufficient cash reserves.</li>
<li>Reiterates the long-term investment strategy of &ldquo;buy when you have money, never sell,&rdquo; and recommends single lump-sum market price purchases.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Extracting Life Wisdom 
    <div id="extracting-life-wisdom" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#extracting-life-wisdom" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Strive for daily progress, reflect and summarize regularly (daily, monthly, yearly). Extract life philosophy from experiences and store them in your personal &ldquo;database&rdquo; to continuously accumulate wisdom.</li>
<li>Reflect on everything, from trivial matters (like growing tomatoes) to major social events, to form a comprehensive outlook on life and investment philosophy.</li>
<li>Learn from past experiences. Reflect on what you would do differently if given a second chance to improve yourself.</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">III. Q&amp;A Session 
    <div id="iii-qa-session" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii-qa-session" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Michael 
    <div id="michael" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#michael" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question 1: How to use the smart rebalancing strategy before retirement?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: As long as you hold leveraged funds, you can use the smart rebalancing strategy.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2: How to calculate the Beta value of a portfolio holding TQQQ, QQQ, and cash?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: Calculate the weighted average based on the proportion of each asset and its corresponding Beta value (cash is 0, QQQ is 1, TQQQ is 3). He reshared the calculation formula with the audience.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Louis Lu 
    <div id="louis-lu" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#louis-lu" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Expressed admiration for James&rsquo;s insights from a month prior regarding the possibility of Bitcoin becoming a reserve currency for the US dollar, noting that James&rsquo;s response aligned with Federal Reserve Chairman Powell&rsquo;s views.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Comment:  Expressed gratitude for the acknowledgment and mentioned that it&rsquo;s a fundamental concept in finance and monetary policy, covered in previous lessons.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Shu Fen 
    <div id="shu-fen" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#shu-fen" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing:  Shared her experience of investing most of her retirement funds in savings insurance a few years ago, resulting in much lower returns than expected. This year, she redeemed a portion of the funds and invested in QQQ, achieving better returns (13.68% in three months). However, with the current market reaching new highs, she&rsquo;s hesitant to invest further, finding it difficult to overcome the psychological barrier of &ldquo;buying with eyes closed.&rdquo;
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Comment: Courage comes from the subconscious and requires training.  Believe that the market will continue to rise and practice self-hypnosis to reinforce the &ldquo;buy when you have money&rdquo; concept. Used the example of QQQ potentially reaching $500,000 to illustrate that the current price is still very cheap.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Sen Lin 
    <div id="sen-lin" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#sen-lin" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question: What&rsquo;s the difference between 00662 and QQQ?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply:  Suggested referring to the relevant link, as this question has been answered multiple times to avoid redundant explanations.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Yi Wan 
    <div id="yi-wan" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#yi-wan" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Agreed with James&rsquo;s investment method but hesitated to share it with older or same-age individuals. Felt more comfortable sharing with younger people, such as encouraging students to start saving $50-$100 per month.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Comment: Sharing depends on缘分 (affinity/serendipity).  Sometimes our remedy is another&rsquo;s poison. Sharing can also have negative consequences.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Zai 
    <div id="zai" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#zai" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Responded to Shu Fen&rsquo;s question about lump-sum buying, suggesting buying in batches or on specific dates, such as birthdays, to overcome psychological barriers.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Comment: Investing requires reaching a state of belief.  Continuous self-hypnosis is needed.  &ldquo;Buy immediately at market price when you have money&rdquo; is the only truth, no further analysis needed.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Ai Na 
    <div id="ai-na" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ai-na" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: After following James&rsquo;s advice, she redeemed funds from savings insurance and invested in QQQ and QLD. However, due to insufficient trading frequency, she couldn&rsquo;t purchase QQQ 2D. Her current living expenses are primarily covered by alimony, and the cost of living in Taiwan is relatively low.</li>
<li>Question 1: Does she need to buy and sell repeatedly to meet the trading frequency requirement?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: Yes, she can make small, frequent trades to meet the brokerage&rsquo;s requirements.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2: Can she buy fractional shares in Taiwan?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: Yes, but it&rsquo;s recommended to buy whole shares first and use the remaining funds for fractional shares.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 3: How to calculate retirement fund needs?  Can she receive social security?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: Calculate retirement fund needs based on annual expenses. Alimony can be considered income, but it&rsquo;s recommended to claim social security (even if her ex-husband objects) and adjust the asset allocation ratio accordingly, as alimony is not a permanent income source. She needs to be prepared.  Also recommended switching from SWVXX to BOXX.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chen Feng 
    <div id="chen-feng" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chen-feng" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Shared his personal investment journey, starting from entering the stock market in 2021, experiencing the &ldquo;bruised and battered&rdquo; phase of short-term trading, to shifting to long-term investing after encountering James&rsquo;s channel. He also established a study group of nearly 300 people, experiencing the benefits of &ldquo;teaching and learning from each other.&rdquo; He shared how he introduced the investment philosophy to his sister with 30 years of stock market experience, emphasizing the importance of a gradual approach.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Comment: Affirmed PC&rsquo;s sharing, adding the principles of &ldquo;Buddha saves those who are destined&rdquo; and &ldquo;Sentient beings save the Buddha.&rdquo;  When sharing investment concepts with family, start with small amounts of capital, like planting seeds and nurturing them gradually.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Nai Xi 
    <div id="nai-xi" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#nai-xi" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Thanked James and her friend Yu Sheng for their help.  Shared experiences of learning and sharing investment concepts with friends and expressed gratitude for the study group.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Comment: Shared his early investment experience in 1990, being introduced to investing by his friend Frank, who patiently explained investment knowledge to him weekly, eventually igniting his passion for investing.  Emphasized the importance of mentors.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">IM 
    <div id="im" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#im" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Felt that James is cultivating logical thinking in students and shared experiences of communicating investment concepts with others.</li>
<li>Question 1: How did James achieve such a comprehensive understanding?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: Continuously review and summarize life experiences, extracting the essence, like refining an elixir.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2: How to communicate with people who believe &ldquo;the first $1 million is difficult&rdquo; and are hesitant to go all in?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: Guide them to think about how to achieve the first $1 million goal and the path to wealth.  Suggest small investments based on their risk tolerance, like planting seeds, to gradually cultivate investment confidence.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Hao Qing 
    <div id="hao-qing" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#hao-qing" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing 1: Discussed the psychological pressure of buying after a stock reaches new highs. Experienced investors feel more pressure due to having reference points, while newcomers are more receptive. Like buying discounted items in a supermarket, having the original price as a reference makes purchasing more appealing.</li>
<li>Sharing 2: Shared his views on two newly issued ETFs by Invesco (QBI and QQLV) and compared them to QQQ. QBI selects larger market cap stocks from QQQ, while QQLV selects stocks with lower volatility.</li>
<li>Question: What are James&rsquo;s views on these two new ETFs?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: Doesn&rsquo;t recommend investing in unfamiliar ETFs, even if they perform well.  Stick to investments within your circle of competence.  Used the analogy of marriage, advising to choose a partner you understand. Re-emphasized the importance of focusing on asset allocation and Beta adjustments rather than selecting new investment targets.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">IV. Key Takeaways 
    <div id="iv-key-takeaways" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv-key-takeaways" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>Buy immediately at market price when you have money.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>This is James&rsquo;s repeatedly emphasized investment philosophy, aiming to overcome investors&rsquo; psychological barriers and seize market opportunities.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Life shouldn&rsquo;t be lived in vain.  Continuously reflect, summarize, and extract wisdom from experiences.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>This is not just investment wisdom, but life wisdom.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Teaching and learning promote each other. Buddha saves sentient beings, and sentient beings save the Buddha.
&ndash; James, Chen Feng</p></blockquote>
<p>Both teachers and students can grow through the process of teaching and sharing.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The seed itself is not the problem, it&rsquo;s the soil.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>An analogy for the dissemination of investment philosophy. Even good ideas require the right environment to take root.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">V. Summary 
    <div id="v-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#v-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This session covered investment philosophy, financial management skills, and life wisdom.  James reiterated the importance of long-term and value investing and encouraged everyone to overcome the psychological pressure of market fluctuations, firmly implementing the &ldquo;buy when you have money, never sell&rdquo; strategy. He also reminded everyone to continuously learn and extract wisdom from life experiences to ultimately achieve financial freedom and fulfill life&rsquo;s value. He also encouraged listeners to find their own mentors, learn from each other, and grow together, just like his early experiences.</p>

  



<div
  
    class="flex px-4 py-3 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900"
  >

  <span
    
      class="text-primary-400 ltr:pr-3 rtl:pl-3 flex items-center"
    >

    

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M506.3 417l-213.3-364c-16.33-28-57.54-28-73.98 0l-213.2 364C-10.59 444.9 9.849 480 42.74 480h426.6C502.1 480 522.6 445 506.3 417zM232 168c0-13.25 10.75-24 24-24S280 154.8 280 168v128c0 13.25-10.75 24-23.1 24S232 309.3 232 296V168zM256 416c-17.36 0-31.44-14.08-31.44-31.44c0-17.36 14.07-31.44 31.44-31.44s31.44 14.08 31.44 31.44C287.4 401.9 273.4 416 256 416z"/></svg>

  </span>


  </span>

  <span
    
      class="dark:text-neutral-300"
    ><strong>Disclaimer:</strong> This article is for personal learning notes only and does not constitute any investment advice.</span>
</div>

]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>00485 Buying a house will only make you poor. Investing makes you rich. Borrowing money to keep your assets growing is the way to become wealthy</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1728259977859/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1728259977859/</guid><description>This episode focuses on investment philosophy, strategies to avoid scams, and the impact of China&amp;#39;s newest economic policies on the global market. James reiterates the importance of long-term investment in index funds, specifically QQQ, and advises investors to control their emotions and resist market volatility. He uses real-life examples and data to illustrate the concept of borrowing for consumption, investing for asset growth, and analyzes China&amp;#39;s recent economic stimulus policies, viewing them as a positive sign for global economic recovery.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<lite-youtube videoid="zJdXwFaec2c" playlabel="zJdXwFaec2c" params=""></lite-youtube>



<h2 class="relative group">I. Main Topic 
    <div id="i-main-topic" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-main-topic" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This episode primarily discusses proper investment philosophy, ways to avoid investment traps, and the implications of China&rsquo;s latest economic policies for the global market. James emphasizes the importance of long-term investment in index funds, particularly QQQ, and reminds investors to maintain emotional control and not be swayed by market fluctuations. He uses specific examples and data to illustrate the concept of &ldquo;borrow for consumption, invest for asset growth,&rdquo; while also analyzing China&rsquo;s recently introduced series of economic stimulus policies, believing them to be a positive signal for a global economic recovery.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">II. Briefing Content 
    <div id="ii-briefing-content" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii-briefing-content" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<ul>
<li><strong>Investment Philosophy:</strong>
<ul>
<li>Emotions are the biggest enemy in investing. You need to avoid being influenced by news and information, stay rational, and refrain from chasing rising or falling markets.</li>
<li>Investing requires a long-term perspective, aiming for a timeframe of 40 years or more. Warren Buffett acquired 99% of his wealth after the age of 50, demonstrating that patience is key to wealth creation.</li>
<li>Choose investment targets that are consistently stable and provide high returns. Index funds are the best option, especially QQQ, which boasts a long-term annualized return of 14%.</li>
<li>Adhere to the &ldquo;never sell&rdquo; strategy to allow assets to continue appreciating. Avoid selling stocks unless absolutely necessary.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Scam Avoidance Guide:</strong>
<ul>
<li>Be wary of various investment traps. Do not trust any projects that guarantee high returns, especially those that require you to sell existing assets for new investments.</li>
<li>Do not readily believe any investment or financial management information received via phone, text messages, or online platforms. Any information involving bank accounts or government departments must be verified through official channels.</li>
<li>Be cautious of aggressive sales tactics from financial institutions. Stick to your investment plan and avoid being lured by various fancy financial products.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Regarding Real Estate Investment:</strong>
<ul>
<li>James advises against homeownership for average working individuals, believing it turns them into &ldquo;mortgage slaves&rdquo; burdened with heavy loan pressure, hindering wealth accumulation.</li>
<li>He advocates for a &ldquo;rent instead of buy&rdquo; approach, suggesting using a stock pledge loan to rent high-quality housing at lower interest rates, then investing the saved funds for higher returns.</li>
<li>Consider purchasing real estate only when your assets reach a certain scale and you can comfortably afford the payment.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>New Trends in China&rsquo;s Economy:</strong>
<ul>
<li>The People&rsquo;s Bank of China recently introduced a series of potent fiscal policies, including reserve requirement ratio and interest rate cuts, injecting funds into banks, and encouraging stock purchases, to stimulate economic growth.</li>
<li>These policies will contribute positively to stabilizing China&rsquo;s real estate market, boosting consumer confidence, and promoting global economic recovery.</li>
<li>Investors should pay attention to developments in the Chinese market and seize new investment opportunities.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">III. Q&amp;A Session 
    <div id="iii-qa-session" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii-qa-session" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p><strong>IM:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Through conversations with individuals of different age groups, IM discovered that most people have insufficient awareness of long-term savings and are often constrained by mortgages and other factors. By comparing the returns of index funds in different countries and regions with those of fixed deposits and pensions, IM illustrated the advantages of long-term investment in index funds.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>INGYNYING:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: INGYNYING&rsquo;s mother wanted to sell all her assets to purchase a house but, after persuasion, realized that this would lead to losing opportunities for asset appreciation. Many of INGYNYING&rsquo;s friends are afraid of change, preferring to endure the hardships of their current situation rather than attempt new investment methods.</li>
<li>Question: How to convince family members to accept new investment concepts?</li>
<li>James&rsquo; answer: Utilize data and case studies for illustration, such as comparing the long-term returns of fixed deposits and index funds, and sharing success stories of investors. It&rsquo;s also important to respect family members&rsquo; choices and refrain from forcing them to accept new ideas.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Allen:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Questions:  Should someone with assets worth 50 times their annual living expenses use their salary to pay for a car? How can a couple combine their stock accounts for collateral purposes?</li>
<li>James&rsquo; answer: It is recommended to utilize Tesla&rsquo;s official website loan to purchase a vehicle, then use funds from a stock pledge loan to repay the car loan. Dedicate your salary entirely to investment. Couples can combine their accounts through a joint account for collateral, sharing the limit, while their accounts remain individually managed.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Eric:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Question: Eric&rsquo;s mother is visiting the US and is concerned about medical expenses. How should this be  handled?</li>
<li>James&rsquo; answer:  Purchasing travel insurance is advised, but excessive worry is unnecessary. Most non-emergency situations can be treated back home. If encountering extremely high medical costs, attempting negotiation with the hospital or seeking alternative solutions is possible. Due to the specific circumstances of foreign nationality and lack of income, the hospital may choose not to pursue the medical expenses.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Dean:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Dean purchased a new car using Tesla&rsquo;s website loan and a stock pledge loan, conserving a significant amount of capital. Learning about investing boosted Dean&rsquo;s confidence to decline a high-paying job and choose to stay home with their child.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Michael:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Questions: How to secure a loan from Tesla&rsquo;s official website for a car purchase? Can funds from 401k or IRA accounts be used for collateral? What are the options if QQQ is not available in their company&rsquo;s 401k plan?</li>
<li>James&rsquo; answer: To apply for a car loan through Tesla&rsquo;s website, choose the desired model and configuration, click &ldquo;Order Now&rdquo;, and select &ldquo;Finance&rdquo;. Funds in retirement accounts cannot be used as collateral; it is recommended to transfer part of those funds to a brokerage account for collateral purposes.  Alternative options include choosing an S&amp;P 500 index fund or inquiring with the company about the possibility of Blockage Link to invest in QQQ.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>EVA:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Question: As a single, middle-aged woman with limited savings, how to balance work and investment? Should selling the house be considered for investment purposes?</li>
<li>James&rsquo; answer: Continue working diligently while consistently making monthly investments. Even small amounts will accumulate over 8-9 years, reaching the threshold for collateral, allowing you to leverage and accelerate wealth growth. Selling a house for investment is an option but requires careful consideration based on personal circumstances.  If renting is more cost-effective, choose to rent and allocate the funds to investments yielding higher returns.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Jenny:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Questions:  Any knowledge regarding the latest Roth SEP IRA policy?</li>
<li>James&rsquo; answer: The policy information is quite recent, and the accuracy of the $69,000 limit requires verification. Consulting with professionals like a financial advisor at Chase or Lisa is recommended. As it is a new product, not all institutions may offer it.</li>
<li>Sharing: Jenny shared a personal experience of being scammed, reminding everyone to exercise caution and avoid trusting any investment information, particularly those spread through unofficial channels.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Haoqing:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Haoqing relayed the experiences of close friends falling victim to scams, lamenting that scam tactics are constantly evolving and are hard to guard against, even for highly educated individuals.</li>
<li>Question: How can investment concepts be better conveyed to people around us to prevent them from being deceived? Is there a need to explain professional investment knowledge?</li>
<li>James&rsquo; answer: Avoid explaining intricate investment knowledge; simply emphasize the core principle of long-term investment in index funds. Excessive professional details may confuse them, making them more susceptible to being misled by other investment information and ultimately falling prey to scams.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Jason:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Recounted an NFT scam incident encountered on Clubhouse, warning everyone to be wary of risks in the cryptocurrency world. Expressed gratitude toward James&rsquo; investment philosophy for helping them avoid such traps.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Amy:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Amy shared personal encounters with scams, including impersonations of government departments and courier companies. She emphasized the importance of relying only on written communication and ignoring any investment information delivered through phone calls or text messages. Amy suggested that, when in doubt, contact official channels for clarification.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Becky:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Suggestion: Avoid answering calls from unfamiliar numbers, set up spam filters, and use a less important email address when necessary to share personal information to minimize the risk of scams.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Mike:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Question: What are your thoughts on China&rsquo;s most recent economic policies? Are they sustainable?</li>
<li>James&rsquo; answer: The People&rsquo;s Bank of China has introduced powerful policies that are having a positive impact on economic confidence. Investors should keep an eye on these developments. Although the policies appear to be heading in a positive direction, their sustainability remains to be seen.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Julia:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Question:  Any updates on the Roth SEP IRA policy? Are there any financial institutions already offering related products?</li>
<li>James&rsquo; answer: The policy information is fairly new, and the $69,000 limit&rsquo;s accuracy is debatable. Consulting with a professional is advised. Being a new product, not all institutions might offer it yet.</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">IV. Noteworthy Points 
    <div id="iv-noteworthy-points" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv-noteworthy-points" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>“You have enough money when you have enough.&quot;
&ndash; Many people</p></blockquote>
<p>Many individuals believe that having just enough to get by is sufficient. This is a mistaken notion, as money is never truly enough. True financial freedom lies in possessing the power of choice – going wherever you want, doing whatever you desire – instead of being constrained by finances.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;Never borrow money for investments.&rdquo;
&ndash; Many people</p></blockquote>
<p>Many believe that borrowing for investment is unwise; however, this viewpoint is overly cautious. True investors, like Warren Buffett, skillfully leverage debt. Following the principle of &ldquo;borrow for consumption, invest for asset growth&rdquo;, the correct approach is to use borrowed money for expenses and personal money for investment. This enables rapid wealth accumulation.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“All investment information received through phone calls, text messages, or online platforms is not trustworthy.”
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>Nowadays, numerous scams operate through these channels. It&rsquo;s crucial to exercise caution and avoid blindly believing any financial advice or information. Anything involving bank accounts or government departments must be verified through official sources. Additionally, seeking guidance from qualified professionals is essential.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“Investment must be consistently stable over the long term, which is why index funds are the only viable option.&quot;
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>Within the complex investment landscape, index funds stand out as a few reliable options capable of offering consistent stability and high returns. Index funds are like living organisms; they will never die, whereas all individual stocks will eventually disappear within a century.  If you&rsquo;re looking for generational wealth, index funds are the way to go.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">V. Summary 
    <div id="v-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#v-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This episode is packed with valuable information and insights. It not only reiterates the importance of long-term index fund investment but also offers practical tips on scam prevention and provides an in-depth analysis of China&rsquo;s newest economic policies.  It is recommended to apply this knowledge to your investment practices and strive for financial freedom.</p>

  



<div
  
    class="flex px-4 py-3 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900"
  >

  <span
    
      class="text-primary-400 ltr:pr-3 rtl:pl-3 flex items-center"
    >

    

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M506.3 417l-213.3-364c-16.33-28-57.54-28-73.98 0l-213.2 364C-10.59 444.9 9.849 480 42.74 480h426.6C502.1 480 522.6 445 506.3 417zM232 168c0-13.25 10.75-24 24-24S280 154.8 280 168v128c0 13.25-10.75 24-23.1 24S232 309.3 232 296V168zM256 416c-17.36 0-31.44-14.08-31.44-31.44c0-17.36 14.07-31.44 31.44-31.44s31.44 14.08 31.44 31.44C287.4 401.9 273.4 416 256 416z"/></svg>

  </span>


  </span>

  <span
    
      class="dark:text-neutral-300"
    ><strong>Disclaimer:</strong> This article serves solely as personal study notes and does not constitute any investment advice.</span>
</div>

]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>00477 Eternal Freedom from Worry and Stress: Wisdom and Strategies for Long-Term Investing</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1728565408053/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1728565408053/</guid><description>In this session, James shares his investment philosophy, emphasizing the importance of independent thinking and risk management. He also answers questions from students on topics such as TQQQ, emergency funds, MAGS fund, and real estate investment.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<lite-youtube videoid="CfFEQJkTCBw" playlabel="CfFEQJkTCBw" params=""></lite-youtube>



<h2 class="relative group">I. Main Theme 
    <div id="i-main-theme" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-main-theme" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This session focuses on the philosophy of long-term investing, emphasizing the importance of independent thinking and risk management. James reiterates his long-held investment philosophy: choose the right investment target (such as QQQ), buy in early and hold for the long term, ignoring short-term market fluctuations, and ultimately achieve steady wealth growth. In addition, he discusses how to maintain a positive mindset, deal with stress and anxiety that may arise during the investment process, and how to choose a reliable brokerage to ensure account security.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">II. Briefing Content 
    <div id="ii-briefing-content" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii-briefing-content" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<ul>
<li><strong>Wealth is accumulated slowly, and enjoying the process of wealth accumulation is the meaning of life.</strong> Getting rich overnight or quickly is not the best way. Slowly accumulating wealth and enjoying it allows you to experience the true meaning of life and learn and grow from it.</li>
<li><strong>Don&rsquo;t blindly pursue high returns while ignoring risks.</strong> Many people pursue quick riches and hope for super high returns, but often overlook the risks involved, which may ultimately lead to losses outweighing gains. Learn to assess risk and choose an investment strategy that matches your risk tolerance.</li>
<li><strong>Investing requires finding a definite eternity, ignoring market noise, and maintaining inner peace.</strong> Index fund investing is a definite and eternal strategy that does not require painstaking research and operation. Simply holding for the long term can yield considerable returns.</li>
<li><strong>Investment is a loser&rsquo;s game, not seeking to win, but seeking not to lose.</strong>  In investing, avoiding mistakes is more important than pursuing victory. Index fund investing can help investors reduce mistakes and ultimately achieve victory.</li>
<li><strong>Buying in a lump sum at any time and holding for the long term is superior to other investment methods.</strong> Investing early and holding for the long term maximizes returns and delivers the best investment returns.</li>
<li><strong>Learn to distinguish between what can be done, what is effective, what can be worried about, and what is not worth worrying about.</strong> Focus your energy on important and solvable issues, ignore those that are irrelevant or beyond your control to improve efficiency and reduce unnecessary anxiety.</li>
<li><strong>Don&rsquo;t work too hard, let your money work for you.</strong> Put your money into the market and let it create wealth for you instead of devoting all your energy to work. Learn to utilize investment tools to achieve passive wealth growth.</li>
<li><strong>All pressure comes from expectations, and all worries come from not having a solution.</strong> Lower your expectations and actively seek solutions to relieve stress and anxiety.</li>
<li><strong>Learn to transfer pressure to those who can bear it and think about solutions for the worst-case scenario.</strong> Don&rsquo;t bear the pressure alone, learn to seek help, and think in advance about solutions to the worst-case scenario to calmly deal with challenges.</li>
<li><strong>Maintain inner peace, focus on the important things, and ignore the insignificant things.</strong> Stick to simple things, don&rsquo;t get involved in complex things, to maintain inner peace and focus on what really matters in life.</li>
<li><strong>Account security is the primary issue in investing. Choose a large, reputable brokerage to open an account and avoid using online brokers.</strong> Online brokers have security risks, such as account theft and asset freezing. Choosing a large, reputable brokerage can better protect your account security.</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">III. Q&amp;A Session 
    <div id="iii-qa-session" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii-qa-session" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p><strong>Dave:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing:</strong>
Shared the results of James&rsquo; TQQQ simulation backtest and raised the question of how to avoid the risk of a sharp TQQQ drawdown.</li>
<li><strong>Question and James&rsquo;s Reply:</strong>
James believes that it is impossible to predict the market and avoid all risks completely. The important thing is to control risk exposure and avoid over-betting. If you are worried about the volatility of TQQQ, you can choose a more conservative investment strategy, such as QQQ. James also reminds everyone to distinguish between personal thinking and public advice, and not to be easily swayed by the thoughts of others.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Minjianlian:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing:</strong>
Shared his experience of investing in stocks through his company&rsquo;s savings association, as well as discussions about the MAGS fund and emergency funds.</li>
<li><strong>Question and James&rsquo;s Reply:</strong>
<ol>
<li>About the MAGS fund: James believes that it is uncertain whether the MAGS fund can outperform QQQ in the long term. Investment should choose targets that have been tested by time, such as QQQ or SPY.</li>
<li>About emergency funds: James believes that emergency funds are a personal responsibility and government policies cannot be relied upon entirely. Everyone should prepare sufficient emergency funds according to their own circumstances to cope with contingencies.</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Learn:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Question and James&rsquo;s Reply:</strong>
Regarding the performance of 00670L, James explained the performance difference caused by USD hedging and how to solve it by investing in QLD through sub-brokerage. He emphasized that Beta and ROI are different concepts. Beta represents volatility, not ROI. The investment model in Taiwan needs to be adjusted according to specific circumstances, such as  maintenance margin requirements and exchange rate fluctuations.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>JJU:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing:</strong>
Shared his insights on market unpredictability and the importance of mentors and friends. He believes that investing, in addition to selecting good targets, is more about maintaining inner peace and enhancing one&rsquo;s spiritual level.</li>
<li><strong>Question and James&rsquo;s Reply:</strong>
<ol>
<li>About the difference between reinvest and buy share: James explained the difference between reinvesting and buying shares. The former automatically invests dividends or capital gains into the investment target, while the latter uses new funds to buy shares.</li>
<li>About the fund ratio of Roth IRA and Individual Brokerage Account: It is recommended to maximize the Roth IRA limit if possible.</li>
<li>About real estate mortgage investment: It is recommended to sell the property if possible to reduce the risk of investing in real estate. Otherwise, consider a Home Equity Line of Credit (HELOC) for investment, but pay attention to risk control and ensure that you can repay the loan on time. HELOC is a revolving credit line, similar to a credit card, which can be withdrawn and repaid at any time.</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Draft down:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing:</strong>
Proposed the possibility of leveraging 0% interest credit cards for investment and using the box spread strategy to increase capital utilization.</li>
<li><strong>Question and James&rsquo;s Reply:</strong>
<ol>
<li>About credit card investment: James believes that credit card limits are limited and there is a risk of not being able to renew the loan, making it unsuitable as a main source of investment funds. It is only suitable for short-term turnover of small amounts of funds.</li>
<li>About the box spread strategy: James believes that the box spread strategy is too complex and risky and is not recommended for ordinary investors.</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Jason:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Question and James&rsquo;s Reply:</strong>
<ol>
<li>How to overcome short-term pain in the investment process: James suggested lowering expectations, not pursuing perfection or getting rich quickly, finding solutions to problems, and transferring the pressure to those who can bear it, such as superiors or more experienced individuals. Think about solutions for the worst-case scenario, such as job loss or investment losses, and maintain a positive mindset, believing that the problem will eventually be solved.</li>
<li>About non-US tax resident investing in US stocks: James believes that non-US tax residents can use their passports to open brokerage accounts in the US without a Social Security Number. It is recommended to choose large, reputable brokers, such as Charles Schwab, and avoid using online brokers, such as Webull and Robinhood, as online brokers have security risks and imperfect regulations.</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">IV. Key Insights 
    <div id="iv-key-insights" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv-key-insights" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>Investment is a loser&rsquo;s game, not seeking to win, but seeking not to lose.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>In investing, avoiding mistakes is more important than pursuing victory. Choosing the right investment target, formulating a reasonable investment strategy and strictly adhering to discipline can reduce mistakes and ultimately achieve long-term stable returns.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Buying in a lump sum at any time and holding for the long term is superior to other investment methods.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>Investing early and holding for the long term maximizes returns and delivers the best investment returns. Time is a friend of investment. Starting early allows time to work its magic of compounding.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>All pressure comes from expectations, and all worries come from not having a solution.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>Lower your expectations and actively seek solutions to relieve stress and anxiety. When facing challenges, maintain a positive attitude and believe that you can find a way to solve the problem.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Wealth is accumulated slowly, and enjoying the process of wealth accumulation is the meaning of life.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>Getting rich overnight or quickly is not the best way. Slowly accumulating wealth and enjoying it allows you to experience the true meaning of life. Investing is a long-term process. Don&rsquo;t be impatient and enjoy the process of wealth accumulation, learning and growing from it.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Good teachers and helpful friends are important. You may not be right if you agree with someone.
&ndash; JJU</p></blockquote>
<p>In the investment process, be good at learning and thinking. Don&rsquo;t blindly believe anyone&rsquo;s point of view, including teachers and friends. Make your own independent thinking and judgment to make the right investment decisions.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Account security is the primary issue in investing.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>Choosing a large, reputable brokerage to open an account, such as Charles Schwab, can better protect your account security. Avoid using online brokers as online brokers have security risks and imperfect regulations.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">V. Summary 
    <div id="v-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#v-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This session focuses on the long-term investment philosophy, risk control, and mindset management. James helps students better understand the essence of investment through vivid examples and in-depth explanations. He answers students&rsquo; various questions encountered in the investment process, such as the risks of TQQQ, the importance of emergency funds, and real estate investment strategies. At the same time, students also actively share their experiences and confusion, such as using credit cards for investment and using the box spread strategy, triggering deeper thinking and discussion. James emphasizes the importance of independent thinking, advising against blindly believing anyone&rsquo;s point of view. He encourages making independent thinking and judgment to make the right investment decisions. At the same time, he also reminds everyone to pay attention to account security, choose large, reputable brokers to open accounts, and avoid using online brokers.</p>

  



<div
  
    class="flex px-4 py-3 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900"
  >

  <span
    
      class="text-primary-400 ltr:pr-3 rtl:pl-3 flex items-center"
    >

    

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M506.3 417l-213.3-364c-16.33-28-57.54-28-73.98 0l-213.2 364C-10.59 444.9 9.849 480 42.74 480h426.6C502.1 480 522.6 445 506.3 417zM232 168c0-13.25 10.75-24 24-24S280 154.8 280 168v128c0 13.25-10.75 24-23.1 24S232 309.3 232 296V168zM256 416c-17.36 0-31.44-14.08-31.44-31.44c0-17.36 14.07-31.44 31.44-31.44s31.44 14.08 31.44 31.44C287.4 401.9 273.4 416 256 416z"/></svg>

  </span>


  </span>

  <span
    
      class="dark:text-neutral-300"
    ><strong>Disclaimer:</strong> This article is only for personal learning notes and does not constitute any investment advice.</span>
</div>

]]></content:encoded></item></channel></rss>