<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Investment Philosophy on QQQ Investor</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/tags/investment-philosophy/</link><description>Recent content in Investment Philosophy on QQQ Investor</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jomonylw.github.io/en/tags/investment-philosophy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>00503 The Wealth Code the Market Won't Teach You: 99% of Investment Courses on the Market are Fleecing Sheep. Our Channel is Better Than Financial Advisors and MBA Investment Courses</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1740288562129/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1740288562129/</guid><description>This episode delves into the differences between CLEC Investment Education and traditional investment education and influencers, analyzing investment philosophies, asset allocation, the importance of long-term investing, and discussing issues such as the A-share NASDAQ premium, American politics, and AI regulation.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<lite-youtube videoid="eT8qj07y96E" playlabel="eT8qj07y96E" params=""></lite-youtube>



<h2 class="relative group">I. Current Topic 
    <div id="i-current-topic" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-current-topic" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This episode revolves around ChatGPT&rsquo;s analysis of CLEC Investment Education, deeply comparing CLEC investment with common investment education on the market, influencers, and common investment books. It emphasizes the uniqueness, practicality, executability, and systematic nature of CLEC investment. At the same time, James shares the growth path of investors, the necessity of asset allocation, the importance of cash flow management, and how to deal with market fluctuations, and answers questions raised by students regarding the A-share NASDAQ premium, the American political economy, and AI regulation.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">II. Briefing Content 
    <div id="ii-briefing-content" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii-briefing-content" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Investment Philosophy and Strategy 
    <div id="investment-philosophy-and-strategy" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#investment-philosophy-and-strategy" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>
<p><strong>Differences between CLEC Investment and Market Books, Influencers:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Core Strategy:</strong> CLEC uses the NASDAQ 100 Index Fund (QQQ) as its core, combined with leveraged funds (QLD) and bank pledges for asset allocation, targeting an annualized return of 12%~20%.</li>
<li><strong>Traditional Investment Education:</strong> Usually only emphasizes large-cap index investing (such as VOO, SPY) or value investing, rarely mentions leveraged funds, and even less involves specific capital operation strategies (such as stock pledges).</li>
<li><strong>Influencer Finance:</strong> Often oversimplifies investing or recommends various immature investment targets (such as newly issued ETFs), lacking systematicity and risk control.</li>
<li><strong>Financial Freedom Strategy:</strong> CLEC provides a clear path to financial freedom, including when to start stock pledges, the amount that can be safely withdrawn each year, and how to achieve financial freedom through capital operations, rather than just &ldquo;saving money + investing.&rdquo;</li>
<li><strong>Practicality and Executability:</strong> CLEC provides concrete and actionable plans, such as how much assets you need to reach to start pledging, how to adjust asset allocation according to market conditions, while many books and courses only have theory and lack practical guidance.</li>
<li><strong>Capital Operation:</strong> CLEC emphasizes capital operation through bank credit, wealth management mortgages, stock pledges, etc., to achieve the goal of &ldquo;borrowing money to invest, borrowing money to spend, and asset appreciation,&rdquo; which is rarely involved in traditional investment education and influencer finance.</li>
<li><strong>Risk Management:</strong> Emphasizes risk control and has specific coping methods in the event of a downturn.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Comparison with Common Investment Books:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>&ldquo;The Psychology of Money&rdquo;:</strong> Emphasizes long-term investing and saving, but CLEC goes a step further by accelerating wealth accumulation through leverage and capital operations.</li>
<li><strong>&ldquo;A Random Walk Down Wall Street&rdquo;:</strong> Advocates investing in the broad market index (SPY), but CLEC believes that QQQ has more growth potential and combines leveraged funds and cash for asset allocation.</li>
<li><strong>Buffett:</strong> Buffett is the representative of value investing, requiring in-depth research on companies and industries, while CLEC believes that ordinary people do not need to have professional knowledge and only need to invest in index funds.</li>
<li><strong>&ldquo;Rich Dad, Poor Dad&rdquo;:</strong> Focuses on real estate investment, while CLEC believes that stock investment and capital operations are more efficient and does not recommend investing in real estate.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Investor Growth Process:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Beginner Stage:</strong> Learn and practice long-term investing principles, and don&rsquo;t panic and sell (already in the top 20% of the market).</li>
<li><strong>Advanced Stage:</strong> Learn and use leveraged funds and stock pledges (top 20% of the market).</li>
<li><strong>Advanced Stage:</strong> Proficient in stock pledges, cash flow management, and asset allocation, and fearless of market fluctuations (top 1% of the market).</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Core Investment Philosophy:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Mission:</strong> To awaken the capital awareness of ordinary people and help them achieve financial freedom, rather than for traffic and making money.</li>
<li><strong>Investment Target:</strong> Focus on investing in QQQ, believing in the long-term development of American technology.</li>
<li><strong>Leverage Use:</strong> Reasonably use leveraged funds (QLD) to magnify returns, but strictly control risk and avoid short-term operations.</li>
<li><strong>Smart Rebalancing:</strong> According to market ups and downs, dynamically adjust between QQQ and cash (or short-term bonds) to achieve &ldquo;buy low and sell high.&rdquo;</li>
<li><strong>Stock Pledge:</strong> Obtain cash flow through stock pledge to achieve &ldquo;consuming without selling stocks&rdquo; and ensure continuous asset appreciation.</li>
<li><strong>Simple and Effective:</strong> The investment strategy is simple and easy to understand, can be executed in the long term, does not require monitoring the market, and does not require stock picking.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Asset Allocation and Risk Management 
    <div id="asset-allocation-and-risk-management" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#asset-allocation-and-risk-management" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>
<p><strong>Importance of Asset Allocation:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Survival Guarantee:</strong> When the market fluctuates violently, reasonable asset allocation is the key to survival.</li>
<li><strong>Cash is King:</strong> Always maintain at least 20% of cash (or cash equivalents) to cope with emergencies and market declines.</li>
<li><strong>Dynamic Balance:</strong> Adjust between different asset classes according to market conditions to reduce risk and increase returns.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Importance of Long-Term Investing:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Market Trends:</strong> Firmly believe that the market will move upwards in the long run and do not predict short-term fluctuations.</li>
<li><strong>Patient Holding:</strong> Investing requires time and patience, and wealth accumulation takes time.</li>
<li><strong>Emotional Control:</strong> Not affected by market sentiment and short-term information, and maintain an optimistic attitude.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Risk Management:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Risk Awareness:</strong> Recognize the high risk of investment and be mentally prepared for a possible drop of 50% or even 70%.</li>
<li><strong>Survival First:</strong> The primary goal of investing is to &ldquo;stay alive&rdquo; rather than pursuing short-term high returns.</li>
<li><strong>Cash Reserve:</strong> Adequate cash reserve is the most effective means to cope with risks.</li>
<li><strong>Smart Rebalancing:</strong> When the market falls, use cash to buy more QQQ or QLD to lower the average cost.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Stock Pledge:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Core Strategy:</strong> Obtain cash flow through stock pledge for living expenses or other investments to achieve &ldquo;spending money without selling stocks.&rdquo;</li>
<li><strong>Advantages:</strong> Avoid selling high-quality assets and enjoy the benefits of continuous asset appreciation; achieve the ideal state of &ldquo;borrowing money forever, never repaying, and no interest.&rdquo;</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Other 
    <div id="other" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#other" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>About Group Discussions:</strong>
<ul>
<li><strong>Focus on the Topic:</strong> Group discussions should revolve around CLEC investment philosophy and strategies, and not discuss content beyond the scope.</li>
<li><strong>Avoid Misleading:</strong> Do not discuss newly issued ETFs or other investment targets that do not conform to CLEC investment principles.</li>
<li><strong>Answer Questions:</strong> The group owner and senior students should help new students answer questions.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">III. Q&amp;A Session 
    <div id="iii-qa-session" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii-qa-session" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Eason 
    <div id="eason" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#eason" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>
<p><strong>Sharing:</strong></p>
<ol>
<li><strong>A-share NASDAQ ETF Premium Issue:</strong> Elaborated in detail the fundamental reasons for the premium of domestic A-share NASDAQ ETFs (such as 513100, 159941, etc.):
<ul>
<li><strong>Foreign Exchange Control:</strong> China implements foreign exchange control, and each fund company has a state-approved quota. The quotas of old fund companies are usually tight, resulting in limited off-site subscriptions (suspension or limits), and investors can only turn to buying ETFs on the market, which pushes up on-site prices and forms a premium.</li>
<li><strong>Market Sentiment:</strong> The A-share market is easily affected by policies, hot spots, and other factors, and rapid capital flows can lead to violent fluctuations in the premium of the NASDAQ ETF. For example, when the market pursues other hot sectors, funds may withdraw from the NASDAQ ETF, leading to a decrease in the premium or even a discount.</li>
<li><strong>Long-Term Trends:</strong> In the long run, due to the existence of foreign exchange controls and investors&rsquo; continued optimism about the NASDAQ, the premium will exist for a long time. However, in the short term, the premium will be affected by market sentiment and capital flows.</li>
<li><strong>On-site and Off-site Differences:</strong> The same fund has different codes and trading methods on-site (exchange-traded funds, ETFs) and off-site (subscribed and redeemed through the fund company). Off-site subscriptions are usually based on the fund&rsquo;s net value, while on-site transaction prices are affected by supply and demand, which may result in premiums or discounts.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Impact on Investors:</strong> The premium of the A-share NASDAQ ETF is unfavorable to ordinary investors, especially buying at a higher premium, which increases the investment cost.</li>
<li><strong>Investment Recommendations:</strong>
<ul>
<li><strong>Long-Term Investing:</strong> If it is a long-term investment, there is no need to worry too much about short-term premium fluctuations.</li>
<li><strong>Be Cautious When the Premium is Too High:</strong> When the premium is too high (such as exceeding 10%), you can wait appropriately or consider other investment channels.</li>
<li><strong>Pay Attention to Discount Opportunities:</strong> When a discount occurs, it is a good time to buy.</li>
<li><strong>Open an Account in Hong Kong:</strong> If conditions permit, you can consider opening an account in Hong Kong to directly purchase US stock QQQ, avoiding premium problems, and you can also allocate leveraged funds (QLD).</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ol>
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo; Comments:</strong>
<ul>
<li>Fully agrees with the doctor&rsquo;s analysis that the premium problem of A-share NASDAQ ETF is indeed caused by factors such as foreign exchange controls and market sentiment.</li>
<li>Suggests that investors who are more sensitive to premiums or want greater investment flexibility can consider opening an account in Hong Kong.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Question 1:</strong> After Trump takes office again, will his domestic and foreign policies be very different from the past (including his first term), and will these changes shake the American system?</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo; Response:</strong>
<ul>
<li><strong>American Strength:</strong> Clearly stated that the United States is very strong and Trump will make the United States stronger.</li>
<li><strong>Quality of Political Officials:</strong> American political officials are very good, they are loyal to the country, and can give up personal interests for national interests (for example, many political officials come from Goldman Sachs and other Wall Street investment banks, giving up high-paying positions).</li>
<li><strong>International Situation:</strong> Touched on international issues without commenting too much to avoid controversy.</li>
<li><strong>Ukraine Issue:</strong> Believes that the Ukraine issue was caused by Zelensky, who should be responsible for the current situation in Ukraine. Implies that Ukraine is being used by the United States.</li>
<li><strong>Summary:</strong> Overall optimistic about the United States and Trump&rsquo;s policies, believing that the United States will continue to remain strong.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Belle 
    <div id="belle" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#belle" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing:</strong>
<ol>
<li><strong>Learning Experience:</strong> Shared in detail her learning journey following James to learn CLEC investment for 4-5 years, from a &ldquo;newbie&rdquo; who knew nothing about investment to gradually understanding and practicing long-term investment, leveraged funds, stock pledges, asset allocation, and other concepts, and finally realizing a change in mentality and improvement in investment skills.</li>
<li><strong>ChatGPT Application:</strong> Introduced how she input the learning content and personal experience of CLEC investment into ChatGPT (version 4.0) and obtained ChatGPT&rsquo;s in-depth analysis and summary of CLEC investment. She found that ChatGPT can not only understand the core strategy of CLEC investment, but also analyze her psychological changes and decision-making logic in the investment process.</li>
<li><strong>Comparison with Other Investment Methods:</strong> In the learning process, Belle also read other investment books and influencer viewpoints, but she found that many investment methods are either too complex or too one-sided, lacking systematicity and operability. She believes that CLEC investment provides a complete, clear, and executable investment system, which makes her full of confidence in future financial freedom.</li>
</ol>
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo; Comments:</strong>
<ul>
<li>Highly praised Belle&rsquo;s learning achievements and summarizing ability, believing that her understanding of CLEC investment is very accurate.</li>
<li>Expressed surprise and appreciation for ChatGPT&rsquo;s analysis results, believing that ChatGPT&rsquo;s understanding of CLEC investment even exceeded his own, which gave him a deeper understanding of the potential of AI.</li>
<li>Affirmed Belle&rsquo;s questioning skills.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">IM 
    <div id="im" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#im" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>
<p><strong>Sharing:</strong></p>
<ol>
<li><strong>Learning Experience:</strong> Shared his feelings about learning CLEC investment, believing that CLEC investment not only makes him feel at ease and confident about his future financial situation, but also makes him think more deeply about life.</li>
<li><strong>Case Observation:</strong> Shared his observation of a 70-year-old retiree. This old man had devoted his whole life to his family and work, but felt confused and empty after retirement, and did not know where his life value was.</li>
</ol>
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo; Comments:</strong>
<ul>
<li><strong>Dilemma of the Working Class:</strong> Pointed out that this is a common dilemma for many working-class people, who spend their whole lives working for others but neglect their own life goals and values.</li>
<li><strong>Awakening of Life:</strong> Emphasized the importance of awakening in life, realizing that you are not living for others but for yourself. Plan your life early and don&rsquo;t feel confused until retirement.</li>
<li><strong>Significance of Financial Freedom:</strong> Financial freedom is not only the accumulation of wealth, but also to obtain more time and freedom to pursue your life goals, to accompany your family, and to experience life.</li>
<li><strong>Living in the Present:</strong> Introduced the concept of &ldquo;mindfulness,&rdquo; that is, focusing on the present, reducing thoughts, and living in every moment, so as to obtain inner peace and happiness.</li>
<li><strong>Definition of Capitalist:</strong> Redefined the concept of &ldquo;capitalist,&rdquo; pointing out that true capitalists are those who do not need to work themselves and can obtain wealth through capital operation.</li>
<li><strong>Three Levels of Investment:</strong> Divided investors into three levels:
<ul>
<li><strong>Rich People:</strong> Obtain a certain amount of wealth through investment (such as index funds).</li>
<li><strong>Wealthy People:</strong> In addition to investment, they also know how to use leverage (such as credit, wealth management mortgages) to accelerate wealth accumulation.</li>
<li><strong>Tycoons:</strong> Master advanced capital operation techniques such as stock pledge to achieve &ldquo;consuming without selling stocks&rdquo; and continuous asset appreciation.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Social Contribution:</strong> Emphasized that although CLEC investors &ldquo;do not work hard,&rdquo; they make huge contributions to society through capital allocation.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Question:</strong> How to get along with people (especially family and friends) who do not understand the CLEC investment philosophy? They may think we are &ldquo;not doing our job&rdquo; or &ldquo;fond of ease and averse to labor.&rdquo;</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo; Response:</strong>
<ul>
<li><strong>Understand the Differences:</strong> Acknowledged that there are differences between the CLEC investment philosophy and traditional concepts, and it is normal not to be understood.</li>
<li><strong>Do Your Own Thing:</strong> Do not need to force others to understand, do your own investment well, and prove it with practical results.</li>
<li><strong>Patient Communication:</strong> If the other party is willing to understand, you can patiently explain the principles and advantages of CLEC investment.</li>
<li><strong>Share Resources:</strong> You can share James&rsquo; videos, articles, handouts, and other resources to give the other party a more comprehensive understanding of CLEC investment.</li>
<li><strong>Respect Choices:</strong> Respect everyone&rsquo;s choices, do not force, and do not argue.</li>
<li><strong>Example is Better Than Precept:</strong> Put it into practice yourself and live a life of financial freedom and spiritual freedom, which is the best demonstration.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Dave 
    <div id="dave" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#dave" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing:</strong>
<ol>
<li><strong>Responding to &ldquo;National QQQ&rdquo; Concerns:</strong> Some students worry that if everyone buys QQQ, will it lead to market imbalances or a decline in QQQ&rsquo;s returns. Dave pointed out that this concern is unnecessary.</li>
<li><strong>Small Market Value of QQQ:</strong> He provided data, pointing out that the market value of QQQ (about $300 billion) is very small (about 0.5%) relative to the total market value of the entire US stock market (about $62 trillion), and even if more people buy QQQ, it will not have a big impact on the market.</li>
<li><strong>The Choice of a Few:</strong> Emphasized that CLEC investors are a minority, not a majority, and the vast majority of investors will still choose other investment methods.</li>
</ol>
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo; Comments:</strong>
<ul>
<li>Fully agrees with Dave&rsquo;s point of view, and reiterated that the market value of QQQ is very small and CLEC investors are a minority.</li>
<li>Added that even if everyone comes to buy QQQ, there will be no problem because the market will automatically adjust.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Haoqing 
    <div id="haoqing" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#haoqing" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing:</strong>
<ol>
<li><strong>Economic Comparison between Taiwan and South Korea:</strong> Compared the economic development of Taiwan and South Korea, pointing out that Taiwan&rsquo;s economic growth mainly relies on a few technology companies such as TSMC, while South Korea&rsquo;s economy is more diversified, mainly dominated by large chaebols such as Samsung and Hyundai.</li>
<li><strong>&ldquo;Individual Stocks&rdquo; and &ldquo;ETFs&rdquo;:</strong> He believes that Taiwan&rsquo;s economic model is more like &ldquo;heavy positions in individual stocks&rdquo; (TSMC), while South Korea&rsquo;s chaebol model is more like &ldquo;investing in ETFs&rdquo; (containing multiple industries and companies).</li>
<li><strong>Taiwan&rsquo;s Worries:</strong> Worried that Taiwan is overly dependent on a single industry, and once TSMC has problems, it will have a great impact on Taiwan&rsquo;s economy.</li>
<li><strong>Impressions of South Korea:</strong> South Korea is unfriendly</li>
</ol>
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo; Comments:</strong>
<ul>
<li><strong>Agree with Observations:</strong> Agreed with Haoqing&rsquo;s observations on the economic models of Taiwan and South Korea.</li>
<li><strong>Taiwan&rsquo;s Advantages:</strong> Pointed out that Taiwan&rsquo;s soft power (such as talent, innovation ability, financial environment, etc.) is very strong, but compared with the United States, there is still a big gap.</li>
<li><strong>Focus on Yourself:</strong> Emphasized that Taiwan should focus on developing its own advantageous industries and improve its overall competitiveness, rather than comparing with other countries and regions.</li>
<li><strong>Importance of Capitalists:</strong> Reiterated that both individuals and countries should learn the thinking of capital operation and become capitalists, rather than relying solely on labor and production.</li>
<li><strong>Taiwan&rsquo;s Financial Environment:</strong> Believes that Taiwan&rsquo;s financial environment is very good, even better than the United States (such as low interest rates, no capital gains tax, etc.), providing good conditions for investors.</li>
<li><strong>No Need to Compare:</strong> Taiwan doesn&rsquo;t need to compare with other Asian little dragons.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Lina 
    <div id="lina" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#lina" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Question:</strong> Regarding the issues of AI regulation and AI fraud, how should ordinary people prevent it?
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo; Response:</strong>
<ul>
<li><strong>People Vulnerable to Fraud:</strong> Pointed out that elderly people, people who lack investment knowledge, and people who covet petty gains are more vulnerable to AI fraud.</li>
<li><strong>Preventive Measures:</strong>
<ul>
<li><strong>Do Not Click on Links Randomly:</strong> Do not click on links from unknown sources, especially those that claim to provide free benefits.</li>
<li><strong>Do Not Join Unknown Groups:</strong> Do not join investment groups, financial management groups, etc. from unknown sources.</li>
<li><strong>Do Not Covet Petty Gains:</strong> Do not believe in &ldquo;pie in the sky&rdquo; good things, and do not be tempted by promises of high returns and low risks.</li>
<li><strong>Verify from Multiple Parties:</strong> If you encounter suspicious investment opportunities, verify from multiple parties and consult professional opinions.</li>
<li><strong>Protect Personal Information:</strong> Do not easily disclose personal information, especially sensitive information such as bank accounts and passwords.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>AI Regulation Issues:</strong>
<ul>
<li><strong>OpenAI is Not Open:</strong> Pointed out that OpenAI&rsquo;s &ldquo;non-openness&rdquo; is a problem. The decision-making process of AI should be transparent to humans and accept human supervision.</li>
<li><strong>Honesty of AI:</strong> Believes that AI should be honest with humans and should not deceive humans.</li>
<li><strong>Necessity of Regulation:</strong> Emphasized the necessity of AI regulation, but how to regulate it specifically still needs further discussion.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Jason 
    <div id="jason" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#jason" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing:</strong>
<ol>
<li><strong>Organizing Manuscript:</strong> Shared the progress of organizing James&rsquo; videos and articles into a manuscript, which has been organized to the fifth chapter.</li>
<li><strong>Personal Gains:</strong>
<ul>
<li><strong>Deepen Understanding:</strong> Deepened his understanding of the CLEC investment philosophy by organizing the manuscript.</li>
<li><strong>Leave Information:</strong> Reduced his attention to financial news and market information and focused more on long-term investment.</li>
<li><strong>Focus on Life:</strong> Has more time and energy to invest in his hobbies and public welfare activities.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ol>
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo; Comments:</strong>
<ul>
<li>Highly affirmed and appreciated Jason&rsquo;s organizing work and personal growth.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question:</strong> For investors in mainland China who cannot purchase leveraged funds (QLD), is it possible to keep investing in QQQ at regular intervals? Is this method feasible?
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo; Response:</strong>
<ul>
<li><strong>Completely Feasible:</strong> For investors in mainland China, since they cannot purchase leveraged funds, the following strategies can be adopted:
<ul>
<li><strong>Office Workers:</strong>
<ul>
<li>Retain six months of emergency reserve funds (cash).</li>
<li>Invest all remaining funds in A-share NASDAQ ETFs (such as 513100, 159941, etc.).</li>
<li>Hold for the long term and invest regularly.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Retirees:</strong>
<ul>
<li>Adopt an 80/20 asset allocation (80% invested in A-share NASDAQ ETFs, 20% invested in cash or short-term bonds).</li>
<li>Rebalance regularly.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Advanced Strategies:</strong>
<ul>
<li><strong>Open an Account in Hong Kong:</strong> Suggests that after investing for a period of time (such as 3-5 years), if conditions permit, investors can consider opening an account in Hong Kong to directly purchase US stock QQQ and QLD and enjoy lower transaction fees and more flexible investment options.</li>
<li><strong>Gradual Transition:</strong> Gradually transfer A-share assets to a Hong Kong account to achieve a more optimized asset allocation.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Additional Notes:</strong></li>
<li>Keep it simple when you first start investing
*   If the child&rsquo;s account is not managed by him, you can invest in QLD</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Julie 
    <div id="julie" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#julie" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Question:</strong> Worries about inflation and the Fed&rsquo;s policies. Recently, US CPI data has risen, and the market is worried that the Fed will postpone interest rate cuts or even raise interest rates, which will negatively affect the stock market?
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo; Response:</strong>
<ul>
<li><strong>Relationship between Interest Rates and the Stock Market:</strong>
<ul>
<li><strong>No Obvious Correlation:</strong> Clearly pointed out that there is no obvious correlation between the 10-year US Treasury yield (TNX) and the trend of QQQ. Suggested that students can make their own graphs for comparison to verify this conclusion.</li>
<li><strong>Do Not Pay Too Much Attention:</strong> Do not pay too much attention to interest rates and the Fed&rsquo;s policies, as these factors have little impact on the long-term trend of the stock market.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>US Economic Prospects:</strong>
<ul>
<li><strong>Very Optimistic:</strong> Very optimistic about the US economic prospects, believing that the next four years (Trump&rsquo;s second term) will be better than any of the past four years.</li>
<li><strong>Reasons:</strong>
<ul>
<li><strong>Strong System:</strong> The United States has a strong political and economic system that can self-repair and adjust.</li>
<li><strong>Excellent Political Officials:</strong> Trump&rsquo;s government officials are very good and have the ability to cope with various challenges.</li>
<li><strong>Economic Policies:</strong> Trump&rsquo;s economic policies (such as tax cuts, trade protection, etc.) are conducive to the long-term development of the US economy.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Investment Recommendations:</strong>
<ul>
<li><strong>Hold for the Long Term:</strong> Continue to hold QQQ for the long term and do not be affected by short-term market fluctuations.</li>
<li><strong>Seize Opportunities:</strong> Do not miss the opportunity for the rapid development of the US economy, now is a good time to invest in the United States.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Mike 
    <div id="mike" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#mike" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing:</strong>
<ol>
<li><strong>TSMC Premium:</strong> Discussed the issue that TSMC&rsquo;s ADR (TSM) in the United States has a premium relative to the Taiwan parent stock (2330.TW).</li>
<li><strong>US Policies:</strong> Shared his views on US policies, believing that the United States is taking a series of measures to enhance its competitiveness.</li>
</ol>
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo; Comments:</strong>
<ul>
<li><strong>Reasons for the Premium:</strong>
<ul>
<li><strong>Market Differences:</strong> Premiums and discounts are normal phenomena between different markets, just like the price of the same commodity may be different in different stores.</li>
<li><strong>Capital Flows:</strong> The US market has more funds and institutional investors, and the demand for high-quality assets is higher, leading to price increases.</li>
<li><strong>Convenience:</strong> US investors are more inclined to buy familiar stocks in the local market, even if there is a premium.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Taiwan&rsquo;s Financial Opening:</strong> Believes that whether Taiwan&rsquo;s financial market is fully open has no direct relationship with TSMC&rsquo;s premium in the United States.</li>
<li><strong>TSMC&rsquo;s Strategy:</strong> Suggests that TSMC adopt a &ldquo;cold treatment&rdquo; strategy for the investment requirements of the United States and not easily give in.</li>
<li><strong>Affirm Mike:</strong> Affirmed Mike&rsquo;s insights and analytical skills.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Becky 
    <div id="becky" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#becky" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing:</strong>
<ol>
<li><strong>California Problems:</strong> Expressed dissatisfaction with the current situation in California, including severe homelessness, inefficient government, insufficient public services, high home insurance costs, and difficulty in reconstruction.</li>
<li><strong>Medicare Issues:</strong> Shared the difficulties encountered in helping family members apply for Medicare (federal health insurance), believing that the Medicare system is very complex and difficult for ordinary people to understand.</li>
</ol>
<ul>
<li><strong>James and Mike&rsquo;s Response:</strong></li>
<li><strong>Acknowledge the Problems:</strong>
<ul>
<li>Acknowledged that there are many problems in California, and these problems are real.</li>
<li>Pointed out that these problems are mainly caused by the mismanagement of the California governor and government.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>America Needs Reform:</strong>
<ul>
<li>Emphasized that the United States needs to be reformed, especially in government efficiency, public services, and health insurance.</li>
<li>Believes that the Trump administration is working hard to solve these problems.
- <strong>Side Effects of Capitalism:</strong></li>
<li>Pointed out that problems such as homelessness and wealth inequality are inherent defects of the capitalist system and cannot be completely avoided.</li>
<li>The goal of CLEC investment is to help people achieve financial freedom under the capitalist system and reduce the impact of these problems on individuals.
-   <strong>Importance of Personal Decisions:</strong></li>
<li>Emphasized that personal decisions in investment and life are very important.</li>
<li>Pointed out that the house being burned down was a mistake in personal investment decision-making (over-reliance on real estate).</li>
<li>Suggested that everyone learn CLEC investment and reduce risks through reasonable asset allocation.
-   <strong>Taiwan&rsquo;s Experience:</strong></li>
<li>Shared Taiwan&rsquo;s experience in taxation, medical care, public services, etc., believing that Taiwan&rsquo;s system is simpler and more efficient than the United States.</li>
<li>Believes that the United States can learn from Taiwan&rsquo;s experience.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">J 
    <div id="j" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#j" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Question:</strong> How to introduce the CLEC investment philosophy to my children aged 30-40? Are there any specific videos or materials that can be recommended to them so that they can quickly understand the core ideas of CLEC investment?
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo; Response:</strong>
<ul>
<li><strong>Understand the Needs:</strong> Recognized that introducing CLEC investment to young people requires a more concise and direct approach.</li>
<li><strong>Consider Special Lectures:</strong> Considered making a special lecture on &ldquo;From Rich to Wealthy to Tycoon,&rdquo; focusing on explaining the key differences and transformation methods between these three stages.</li>
<li><strong>Emphasize &ldquo;No Income&rdquo;:</strong> Emphasized the importance of &ldquo;how to get yourself no income,&rdquo; which is a key step in achieving financial freedom.</li>
<li><strong>Follow-up Plans:</strong> Expressed that he would seriously consider this issue and launch related teaching content as soon as possible.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">IV. Wonderful Quotes 
    <div id="iv-wonderful-quotes" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv-wonderful-quotes" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>Investing is very simple, but not easy, not easy.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>Emphasizes the importance of learning and understanding investment concepts, which requires time and patience, and should not be rushed.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Happiness is a gift, wealth is a human right. Financial freedom is a right that everyone should have.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>Emphasizes the importance of financial freedom, encouraging everyone to pursue financial freedom, which is a right and an attitude towards life.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Let him be strong, the breeze caresses the mountains. Let him hate, the bright moon creates the great river. Let him be ruthless, let him be evil, I have enough true energy in one breath.
&ndash; Jin Yong</p></blockquote>
<p>When discussing the economic comparison between Taiwan and South Korea, James quoted Jin Yong&rsquo;s poems, emphasizing focusing on one&rsquo;s own development, not comparing with others, and doing one&rsquo;s own thing best.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>My destiny is determined by me, not by heaven.
&ndash; Nezha</p></blockquote>
<p>Emphasizes the autonomy of life, fate is in one&rsquo;s own hands, and should not be influenced by external factors.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>What is the final decision of the success of life? How many people love you?
&ndash; Munger
Emphasizes the importance of interpersonal relationships, money is not everything in life, love and being loved are the most important.</p></blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>Borrow money forever, never repay, no interest.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>The core concept of stock pledge, achieving financial freedom through borrowing, while assets continue to appreciate, which is an advanced strategy of CLEC investment.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>American warships have cannons, and the bullets don&rsquo;t cost money.
&ndash;James</p></blockquote>
<p>Taiwan&rsquo;s financial investment environment is better than that of the United States. The cost of borrowing is low, and the investment environment is more favorable.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>How to get yourself no income? It is a kind of wisdom and a kind of ability.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>Emphasizes the importance of reducing taxable income through legal means, which is a key step in achieving financial freedom and a kind of wisdom.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Homelessness is a side effect of capitalism.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>While capitalism brings economic development, it also leads to problems such as wealth inequality and homelessness, which cannot be completely avoided.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">V. Summary 
    <div id="v-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#v-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This episode contains a lot of information. Through ChatGPT&rsquo;s analysis, James systematically elaborated on the concepts, strategies, and advantages of CLEC investment, and compared it with traditional investment education and influencer financial management. At the same time, it also deeply discussed important topics such as investor growth paths, asset allocation, risk management, and cash flow management, and answered various questions raised by students regarding the A-share NASDAQ premium, the American political economy, AI regulation, and personal financial planning.</p>
<p>James emphasized that long-term investing, focusing on indices, reasonably using leverage, doing a good job of asset allocation, maintaining cash flow, living in the present, and pursuing financial freedom and spiritual freedom are the core ideas of CLEC investment. He encouraged everyone to learn and practice CLEC investment and achieve financial freedom and control their lives through their own efforts.</p>

  



<div
  
    class="flex px-4 py-3 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900"
  >

  <span
    
      class="text-primary-400 ltr:pr-3 rtl:pl-3 flex items-center"
    >

    

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M506.3 417l-213.3-364c-16.33-28-57.54-28-73.98 0l-213.2 364C-10.59 444.9 9.849 480 42.74 480h426.6C502.1 480 522.6 445 506.3 417zM232 168c0-13.25 10.75-24 24-24S280 154.8 280 168v128c0 13.25-10.75 24-23.1 24S232 309.3 232 296V168zM256 416c-17.36 0-31.44-14.08-31.44-31.44c0-17.36 14.07-31.44 31.44-31.44s31.44 14.08 31.44 31.44C287.4 401.9 273.4 416 256 416z"/></svg>

  </span>


  </span>

  <span
    
      class="dark:text-neutral-300"
    ><strong>Disclaimer:</strong> This article is only a personal study note and does not constitute any investment advice.</span>
</div>

]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>00502 Financial Leverage: How to Maximize Asset Allocation Returns? The Market Has No Lows, Only Highs: How to Escape Wrong Timing Strategies?</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1739684105629/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1739684105629/</guid><description>This episode mainly revolves around topics such as investment philosophy, asset allocation, insurance selection, and retirement planning, emphasizing long-term investment and overcoming human nature.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<lite-youtube videoid="dv2AJ4sVgfQ" playlabel="dv2AJ4sVgfQ" params=""></lite-youtube>



<h2 class="relative group">I. Current Theme 
    <div id="i-current-theme" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-current-theme" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This episode mainly discusses the following core themes:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Investing in Humanity for the Long Term:</strong> Emphasizing that the essence of investment is investing in the development of the entire human society, rather than short-term market fluctuations or individual company financial reports.</li>
<li><strong>Overcoming Human Weaknesses:</strong> Investors need to overcome human weaknesses such as fear and greed, and maintain extreme optimism and a long-term perspective.</li>
<li><strong>Importance of Asset Allocation:</strong> Recommend different asset allocation strategies for different age groups and financial situations, such as the 442, 433, or 80/20 principles.</li>
<li><strong>Avoiding Financial Scams:</strong> Exposing financial scams and insurance traps under the capitalist system, reminding investors to be vigilant.</li>
<li><strong>Cancel Insurance Early:</strong> Strongly recommend canceling all insurance policies, unless it is term life insurance for the family&rsquo;s primary income earner with minor children.</li>
<li><strong>Sell Property Early:</strong> Suggest selling property and investing the funds in index funds for higher returns.</li>
<li><strong>Asset Pledging:</strong> Discussing how to obtain funds through asset pledging and use them for investment to improve overall returns.</li>
<li><strong>Attitude Towards Evangelists:</strong> Like Christian missionaries, convey investment ideas without forcing others to accept them.</li>
<li><strong>Importance of Cash:</strong> Asset allocation should include at least 20% cash.</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">II. Briefing Content 
    <div id="ii-briefing-content" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii-briefing-content" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">1. Investment Philosophy 
    <div id="1-investment-philosophy" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#1-investment-philosophy" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Investing in Humanity&rsquo;s Financial Reports:</strong> Instead of looking at individual company financial reports and short-term economic situations, focus on the development trend of the entire human race over thousands of years. Invest in indexes, looking at the performance of all of humanity.</li>
<li><strong>Investors Are Always Extremely Optimistic:</strong> Investment requires long-term optimism, believing that the market will eventually rise.</li>
<li><strong>Overcoming Human Nature, Looking at the Market with a Cold Eye:</strong> Investors must overcome human weaknesses and not be affected by short-term market fluctuations. Need to practice remaining calm in the face of a tiger, believing there is glass in front of you, believing there is a safety net, no matter how the market falls.</li>
<li><strong>Understanding the Demons and Monsters of Capitalism:</strong> Recognize financial scams, insurance traps, and the government&rsquo;s wrong policies under the capitalist system, and avoid being exploited. Capitalism is efficient, but has side effects, coupled with financial industry scams, deception, and government collusion or wrong policies.</li>
<li><strong>Wealth is a Talent, and It Can Come True:</strong> The capitalist system allows everyone to have the opportunity to get rich, but requires correct knowledge and strategies. The education system is cultivating slave labor, while the financial industry is exploiting human weaknesses to sell fear. You can listen to Li Lu&rsquo;s speech to understand the difference between investment and speculation.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">2. Asset Allocation 
    <div id="2-asset-allocation" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#2-asset-allocation" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Young People:</strong> Young people who are still working should directly invest in the Nasdaq 100 index fund (QQQ) and consider using leveraged funds to increase returns. Young people must increase returns, there is no other choice, try to buy leveraged funds.</li>
<li><strong>Retirees:</strong>
<ul>
<li>Insufficient Assets: Take other strategies.</li>
<li>Sufficient Assets: Choose different asset allocation strategies depending on whether there is stock pledging and whether there are other income sources.
<ul>
<li><strong>No Pledging, Need to Withdraw Money from Assets:</strong> 80/20 principle (80% index funds, 20% cash).</li>
<li><strong>With Pledging, No Need to Withdraw Money from Stock Assets:</strong> 442 principle (40% index funds, 40% leveraged funds, 20% cash).</li>
<li><strong>No Pledging, No Other Income:</strong> 433 principle. If there is no other income, and you need to withdraw money from assets, only 80/20. Have stock pledging, do not need to withdraw money from assets to use 442.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Emergency Fund:</strong> Use 00864B as an emergency fund to cope with unexpected situations.</li>
<li><strong>About Loans:</strong>
<ul>
<li>All loans must be able to be repaid from salary or stable cash flow.</li>
<li>Try to pay off loans before retirement.</li>
<li>If there is a mortgage that has not been paid off after retirement, part of the funds can be invested in high-dividend ETFs (such as 0056), and the dividends used to pay the mortgage interest, with the remaining funds used for investment. For example, borrow NT$10 million, with an interest rate of 2.78%, and no repayment is required for 20 years. The annual interest is NT$278,000, requiring NT$4.5 million to be placed in 0056, because 0056 has a 6% dividend yield, and the remaining NT$5.5 million is added to the 433 or 442 allocation. If there is also rental income, you can use 442.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">3. Insurance 
    <div id="3-insurance" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#3-insurance" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Strongly Recommend Canceling All Insurance:</strong> Most insurance policies are scams, exploiting human weaknesses to sell fear.</li>
<li><strong>Term Life Insurance:</strong> If you are the family&rsquo;s primary income earner and have minor children, you can purchase term life insurance to protect the family&rsquo;s financial security in the event of an accident. Only buy term life insurance that is purchased once a year, which is cheaper. If your assets reach 20-30 million, you don&rsquo;t need to insure anymore.</li>
<li><strong>Funds from Redeeming Insurance:</strong> Invest in index funds to obtain higher returns.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">4. Property 
    <div id="4-property" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#4-property" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Not Recommended to Purchase Property:</strong> Houses are fixed assets, lack liquidity, and have high risks. Taichung Shin Kong Mitsukoshi will close down, and real estate will too. If you buy a house to live in for 60 years, and are forced to live in the same house for 60 years, that&rsquo;s strange.</li>
<li><strong>Sell Property:</strong> Suggest selling property and investing the funds in index funds to obtain higher returns.</li>
<li><strong>Rich People Buy Houses:</strong> Only after becoming rich can you buy houses as casually as buying slippers.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">5. Other 
    <div id="5-other" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#5-other" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Convert Roth IRA:</strong> Don&rsquo;t wait for the market to fall before converting to a Roth IRA, do what needs to be done as soon as possible. January 1st and 2nd may be the lowest points of this year.</li>
<li><strong>Overcoming Human Nature:</strong> In the face of market fluctuations, stay optimistic, eat well, sleep well, and have no worries.</li>
<li><strong>AI and Tech Development:</strong> The development of AI may promote exponential growth in U.S. stocks, with long-term returns expected.</li>
<li><strong>Longevity Risk:</strong> Need to consider the financial risks brought about by longevity and plan ahead. Need to plan to live to 120 years old.</li>
<li><strong>Children&rsquo;s Education:</strong> The focus should be on letting children learn happily and explore life goals, not just to make money.</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">III. Q&amp;A Session 
    <div id="iii-qa-session" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii-qa-session" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Xiaoxia 
    <div id="xiaoxia" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#xiaoxia" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question 1: The family income is divided between husband and wife. Is the 433 or 442 asset allocation based on the husband or the family income?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Response: It depends on each family&rsquo;s situation. If it is centrally managed or centrally thought out, you can think in the thinking mode of the whole family, depending on whether you understand the financial situation of the whole family. If the husband is more conservative and mostly in cash, the wife can be more aggressive and buy leveraged funds to balance it.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2: My son is studying abroad, and the monthly expenses are NT$40,000. How should I include this in the expenses?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Response: Treat this expense as a fixed deposit asset, deduct it directly from 00864B, and separate it from investment assets. This part will be spent this year and cannot be regarded as an investment asset. Transfer it directly to 00864B so that it will not be affected by market fluctuations for at least one year.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Feida 
    <div id="feida" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#feida" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question: Currently holding 00662 and 00670L, allocated in an 80/20 ratio, and not withdrawing money from stock assets, do I need to adjust to 442?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Response: If you need money, you can consider using credit, and then use the extra money you borrowed to allocate to 442. Borrow money, buy stocks with NT$1 million borrowed, and put NT$1 million in cash. Switching to 442 immediately will increase your return through two-tenths of the cash. Ask how much you can borrow. If the bank dares to lend, don&rsquo;t be afraid.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question: If gradually adjusting to 442, how to arrange the buying order?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Response: Sell 00662 and convert to 00670L, as long as the total asset beta value is 1.2, the rate of return will remain unchanged. If you can take out a loan, take out the loan as soon as possible and adjust to 442 immediately. Hurry up and borrow, change it immediately.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Grace 
    <div id="grace" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#grace" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question: Trump may carry out tax reform. Should I suspend converting to a Roth IRA?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Response: Do what needs to be done first, don&rsquo;t wait. Trump&rsquo;s policies will not have a big impact in the short term, and you can change your strategy after he signs it. Trump has a lot of things to do, and the tax exemption for Social Security isn&rsquo;t signed yet.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Sara 
    <div id="sara" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#sara" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question 1: How did you come to the conclusion that you may live to 120 years old in the future?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Response: Now technology is developing rapidly, many diseases can be treated, and parents&rsquo; genes also have an impact, so living to 120 years old is expected.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2: How do you view the possibility of exponential growth in U.S. stocks after the AI breakout?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Response: U.S. stocks have always had exponential growth, and now because of AI, the annualized return may be higher in the future. It used to be 6%, then it jumped to 8% when the steam engine and electricity appeared, then it jumped to 12-14% when the Internet appeared, and now it may jump to 25% because of AI.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Summer 
    <div id="summer" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#summer" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question: I bought an investment property in the Bay Area. Should I sell it now?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Response: Sell it immediately. The later you wait, the greater the loss. Non-Americans who buy American houses pay very high taxes, and the estate tax is also very high, which is not cost-effective. If your child plans to study in the United States in the future, then wait until you need it. If you buy it, you will earn money in the future, and your taxes will be very high, and 1/3 will be taken away first. The asset estate tax is 40%, and the tax exemption is only 60,000.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Jia 
    <div id="jia" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#jia" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question 1: Is it possible to borrow Japanese yen through Interactive Brokers to spend?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Response: It&rsquo;s better to borrow Japanese yen to invest in U.S. stocks, just like Buffett, so there is no exchange rate risk. Just spend the money you can afford to spend now.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2: Is it worth it for a 15-year-old child to work at McDonald&rsquo;s to open a Roth IRA?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Response: A 15-year-old child should study hard and live a happy life. Making money is not what they should be doing now. They should be taught how to manage money.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Jenny 
    <div id="jenny" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#jenny" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question 1: If the bank wants to liquidate debts after asset pledging, will the stocks be sold?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Response: The bank will not ask you to repay the money. The debt can be divided. The heirs inherit the assets and inherit the debts at the same time. Putting the account in a trust can also avoid a certification. After putting it in the trust, you can save on probate, just follow the trust. Trust just avoids probation.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2: Recent retirees have property and savings. Do they need to open a Rollover IRA?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Response: If they refuse to sell the property, there is no way to help them with financial planning. Sell the property, put it in a brokerage account, and live on 80/20 borrowing is fine.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 3: Children&rsquo;s company stocks are doing well. Should they be sold to buy QQQ?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Response: If you sell employee stocks now and earn 50,000 tax-free, you can slowly transfer them; otherwise, exchange for QQQ when you have income.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 4: How can I get the kids to take the money they earn to buy QQQ?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Response: This guy is already addicted to drugs, it&rsquo;s very difficult to quit. Encourage him to invest more money, match as much as you can in the brokerage account, and see if they are willing to do what you say. You can encourage children to invest more money into the brokerage account.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Max 
    <div id="max" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#max" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question: How to prevent elders in the countryside from being tempted by insurance agents and keep holding stocks?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Response: Keep in touch, accompany him, and cheer him up. Join the group, and everyone can help him analyze and answer his questions. You can transfer the stocks to a Yuanta Securities pledging account, but don&rsquo;t pledge them, so you can&rsquo;t buy or sell them, and there is an emergency available amount. Tell him that it has been pledged and there is no cash.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Christina 
    <div id="christina" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#christina" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question 1: How to open a Roth IRA account for a child who works part-time in high school?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Response: Find Lisa to open an account, either online or in the office, and open an account in the child&rsquo;s name. If you want to see the account online, you need to sign for power of attorney.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2: How to join Chen Feng and Naixin&rsquo;s group?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Response: There is a link on the message board. You can only join with a LINE registered with a Taiwanese mobile phone number. You can also add Peter&rsquo;s and the doctor&rsquo;s WeChat.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Shufen (Sharing) 
    <div id="shufen-sharing" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#shufen-sharing" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Because insurance was cancelled and entered QQQ (525), I wasn&rsquo;t too worried even after the price dropped.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Response: Thumbs up</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Grace (Sharing) 
    <div id="grace-sharing" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#grace-sharing" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: After listening to James, I bought QQQ and have a large sum of money now. Now I&rsquo;ve started asking my son to buy QQQ, and a masseuse who heard her sharing also wants to learn about investing.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Comment: Very happy to have helped more people.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chen Feng (Sharing) 
    <div id="chen-feng-sharing" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chen-feng-sharing" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Relatives and friends have become interested in investing due to continuous persuasion. Investment itself is psychology, and if the 80/20 allocation doesn&rsquo;t work, the mental account doesn&rsquo;t work.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Response: The 20% cash in asset allocation is very important, to preach, whether or not someone understands is their business.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">IV. Wonderful Views 
    <div id="iv-wonderful-views" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv-wonderful-views" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>Investors can only be extremely optimistic, there is no other way. Investors always influence the sunshine, the market will eventually rise, investment requires patience, and wealth is worth waiting for.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p><em>Background: This is a summary of investor mentality, emphasizing the confidence and patience of long-term investment.</em></p>
<blockquote>
<p>The world is unfair. I always say that one day, two lives, three lucks, heaven is your DNA, this is impossible, life is which country you were born in, this is life.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p><em>Background: When discussing his feelings about traveling to Egypt, he expressed his feelings about the unfairness of the world, and that fate is different when you are born in different places.</em></p>
<blockquote>
<p>Correct you immediately if you are wrong, the later you wait, the greater your loss.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p><em>Background: Emphasized that in investment decisions, if you find an error, correct it in time, do not hesitate, and cause greater losses.</em></p>
<blockquote>
<p>Young people who are still working should directly invest in the Nasdaq 100 index fund, there is no other choice, because you must increase your returns, right?
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p><em>Background: Aiming at young investors, it is recommended to invest heavily in the Nasdaq 100 index fund to obtain higher returns.</em></p>
<blockquote>
<p>Now in the United States, the leader is the Joint Group will speak a possible place where it is possible to have to expand all the full amount to buy a house, because you can&rsquo;t buy insurance, the United States if you can&rsquo;t buy insurance that can only buy a full amount of housing.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p><em>Background: Shared the potential risks of the US real estate market. In some areas, houses may be difficult to sell due to insurance issues.</em></p>
<blockquote>
<p>Capitalism itself is a fair, just, and open system, but everyone is using this system to say things that are seemingly true.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p><em>Background: Pointed out the problems of the capitalist system, which is that it is used by some people for financial scams and transfer of benefits.</em></p>
<blockquote>
<p>Financial management is a scam to me, and insurance is also a scam.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p><em>Background: He bluntly expressed his views on financial management products and insurance, believing that many of them use human weaknesses to commit fraud.</em></p>
<blockquote>
<p>If you are tormented by the market for a long time, then you need to think about whether your position is too heavy? Or are you not suitable for investing at all?
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p><em>Background: Reminded investors that if they are affected by market fluctuations for a long time, they should reflect on whether their positions are too heavy, or whether they are suitable for investing.</em></p>
<blockquote>
<p>Redeem all insurance, and then unless your children are very small, buy term life insurance, which is to buy it once a year, buy one every year.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p><em>Background: Re-emphasized the choice of insurance, and that term life insurance is only needed in special circumstances.</em></p>


<h2 class="relative group">V. Summary 
    <div id="v-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#v-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>In this episode, James emphasized the importance of long-term investment, overcoming human weaknesses, avoiding financial scams and unnecessary risks, and adopting appropriate asset allocation strategies to achieve wealth growth. At the same time, he reminded everyone that investment is a process that requires continuous learning and companionship.</p>

  



<div
  
    class="flex px-4 py-3 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900"
  >

  <span
    
      class="text-primary-400 ltr:pr-3 rtl:pl-3 flex items-center"
    >

    

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M506.3 417l-213.3-364c-16.33-28-57.54-28-73.98 0l-213.2 364C-10.59 444.9 9.849 480 42.74 480h426.6C502.1 480 522.6 445 506.3 417zM232 168c0-13.25 10.75-24 24-24S280 154.8 280 168v128c0 13.25-10.75 24-23.1 24S232 309.3 232 296V168zM256 416c-17.36 0-31.44-14.08-31.44-31.44c0-17.36 14.07-31.44 31.44-31.44s31.44 14.08 31.44 31.44C287.4 401.9 273.4 416 256 416z"/></svg>

  </span>


  </span>

  <span
    
      class="dark:text-neutral-300"
    ><strong>Disclaimer:</strong> This article is only a personal study note and does not constitute any investment advice.</span>
</div>

]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>00494 Leveraging Debt for Wealth: A New Approach to Retirement Planning; Unlocking Family Assets: Combining Equity-Release Mortgages with Index Funds</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1733617616782/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1733617616782/</guid><description>In this session, James discusses the utilization of revolving line of credit home loans, investment philosophy, how to overcome the psychological pressure brought on by market fluctuations, and how to extract wisdom from life experiences. He emphasizes the importance of long-term and value investing, reiterating the investment philosophy of &amp;#39;buy when you have money, never sell.&amp;#39; He also addresses questions from students regarding leveraged funds, price-to-earnings ratios, and newly issued ETFs.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<lite-youtube videoid="g4KoDgPDNjs" playlabel="g4KoDgPDNjs" params=""></lite-youtube>



<h2 class="relative group">I. Main Topic 
    <div id="i-main-topic" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-main-topic" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This session revolves around investment and life wisdom. The core idea is to maintain a long-term perspective on investments, avoid being influenced by short-term market fluctuations, and continuously learn from life experiences to form one&rsquo;s own investment philosophy and life wisdom.  Just like life, investment also requires continuous learning and reflection.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">II. Presentation Content 
    <div id="ii-presentation-content" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii-presentation-content" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Utilizing Revolving Line of Credit Home Loans 
    <div id="utilizing-revolving-line-of-credit-home-loans" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#utilizing-revolving-line-of-credit-home-loans" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>People nearing retirement can consider using a revolving line of credit home loan (HELOC), treating the credit line as a part of their cash reserves for living expenses without touching the principal investment, thereby increasing overall asset returns.  For example, if someone has $40 million in retirement funds and obtains a $10 million HELOC, the total assets become $50 million, and the annual disposable funds increase from $800,000 to $1 million.</li>
<li>The HELOC credit line can supplement the 20% cash portion of asset allocation.</li>
<li>Note: It&rsquo;s easier to obtain a HELOC before retirement; it becomes more difficult afterward. The loan term typically doesn&rsquo;t exceed age 90.</li>
<li>It&rsquo;s not recommended to take out a loan after retirement to repay the HELOC.</li>
<li>A listener shared a strategy of using a HELOC for living expenses, which James considers a good option.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Investment Philosophy and Market Analysis 
    <div id="investment-philosophy-and-market-analysis" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#investment-philosophy-and-market-analysis" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>The market, like life, requires a long-term perspective to see the big picture. Avoid being misled by short-term fluctuations.</li>
<li>In the age of AI, human development will accelerate, and the market will continue to rise. The next two to three decades will be a period of prosperity. QQQ might reach $500,000.</li>
<li>Focus on long-term trends in investing. Don&rsquo;t be swayed by short-term market analysts or news.  Focus on long-term growth, not short-term gains.</li>
<li>If you can&rsquo;t withstand a 50% loss, it&rsquo;s not recommended to enter the market.</li>
<li>Invest in Nasdaq 100 index funds (QQQ), unless retirement funds are insufficient.</li>
<li>Short-term declines are inevitable. Be mentally prepared and maintain sufficient cash reserves.</li>
<li>Reiterates the long-term investment strategy of &ldquo;buy when you have money, never sell,&rdquo; and recommends single lump-sum market price purchases.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Extracting Life Wisdom 
    <div id="extracting-life-wisdom" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#extracting-life-wisdom" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Strive for daily progress, reflect and summarize regularly (daily, monthly, yearly). Extract life philosophy from experiences and store them in your personal &ldquo;database&rdquo; to continuously accumulate wisdom.</li>
<li>Reflect on everything, from trivial matters (like growing tomatoes) to major social events, to form a comprehensive outlook on life and investment philosophy.</li>
<li>Learn from past experiences. Reflect on what you would do differently if given a second chance to improve yourself.</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">III. Q&amp;A Session 
    <div id="iii-qa-session" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii-qa-session" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Michael 
    <div id="michael" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#michael" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question 1: How to use the smart rebalancing strategy before retirement?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: As long as you hold leveraged funds, you can use the smart rebalancing strategy.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2: How to calculate the Beta value of a portfolio holding TQQQ, QQQ, and cash?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: Calculate the weighted average based on the proportion of each asset and its corresponding Beta value (cash is 0, QQQ is 1, TQQQ is 3). He reshared the calculation formula with the audience.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Louis Lu 
    <div id="louis-lu" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#louis-lu" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Expressed admiration for James&rsquo;s insights from a month prior regarding the possibility of Bitcoin becoming a reserve currency for the US dollar, noting that James&rsquo;s response aligned with Federal Reserve Chairman Powell&rsquo;s views.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Comment:  Expressed gratitude for the acknowledgment and mentioned that it&rsquo;s a fundamental concept in finance and monetary policy, covered in previous lessons.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Shu Fen 
    <div id="shu-fen" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#shu-fen" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing:  Shared her experience of investing most of her retirement funds in savings insurance a few years ago, resulting in much lower returns than expected. This year, she redeemed a portion of the funds and invested in QQQ, achieving better returns (13.68% in three months). However, with the current market reaching new highs, she&rsquo;s hesitant to invest further, finding it difficult to overcome the psychological barrier of &ldquo;buying with eyes closed.&rdquo;
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Comment: Courage comes from the subconscious and requires training.  Believe that the market will continue to rise and practice self-hypnosis to reinforce the &ldquo;buy when you have money&rdquo; concept. Used the example of QQQ potentially reaching $500,000 to illustrate that the current price is still very cheap.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Sen Lin 
    <div id="sen-lin" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#sen-lin" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question: What&rsquo;s the difference between 00662 and QQQ?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply:  Suggested referring to the relevant link, as this question has been answered multiple times to avoid redundant explanations.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Yi Wan 
    <div id="yi-wan" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#yi-wan" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Agreed with James&rsquo;s investment method but hesitated to share it with older or same-age individuals. Felt more comfortable sharing with younger people, such as encouraging students to start saving $50-$100 per month.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Comment: Sharing depends on (affinity/serendipity).  Sometimes our remedy is another&rsquo;s poison. Sharing can also have negative consequences.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Zai 
    <div id="zai" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#zai" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Responded to Shu Fen&rsquo;s question about lump-sum buying, suggesting buying in batches or on specific dates, such as birthdays, to overcome psychological barriers.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Comment: Investing requires reaching a state of belief.  Continuous self-hypnosis is needed.  &ldquo;Buy immediately at market price when you have money&rdquo; is the only truth, no further analysis needed.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Ai Na 
    <div id="ai-na" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ai-na" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: After following James&rsquo;s advice, she redeemed funds from savings insurance and invested in QQQ and QLD. However, due to insufficient trading frequency, she couldn&rsquo;t purchase QQQ 2D. Her current living expenses are primarily covered by alimony, and the cost of living in Taiwan is relatively low.</li>
<li>Question 1: Does she need to buy and sell repeatedly to meet the trading frequency requirement?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: Yes, she can make small, frequent trades to meet the brokerage&rsquo;s requirements.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2: Can she buy fractional shares in Taiwan?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: Yes, but it&rsquo;s recommended to buy whole shares first and use the remaining funds for fractional shares.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 3: How to calculate retirement fund needs?  Can she receive social security?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: Calculate retirement fund needs based on annual expenses. Alimony can be considered income, but it&rsquo;s recommended to claim social security (even if her ex-husband objects) and adjust the asset allocation ratio accordingly, as alimony is not a permanent income source. She needs to be prepared.  Also recommended switching from SWVXX to BOXX.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chen Feng 
    <div id="chen-feng" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chen-feng" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Shared his personal investment journey, starting from entering the stock market in 2021, experiencing the &ldquo;bruised and battered&rdquo; phase of short-term trading, to shifting to long-term investing after encountering James&rsquo;s channel. He also established a study group of nearly 300 people, experiencing the benefits of &ldquo;teaching and learning from each other.&rdquo; He shared how he introduced the investment philosophy to his sister with 30 years of stock market experience, emphasizing the importance of a gradual approach.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Comment: Affirmed PC&rsquo;s sharing, adding the principles of &ldquo;Buddha saves those who are destined&rdquo; and &ldquo;Sentient beings save the Buddha.&rdquo;  When sharing investment concepts with family, start with small amounts of capital, like planting seeds and nurturing them gradually.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Nai Xi 
    <div id="nai-xi" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#nai-xi" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Thanked James and her friend Yu Sheng for their help.  Shared experiences of learning and sharing investment concepts with friends and expressed gratitude for the study group.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Comment: Shared his early investment experience in 1990, being introduced to investing by his friend Frank, who patiently explained investment knowledge to him weekly, eventually igniting his passion for investing.  Emphasized the importance of mentors.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">IM 
    <div id="im" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#im" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Felt that James is cultivating logical thinking in students and shared experiences of communicating investment concepts with others.</li>
<li>Question 1: How did James achieve such a comprehensive understanding?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: Continuously review and summarize life experiences, extracting the essence, like refining an elixir.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2: How to communicate with people who believe &ldquo;the first $1 million is difficult&rdquo; and are hesitant to go all in?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: Guide them to think about how to achieve the first $1 million goal and the path to wealth.  Suggest small investments based on their risk tolerance, like planting seeds, to gradually cultivate investment confidence.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Hao Qing 
    <div id="hao-qing" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#hao-qing" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing 1: Discussed the psychological pressure of buying after a stock reaches new highs. Experienced investors feel more pressure due to having reference points, while newcomers are more receptive. Like buying discounted items in a supermarket, having the original price as a reference makes purchasing more appealing.</li>
<li>Sharing 2: Shared his views on two newly issued ETFs by Invesco (QBI and QQLV) and compared them to QQQ. QBI selects larger market cap stocks from QQQ, while QQLV selects stocks with lower volatility.</li>
<li>Question: What are James&rsquo;s views on these two new ETFs?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: Doesn&rsquo;t recommend investing in unfamiliar ETFs, even if they perform well.  Stick to investments within your circle of competence.  Used the analogy of marriage, advising to choose a partner you understand. Re-emphasized the importance of focusing on asset allocation and Beta adjustments rather than selecting new investment targets.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">IV. Key Takeaways 
    <div id="iv-key-takeaways" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv-key-takeaways" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>Buy immediately at market price when you have money.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>This is James&rsquo;s repeatedly emphasized investment philosophy, aiming to overcome investors&rsquo; psychological barriers and seize market opportunities.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Life shouldn&rsquo;t be lived in vain.  Continuously reflect, summarize, and extract wisdom from experiences.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>This is not just investment wisdom, but life wisdom.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Teaching and learning promote each other. Buddha saves sentient beings, and sentient beings save the Buddha.
&ndash; James, Chen Feng</p></blockquote>
<p>Both teachers and students can grow through the process of teaching and sharing.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The seed itself is not the problem, it&rsquo;s the soil.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>An analogy for the dissemination of investment philosophy. Even good ideas require the right environment to take root.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">V. Summary 
    <div id="v-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#v-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This session covered investment philosophy, financial management skills, and life wisdom.  James reiterated the importance of long-term and value investing and encouraged everyone to overcome the psychological pressure of market fluctuations, firmly implementing the &ldquo;buy when you have money, never sell&rdquo; strategy. He also reminded everyone to continuously learn and extract wisdom from life experiences to ultimately achieve financial freedom and fulfill life&rsquo;s value. He also encouraged listeners to find their own mentors, learn from each other, and grow together, just like his early experiences.</p>

  



<div
  
    class="flex px-4 py-3 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900"
  >

  <span
    
      class="text-primary-400 ltr:pr-3 rtl:pl-3 flex items-center"
    >

    

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M506.3 417l-213.3-364c-16.33-28-57.54-28-73.98 0l-213.2 364C-10.59 444.9 9.849 480 42.74 480h426.6C502.1 480 522.6 445 506.3 417zM232 168c0-13.25 10.75-24 24-24S280 154.8 280 168v128c0 13.25-10.75 24-23.1 24S232 309.3 232 296V168zM256 416c-17.36 0-31.44-14.08-31.44-31.44c0-17.36 14.07-31.44 31.44-31.44s31.44 14.08 31.44 31.44C287.4 401.9 273.4 416 256 416z"/></svg>

  </span>


  </span>

  <span
    
      class="dark:text-neutral-300"
    ><strong>Disclaimer:</strong> This article is for personal learning notes only and does not constitute any investment advice.</span>
</div>

]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>00485 Buying a house will only make you poor. Investing makes you rich. Borrowing money to keep your assets growing is the way to become wealthy</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1728259977859/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1728259977859/</guid><description>This episode focuses on investment philosophy, strategies to avoid scams, and the impact of China&amp;#39;s newest economic policies on the global market. James reiterates the importance of long-term investment in index funds, specifically QQQ, and advises investors to control their emotions and resist market volatility. He uses real-life examples and data to illustrate the concept of borrowing for consumption, investing for asset growth, and analyzes China&amp;#39;s recent economic stimulus policies, viewing them as a positive sign for global economic recovery.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<lite-youtube videoid="zJdXwFaec2c" playlabel="zJdXwFaec2c" params=""></lite-youtube>



<h2 class="relative group">I. Main Topic 
    <div id="i-main-topic" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-main-topic" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This episode primarily discusses proper investment philosophy, ways to avoid investment traps, and the implications of China&rsquo;s latest economic policies for the global market. James emphasizes the importance of long-term investment in index funds, particularly QQQ, and reminds investors to maintain emotional control and not be swayed by market fluctuations. He uses specific examples and data to illustrate the concept of &ldquo;borrow for consumption, invest for asset growth,&rdquo; while also analyzing China&rsquo;s recently introduced series of economic stimulus policies, believing them to be a positive signal for a global economic recovery.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">II. Briefing Content 
    <div id="ii-briefing-content" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii-briefing-content" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<ul>
<li><strong>Investment Philosophy:</strong>
<ul>
<li>Emotions are the biggest enemy in investing. You need to avoid being influenced by news and information, stay rational, and refrain from chasing rising or falling markets.</li>
<li>Investing requires a long-term perspective, aiming for a timeframe of 40 years or more. Warren Buffett acquired 99% of his wealth after the age of 50, demonstrating that patience is key to wealth creation.</li>
<li>Choose investment targets that are consistently stable and provide high returns. Index funds are the best option, especially QQQ, which boasts a long-term annualized return of 14%.</li>
<li>Adhere to the &ldquo;never sell&rdquo; strategy to allow assets to continue appreciating. Avoid selling stocks unless absolutely necessary.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Scam Avoidance Guide:</strong>
<ul>
<li>Be wary of various investment traps. Do not trust any projects that guarantee high returns, especially those that require you to sell existing assets for new investments.</li>
<li>Do not readily believe any investment or financial management information received via phone, text messages, or online platforms. Any information involving bank accounts or government departments must be verified through official channels.</li>
<li>Be cautious of aggressive sales tactics from financial institutions. Stick to your investment plan and avoid being lured by various fancy financial products.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Regarding Real Estate Investment:</strong>
<ul>
<li>James advises against homeownership for average working individuals, believing it turns them into &ldquo;mortgage slaves&rdquo; burdened with heavy loan pressure, hindering wealth accumulation.</li>
<li>He advocates for a &ldquo;rent instead of buy&rdquo; approach, suggesting using a stock pledge loan to rent high-quality housing at lower interest rates, then investing the saved funds for higher returns.</li>
<li>Consider purchasing real estate only when your assets reach a certain scale and you can comfortably afford the payment.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>New Trends in China&rsquo;s Economy:</strong>
<ul>
<li>The People&rsquo;s Bank of China recently introduced a series of potent fiscal policies, including reserve requirement ratio and interest rate cuts, injecting funds into banks, and encouraging stock purchases, to stimulate economic growth.</li>
<li>These policies will contribute positively to stabilizing China&rsquo;s real estate market, boosting consumer confidence, and promoting global economic recovery.</li>
<li>Investors should pay attention to developments in the Chinese market and seize new investment opportunities.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">III. Q&amp;A Session 
    <div id="iii-qa-session" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii-qa-session" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p><strong>IM:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Through conversations with individuals of different age groups, IM discovered that most people have insufficient awareness of long-term savings and are often constrained by mortgages and other factors. By comparing the returns of index funds in different countries and regions with those of fixed deposits and pensions, IM illustrated the advantages of long-term investment in index funds.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>INGYNYING:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: INGYNYING&rsquo;s mother wanted to sell all her assets to purchase a house but, after persuasion, realized that this would lead to losing opportunities for asset appreciation. Many of INGYNYING&rsquo;s friends are afraid of change, preferring to endure the hardships of their current situation rather than attempt new investment methods.</li>
<li>Question: How to convince family members to accept new investment concepts?</li>
<li>James&rsquo; answer: Utilize data and case studies for illustration, such as comparing the long-term returns of fixed deposits and index funds, and sharing success stories of investors. It&rsquo;s also important to respect family members&rsquo; choices and refrain from forcing them to accept new ideas.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Allen:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Questions:  Should someone with assets worth 50 times their annual living expenses use their salary to pay for a car? How can a couple combine their stock accounts for collateral purposes?</li>
<li>James&rsquo; answer: It is recommended to utilize Tesla&rsquo;s official website loan to purchase a vehicle, then use funds from a stock pledge loan to repay the car loan. Dedicate your salary entirely to investment. Couples can combine their accounts through a joint account for collateral, sharing the limit, while their accounts remain individually managed.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Eric:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Question: Eric&rsquo;s mother is visiting the US and is concerned about medical expenses. How should this be  handled?</li>
<li>James&rsquo; answer:  Purchasing travel insurance is advised, but excessive worry is unnecessary. Most non-emergency situations can be treated back home. If encountering extremely high medical costs, attempting negotiation with the hospital or seeking alternative solutions is possible. Due to the specific circumstances of foreign nationality and lack of income, the hospital may choose not to pursue the medical expenses.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Dean:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Dean purchased a new car using Tesla&rsquo;s website loan and a stock pledge loan, conserving a significant amount of capital. Learning about investing boosted Dean&rsquo;s confidence to decline a high-paying job and choose to stay home with their child.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Michael:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Questions: How to secure a loan from Tesla&rsquo;s official website for a car purchase? Can funds from 401k or IRA accounts be used for collateral? What are the options if QQQ is not available in their company&rsquo;s 401k plan?</li>
<li>James&rsquo; answer: To apply for a car loan through Tesla&rsquo;s website, choose the desired model and configuration, click &ldquo;Order Now&rdquo;, and select &ldquo;Finance&rdquo;. Funds in retirement accounts cannot be used as collateral; it is recommended to transfer part of those funds to a brokerage account for collateral purposes.  Alternative options include choosing an S&amp;P 500 index fund or inquiring with the company about the possibility of Blockage Link to invest in QQQ.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>EVA:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Question: As a single, middle-aged woman with limited savings, how to balance work and investment? Should selling the house be considered for investment purposes?</li>
<li>James&rsquo; answer: Continue working diligently while consistently making monthly investments. Even small amounts will accumulate over 8-9 years, reaching the threshold for collateral, allowing you to leverage and accelerate wealth growth. Selling a house for investment is an option but requires careful consideration based on personal circumstances.  If renting is more cost-effective, choose to rent and allocate the funds to investments yielding higher returns.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Jenny:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Questions:  Any knowledge regarding the latest Roth SEP IRA policy?</li>
<li>James&rsquo; answer: The policy information is quite recent, and the accuracy of the $69,000 limit requires verification. Consulting with professionals like a financial advisor at Chase or Lisa is recommended. As it is a new product, not all institutions may offer it.</li>
<li>Sharing: Jenny shared a personal experience of being scammed, reminding everyone to exercise caution and avoid trusting any investment information, particularly those spread through unofficial channels.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Haoqing:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Haoqing relayed the experiences of close friends falling victim to scams, lamenting that scam tactics are constantly evolving and are hard to guard against, even for highly educated individuals.</li>
<li>Question: How can investment concepts be better conveyed to people around us to prevent them from being deceived? Is there a need to explain professional investment knowledge?</li>
<li>James&rsquo; answer: Avoid explaining intricate investment knowledge; simply emphasize the core principle of long-term investment in index funds. Excessive professional details may confuse them, making them more susceptible to being misled by other investment information and ultimately falling prey to scams.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Jason:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Recounted an NFT scam incident encountered on Clubhouse, warning everyone to be wary of risks in the cryptocurrency world. Expressed gratitude toward James&rsquo; investment philosophy for helping them avoid such traps.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Amy:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Amy shared personal encounters with scams, including impersonations of government departments and courier companies. She emphasized the importance of relying only on written communication and ignoring any investment information delivered through phone calls or text messages. Amy suggested that, when in doubt, contact official channels for clarification.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Becky:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Suggestion: Avoid answering calls from unfamiliar numbers, set up spam filters, and use a less important email address when necessary to share personal information to minimize the risk of scams.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Mike:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Question: What are your thoughts on China&rsquo;s most recent economic policies? Are they sustainable?</li>
<li>James&rsquo; answer: The People&rsquo;s Bank of China has introduced powerful policies that are having a positive impact on economic confidence. Investors should keep an eye on these developments. Although the policies appear to be heading in a positive direction, their sustainability remains to be seen.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Julia:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Question:  Any updates on the Roth SEP IRA policy? Are there any financial institutions already offering related products?</li>
<li>James&rsquo; answer: The policy information is fairly new, and the $69,000 limit&rsquo;s accuracy is debatable. Consulting with a professional is advised. Being a new product, not all institutions might offer it yet.</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">IV. Noteworthy Points 
    <div id="iv-noteworthy-points" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv-noteworthy-points" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>You have enough money when you have enough.&quot;
&ndash; Many people</p></blockquote>
<p>Many individuals believe that having just enough to get by is sufficient. This is a mistaken notion, as money is never truly enough. True financial freedom lies in possessing the power of choice  going wherever you want, doing whatever you desire  instead of being constrained by finances.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;Never borrow money for investments.&rdquo;
&ndash; Many people</p></blockquote>
<p>Many believe that borrowing for investment is unwise; however, this viewpoint is overly cautious. True investors, like Warren Buffett, skillfully leverage debt. Following the principle of &ldquo;borrow for consumption, invest for asset growth&rdquo;, the correct approach is to use borrowed money for expenses and personal money for investment. This enables rapid wealth accumulation.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>All investment information received through phone calls, text messages, or online platforms is not trustworthy.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>Nowadays, numerous scams operate through these channels. It&rsquo;s crucial to exercise caution and avoid blindly believing any financial advice or information. Anything involving bank accounts or government departments must be verified through official sources. Additionally, seeking guidance from qualified professionals is essential.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Investment must be consistently stable over the long term, which is why index funds are the only viable option.&quot;
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>Within the complex investment landscape, index funds stand out as a few reliable options capable of offering consistent stability and high returns. Index funds are like living organisms; they will never die, whereas all individual stocks will eventually disappear within a century.  If you&rsquo;re looking for generational wealth, index funds are the way to go.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">V. Summary 
    <div id="v-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#v-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This episode is packed with valuable information and insights. It not only reiterates the importance of long-term index fund investment but also offers practical tips on scam prevention and provides an in-depth analysis of China&rsquo;s newest economic policies.  It is recommended to apply this knowledge to your investment practices and strive for financial freedom.</p>

  



<div
  
    class="flex px-4 py-3 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900"
  >

  <span
    
      class="text-primary-400 ltr:pr-3 rtl:pl-3 flex items-center"
    >

    

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M506.3 417l-213.3-364c-16.33-28-57.54-28-73.98 0l-213.2 364C-10.59 444.9 9.849 480 42.74 480h426.6C502.1 480 522.6 445 506.3 417zM232 168c0-13.25 10.75-24 24-24S280 154.8 280 168v128c0 13.25-10.75 24-23.1 24S232 309.3 232 296V168zM256 416c-17.36 0-31.44-14.08-31.44-31.44c0-17.36 14.07-31.44 31.44-31.44s31.44 14.08 31.44 31.44C287.4 401.9 273.4 416 256 416z"/></svg>

  </span>


  </span>

  <span
    
      class="dark:text-neutral-300"
    ><strong>Disclaimer:</strong> This article serves solely as personal study notes and does not constitute any investment advice.</span>
</div>

]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>00477 Eternal Freedom from Worry and Stress: Wisdom and Strategies for Long-Term Investing</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1728565408053/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1728565408053/</guid><description>In this session, James shares his investment philosophy, emphasizing the importance of independent thinking and risk management. He also answers questions from students on topics such as TQQQ, emergency funds, MAGS fund, and real estate investment.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<lite-youtube videoid="CfFEQJkTCBw" playlabel="CfFEQJkTCBw" params=""></lite-youtube>



<h2 class="relative group">I. Main Theme 
    <div id="i-main-theme" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-main-theme" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This session focuses on the philosophy of long-term investing, emphasizing the importance of independent thinking and risk management. James reiterates his long-held investment philosophy: choose the right investment target (such as QQQ), buy in early and hold for the long term, ignoring short-term market fluctuations, and ultimately achieve steady wealth growth. In addition, he discusses how to maintain a positive mindset, deal with stress and anxiety that may arise during the investment process, and how to choose a reliable brokerage to ensure account security.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">II. Briefing Content 
    <div id="ii-briefing-content" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii-briefing-content" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<ul>
<li><strong>Wealth is accumulated slowly, and enjoying the process of wealth accumulation is the meaning of life.</strong> Getting rich overnight or quickly is not the best way. Slowly accumulating wealth and enjoying it allows you to experience the true meaning of life and learn and grow from it.</li>
<li><strong>Don&rsquo;t blindly pursue high returns while ignoring risks.</strong> Many people pursue quick riches and hope for super high returns, but often overlook the risks involved, which may ultimately lead to losses outweighing gains. Learn to assess risk and choose an investment strategy that matches your risk tolerance.</li>
<li><strong>Investing requires finding a definite eternity, ignoring market noise, and maintaining inner peace.</strong> Index fund investing is a definite and eternal strategy that does not require painstaking research and operation. Simply holding for the long term can yield considerable returns.</li>
<li><strong>Investment is a loser&rsquo;s game, not seeking to win, but seeking not to lose.</strong>  In investing, avoiding mistakes is more important than pursuing victory. Index fund investing can help investors reduce mistakes and ultimately achieve victory.</li>
<li><strong>Buying in a lump sum at any time and holding for the long term is superior to other investment methods.</strong> Investing early and holding for the long term maximizes returns and delivers the best investment returns.</li>
<li><strong>Learn to distinguish between what can be done, what is effective, what can be worried about, and what is not worth worrying about.</strong> Focus your energy on important and solvable issues, ignore those that are irrelevant or beyond your control to improve efficiency and reduce unnecessary anxiety.</li>
<li><strong>Don&rsquo;t work too hard, let your money work for you.</strong> Put your money into the market and let it create wealth for you instead of devoting all your energy to work. Learn to utilize investment tools to achieve passive wealth growth.</li>
<li><strong>All pressure comes from expectations, and all worries come from not having a solution.</strong> Lower your expectations and actively seek solutions to relieve stress and anxiety.</li>
<li><strong>Learn to transfer pressure to those who can bear it and think about solutions for the worst-case scenario.</strong> Don&rsquo;t bear the pressure alone, learn to seek help, and think in advance about solutions to the worst-case scenario to calmly deal with challenges.</li>
<li><strong>Maintain inner peace, focus on the important things, and ignore the insignificant things.</strong> Stick to simple things, don&rsquo;t get involved in complex things, to maintain inner peace and focus on what really matters in life.</li>
<li><strong>Account security is the primary issue in investing. Choose a large, reputable brokerage to open an account and avoid using online brokers.</strong> Online brokers have security risks, such as account theft and asset freezing. Choosing a large, reputable brokerage can better protect your account security.</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">III. Q&amp;A Session 
    <div id="iii-qa-session" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii-qa-session" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p><strong>Dave:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing:</strong>
Shared the results of James&rsquo; TQQQ simulation backtest and raised the question of how to avoid the risk of a sharp TQQQ drawdown.</li>
<li><strong>Question and James&rsquo;s Reply:</strong>
James believes that it is impossible to predict the market and avoid all risks completely. The important thing is to control risk exposure and avoid over-betting. If you are worried about the volatility of TQQQ, you can choose a more conservative investment strategy, such as QQQ. James also reminds everyone to distinguish between personal thinking and public advice, and not to be easily swayed by the thoughts of others.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Minjianlian:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing:</strong>
Shared his experience of investing in stocks through his company&rsquo;s savings association, as well as discussions about the MAGS fund and emergency funds.</li>
<li><strong>Question and James&rsquo;s Reply:</strong>
<ol>
<li>About the MAGS fund: James believes that it is uncertain whether the MAGS fund can outperform QQQ in the long term. Investment should choose targets that have been tested by time, such as QQQ or SPY.</li>
<li>About emergency funds: James believes that emergency funds are a personal responsibility and government policies cannot be relied upon entirely. Everyone should prepare sufficient emergency funds according to their own circumstances to cope with contingencies.</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Learn:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Question and James&rsquo;s Reply:</strong>
Regarding the performance of 00670L, James explained the performance difference caused by USD hedging and how to solve it by investing in QLD through sub-brokerage. He emphasized that Beta and ROI are different concepts. Beta represents volatility, not ROI. The investment model in Taiwan needs to be adjusted according to specific circumstances, such as  maintenance margin requirements and exchange rate fluctuations.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>JJU:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing:</strong>
Shared his insights on market unpredictability and the importance of mentors and friends. He believes that investing, in addition to selecting good targets, is more about maintaining inner peace and enhancing one&rsquo;s spiritual level.</li>
<li><strong>Question and James&rsquo;s Reply:</strong>
<ol>
<li>About the difference between reinvest and buy share: James explained the difference between reinvesting and buying shares. The former automatically invests dividends or capital gains into the investment target, while the latter uses new funds to buy shares.</li>
<li>About the fund ratio of Roth IRA and Individual Brokerage Account: It is recommended to maximize the Roth IRA limit if possible.</li>
<li>About real estate mortgage investment: It is recommended to sell the property if possible to reduce the risk of investing in real estate. Otherwise, consider a Home Equity Line of Credit (HELOC) for investment, but pay attention to risk control and ensure that you can repay the loan on time. HELOC is a revolving credit line, similar to a credit card, which can be withdrawn and repaid at any time.</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Draft down:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing:</strong>
Proposed the possibility of leveraging 0% interest credit cards for investment and using the box spread strategy to increase capital utilization.</li>
<li><strong>Question and James&rsquo;s Reply:</strong>
<ol>
<li>About credit card investment: James believes that credit card limits are limited and there is a risk of not being able to renew the loan, making it unsuitable as a main source of investment funds. It is only suitable for short-term turnover of small amounts of funds.</li>
<li>About the box spread strategy: James believes that the box spread strategy is too complex and risky and is not recommended for ordinary investors.</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Jason:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Question and James&rsquo;s Reply:</strong>
<ol>
<li>How to overcome short-term pain in the investment process: James suggested lowering expectations, not pursuing perfection or getting rich quickly, finding solutions to problems, and transferring the pressure to those who can bear it, such as superiors or more experienced individuals. Think about solutions for the worst-case scenario, such as job loss or investment losses, and maintain a positive mindset, believing that the problem will eventually be solved.</li>
<li>About non-US tax resident investing in US stocks: James believes that non-US tax residents can use their passports to open brokerage accounts in the US without a Social Security Number. It is recommended to choose large, reputable brokers, such as Charles Schwab, and avoid using online brokers, such as Webull and Robinhood, as online brokers have security risks and imperfect regulations.</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">IV. Key Insights 
    <div id="iv-key-insights" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv-key-insights" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>Investment is a loser&rsquo;s game, not seeking to win, but seeking not to lose.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>In investing, avoiding mistakes is more important than pursuing victory. Choosing the right investment target, formulating a reasonable investment strategy and strictly adhering to discipline can reduce mistakes and ultimately achieve long-term stable returns.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Buying in a lump sum at any time and holding for the long term is superior to other investment methods.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>Investing early and holding for the long term maximizes returns and delivers the best investment returns. Time is a friend of investment. Starting early allows time to work its magic of compounding.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>All pressure comes from expectations, and all worries come from not having a solution.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>Lower your expectations and actively seek solutions to relieve stress and anxiety. When facing challenges, maintain a positive attitude and believe that you can find a way to solve the problem.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Wealth is accumulated slowly, and enjoying the process of wealth accumulation is the meaning of life.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>Getting rich overnight or quickly is not the best way. Slowly accumulating wealth and enjoying it allows you to experience the true meaning of life. Investing is a long-term process. Don&rsquo;t be impatient and enjoy the process of wealth accumulation, learning and growing from it.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Good teachers and helpful friends are important. You may not be right if you agree with someone.
&ndash; JJU</p></blockquote>
<p>In the investment process, be good at learning and thinking. Don&rsquo;t blindly believe anyone&rsquo;s point of view, including teachers and friends. Make your own independent thinking and judgment to make the right investment decisions.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Account security is the primary issue in investing.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>Choosing a large, reputable brokerage to open an account, such as Charles Schwab, can better protect your account security. Avoid using online brokers as online brokers have security risks and imperfect regulations.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">V. Summary 
    <div id="v-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#v-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This session focuses on the long-term investment philosophy, risk control, and mindset management. James helps students better understand the essence of investment through vivid examples and in-depth explanations. He answers students&rsquo; various questions encountered in the investment process, such as the risks of TQQQ, the importance of emergency funds, and real estate investment strategies. At the same time, students also actively share their experiences and confusion, such as using credit cards for investment and using the box spread strategy, triggering deeper thinking and discussion. James emphasizes the importance of independent thinking, advising against blindly believing anyone&rsquo;s point of view. He encourages making independent thinking and judgment to make the right investment decisions. At the same time, he also reminds everyone to pay attention to account security, choose large, reputable brokers to open accounts, and avoid using online brokers.</p>

  



<div
  
    class="flex px-4 py-3 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900"
  >

  <span
    
      class="text-primary-400 ltr:pr-3 rtl:pl-3 flex items-center"
    >

    

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M506.3 417l-213.3-364c-16.33-28-57.54-28-73.98 0l-213.2 364C-10.59 444.9 9.849 480 42.74 480h426.6C502.1 480 522.6 445 506.3 417zM232 168c0-13.25 10.75-24 24-24S280 154.8 280 168v128c0 13.25-10.75 24-23.1 24S232 309.3 232 296V168zM256 416c-17.36 0-31.44-14.08-31.44-31.44c0-17.36 14.07-31.44 31.44-31.44s31.44 14.08 31.44 31.44C287.4 401.9 273.4 416 256 416z"/></svg>

  </span>


  </span>

  <span
    
      class="dark:text-neutral-300"
    ><strong>Disclaimer:</strong> This article is only for personal learning notes and does not constitute any investment advice.</span>
</div>

]]></content:encoded></item></channel></rss>