<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Posts on QQQ Investor</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on QQQ Investor</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>00496 Global Markets and the Tech Wave: How to Seize Opportunities for Wealth Growth Amidst Volatility. The Philosophy of Financial Freedom: From Personalized Investing to Exploring Life's Values</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1735482278058/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1735482278058/</guid><description>At the end of 2024, with market fluctuations, Teacher James shared his insights on the current economic situation, financial markets, and investment strategies. In addition, several students asked questions online, covering asset allocation, business operations, health and wellness, tax planning, stock leveraging, and other areas.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Part One
<lite-youtube videoid="9F1rAWjCGX8" playlabel="9F1rAWjCGX8" params=""></lite-youtube>
</p>
<p>Part Two
<lite-youtube videoid="oPb4m81Nv24" playlabel="oPb4m81Nv24" params=""></lite-youtube>
</p>


<h2 class="relative group">I. Main Topic of the Session 
    <div id="i-main-topic-of-the-session" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-main-topic-of-the-session" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>Investment mindset and strategy adjustments amidst year-end market volatility, along with comprehensive reflections on personal life and financial health.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">II. Presentation Content 
    <div id="ii-presentation-content" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii-presentation-content" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Market Volatility and Investment Mindset 
    <div id="market-volatility-and-investment-mindset" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#market-volatility-and-investment-mindset" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>The only constant in the market is volatility. Investors should ignore market fluctuations, international situations, market analysis, financial reports, and economic situations, and focus on long-term investment.</li>
<li>Disclaimer: The content of the COC investment and financial management channel is for educational purposes only and does not constitute investment advice. Investment involves high risks, and proper asset allocation is necessary.</li>
<li>Newcomers should watch the YouTube episode 00451 &ldquo;Investment Lecture Worth 100 Million&rdquo; and also find related content on Bilibili and podcasts.</li>
<li>Investing requires independent thinking. Do not blindly follow advice or join any groups to avoid being deceived.</li>
<li>The Nasdaq 100 index fund is recommended as the only focused fund, with others being supplementary.</li>
<li>The handout includes information on Nasdaq 100 index funds worldwide, including leveraged funds, and information on retirement accounts in various regions, with content continuously updated.</li>
<li>The &ldquo;Investment Lecture Worth 100 Million&rdquo; video is the most important. Investors should always be extremely optimistic; the market will eventually rise and reach new highs.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">UK and European Financial Information 
    <div id="uk-and-european-financial-information" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#uk-and-european-financial-information" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Showcasing information provided by a UK friend regarding UK investments, loans, retirement accounts, ETFs, and insurance companies, particularly information on 2x leveraged funds on the PEA website.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">US-China Trade War and Globalization 
    <div id="us-china-trade-war-and-globalization" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#us-china-trade-war-and-globalization" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Issues like the US-China trade war and tariffs do not affect technological advancements and the innovation of American companies, thus having little impact on index investing.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Risks and Returns of Leveraged Funds 
    <div id="risks-and-returns-of-leveraged-funds" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#risks-and-returns-of-leveraged-funds" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>The risk of a 2x leveraged fund is not simply double, and the return is not twice the annualized rate of return, but approximately 1.4 times.</li>
<li>The annualized return of QQQ over 20 years is 14%, while QLD&rsquo;s is 19.6%. QLD&rsquo;s total return over 20 years is 2.6 times that of QQQ, far exceeding double.</li>
<li>Combining leveraged funds with cash can reduce risk and increase returns.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Investment Wisdom and Market Essence 
    <div id="investment-wisdom-and-market-essence" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#investment-wisdom-and-market-essence" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>The market is always smarter than individual investors. Stock picking and timing the market are futile.</li>
<li>In a bull market, many &ldquo;gurus&rdquo; emerge, but they disappear when the market falls; this is a market norm.</li>
<li>Controlling the major stocks on Wall Street means controlling the world.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Investment Sharing and Personal Insights 
    <div id="investment-sharing-and-personal-insights" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#investment-sharing-and-personal-insights" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Investment sharers need to provide clear, diverse, and universally applicable investment methods and benefit from them.</li>
<li>Buffett&rsquo;s investment philosophy emphasizes long-term investment, perfecting the investment system.</li>
<li>Understanding the essence of finance, economics, accounting, and logic helps resist external interference and adhere to index investing.</li>
<li>Asset allocation is simplified into two types: 433 (conservative) and 442 (aggressive), pursuing safety rather than high returns, with cash being a safe asset.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Finance and Monetary Theory 
    <div id="finance-and-monetary-theory" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#finance-and-monetary-theory" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>The foundation of capitalism is currency. Understanding monetary theory is crucial to understanding finance, investment, and the economy.</li>
<li>The status of the US dollar as the world&rsquo;s reserve currency determines the subordinate status of other countries, especially those holding large amounts of US dollar foreign exchange reserves.</li>
<li>China and other emerging countries are trying to break away from their dependence on the US dollar to escape US control.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Life&rsquo;s Meaning and Happiness 
    <div id="lifes-meaning-and-happiness" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#lifes-meaning-and-happiness" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>The happiest thing in life is giving. Happiness is a human right. Sharing and giving energy on a spiritual level can bring more happiness than material things.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Extremes of Capitalism and Social Issues 
    <div id="extremes-of-capitalism-and-social-issues" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#extremes-of-capitalism-and-social-issues" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Capitalism will lead to an expansion of the wealth gap. The development of robots will make spiritual education even more important.</li>
<li>Systemic discrimination exists in society, leading to a vicious cycle of poverty. Our goal is to help eliminate poverty as much as possible.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">US Accounting System and Social Phenomena 
    <div id="us-accounting-system-and-social-phenomena" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#us-accounting-system-and-social-phenomena" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>The US accounting system is very complete. Phenomena like &ldquo;zero-dollar shopping&rdquo; are the result of accounting costs and leftist thinking, and there is no need to over-interpret them.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Wealth and Government Relations 
    <div id="wealth-and-government-relations" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#wealth-and-government-relations" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Wealthy individuals escape government control by paying taxes, while the poor are trapped.</li>
<li>Legitimate tax avoidance is an important topic.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Personalization of Diet and Asset Allocation 
    <div id="personalization-of-diet-and-asset-allocation" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#personalization-of-diet-and-asset-allocation" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Both diet and asset allocation should be customized according to individual circumstances and cannot be generalized.</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">III. Q&amp;A Session 
    <div id="iii-qa-session" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii-qa-session" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Zhang Yong 
    <div id="zhang-yong" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#zhang-yong" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing</strong>: The chaos in the domestic insurance industry, where banks lure customers into buying insurance with high commissions, is even linked to the performance evaluations of customer managers. Many customers do not understand investments and choose low-yield or even risky insurance products to preserve their capital. He also shared a case of a friend who was defrauded of over 1.7 million in a romance scam, illustrating the complexity of the domestic financial environment.
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s comment</strong>: The US financial system strictly separates life insurance from other financial businesses, and there is no such thing as banks selling insurance. The financial supervision in China and Taiwan is problematic. Banks should focus on deposit and loan business and should not be involved in insurance and investment. This chaos will ultimately harm the interests of emerging countries.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question</strong>: Does Teacher James share content each week based on reflections on the same theme, or does he summarize viewpoints from reading many books?
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s reply</strong>: In addition to reading a lot of books, more importantly, independent thinking and critical thinking are involved. The formation of monetary theory stems from thinking about the nature of capitalism, and the content of the handouts mostly comes from students&rsquo; questions and his own reflections. This information is endless. To be an excellent sharer, one needs to have basic knowledge, thinking ability, and originality.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Xiao Cai 
    <div id="xiao-cai" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#xiao-cai" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing 1</strong>: Took over the family food business ten years ago when the company&rsquo;s assets and liabilities were zero. After ten years of operation, the company turned a profit, and its current value (including real estate) is about 300 million NTD. Over the past decade, he distributed about 200 million NTD of revenue to his family, retaining 100 million NTD for loan purposes. Currently, he has invested 80 million in 00662 (a 2x leveraged Nasdaq 100 index ETF) and 20 million in 00631L (Taiwan&rsquo;s 50 Positive 2 ETF).
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s comment</strong>: None</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question 1</strong>: The bank will allocate a loan of 60 million NTD on January 1st. Should this fund be used to buy 00662 all at once, or should he wait for a 20% market drop before buying? Also, if the market crashes and 00662 and 00631L go to zero, how will he deal with it?
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s reply</strong>: If the market goes to zero, the company can still make loan payments. The worst-case scenario is that the land is auctioned off, and he can still get tens of millions. Since the worst has been considered, how to buy the 60 million is not important. If it were me, I would buy it all on Monday. If you choose to wait for a 20% drop before buying, you can follow your plan and inform everyone when you buy.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question 2</strong>: How to maintain good health?
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s reply</strong>: Regular comprehensive physical examinations are necessary. I have been doing annual check-ups since my thirties. Wellness, like asset allocation, needs to be personalized. The advice I can give everyone now is to eat well, sleep well, and don&rsquo;t worry. What to eat specifically, what exercises to do, etc., need to be decided according to personal circumstances and cannot be given a unified recommendation.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question 3</strong>: What are your views on Taiwan&rsquo;s politics and how to support political parties?
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s reply</strong>: Regarding politics and religious beliefs, everyone has different positions and viewpoints. Discussing these issues in the classroom is meaningless and fruitless. It is recommended that students do not discuss these topics in the classroom and keep their opinions to themselves.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question 4</strong>: How to preserve assets in response to potential cross-strait issues? He currently has about 200 million NTD in assets in Taiwan and a house worth 8 million in Vietnam. How should he allocate his assets?
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s reply</strong>: If you can&rsquo;t sleep due to worries about cross-strait issues, it&rsquo;s recommended to immigrate as soon as possible. If you choose to stay in Taiwan, you need to make some decisions, such as whether to close the company. If the 40 employees are causing you distress, consider closing the company and compensating them. Life decisions should be decisive, not prolonged. Be responsible for your own happiness.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Additional question</strong>: How to get rid of the shackles of the family business?
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s reply</strong>: You have managed the company very well. The choice is your life. Do whatever makes you happy. If the family business makes you unhappy, shut it down and give the employees a good severance package. Consider your own life, not your father&rsquo;s. If your father&rsquo;s business is no longer your concern, and it&rsquo;s not bringing you happiness, then let it go.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Repeated emphasis</strong>: Believes that apart from investment and financial management, health is the most important asset in life, and cited the example of &ldquo;Yu (Yuan) Lingqi&rdquo; to emphasize the importance of regular health check-ups, hoping the channel will pay more attention to health issues.
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s reply</strong>: Health is very important. Everyone&rsquo;s health condition is different, and it is impossible to provide a unified recommendation. Everyone needs to pay attention to and manage their health according to their own situation.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Lare 
    <div id="lare" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#lare" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Question</strong>: Based in Canada, unable to leverage stocks. If income decreases in a certain year, and the tax rate drops from 32% to 24%, is it worth selling some stocks to increase income to the 32% tax bracket to improve the future cost basis?
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s reply</strong>: It is not recommended to sell stocks because selling incurs taxes. Canada&rsquo;s tax system is very unfavorable for stock investments. When immigrating, consider future generations and choose countries with development prospects. In Canada, you can consider using an IB account for loans, but this will face inheritance tax issues, possibly up to 40%. Therefore, when planning estates, minimize assets in IB accounts. In the long run, trusts can be used to avoid taxes. It is currently not recommended to sell stocks for short-term tax benefits. Consider selling after retirement when income is lower.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Additional explanation</strong>: IB accounts have a low financing ratio for Canadian stocks, only up to 50%.
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s addition</strong>: You can borrow 40% first, and add more if needed. But ultimately, there will still be inheritance tax issues.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Terry 
    <div id="terry" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#terry" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Question 1</strong>: How to transfer taxable accounts or retirement accounts to tax-free accounts, such as Roth IRA? What are the specific steps?
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s reply</strong>: If it&rsquo;s within the same brokerage, such as Charles Schwab, you can fill out a form online directly. If it&rsquo;s at different brokerages, you need to contact the brokerage to obtain and fill out a form. For specific steps, you can refer to the previously released video &ldquo;Investment and Financial Management Tips 26: How to Transfer from a Traditional Taxable Account to a Roth IRA Online at 722.&rdquo;</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question 2</strong>: What is your view on Crypto, and will QQQ include Crypto companies in the future?
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s reply</strong>: I don&rsquo;t know much about Crypto and am not sure if it will exist forever, so I won&rsquo;t answer.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">IM 
    <div id="im" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#im" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing</strong>: Through learning, I realized that my investment was too risky, and emergency funds should not all be invested in QQQ. Now I have withdrawn 36 months of emergency funds back to the Money Market Fund. When starting with small funds, one should focus on their main job and increase income sources. After investing in index funds, my mindset changed, and I began to focus on the importance of timing. Therefore, I started to focus on diet, fitness, and learning from the experiences of long-lived people around me. In addition, I learned from investing to avoid risks, such as giving up dangerous activities like diving.
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s comment</strong>: It is wise to learn from the experiences of others. Being overly aggressive is human nature, but it is important to realize and correct it in time. It is wrong to increase positions when the market is rising and to be fearful when it is falling. It should be the other way around. Emergency funds should not be added to.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question</strong>: How to judge whether you are being too adventurous? For example, increasing the leverage ratio of asset allocation from 1.0 to 1.8 when stocks are rising.
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s reply</strong>: This is also a necessary evil. Now that you realize it&rsquo;s not right, you can start to retreat, or when it rises, you buy in, and when it falls, you get scared. Oh, what to do? Then start to retreat. Once you have learned, don&rsquo;t do it again. So, as Buffett said, when others are greedy, you should be fearful, and when others are fearful, you should be greedy. That&rsquo;s the right pace. So, when you want to increase your position in the future, it should be when others are fearful. That&rsquo;s how I do it. This emergency fund should not be increased. Regardless of whether the market is rising or falling, you should not add to this cervical spine disease. How could you add to it? This is not allowed. Then, if you use our asset allocation, when the market falls, you automatically buy in for one year, and when the market rises, you automatically withdraw from the leveraged fund. This is passive, and this has already achieved the practice of being greedy when others are fearful and being fearful when others are greedy.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Patty 
    <div id="patty" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#patty" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Question</strong>: The relationship between the asset-backed ratio and cash reserves. If asset-backed financing is carried out, how to ensure that the cash on hand is greater than the pledged amount? For example, with assets of 1 million, allocated according to the 721 ratio, 200,000 is pledged, but 100,000 in cash cannot be moved. Is it necessary to balance for one or two years to accumulate 200,000 in cash before making a pledge?
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s reply</strong>: You cannot borrow 200,000 all at once; you can only borrow 2% per year. When conducting asset-backed financing, the asset allocation should be 433, not 721. Borrow 2% each year and conduct &ldquo;smart rebalancing.&rdquo; Even if the market falls, you will not be forced to liquidate. The cash ratio may be lower than the loan ratio in extreme cases (such as a continuous 10-year decline), but since the total asset value is still greater than the debt, there will be no problem.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Mike 
    <div id="mike" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#mike" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing</strong>: A friend&rsquo;s experience. The friend took over his father&rsquo;s family business and eventually had health problems due to overwork. He later sold the company for over 600 million and invested the funds in QQQ. He is now very happy.
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s comment</strong>: None</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question 1</strong>: Regarding 401k and RMD. Previously, company stock was placed in a 401k, and now it has a high value, facing the RMD issue. After Trump takes office, is it possible to abolish RMD and change it to a 15% capital gains tax?
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s reply</strong>: This possibility is extremely slim. The government is unlikely to give up the tax revenue brought by RMD.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question 2</strong>: Regarding the Debt to Equity Ratio of companies. It is found that there are large differences in the debt-to-equity ratios of Buffett and many technology companies. Is this related to the nature of the industry? For example, the debt-to-equity ratio of software companies is usually low, while that of hardware companies like Apple is high. So, for individuals, is it a healthy level to control the debt-to-equity ratio at 0.2?
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s reply</strong>: The higher the debt-to-equity ratio, the higher the ROE usually is, but this needs to be based on healthy debt. Healthy debt refers to debt that can be repaid through its own operating activities, such as credit, stock-backed loans (under safe circumstances), and mortgages (that can be repaid). Apple&rsquo;s debt-to-equity ratio is high because it borrows a lot of money to pay dividends and places assets overseas. In addition, it has a large amount of accounts payable. Therefore, it cannot be simply considered that a high debt-to-equity ratio is bad. It is necessary to analyze the nature and safety of the debt specifically.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question 3</strong>: What are your thoughts on the Jetson Orin product launched by Nvidia? This product is mainly for the personal AI market, is cheap, can use ChatGPT to generate code, and runs locally, thereby creating your own AI database.
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s reply</strong>: I don&rsquo;t know much about this product. Our AI is mainly trained using ChatGPT as a personal assistant. Currently, I don&rsquo;t use other devices for personal AI.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">IV. Highlighted Quotes 
    <div id="iv-highlighted-quotes" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv-highlighted-quotes" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>The only constant in the market is volatility.
&ndash; Teacher James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This viewpoint emphasizes the normality of market fluctuations. Investors should be mentally prepared and not be affected by short-term market fluctuations.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Investing requires independent thinking. Do not blindly follow advice or join any groups to avoid being deceived.
&ndash; Teacher James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This viewpoint emphasizes the importance of independent thinking in investing. Investors should make investment decisions based on their own judgment rather than blindly following others&rsquo; opinions or joining unreliable investment groups.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The happiest thing in life is giving. Happiness is a human right. Sharing and giving energy on a spiritual level can bring more happiness than material things.
&ndash; Teacher James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This viewpoint emphasizes that spiritual pursuits are more important than material ones. Giving and sharing can bring greater happiness.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>If you, as a commercial bank, do lending well, then focus on lending. Deposits are 2%. Then your lending is 3.5%, 4%. You just make that 2% difference. This is what a commercial bank should do. Commerce should not touch insurance.
&ndash; Teacher James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This viewpoint points out that commercial banks should focus on deposit and loan business instead of being involved in areas like insurance, which not only violates financial regulations but also harms the interests of customers.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Happiness is a human right. If you are alive, you should be happy. If you live so miserably, why bother?
&ndash; Teacher James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This viewpoint reminds everyone to pursue happiness and not sacrifice their happiness for money or other goals.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Impotence is also a kind of strength because accepting one&rsquo;s own impotence and acknowledging one&rsquo;s own impotence is also a kind of strength.
&ndash; Teacher James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This viewpoint expresses a broad-minded attitude towards life. Acknowledging one&rsquo;s limitations is not a bad thing; instead, it can make one more relaxed.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The truly wealthy are those who foresee a future eternally disconnected from government oversight, swiftly settling their dues to escape the clutches of authority.
&ndash; Teacher James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This perspective highlights how affluent individuals utilize legitimate tax avoidance strategies to minimize governmental control over their wealth.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Learning from the experiences of others is a wise approach.
&ndash; IM</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This viewpoint emphasizes the importance of learning and drawing lessons from others&rsquo; experiences, which can help us avoid making the same mistakes.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>When others are greedy, you should be fearful; when others are fearful, you should be greedy.
&ndash; Teacher James, quoting Buffett</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This is a very important principle in investing, namely, contrarian thinking, staying calm when the market is frenzied and looking for opportunities when the market is panicking.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Just be happy. There&rsquo;s nothing to it, nothing to fight for, no particular meaning, nothing that grand or great.
&ndash; Teacher James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This viewpoint expresses a detached attitude towards life. Don&rsquo;t put too much pressure on yourself; learn to enjoy life.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Don&rsquo;t wait until it&rsquo;s too late, leaving no time for regrets.
&ndash; Teacher James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Drawing on investment principles, this perspective underscores the importance of early health screenings, urging not to wait until problems arise before regretting, echoing Xiao Cai&rsquo;s shared viewpoint.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>We investors are always extremely optimistic. Market fluctuations should be ignored. The market will eventually rise and always reach new highs.
&ndash; Teacher James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This viewpoint emphasizes the optimistic attitude towards the long-term trend of the market and the neglect of short-term fluctuations, demonstrating the proper mindset for long-term investors.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">V. Summary 
    <div id="v-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#v-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>The content of this episode of the COC investment and financial management channel is rich. Teacher James not only shared his views on the current market and investment strategies but also answered the practical questions of many students, involving asset allocation, business operations, health and wellness, tax planning, and other aspects. In addition, he also emphasized the importance of happiness and health, as well as investment concepts such as independent thinking, long-term investment, and reasonable tax avoidance. In summary, the content of this episode provides valuable guidance and inspiration for investors, helping everyone make wise decisions in a complex market environment and have a healthier and happier life.</p>

  



<div
  
    class="flex px-4 py-3 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900"
  >

  <span
    
      class="text-primary-400 ltr:pr-3 rtl:pl-3 flex items-center"
    >

    

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M506.3 417l-213.3-364c-16.33-28-57.54-28-73.98 0l-213.2 364C-10.59 444.9 9.849 480 42.74 480h426.6C502.1 480 522.6 445 506.3 417zM232 168c0-13.25 10.75-24 24-24S280 154.8 280 168v128c0 13.25-10.75 24-23.1 24S232 309.3 232 296V168zM256 416c-17.36 0-31.44-14.08-31.44-31.44c0-17.36 14.07-31.44 31.44-31.44s31.44 14.08 31.44 31.44C287.4 401.9 273.4 416 256 416z"/></svg>

  </span>


  </span>

  <span
    
      class="dark:text-neutral-300"
    ><strong>Disclaimer:</strong> This article is only a personal study note and does not constitute any investment advice.</span>
</div>

]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Let Time Help You Slowly Get Rich: Book Notes</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1734847682781/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1734847682781/</guid><description>This book primarily explains the strategy of regular investing, emphasizing that it&amp;#39;s the best investment method for ordinary people. The author, Li Xiaolai, elaborates on the core concepts, advantages, and correct execution of regular investing, combining personal experiences and market examples to demonstrate the importance of long-term and value investing. Furthermore, he explores topics like proactivity vs. passivity, trends, and personal growth, aiming to help readers establish a sound investment philosophy and wealth outlook, ultimately achieving financial freedom.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[

<h2 class="relative group">I. Summary 
    <div id="i-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>The core argument of this book is: <strong>Regular investing is the optimal investment strategy for ordinary people.</strong> Li Xiaolai uses a unique perspective and accessible language to systematically explain the advantages, principles, and implementation of regular investing. He argues that compared to other investment methods, regular investing is more suitable for ordinary people due to its simplicity, lower risk, and ability to overcome human weaknesses.  It helps investors maintain rationality amidst market fluctuations, ultimately achieving steady wealth growth.  Beyond investment techniques, the book also touches upon personal growth, mindset, and life choices, aiming to help readers establish a sound investment philosophy and wealth outlook, ultimately achieving financial freedom and happiness.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">II. Chapter Summaries 
    <div id="ii-chapter-summaries" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii-chapter-summaries" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">1. Almost Everyone is Qualified and Capable of Regular Investing 
    <div id="1-almost-everyone-is-qualified-and-capable-of-regular-investing" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#1-almost-everyone-is-qualified-and-capable-of-regular-investing" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Most people possess the ability to invest regularly, but they often choose the wrong target (real estate).</strong> The author uses the common phenomenon of &ldquo;mortgage slaves&rdquo; to illustrate that most people are unconsciously engaged in a form of regular investing â€“ real estate.  Their monthly mortgage payments essentially constitute a form of regular investment. However, due to high interest rates and low liquidity, real estate is not the optimal choice. He contrasts this with the example of investing regularly in Kweichow Moutai stock for 18 years, resulting in a 180-fold increase, highlighting the significant advantages of stock investing in terms of long-term returns and liquidity.  This emphasizes the crucial importance of selecting the right investment target.  Due to mortgage burdens, many become &ldquo;mortgage millionaires,&rdquo; possessing seemingly large assets but lacking cash flow and a high quality of life.</li>
<li><strong>Advantages of regular investment in stocks/index funds: low barrier to entry, high liquidity, potential for high returns.</strong> Compared to other investment methods like investing in early-stage startups or art, stocks and index funds have a low barrier to entry, making them accessible to everyone.  Moreover, they offer high liquidity, allowing investors to buy and sell at any time, facilitating adjustments to their investment strategies as needed.  More importantly, over the long term, the stock market tends to rise with economic development, giving regular investment in stocks/index funds the potential for high returns. The author believes the stock market offers ordinary people an opportunity to share in the growth dividends of excellent companies, an advantage difficult to obtain through other investment avenues.</li>
<li><strong>The importance of participating in a regular investing community.</strong>  The author points out that regular investing is not just an investment strategy but also a social activity. Due to widespread misunderstandings and biases about stock investing (such as &ldquo;investment is risky&rdquo; or &ldquo;only the rich invest&rdquo;), investing regularly alone can be easily influenced by external factors, making it difficult to persist. Participating in a regular investing community can help investors overcome these negative influences, gain support and encouragement from peers, establish a correct investment philosophy, and learn more investment knowledge and experience. Within such communities, members can exchange experiences, share insights, and create a positive feedback loop.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">2. The Stock Market is the Ninth Wonder of the World 
    <div id="2-the-stock-market-is-the-ninth-wonder-of-the-world" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#2-the-stock-market-is-the-ninth-wonder-of-the-world" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>The stock market gives ordinary people the chance to be &ldquo;bosses&rdquo; and share in the growth dividends of excellent companies.</strong> The author believes the stock market provides a unique opportunity for ordinary people to invest in well-managed, high-quality companies and share in their profits, even if they have no understanding of business operations. This is an advantage difficult to gain even by working at a company, including publicly listed ones. Through investing, ordinary people can indirectly &ldquo;own&rdquo; multiple excellent companies, achieving wealth appreciation.</li>
<li><strong>A simple method for stock selection: choose the most favored stocks or index funds in the market.</strong> The author suggests that choosing stocks doesn&rsquo;t require complex analysis and research. One can directly choose the most popular stocks or index funds in the market, such as Kweichow Moutai, Apple, or Tencent.  These represent the collective wisdom of the smartest people in the market, and choosing them is akin to leveraging their free advice.  He further notes that the advice from the smartest people in the market is often free, like Warren Buffett&rsquo;s portfolio information and popular stock choices.</li>
<li><strong>Don&rsquo;t worry about making the wrong choice; market consensus is more important than individual judgment.</strong> Even if the most favored stock in the market eventually fails, there&rsquo;s no need for excessive self-blame, as it represented the best available advice at the time.  Individual judgment rarely surpasses market consensus. In the long run, market forces will correct errors, so the key is to hold long-term and trust the power of the market.  The author believes that rather than spending significant time and energy researching individual stocks, it&rsquo;s better to trust the collective wisdom of the market and choose widely recognized, excellent companies.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">3. Are There Any Investment Targets that Only Go Up? 
    <div id="3-are-there-any-investment-targets-that-only-go-up" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#3-are-there-any-investment-targets-that-only-go-up" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Investing in a single stock is high-risk, with unlimited opportunity cost, and requires diversification.</strong> Even the best-performing single company can face significant risks due to industry decline, black swan events, or other unpredictable factors. Concentrating funds in a single stock represents high risk, and losses can be difficult to recover if problems arise.  The author cites Kodak and Nokia as examples, illustrating how even once-great companies can decline. Hence, diversification is essential to mitigate risk.</li>
<li><strong>In the long run, the only investment that only goes up is human economic development, which can be accessed through index funds.</strong> The author argues that the human economy generally trends upwards over the long term, and index funds track the overall market performance.  By investing in index funds, one can effectively diversify risk and share in the dividends of long-term economic growth.  The 40-year performance chart of the S&amp;P 500 is compelling evidence.  Investing in index funds is like betting on the national, or even global, economy, and offers better odds in the long run.</li>
<li><strong>Long-term investment is necessary to dilute risk and ultimately achieve stable returns.</strong> Short-term market fluctuations are difficult to predict and are full of noise and randomness.  Only long-term investment can effectively smooth these fluctuations and ultimately generate stable returns.  The author emphasizes that there are no investment targets that only go up, only the long-term general upward trend of the human economy.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">4. The Only Correct Way for Ordinary People to Invest 
    <div id="4-the-only-correct-way-for-ordinary-people-to-invest" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#4-the-only-correct-way-for-ordinary-people-to-invest" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Regular investing is the most reliable investment method for ordinary people.</strong> The author uses the example of Longmen Fund, comparing lump-sum investing with regular investing. The results show that regular investing achieved a significantly higher return: 74.01% vs. 10.81%.  Regular investing can effectively smooth market fluctuations and reduce investment risk.</li>
<li><strong>Regular investing helps investors overcome fear and greed, maintaining rationality during market fluctuations.</strong> Through regular, fixed-amount investments, investors can buy more shares at lower prices during market downturns, averaging down their cost.  During market upturns, it prevents investing too much at once, avoiding being trapped at high prices.  The discipline of regular investing can help investors overcome the human weakness of chasing rising markets and selling during falls.</li>
<li><strong>Regular investing is a long-term strategy that requires patience and discipline.</strong> Returns from regular investing take time to accumulate. Investors need to be patient and maintain discipline, not easily interrupting or changing their investment plan, to achieve significant returns.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">5. Why So Few People Use Regular Investing 
    <div id="5-why-so-few-people-use-regular-investing" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#5-why-so-few-people-use-regular-investing" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>&ldquo;Fear of simplicity&rdquo; hinders people from accepting regular investing.</strong> People tend to believe in complex and sophisticated methods, underestimating the power of simplicity.  This is similar to how it took a long time for people to think of adding wheels to luggage, learning English through consistent reading aloud, improving writing through effective reading, and maintaining health through regular exercise.</li>
<li><strong>Regular investing&rsquo;s simplicity makes it easier to adhere to, avoiding the risks of frequent trading.</strong> Compared to complex trading strategies, regular investing is simple and easy to follow, avoiding transaction costs and the risk of misjudgment associated with frequent trading.  The author believes that this simplicity is precisely the greatest advantage of regular investing.</li>
<li><strong>People lack understanding and patience for long-term investing.</strong> Most people crave quick riches and struggle to endure the &ldquo;loneliness&rdquo; of long-term investing. They are easily influenced by short-term market fluctuations and often give up, as seen in the Longmen Fund example, where lump-sum investors were more prone to panic selling during market declines.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">6. The Profound Mechanisms Behind the Magic of Regular Investing 
    <div id="6-the-profound-mechanisms-behind-the-magic-of-regular-investing" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#6-the-profound-mechanisms-behind-the-magic-of-regular-investing" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Proactive personality is important, but recognize the boundaries of proactivity.</strong> Be proactive within your circle of influence, but also recognize your limitations.  Don&rsquo;t try to control what you cannot, such as your children&rsquo;s future or the operations of companies you&rsquo;ve invested in.</li>
<li><strong>Factors that determine destiny often lie outside our control, such as trends.</strong> Personal effort is important, but it&rsquo;s also essential to align with the trends of the times.  Like snooker player Ronnie O&rsquo;Sullivan, even with immense effort, competitors find it challenging to defeat him at his peak.</li>
<li><strong>Active passivity is the best strategy for navigating trends.</strong> Actively choose the right trend, then passively wait for the trend to unfold. In investing, this means actively choosing promising assets or indices for the long term, then passively adhering to a regular investment schedule.</li>
<li><strong>Regular investing is the best practice of &ldquo;active passivity.&rdquo;</strong> Choosing worthy long-term investments is active; regularly buying a fixed amount and holding long-term is passive.</li>
<li><strong>The power of passivity is fully demonstrated in long-term investing.</strong> The long-term performance of passive funds often surpasses that of actively managed funds, demonstrating the limitations of &ldquo;active management&rdquo; and the strength of long-term holding.</li>
<li><strong>Ordinary people can improve their investment abilities by controlling their own behavior, such as improving their ability to earn outside of the market.</strong>  Earning power outside of the market is the cornerstone of regular investing and a key factor ordinary people can actively improve.</li>
<li><strong>Understanding &ldquo;long-term&rdquo; determines investment outcomes.</strong> &ldquo;Long-term&rdquo; doesn&rsquo;t mean forever, but &ldquo;at least two major cycles,&rdquo; which, based on market changes, is approximately seven years.</li>
<li><strong>Ordinary people&rsquo;s money has no expiration date, a significant advantage over professional fund managers.</strong> Professional fund managers are constrained by fund deadlines and investor pressure, while ordinary people can invest long-term with more composure, fully utilizing the power of time.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">7. The Difference Between Stupidity and Ignorance, and Passive Intelligence 
    <div id="7-the-difference-between-stupidity-and-ignorance-and-passive-intelligence" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#7-the-difference-between-stupidity-and-ignorance-and-passive-intelligence" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Smart people can make ignorant mistakes in unfamiliar fields.</strong> Like Archimedes and Zu Chongzhi, geniuses in their respective fields could make mistakes in the unfamiliar territory of the stock market due to a lack of specific knowledge.</li>
<li><strong>Regular investing allows ordinary people to be passively intelligent investors from the start.</strong>  The strategy&rsquo;s simplicity avoids errors associated with complex operations, allowing ordinary people to achieve reasonable returns without becoming investment experts.</li>
<li><strong>Regular investing cultivates patience, discipline, and the habit of investing within one&rsquo;s means.</strong> Long-term regular investing requires patience and discipline. The investment amount should also be within one&rsquo;s means to avoid impacting daily life. These are all good investment habits.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">8. Some People Are Always on the Right Side 
    <div id="8-some-people-are-always-on-the-right-side" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#8-some-people-are-always-on-the-right-side" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>People with great goals are more likely to make the right choices in a mirrored world.</strong>  A sense of purpose allows focus on long-term value instead of being distracted by short-term fluctuations.  The author quotes Arnold Schwarzenegger&rsquo;s speech, emphasizing the importance of goals: &ldquo;The only reason I&rsquo;m standing here today is because I had a goal.&rdquo;</li>
<li><strong>Imbuing what you do with great meaning can ignite powerful self-motivation.</strong>  A sense of meaning provides stronger motivation to persist. The author uses his own writing and teaching experience to illustrate the significance of meaning and encourages readers to find meaning in their regular investing, such as &ldquo;for the children&rsquo;s future&rdquo; or &ldquo;for early retirement.&rdquo;</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">9.  A Glimpse into the Other Side of the Mirror World 
    <div id="9--a-glimpse-into-the-other-side-of-the-mirror-world" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#9--a-glimpse-into-the-other-side-of-the-mirror-world" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Investors who don&rsquo;t adopt regular investing easily fall into various investment traps, ultimately leading to losses.</strong> These include chasing rising markets, frequent trading, blindly following the crowd, and listening to rumors, often resulting in substantial losses during market volatility.</li>
<li><strong>Many investors blame their losses on greed, but the real root cause is a lack of understanding of the investment target.</strong> The author argues that greed is human nature and not the fundamental reason for investment failures.  The true cause lies in a lack of understanding of the investment target, an inability to judge its intrinsic value, leading to blind following or emotionally driven decisions, ultimately resulting in buying high and selling low.</li>
<li><strong>Even those who use regular investing need to deeply understand its core principles to avoid becoming half-baked investors.</strong>  This includes failing to carefully select investment targets, not holding long-term, investing too little, or easily interrupting the investment plan.  The author criticizes investors who don&rsquo;t truly grasp the essence of regular investing and merely engage in mechanical operations.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">10. Regular Investing is Essential for Ordinary People 
    <div id="10-regular-investing-is-essential-for-ordinary-people" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#10-regular-investing-is-essential-for-ordinary-people" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>The insignificance of effort: Ordinary people have limited free time, making it difficult to achieve significant success solely through hard work.</strong> The author uses data and personal experiences to illustrate that even with extraordinary effort, such as working 24 years without holidays or cutting his own hair, the gains are limited. He only managed to gain 1.26 years of effective working time compared to others.</li>
<li><strong>The essence of investing is to make money work for you, compensating for limited time and energy.</strong> Investing allows money to work 24/7, amplifying returns far beyond what one can earn through personal labor. Warren Buffett&rsquo;s 78-year investing journey serves as a prime example.</li>
<li><strong>Regular investing is an effective path for ordinary people to achieve financial freedom.</strong>  The strategy is simple and easy to execute.  Long-term adherence can generate substantial returns, helping ordinary people accumulate wealth and eventually achieve financial freedom.</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">III. Key Quotes 
    <div id="iii-key-quotes" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii-key-quotes" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>Diligence in practice makes one invincible!</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>Regular investing is the only reliable investment method for ordinary people.</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>There are no investment targets that only rise, only those that rise in the long term.</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>Be proactive when you should be, and passive when you should be.</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>Your money may not be much, but it has no expiration date.</p>
</blockquote>


<h2 class="relative group">IV.  Guiding Significance 
    <div id="iv--guiding-significance" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv--guiding-significance" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<ul>
<li><strong>Establishing a sound investment philosophy:</strong>  Helping readers avoid investment pitfalls and recognize the importance of long-term, value, and passive investing, while avoiding mistakes like chasing rising markets and frequent trading.</li>
<li><strong>Providing practical investment methods:</strong>  The regular investing strategy is simple and easy to implement, accessible even to those with no prior investment experience.</li>
<li><strong>Promoting personal growth:</strong>  Encouraging readers to cultivate a proactive personality, recognize the boundaries of their control, and learn how to be actively passive, aligning with trends.</li>
<li><strong>Guiding life choices:</strong> Inspiring readers to reflect on the meaning and goals of life and strive towards them, ultimately achieving financial freedom and happiness.</li>
<li><strong>Cultivating a healthy mindset:</strong> Reminding readers not to be swayed by short-term fluctuations, maintaining patience and discipline, overcoming fear and greed, and believing in the power of time.</li>
</ul>
<p>In conclusion, this book not only provides practical investment techniques but, more importantly, helps readers establish a healthy wealth outlook and life philosophy, ultimately achieving financial freedom and happiness.  The book also encourages readers to join regular investing communities for mutual learning, support, and progress.</p>
<hr>
<a id="github-e02127fda5246656fa0433195f17cabe" target="_blank" href="https://github.com/xiaolai/regular-investing-in-box" class="cursor-pointer">
  <div
    class="w-full md:w-auto pt-3 p-5 border border-neutral-200 dark:border-neutral-700 border rounded-md shadow-2xl">

    <div class="flex items-center">
      <span class="text-2xl text-neutral-800 dark:text-neutral" style="margin-right:10px;">
        

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 496 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M165.9 397.4c0 2-2.3 3.6-5.2 3.6-3.3.3-5.6-1.3-5.6-3.6 0-2 2.3-3.6 5.2-3.6 3-.3 5.6 1.3 5.6 3.6zm-31.1-4.5c-.7 2 1.3 4.3 4.3 4.9 2.6 1 5.6 0 6.2-2s-1.3-4.3-4.3-5.2c-2.6-.7-5.5.3-6.2 2.3zm44.2-1.7c-2.9.7-4.9 2.6-4.6 4.9.3 2 2.9 3.3 5.9 2.6 2.9-.7 4.9-2.6 4.6-4.6-.3-1.9-3-3.2-5.9-2.9zM244.8 8C106.1 8 0 113.3 0 252c0 110.9 69.8 205.8 169.5 239.2 12.8 2.3 17.3-5.6 17.3-12.1 0-6.2-.3-40.4-.3-61.4 0 0-70 15-84.7-29.8 0 0-11.4-29.1-27.8-36.6 0 0-22.9-15.7 1.6-15.4 0 0 24.9 2 38.6 25.8 21.9 38.6 58.6 27.5 72.9 20.9 2.3-16 8.8-27.1 16-33.7-55.9-6.2-112.3-14.3-112.3-110.5 0-27.5 7.6-41.3 23.6-58.9-2.6-6.5-11.1-33.3 2.6-67.9 20.9-6.5 69 27 69 27 20-5.6 41.5-8.5 62.8-8.5s42.8 2.9 62.8 8.5c0 0 48.1-33.6 69-27 13.7 34.7 5.2 61.4 2.6 67.9 16 17.7 25.8 31.5 25.8 58.9 0 96.5-58.9 104.2-114.8 110.5 9.2 7.9 17 22.9 17 46.4 0 33.7-.3 75.4-.3 83.6 0 6.5 4.6 14.4 17.3 12.1C428.2 457.8 496 362.9 496 252 496 113.3 383.5 8 244.8 8zM97.2 352.9c-1.3 1-1 3.3.7 5.2 1.6 1.6 3.9 2.3 5.2 1 1.3-1 1-3.3-.7-5.2-1.6-1.6-3.9-2.3-5.2-1zm-10.8-8.1c-.7 1.3.3 2.9 2.3 3.9 1.6 1 3.6.7 4.3-.7.7-1.3-.3-2.9-2.3-3.9-2-.6-3.6-.3-4.3.7zm32.4 35.6c-1.6 1.3-1 4.3 1.3 6.2 2.3 2.3 5.2 2.6 6.5 1 1.3-1.3.7-4.3-1.3-6.2-2.2-2.3-5.2-2.6-6.5-1zm-11.4-14.7c-1.6 1-1.6 3.6 0 5.9 1.6 2.3 4.3 3.3 5.6 2.3 1.6-1.3 1.6-3.9 0-6.2-1.4-2.3-4-3.3-5.6-2z"/></svg>

  </span>


      </span>
      <div
        id="github-e02127fda5246656fa0433195f17cabe-full_name"
        class="m-0 font-bold text-xl text-neutral-800 decoration-primary-500 hover:underline hover:underline-offset-2 dark:text-neutral">
        xiaolai/regular-investing-in-box
      </div>
    </div>

    <p id="github-e02127fda5246656fa0433195f17cabe-description" class="m-0 mt-2 text-md text-neutral-800 dark:text-neutral">
      å®šæŠ•æ”¹å˜å‘½è¿ â€”â€” è®©æ—¶é—´é™ªä½ æ…¢æ…¢å˜å¯Œ <a href="https://onregularinvesting.com" target="_blank">https://onregularinvesting.com</a>
    </p>

    <div class="m-0 mt-2 flex items-center">

      <span class="mr-1 inline-block h-3 w-3 rounded-full"
        style="background-color: #3572A5"></span>
      <div class="m-0 mr-5 text-md text-neutral-800 dark:text-neutral">
         Python 
      </div>

      <span class="text-md mr-1 text-neutral-800 dark:text-neutral">
        

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 576 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M287.9 0C297.1 0 305.5 5.25 309.5 13.52L378.1 154.8L531.4 177.5C540.4 178.8 547.8 185.1 550.7 193.7C553.5 202.4 551.2 211.9 544.8 218.2L433.6 328.4L459.9 483.9C461.4 492.9 457.7 502.1 450.2 507.4C442.8 512.7 432.1 513.4 424.9 509.1L287.9 435.9L150.1 509.1C142.9 513.4 133.1 512.7 125.6 507.4C118.2 502.1 114.5 492.9 115.1 483.9L142.2 328.4L31.11 218.2C24.65 211.9 22.36 202.4 25.2 193.7C28.03 185.1 35.5 178.8 44.49 177.5L197.7 154.8L266.3 13.52C270.4 5.249 278.7 0 287.9 0L287.9 0zM287.9 78.95L235.4 187.2C231.9 194.3 225.1 199.3 217.3 200.5L98.98 217.9L184.9 303C190.4 308.5 192.9 316.4 191.6 324.1L171.4 443.7L276.6 387.5C283.7 383.7 292.2 383.7 299.2 387.5L404.4 443.7L384.2 324.1C382.9 316.4 385.5 308.5 391 303L476.9 217.9L358.6 200.5C350.7 199.3 343.9 194.3 340.5 187.2L287.9 78.95z"/></svg>
  </span>


      </span>
      <div id="github-e02127fda5246656fa0433195f17cabe-stargazers" class="m-0 mr-5 text-md text-neutral-800 dark:text-neutral">
        5736
      </div>

      <span class="text-md mr-1 text-neutral-800 dark:text-neutral">
        

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 448 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M80 104c13.3 0 24-10.7 24-24s-10.7-24-24-24S56 66.7 56 80s10.7 24 24 24zm80-24c0 32.8-19.7 61-48 73.3V192c0 17.7 14.3 32 32 32H304c17.7 0 32-14.3 32-32V153.3C307.7 141 288 112.8 288 80c0-44.2 35.8-80 80-80s80 35.8 80 80c0 32.8-19.7 61-48 73.3V192c0 53-43 96-96 96H256v70.7c28.3 12.3 48 40.5 48 73.3c0 44.2-35.8 80-80 80s-80-35.8-80-80c0-32.8 19.7-61 48-73.3V288H144c-53 0-96-43-96-96V153.3C19.7 141 0 112.8 0 80C0 35.8 35.8 0 80 0s80 35.8 80 80zm208 24c13.3 0 24-10.7 24-24s-10.7-24-24-24s-24 10.7-24 24s10.7 24 24 24zM248 432c0-13.3-10.7-24-24-24s-24 10.7-24 24s10.7 24 24 24s24-10.7 24-24z"/></svg>
  </span>


      </span>
      <div id="github-e02127fda5246656fa0433195f17cabe-forks" class="m-0 mr-5 text-md text-neutral-800 dark:text-neutral">
        2001
      </div>

    </div>

  </div>
  <script>
    fetch("https://api.github.com/repos/xiaolai/regular-investing-in-box", {
      headers: new Headers({
        'User-agent': 'Mozilla/4.0 Custom User Agent'
      })
    })
      .then(response => response.json())
      .then(data => {
        document.getElementById('github-e02127fda5246656fa0433195f17cabe-full_name').innerHTML = data.full_name;
        document.getElementById('github-e02127fda5246656fa0433195f17cabe-description').innerHTML = data.description;
        document.getElementById('github-e02127fda5246656fa0433195f17cabe-stargazers').innerHTML = data.stargazers_count;
        document.getElementById('github-e02127fda5246656fa0433195f17cabe-forks').innerHTML = data.forks;
      })
      .catch(error => console.error(error))
  </script>
</a>
<hr>

<section class="space-y-10 w-full">
    
    
</section>
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>00495 Market Highs and Lows Don't Exist: The Only Truth in Long-Term Investing; The Privilege of the Rich and the Secret of Asset Appreciation</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1734846063547/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1734846063547/</guid><description>In this session, James shares his year-end rebalancing strategy, investment philosophy, 433 asset allocation plan, and answers questions from students regarding QQQ, leveraged ETFs, ETNs, real estate, personal finance, and CLEC short video production.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<lite-youtube videoid="TCfozoZu0Hw" playlabel="TCfozoZu0Hw" params=""></lite-youtube>



<h2 class="relative group">I. Main Topic 
    <div id="i-main-topic" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-main-topic" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This session focuses on year-end investment strategies. James emphasizes the importance of rebalancing and delves into investment philosophy, asset allocation, handling market fluctuations, and other practical investment tips. The core message is: adopt a long-term investment approach, adhere to the &ldquo;buy whenever you have money, never sell&rdquo; strategy, and implement a suitable asset allocation and rebalancing plan based on individual circumstances.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">II. Briefing Content 
    <div id="ii-briefing-content" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii-briefing-content" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Year-End Rebalancing and Asset Allocation 
    <div id="year-end-rebalancing-and-asset-allocation" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#year-end-rebalancing-and-asset-allocation" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Importance of Rebalancing:</strong> James stresses the importance of rebalancing at the end or beginning of the year. He recommends passive rebalancing, which means rebalancing when the market is performing well, to avoid panic selling during market downturns. He points out that many investors are reluctant to rebalance during market rallies, hoping to earn more, but end up succumbing to losses during declines and selling at the bottom, resulting in greater losses.</li>
<li><strong>Pledging Stocks for Tax Payment:</strong> He advises individuals with pledged stocks to borrow money for tax payments instead of selling the stocks to avoid increasing capital gains tax and to better utilize their funds. He emphasizes that under the premise of sound asset allocation and risk management, the borrowed money can be used flexibly.</li>
<li><strong>Real Estate Investment:</strong>  James advises against buying real estate, believing it restricts personal freedom. He uses the example of a friend in the Bay Area selling their property to support this viewpoint, pointing out the high holding costs of real estate, including property taxes, maintenance fees, and insurance, which can put significant financial pressure on individuals.</li>
<li><strong>Children&rsquo;s Education and Wealth Perspective:</strong> He suggests parents support their children&rsquo;s choices, believing that happiness is more important than wealth. Children shouldn&rsquo;t live for the sake of glorifying their family but should pursue happiness, serve others, and do what they love.</li>
<li><strong>433 Asset Allocation Plan:</strong> James recommends the 433 asset allocation plan (40% QQQ, 30% TQQQ, 30% Cash) for the general public, adjustable based on individual circumstances. For retirees who are not pledging stocks, he suggests an 80/20 allocation (80% index funds, 20% cash). For investors unfamiliar with or averse to leveraged ETFs, he recommends 100% investment in QQQ or 00662.</li>
<li><strong>Taiwan&rsquo;s Investment Environment Advantage:</strong> James highly praises Taiwan&rsquo;s investment environment, believing it possesses cutting-edge financial tools, tax-free policies, and low interest rates, making it an ideal place for investment. He encourages Taiwanese investors to leverage this advantage.</li>
<li><strong>Mid-Life Investment Strategy:</strong> He advises middle-aged individuals, even with modest incomes, to persist in monthly investments, accumulating wealth gradually for retirement. He illustrates the returns of monthly investments of 5,000 and 10,000 at retirement with specific examples.</li>
<li><strong>Advantages of Nasdaq 100 Index Funds:</strong> James explains the rationale for investing in QQQ, stating that its constituent companies have strong profitability, focus on technology and innovation, and align with long-term human development trends. He also points out that the constituent companies of the Nasdaq 100 index have stronger profitability compared to the S&amp;P 500.</li>
<li><strong>Investment Philosophy:</strong>  He advocates for the &ldquo;buy whenever you have money, never sell&rdquo; strategy, ignoring short-term fluctuations and believing in the long-term upward trajectory of the market. He emphasizes that the purpose of investment is wealth appreciation, not short-term gains, and criticizes the drawbacks of short-term trading.</li>
<li><strong>The Difference Between the Rich and the Poor:</strong> James points out that the rich possess assets and credit, which they can use to &ldquo;print money&rdquo; through leverage for rapid wealth growth.  The poor, lacking investment knowledge, keep their money in banks, missing out on wealth growth opportunities. He uses the example of Warren Buffett issuing bonds to illustrate how the rich utilize credit for investment.</li>
<li><strong>Three Contributions of Investors:</strong>  First, allocating capital to the most efficient companies, promoting technological advancement; second, helping the government invest idle foreign exchange reserves; third, helping the poor activate their funds, maximizing their social value.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Other Investment Advice and Opinions 
    <div id="other-investment-advice-and-opinions" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#other-investment-advice-and-opinions" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Don&rsquo;t blindly trust the investment advice of financial advisors and banks, as they have profit motives and may recommend products beneficial to themselves, not necessarily to investors.</li>
<li>Don&rsquo;t believe in investment recommendations from so-called &ldquo;group leaders&rdquo; or random individuals. Think independently, make your own decisions, and be responsible for your investments.</li>
<li>Focus on investing in broad-market passive funds in the US, such as the Nasdaq 100 Index Fund (QQQ) and the S&amp;P 500 Index Fund (SPY). He provides codes for investing in Nasdaq 100 index funds globally.</li>
<li>Avoid investing in unfamiliar assets like Bitcoin. Focus on core investment strategies to avoid distractions.</li>
<li>Don&rsquo;t overemphasize short-term market fluctuations and various news. Maintain an optimistic mindset and firmly believe in the long-term upward trend of the market.</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">III. Q&amp;A Session 
    <div id="iii-qa-session" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii-qa-session" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Zhang Yong 
    <div id="zhang-yong" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#zhang-yong" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Expresses gratitude to James, shares his 15-year experience in the insurance industry, reflects on some existing problems within the industry, such as promoting low-yield financial insurance, and expresses admiration for the simplicity and effectiveness of the CLEC investment philosophy and how it can change his and his family&rsquo;s financial future. He also shares his desire to help friends and family learn the CLEC investment philosophy but acknowledges the challenges in promotion.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s comments: Affirms Zhang Yong&rsquo;s sharing and thanks Dr. Lao Chai for the recommendation. Emphasizes the power of word-of-mouth marketing and encourages Zhang Yong to continue promoting the CLEC investment philosophy.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Mike 
    <div id="mike" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#mike" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Shares a discussion with friends in Taiwan about QQQ&rsquo;s component stock adjustments and rebalancing mechanism, mentioning the Matthew effect and the idea that the strong get stronger. He also expresses surprise at the relatively small total market capitalization of QQQ.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s comments: Suggests focusing on long-term performance rather than short-term fluctuations and explains that QQQ&rsquo;s smaller market cap is due to the relatively low number of people who understand and invest in it.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 1:  The impact of QQQ component adjustments and rebalancing mechanisms on investments, and whether one should invest in the smaller 90 companies.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s reply:  Advises focusing on long-term performance and volatility, not short-term component adjustments. QQQ&rsquo;s adjustment mechanism ensures the inclusion of the best companies, illustrated by the performance of Mega 7 and MAGS. Points out the &ldquo;stronger get stronger&rdquo; phenomenon among large companies and explains QQQ&rsquo;s rebalancing mechanism.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2: James&rsquo;s methods, tools, and experience in creating short videos, and the application of AI technology.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s reply: Details the short video production process, including writing scripts, using speech recognition software, text-to-video conversion, and subtitle generation. He shares his experience with AI tools, emphasizing the importance of personal creation and the limitations of AI in emotional expression. Mentions using tools like speech recognition software, PowerDirector, and some Chinese and Taiwanese video production software.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Hui 
    <div id="hui" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#hui" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question 1:  FNGS has performed better than QQQ. Can FNGS replace QQQ?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s reply: No, because FNGS has excessive volatility and higher risk, illustrated by the 2000 tech bubble.  Emphasizes that asset allocation should consider volatility and maximum drawdown, not just performance. In the long run, QQQ offers better stability.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2: XLG has lower volatility than QQQ and decent returns.  Is it suitable for allocation?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s reply: No, because XLG&rsquo;s long-term performance is inferior to QQQ. He provides a performance comparison of QQQ and XLG from 2006 to the present, showing QQQ&rsquo;s significantly higher returns. Emphasizes focusing on long-term performance and avoiding investments with poor long-term track records despite low short-term volatility. Investments with less than 30 years of market history are not worth discussing.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Ethan 
    <div id="ethan" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ethan" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Shares his two-year experience learning and promoting the CLEC investment philosophy in China, highlighting the positive impact and challenges. He suggests domestic investors consider opening accounts in Hong Kong to invest in QQQ and shares the advantages of investing in Hong Kong.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s comments: Affirms Ethan&rsquo;s sharing and promotional efforts, agrees with his suggestion of opening accounts in Hong Kong, and adds to the advantages, such as access to leveraged ETFs and money market funds, making the 433 asset allocation plan more comprehensive.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Ling 
    <div id="ling" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ling" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Shares her experience and understanding of the CLEC investment philosophy and how she applies it to life, such as educating her children.  She shares a childhood story of collecting shells for money and her desire for investment.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s comments: Acknowledges Ling&rsquo;s sharing and praises her proactive approach.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question: How to pledge stocks after retirement?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s reply: Explains the process of pledging stocks after retirement and emphasizes the importance of asset allocation.  Suggests the 433 asset allocation plan, adjusted according to the value of the pledged stocks. Explains how to calculate borrowing limits based on the value of pledged stocks and how to add collateral.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Martin 
    <div id="martin" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#martin" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Shares his investment experience and observations in Europe and expresses envy for the US investment environment. Mentions issues such as strict regulations and heavy tax burdens in Europe.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s comments: Agrees with Martin&rsquo;s viewpoint, analyzes the disadvantages of the European investment environment, such as high taxes and restrictions on the tech industry, and explains his focus on the US market. Points out that European socialist ideology and wealth expropriation are detrimental to capital accumulation and economic development.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Ying 
    <div id="ying" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ying" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Reflects on some mistakes in his investment journey, such as missing a year of market gains for a 5% fixed deposit interest rate, and shares his experience and insights on all-in investing in QQQ and TQQQ, and how he persuaded his wife to start investing.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s comments: Affirms Ying&rsquo;s sharing and reiterates the &ldquo;buy whenever you have money, never sell&rdquo; strategy and the all-in investment philosophy. Points out the importance of overcoming human weaknesses for investment success.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Pamela 
    <div id="pamela" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#pamela" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Shares the story of her neighbor being scammed by an accountant, reminding everyone to be cautious of investment risks and not to trust others blindly, even friends or professionals.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s comments: Agrees with Pamela&rsquo;s point, emphasizes the importance of improving one&rsquo;s financial literacy, and advises against over-reliance on financial advisors and accountants.  Points out that an accountant&rsquo;s responsibility is tax filing, not financial planning, so investors should not solely rely on their investment advice.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Nick 
    <div id="nick" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#nick" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Shares his investment experience in Canada, recommends HQU, the Canadian equivalent of QQQ, and discusses using IBKR&rsquo;s margin account. Highlights the challenges of investing in Canada and how to utilize IBKR for leverage.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s comments: Thanks Macro for sharing and suggests that IBKR&rsquo;s margin account might be an option for investors in countries without stock pledging.  Recommends that investors from other countries try and provide feedback on their experience with IBKR&rsquo;s margin account.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Julie 
    <div id="julie" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#julie" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question 1: Will pledging stocks affect mortgage refinancing?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s reply: No, stock pledging does not appear on credit reports and will not affect mortgage refinancing rates. He advises Julie to pledge her stocks as soon as possible and not wait for interest rates to decline, as future interest rate movements are unpredictable.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2: How to use TQQQ for investment and how to balance returns and risks? How to invest the money set aside for property taxes?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s reply: Suggests the 433 asset allocation plan, adjustable based on individual circumstances.  Emphasizes the importance of Beta management and recommends holding leveraged ETFs in retirement accounts. He advises against investing property tax money in TQQQ, recommending instead to keep it in cash or money market funds for unexpected needs.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Other Q&amp;A 
    <div id="other-qa" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#other-qa" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>James answers audience questions on topics such as 20-year investment returns, Warren Buffett&rsquo;s cash holdings, account selection for funds, short video production, the impact of FNG&rsquo;s bankruptcy on QQQ, simulating investments in the top ten stocks, stock pledging in Taiwan, 50/25/25 asset allocation, money market fund selection, leveraged ETF investment ratios, investment time horizons, and investment options in Canada.</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">IV. Key Takeaways 
    <div id="iv-key-takeaways" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv-key-takeaways" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>Buy whenever you have money, never sell.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This is James&rsquo;s consistent investment philosophy and the core strategy of CLEC.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Taiwan is a country with well-equipped weapons and cheap bullets.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>James praises Taiwan&rsquo;s investment environment, believing its financial tools, tax benefits, and low interest rates are highly advantageous for investors.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The most important thing in life is happiness.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>James emphasizes that the meaning of life lies in happiness, not in working and making money for its own sake.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>AI creations lack warmth.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>James shares his experience using AI tools for short video production, highlighting the limitations of AI in conveying emotions.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>You can be a benefactor to others, but whether they benefit depends on their destiny and fate.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>James shares his understanding of wealth and life, believing that an individual&rsquo;s wealth accumulation is influenced by destiny, fate, and luck, in addition to hard work.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The market has no peak, only higher highs; the market has no bottom, only a perpetual absence of a top or bottom.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>James emphasizes the long-term upward trend of the market and advises against trying to predict market tops and bottoms.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">V. Summary 
    <div id="v-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#v-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This session covered year-end rebalancing strategies, investment philosophy, the 433 asset allocation plan, CLEC short video production methods, and addressed various questions from students. James emphasized the importance of long-term investing and encouraged participants to create a reasonable asset allocation and rebalancing plan based on their individual circumstances, ignore short-term market fluctuations, and adhere to the &ldquo;buy whenever you have money, never sell&rdquo; principle.  During the Q&amp;A, students shared their investment experiences and concerns, raising questions about investment environments in different countries and specific investment products.  James provided professional guidance and advice, helping students better understand and apply the CLEC investment philosophy.</p>

  



<div
  
    class="flex px-4 py-3 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900"
  >

  <span
    
      class="text-primary-400 ltr:pr-3 rtl:pl-3 flex items-center"
    >

    

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M506.3 417l-213.3-364c-16.33-28-57.54-28-73.98 0l-213.2 364C-10.59 444.9 9.849 480 42.74 480h426.6C502.1 480 522.6 445 506.3 417zM232 168c0-13.25 10.75-24 24-24S280 154.8 280 168v128c0 13.25-10.75 24-23.1 24S232 309.3 232 296V168zM256 416c-17.36 0-31.44-14.08-31.44-31.44c0-17.36 14.07-31.44 31.44-31.44s31.44 14.08 31.44 31.44C287.4 401.9 273.4 416 256 416z"/></svg>

  </span>


  </span>

  <span
    
      class="dark:text-neutral-300"
    ><strong>Disclaimer:</strong> This article is for personal learning notes only and does not constitute any investment advice.</span>
</div>

]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>00494 Leveraging Debt for Wealth: A New Approach to Retirement Planning; Unlocking Family Assets: Combining Equity-Release Mortgages with Index Funds</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1733617616782/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1733617616782/</guid><description>In this session, James discusses the utilization of revolving line of credit home loans, investment philosophy, how to overcome the psychological pressure brought on by market fluctuations, and how to extract wisdom from life experiences. He emphasizes the importance of long-term and value investing, reiterating the investment philosophy of &amp;#39;buy when you have money, never sell.&amp;#39; He also addresses questions from students regarding leveraged funds, price-to-earnings ratios, and newly issued ETFs.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<lite-youtube videoid="g4KoDgPDNjs" playlabel="g4KoDgPDNjs" params=""></lite-youtube>



<h2 class="relative group">I. Main Topic 
    <div id="i-main-topic" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-main-topic" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This session revolves around investment and life wisdom. The core idea is to maintain a long-term perspective on investments, avoid being influenced by short-term market fluctuations, and continuously learn from life experiences to form one&rsquo;s own investment philosophy and life wisdom.  Just like life, investment also requires continuous learning and reflection.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">II. Presentation Content 
    <div id="ii-presentation-content" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii-presentation-content" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Utilizing Revolving Line of Credit Home Loans 
    <div id="utilizing-revolving-line-of-credit-home-loans" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#utilizing-revolving-line-of-credit-home-loans" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>People nearing retirement can consider using a revolving line of credit home loan (HELOC), treating the credit line as a part of their cash reserves for living expenses without touching the principal investment, thereby increasing overall asset returns.  For example, if someone has $40 million in retirement funds and obtains a $10 million HELOC, the total assets become $50 million, and the annual disposable funds increase from $800,000 to $1 million.</li>
<li>The HELOC credit line can supplement the 20% cash portion of asset allocation.</li>
<li>Note: It&rsquo;s easier to obtain a HELOC before retirement; it becomes more difficult afterward. The loan term typically doesn&rsquo;t exceed age 90.</li>
<li>It&rsquo;s not recommended to take out a loan after retirement to repay the HELOC.</li>
<li>A listener shared a strategy of using a HELOC for living expenses, which James considers a good option.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Investment Philosophy and Market Analysis 
    <div id="investment-philosophy-and-market-analysis" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#investment-philosophy-and-market-analysis" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>The market, like life, requires a long-term perspective to see the big picture. Avoid being misled by short-term fluctuations.</li>
<li>In the age of AI, human development will accelerate, and the market will continue to rise. The next two to three decades will be a period of prosperity. QQQ might reach $500,000.</li>
<li>Focus on long-term trends in investing. Don&rsquo;t be swayed by short-term market analysts or news.  Focus on long-term growth, not short-term gains.</li>
<li>If you can&rsquo;t withstand a 50% loss, it&rsquo;s not recommended to enter the market.</li>
<li>Invest in Nasdaq 100 index funds (QQQ), unless retirement funds are insufficient.</li>
<li>Short-term declines are inevitable. Be mentally prepared and maintain sufficient cash reserves.</li>
<li>Reiterates the long-term investment strategy of &ldquo;buy when you have money, never sell,&rdquo; and recommends single lump-sum market price purchases.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Extracting Life Wisdom 
    <div id="extracting-life-wisdom" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#extracting-life-wisdom" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Strive for daily progress, reflect and summarize regularly (daily, monthly, yearly). Extract life philosophy from experiences and store them in your personal &ldquo;database&rdquo; to continuously accumulate wisdom.</li>
<li>Reflect on everything, from trivial matters (like growing tomatoes) to major social events, to form a comprehensive outlook on life and investment philosophy.</li>
<li>Learn from past experiences. Reflect on what you would do differently if given a second chance to improve yourself.</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">III. Q&amp;A Session 
    <div id="iii-qa-session" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii-qa-session" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Michael 
    <div id="michael" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#michael" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question 1: How to use the smart rebalancing strategy before retirement?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: As long as you hold leveraged funds, you can use the smart rebalancing strategy.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2: How to calculate the Beta value of a portfolio holding TQQQ, QQQ, and cash?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: Calculate the weighted average based on the proportion of each asset and its corresponding Beta value (cash is 0, QQQ is 1, TQQQ is 3). He reshared the calculation formula with the audience.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Louis Lu 
    <div id="louis-lu" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#louis-lu" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Expressed admiration for James&rsquo;s insights from a month prior regarding the possibility of Bitcoin becoming a reserve currency for the US dollar, noting that James&rsquo;s response aligned with Federal Reserve Chairman Powell&rsquo;s views.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Comment:  Expressed gratitude for the acknowledgment and mentioned that it&rsquo;s a fundamental concept in finance and monetary policy, covered in previous lessons.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Shu Fen 
    <div id="shu-fen" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#shu-fen" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing:  Shared her experience of investing most of her retirement funds in savings insurance a few years ago, resulting in much lower returns than expected. This year, she redeemed a portion of the funds and invested in QQQ, achieving better returns (13.68% in three months). However, with the current market reaching new highs, she&rsquo;s hesitant to invest further, finding it difficult to overcome the psychological barrier of &ldquo;buying with eyes closed.&rdquo;
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Comment: Courage comes from the subconscious and requires training.  Believe that the market will continue to rise and practice self-hypnosis to reinforce the &ldquo;buy when you have money&rdquo; concept. Used the example of QQQ potentially reaching $500,000 to illustrate that the current price is still very cheap.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Sen Lin 
    <div id="sen-lin" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#sen-lin" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question: What&rsquo;s the difference between 00662 and QQQ?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply:  Suggested referring to the relevant link, as this question has been answered multiple times to avoid redundant explanations.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Yi Wan 
    <div id="yi-wan" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#yi-wan" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Agreed with James&rsquo;s investment method but hesitated to share it with older or same-age individuals. Felt more comfortable sharing with younger people, such as encouraging students to start saving $50-$100 per month.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Comment: Sharing depends onç¼˜åˆ† (affinity/serendipity).  Sometimes our remedy is another&rsquo;s poison. Sharing can also have negative consequences.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Zai 
    <div id="zai" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#zai" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Responded to Shu Fen&rsquo;s question about lump-sum buying, suggesting buying in batches or on specific dates, such as birthdays, to overcome psychological barriers.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Comment: Investing requires reaching a state of belief.  Continuous self-hypnosis is needed.  &ldquo;Buy immediately at market price when you have money&rdquo; is the only truth, no further analysis needed.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Ai Na 
    <div id="ai-na" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ai-na" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: After following James&rsquo;s advice, she redeemed funds from savings insurance and invested in QQQ and QLD. However, due to insufficient trading frequency, she couldn&rsquo;t purchase QQQ 2D. Her current living expenses are primarily covered by alimony, and the cost of living in Taiwan is relatively low.</li>
<li>Question 1: Does she need to buy and sell repeatedly to meet the trading frequency requirement?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: Yes, she can make small, frequent trades to meet the brokerage&rsquo;s requirements.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2: Can she buy fractional shares in Taiwan?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: Yes, but it&rsquo;s recommended to buy whole shares first and use the remaining funds for fractional shares.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 3: How to calculate retirement fund needs?  Can she receive social security?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: Calculate retirement fund needs based on annual expenses. Alimony can be considered income, but it&rsquo;s recommended to claim social security (even if her ex-husband objects) and adjust the asset allocation ratio accordingly, as alimony is not a permanent income source. She needs to be prepared.  Also recommended switching from SWVXX to BOXX.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chen Feng 
    <div id="chen-feng" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chen-feng" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Shared his personal investment journey, starting from entering the stock market in 2021, experiencing the &ldquo;bruised and battered&rdquo; phase of short-term trading, to shifting to long-term investing after encountering James&rsquo;s channel. He also established a study group of nearly 300 people, experiencing the benefits of &ldquo;teaching and learning from each other.&rdquo; He shared how he introduced the investment philosophy to his sister with 30 years of stock market experience, emphasizing the importance of a gradual approach.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Comment: Affirmed PC&rsquo;s sharing, adding the principles of &ldquo;Buddha saves those who are destined&rdquo; and &ldquo;Sentient beings save the Buddha.&rdquo;  When sharing investment concepts with family, start with small amounts of capital, like planting seeds and nurturing them gradually.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Nai Xi 
    <div id="nai-xi" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#nai-xi" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Thanked James and her friend Yu Sheng for their help.  Shared experiences of learning and sharing investment concepts with friends and expressed gratitude for the study group.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Comment: Shared his early investment experience in 1990, being introduced to investing by his friend Frank, who patiently explained investment knowledge to him weekly, eventually igniting his passion for investing.  Emphasized the importance of mentors.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">IM 
    <div id="im" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#im" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Felt that James is cultivating logical thinking in students and shared experiences of communicating investment concepts with others.</li>
<li>Question 1: How did James achieve such a comprehensive understanding?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: Continuously review and summarize life experiences, extracting the essence, like refining an elixir.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2: How to communicate with people who believe &ldquo;the first $1 million is difficult&rdquo; and are hesitant to go all in?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: Guide them to think about how to achieve the first $1 million goal and the path to wealth.  Suggest small investments based on their risk tolerance, like planting seeds, to gradually cultivate investment confidence.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Hao Qing 
    <div id="hao-qing" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#hao-qing" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing 1: Discussed the psychological pressure of buying after a stock reaches new highs. Experienced investors feel more pressure due to having reference points, while newcomers are more receptive. Like buying discounted items in a supermarket, having the original price as a reference makes purchasing more appealing.</li>
<li>Sharing 2: Shared his views on two newly issued ETFs by Invesco (QBI and QQLV) and compared them to QQQ. QBI selects larger market cap stocks from QQQ, while QQLV selects stocks with lower volatility.</li>
<li>Question: What are James&rsquo;s views on these two new ETFs?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: Doesn&rsquo;t recommend investing in unfamiliar ETFs, even if they perform well.  Stick to investments within your circle of competence.  Used the analogy of marriage, advising to choose a partner you understand. Re-emphasized the importance of focusing on asset allocation and Beta adjustments rather than selecting new investment targets.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">IV. Key Takeaways 
    <div id="iv-key-takeaways" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv-key-takeaways" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>Buy immediately at market price when you have money.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This is James&rsquo;s repeatedly emphasized investment philosophy, aiming to overcome investors&rsquo; psychological barriers and seize market opportunities.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Life shouldn&rsquo;t be lived in vain.  Continuously reflect, summarize, and extract wisdom from experiences.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This is not just investment wisdom, but life wisdom.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Teaching and learning promote each other. Buddha saves sentient beings, and sentient beings save the Buddha.
&ndash; James, Chen Feng</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Both teachers and students can grow through the process of teaching and sharing.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The seed itself is not the problem, it&rsquo;s the soil.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>An analogy for the dissemination of investment philosophy. Even good ideas require the right environment to take root.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">V. Summary 
    <div id="v-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#v-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This session covered investment philosophy, financial management skills, and life wisdom.  James reiterated the importance of long-term and value investing and encouraged everyone to overcome the psychological pressure of market fluctuations, firmly implementing the &ldquo;buy when you have money, never sell&rdquo; strategy. He also reminded everyone to continuously learn and extract wisdom from life experiences to ultimately achieve financial freedom and fulfill life&rsquo;s value. He also encouraged listeners to find their own mentors, learn from each other, and grow together, just like his early experiences.</p>

  



<div
  
    class="flex px-4 py-3 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900"
  >

  <span
    
      class="text-primary-400 ltr:pr-3 rtl:pl-3 flex items-center"
    >

    

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M506.3 417l-213.3-364c-16.33-28-57.54-28-73.98 0l-213.2 364C-10.59 444.9 9.849 480 42.74 480h426.6C502.1 480 522.6 445 506.3 417zM232 168c0-13.25 10.75-24 24-24S280 154.8 280 168v128c0 13.25-10.75 24-23.1 24S232 309.3 232 296V168zM256 416c-17.36 0-31.44-14.08-31.44-31.44c0-17.36 14.07-31.44 31.44-31.44s31.44 14.08 31.44 31.44C287.4 401.9 273.4 416 256 416z"/></svg>

  </span>


  </span>

  <span
    
      class="dark:text-neutral-300"
    ><strong>Disclaimer:</strong> This article is for personal learning notes only and does not constitute any investment advice.</span>
</div>

]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>00493 Financial Risks and Investment Wisdom: How to Accumulate and Utilize Assets; Stock Pledge and Asset Allocation: Smart Choices for Risk Reduction</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1733026874385/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1733026874385/</guid><description>In this episode, James reiterates the current market highs and advises investors to remain patient, adhere to long-term investment strategies, and avoid being swayed by short-term fluctuations. He also addresses questions from students regarding asset allocation, stock pledging, insurance, annuities, children&amp;#39;s education, and how to cope with market volatility, sharing his understanding of Modern Monetary Theory (MMT).</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<lite-youtube videoid="V0d8y8-Jl-w" playlabel="V0d8y8-Jl-w" params=""></lite-youtube>



<h2 class="relative group">I. Main Topic 
    <div id="i-main-topic" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-main-topic" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>The market continues to reach new highs.  Investing doesn&rsquo;t require constant attention; the key is to stick to a long-term investment strategy, maintain a well-diversified asset allocation, and remain patient. The real risk isn&rsquo;t short-term volatility, but the inability to accumulate sufficient wealth over the long term, and not knowing how to utilize accumulated wealth effectively.  Furthermore, it&rsquo;s crucial to be wary of various financial traps and maintain rational investment practices.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">II. Briefing Content 
    <div id="ii-briefing-content" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii-briefing-content" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Market Trends and Investment Strategies 
    <div id="market-trends-and-investment-strategies" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#market-trends-and-investment-strategies" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>The market is at a new high. Don&rsquo;t waste time over-analyzing; stick to long-term investing, buy and hold.  The market generally trends upwards; instead of predicting pullbacks, enter the market early.</li>
<li>Investing doesn&rsquo;t require excessive time. After placing your order, step away and let time work its magic through compounding.</li>
<li>Be wary of scams. Don&rsquo;t trust any investment advice that guarantees stable returns or daily gains.  Be extremely cautious of &ldquo;guaranteed profit&rdquo; schemes.</li>
<li>Ignore the advice of financial advisors and insurance agents. They rarely have the investor&rsquo;s best interests at heart and are often motivated by their own profits. Many financial products are designed to benefit the seller, not the investor.</li>
<li>Investing isn&rsquo;t simple. Even asset allocation within a Nasdaq 100 index fund requires in-depth research and adjustments based on individual circumstances.</li>
<li>Investors should always remain optimistic. The market will eventually rise. Patiently await wealth accumulation. Time is an investor&rsquo;s friend.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Risk Management and Wealth Goals 
    <div id="risk-management-and-wealth-goals" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#risk-management-and-wealth-goals" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>The biggest risks are not market fluctuations, but the failure to accumulate sufficient wealth over the long term and not knowing how to utilize accumulated wealth effectively. The ultimate goal of investing is to achieve financial freedom and enjoy life.</li>
<li>Avoid the instinctive reaction to short-term losses. Overcome fear and don&rsquo;t panic sell. Market downturns are normal and present buying opportunities.</li>
<li>View bear markets as opportunities. Buying low translates to higher future returns. Learn to think contrarily and utilize market fluctuations for mindless rebalancing.</li>
<li>The investment objective is to mitigate the risk of financial hardship, not to maximize returns. A sound investment strategy is more crucial than chasing high returns.</li>
<li>Choose a simple, low-cost, passive index investment strategy, such as a Nasdaq 100 index fund, and hold a portion in cash to maintain psychological balance and cope with market volatility.</li>
<li>Holding safe assets (like certificates of deposit and money market funds) can mitigate short-term risks, stabilize emotions during market fluctuations, and provide a sense of security.</li>
<li>The proportion of safe assets held should be adjusted based on age and risk tolerance. Retirees are advised to hold cash equivalent to 5 years of living expenses, while those yet to retire can hold more.</li>
<li>Young people should prioritize term life insurance to protect their families and avoid other types of insurance to prevent being misled by insurance companies.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Other Advice 
    <div id="other-advice" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#other-advice" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Be skeptical of all information, especially regarding money. Learn to think independently and don&rsquo;t blindly trust so-called &ldquo;experts.&rdquo;</li>
<li>Don&rsquo;t buy insurance or annuities for investment purposes. The essence of insurance is protection, not investment; annuities have high fees and low returns.</li>
<li>Don&rsquo;t disclose your wealth to your children. Encourage them to strive independently and create wealth through their own abilities.</li>
<li>Engage in rational discussions, view investments with a mathematical mindset, and analyze investment results with data.</li>
<li>Avoid over-investing in real estate. Maintain ample cash flow. Real estate has poor liquidity and is difficult to liquidate.</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">III. Q&amp;A Session 
    <div id="iii-qa-session" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii-qa-session" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Ke An 
    <div id="ke-an" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ke-an" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: 16 years old, living in the Netherlands.  Thanked James for his investment methods, which allowed her parents to take her on trips throughout Europe. She also shared that she finds her business management classes easier to understand than her classmates, thanks to James&rsquo;s teachings.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s comments: Praised Ke An&rsquo;s travel experiences and learning attitude, encouraging her to continue learning and explore her career interests.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question: Concerned about starting investing late, wants to open an account and start investing soon. Has saved NT$200,000 and plans to invest in 00662.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s reply: Affirmed the advantage of starting to invest at 16, emphasizing that time is the greatest asset.  Advised her to balance learning, life, and investment, and to enjoy her youth.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Ji Ya 
    <div id="ji-ya" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ji-ya" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question: Has savings equivalent to 8 years of living expenses. Working 40 hours a week only covers expenses. Driving for Uber could increase income but wants more free time. Unsure how to balance work and life and whether early retirement is possible. Is currently 42 years old.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s reply: In 15 years, the 8x annual expenses will grow to 50x due to compounding, enabling retirement. Suggested a BETA of 1.2 to increase investment returns, or driving for Uber a few hours a week to accelerate wealth accumulation and achieve early retirement.  Emphasized that pursuing early retirement shouldn&rsquo;t be the sole focus and that finding a balance between work and life is important. Health is paramount.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chun Xia 
    <div id="chun-xia" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chun-xia" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question 1: Plans to invest a loan of NT$7 million and aims for a return of NT$20-30 million within 10-15 years. Should the investment be lump-sum or staggered?  Has additional monthly income of NT$30,000-40,000.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s reply: Based on a 14% annualized return, there will be NT$67 million after 15 years, reaching the NT$20-30 million target within 10 years. Recommended a lump-sum investment to capitalize on market growth.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2: Wants to share investment philosophy with family in China.  Inquired about account opening procedures and trading software options in China.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s reply: Suggested Chun Xia email him for an introduction to a leader familiar with the Chinese market who can provide specific guidance on account opening and software selection.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Peter 
    <div id="peter" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#peter" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question: How to persuade family members to invest? They&rsquo;ve heard the advice but haven&rsquo;t acted, finding it difficult.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s reply: Acknowledged the &ldquo;familiarity bias&rdquo; that makes it difficult for family members to accept advice. Suggested Peter lead by example, sharing his investment philosophy and success stories. Encourage them to start with a small investment, like $100,000 in QQQ, and offer to cover any losses to build their confidence. He particularly recommended starting with retirement accounts and broad market index funds.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Ling 
    <div id="ling" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ling" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question:  Regarding children&rsquo;s education fund investment plan. Initially planned to invest all children&rsquo;s allowances in 00662 with monthly contributions, but has doubts after hearing James&rsquo;s lessons on children&rsquo;s education.  Should the plan be adjusted?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s reply: Advised prioritizing personal wealth accumulation and achieving financial freedom before focusing on children&rsquo;s education funds. Suggested redirecting the monthly contributions to personal investments to accelerate wealth growth.  Income like Lunar New Year red envelopes can continue to be invested for the children.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Dennis 
    <div id="dennis" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#dennis" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing 1: An insurance agent passed away due to financial problems, highlighting the importance of risk management, even for insurance professionals.</li>
<li>Sharing 2: Family recommended a video by an MIT professor about national debt, who argued that national debt is another form of taxation.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s reply: Explained Modern Monetary Theory (MMT).  U.S. national debt represents savings held by the public. The U.S. government&rsquo;s debt is repaid by Americans. The value of the dollar lies in its credit and the goods and services it can buy, not the level of debt. The government can stimulate the economy by issuing national debt without worrying about excessive debt.  Issuing national debt and lottery tickets are essentially providing investment channels, not just taxation.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Sharing 3: Wants to learn more about MMT.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s reply: Recommended Dennis search for books and materials on &ldquo;Modern Monetary Theory&rdquo; for a deeper understanding of its principles and applications.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Hao Xin 
    <div id="hao-xin" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#hao-xin" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question:  Are the P/E ratios of QQQ and SPY overvalued? How to deal with market fluctuations? Concerned that a prolonged stagnant market will cause borrowing interest to exceed cash reserves.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s reply: P/E ratios are unreliable and unpredictable. Recommended passive rebalancing.  Cash reserves will increase as the market rises; reinvest during downturns. Suggested simulating the 2000-2009 market scenario to test the robustness of the asset allocation strategy. If the market does stagnate for a long time, adjust lifestyle, reduce expenses, or consider other income sources. In the long run, the market will always go up; maintain confidence.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Sharing: Received a suspected scam call where the caller claimed to be from the bank and requested personal information verification.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s comments:  Commended Hao Xin&rsquo;s vigilance and reminded everyone to be cautious of calls requesting personal information to avoid being scammed.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">IV. Key Takeaways 
    <div id="iv-key-takeaways" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv-key-takeaways" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;The first investment earns the most; that performance can never be replicated.&rdquo;
&ndash; Monica</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Monica&rsquo;s statement highlights the importance of early investment and the difficulty of timing the market. Early investments enjoy higher returns, and over time, even with the same investment strategy, it&rsquo;s hard to replicate those early gains.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;The U.S. government&rsquo;s debt is the public&rsquo;s savings.&rdquo;
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This perspective challenges the traditional understanding of national debt, emphasizing the unique nature of U.S. Treasury bonds.  U.S. national debt represents dollar-denominated assets held by U.S. citizens and global investors, reflecting confidence in the American economy.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;Survival is key, not maximizing returns.&rdquo;
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This statement pinpoints the core goal of investing, reminding investors not to be tempted by high returns at the expense of risk management. Preserving capital is more important than chasing high returns during market fluctuations.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;Time is an investor&rsquo;s friend.&rdquo;
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Only long-term investments can fully benefit from the power of compounding. Time is an investor&rsquo;s best ally.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">V. Summary 
    <div id="v-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#v-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>In this episode, James once again emphasized the importance of long-term investing and risk management, offering personalized advice tailored to each student&rsquo;s circumstances. His clear explanations helped students better understand market trends, investment strategies, and the essence of wealth management. He also shared his understanding of Modern Monetary Theory (MMT) and awareness of various financial traps, reminding investors to remain rational and avoid blindly chasing high returns.</p>

  



<div
  
    class="flex px-4 py-3 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900"
  >

  <span
    
      class="text-primary-400 ltr:pr-3 rtl:pl-3 flex items-center"
    >

    

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M506.3 417l-213.3-364c-16.33-28-57.54-28-73.98 0l-213.2 364C-10.59 444.9 9.849 480 42.74 480h426.6C502.1 480 522.6 445 506.3 417zM232 168c0-13.25 10.75-24 24-24S280 154.8 280 168v128c0 13.25-10.75 24-23.1 24S232 309.3 232 296V168zM256 416c-17.36 0-31.44-14.08-31.44-31.44c0-17.36 14.07-31.44 31.44-31.44s31.44 14.08 31.44 31.44C287.4 401.9 273.4 416 256 416z"/></svg>

  </span>


  </span>

  <span
    
      class="dark:text-neutral-300"
    ><strong>Disclaimer:</strong> This article is for personal learning notes only and does not constitute any investment advice.</span>
</div>

]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>00492 Navigating Market Volatility: A Safe and Prudent Investment Approach; Leveraged ETF Strategies and Risk Management</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1732456561528/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1732456561528/</guid><description>This lecture primarily discusses investment philosophy, asset allocation, real estate investment, retirement account management, and personal financial planning. James emphasizes the importance of long-term holding and advises investors to maintain undamaged capital (cash) to cope with market fluctuations. He also answers questions from the audience regarding retirement planning, tax optimization, and real estate investment, sharing specific case studies.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<lite-youtube videoid="oLims_tjx7E" playlabel="oLims_tjx7E" params=""></lite-youtube>



<h2 class="relative group">I. Main Topic 
    <div id="i-main-topic" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-main-topic" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This lecture focuses on the importance of long-term investing and asset allocation, especially the significance of holding cash (undamaged capital). James reiterates the idea that &ldquo;the only constant in the market is volatility&rdquo; and advises investors to adopt a &ldquo;buy and hold&rdquo; strategy similar to Warren Buffett&rsquo;s, investing long-term in Nasdaq 100 index funds (QQQ or 00662). He uses a rent vs. buy case study to demonstrate the advantages of long-term index fund investing. He also explains in detail the importance of maintaining undamaged capital (cash) in asset allocation to buy the dip during market downturns, thereby achieving long-term stable investment returns.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">II. Summary 
    <div id="ii-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Investment Philosophy and Strategy 
    <div id="investment-philosophy-and-strategy" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#investment-philosophy-and-strategy" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Long-term Holding:</strong> Investing requires a timeframe of 20+ years, ideally forever, without worrying about short-term market fluctuations. James uses Warren Buffett as an example, emphasizing the importance of long-term holding, stating that if one isn&rsquo;t prepared to hold for the long term, they shouldn&rsquo;t even hold for 10 minutes.</li>
<li><strong>Invest in the US:</strong> The US is the best country for fairness, justice, and open innovation, so invest only in the US.</li>
<li><strong>Index Funds:</strong> Invest in Nasdaq 100 index funds (QQQ/00662), and recommends new viewers watch introductory videos 00451, 288, and 398.</li>
<li><strong>Market Volatility:</strong> The only constant in the market is volatility. Ignore market fluctuations and adhere to long-term holding. The 2022 market correction was just a financial event, not a bubble.</li>
<li><strong>Bubbles:</strong> Bubbles are rare, occurring only twice in the past 25 years. The best way to deal with them is to ignore them and continue holding index funds.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Asset Allocation and Cash Management 
    <div id="asset-allocation-and-cash-management" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#asset-allocation-and-cash-management" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Undamaged Capital:</strong> Having undamaged capital (cash) is crucial. It helps investors stay calm during market panics and buy the dip, just like wealthy individuals.</li>
<li><strong>The Significance of Cash:</strong> Cash is a stabilizing force that overcomes human flaws in investing (fear and greed), allowing the power of compounding to fully take effect.</li>
<li><strong>Cash Ratio:</strong> Recommends a cash allocation of at least 20% in the portfolio.</li>
<li><strong>Retirement Planning:</strong>  To withdraw $30,000 annually from an investment account after retirement, $1.5 million in cash is needed. James suggests withdrawing $50,000 annually, requiring $2.5 million in cash, approximately 20% of total assets.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Real Estate Investment 
    <div id="real-estate-investment" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#real-estate-investment" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Renting is Superior to Buying:</strong>  In the long run, renting and investing in index funds yields higher returns than buying a house. James shares a PC Excel spreadsheet example demonstrating the advantages of rental investment and encourages viewers to modify the parameters for simulation calculations.</li>
<li><strong>Selling Advice:</strong> Recommends selling real estate and land, investing the funds in the stock market. There&rsquo;s no real estate that can&rsquo;t be sold, only prices that are too high. Even if sold at a lower price, investment returns may quickly compensate for the difference.</li>
<li><strong>Short-term Rental Investment:</strong>  Short-term rental investments aren&rsquo;t worthwhile unless the annualized return is at least 20%.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Retirement Account Management 
    <div id="retirement-account-management" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#retirement-account-management" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Traditional IRA to Roth IRA Conversion:</strong> Recommends converting funds from traditional IRA accounts to Roth IRA accounts when tax rates are lower (below 24%).</li>
<li><strong>Roth IRA Investment:</strong> Recommends investing in leveraged ETFs (TQQQ) within Roth IRA accounts, while holding more cash in traditional retirement accounts. Shares a case study suggesting viewers invest Roth IRA funds in TQQQ and hold more cash in traditional retirement accounts to optimize asset allocation.</li>
<li><strong>Leveraged ETFs:</strong> Retirees should not hold leveraged ETFs. Leveraged ETFs should be held in Roth IRA accounts.</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">III. Q&amp;A Session 
    <div id="iii-qa-session" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii-qa-session" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Lora 
    <div id="lora" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#lora" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Question 1: How can I deduct the interest on a pledged loan against the interest earned on cash holdings?</strong>
<ul>
<li><strong>James:</strong> There&rsquo;s no deduction. If the interest earned on your cash is higher than the loan interest, you&rsquo;re effectively earning more. I recommend buying non-dividend-paying stocks in your personal account, like BOXX, to avoid paying taxes on interest income. Since you don&rsquo;t have a Roth IRA, you can only operate within a brokerage account and will incur some tax costs.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question 2: Which trading software do you recommend?</strong>
<ul>
<li><strong>James:</strong>  Just use your broker&rsquo;s website; no need for additional software. I only use the web version. The &ldquo;positions&rdquo; page on your brokerage website allows you to view the profit and loss of each transaction and manage them in batches.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Run 
    <div id="run" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#run" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Question 1: Can Roth IRA funds be pledged as collateral?</strong>
<ul>
<li><strong>James:</strong> Roth IRA funds cannot be directly pledged. However, they can be used as a credit guarantee to lower interest rates on other loans.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question 2: How should I invest after maxing out my Roth IRA contributions?</strong>
<ul>
<li><strong>James:</strong>  Max out your Roth IRA contributions first. Invest the remaining funds in QQQ within a regular brokerage account.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Zhan 
    <div id="zhan" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#zhan" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Question 1: How should I handle my properties in Canada and the US?</strong>
<ul>
<li><strong>James:</strong> I recommend selling your Canadian property as soon as possible. If your US property is your primary residence, I also suggest selling it and renting instead. It&rsquo;s more cost-effective, as demonstrated in the rent vs. buy case study in the presentation.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question 2: What should I do with my Canadian pension plan?</strong>
<ul>
<li><strong>James:</strong> I recommend withdrawing the money from your pension plan and investing it in QQQ within a brokerage account. Don&rsquo;t use the 403(b) and TDA accounts provided by your school, as their performance is poor. Stick to your own IRA account.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">IM 
    <div id="im" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#im" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Comment 1: There&rsquo;s a significant wealth gap among young people, and some try to fill it by borrowing money. How can I avoid this trap?</strong>
<ul>
<li><strong>James:</strong> First, cultivate strong mental fortitude, which can be achieved through reading. Second, don&rsquo;t lend money casually. Third, don&rsquo;t buy things you don&rsquo;t need. Even Warren Buffett, despite his wealth, doesn&rsquo;t buy unnecessary things.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Comment 2: I participated in an 11-day meditation retreat and gained insights into the relationship between meditation and investing, particularly the importance of focus.</strong>
<ul>
<li><strong>James:</strong> Avoid distractions outside the stock market and focus on your investment strategy.  Treat distractions like &ldquo;demons and monsters&rdquo;â€”don&rsquo;t listen, don&rsquo;t watch, don&rsquo;t engageâ€”and you&rsquo;ll maintain composure.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question: Does focusing solely on my own investments lead to detachment from the world?</strong>
<ul>
<li><strong>James:</strong> There&rsquo;s no need to be overly connected to worldly affairs. Focus on your investments and avoid excessive external information. Important information will eventually reach you.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Lin 
    <div id="lin" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#lin" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Question: How should I rebalance my portfolio?</strong>
<ul>
<li><strong>James:</strong> Since you&rsquo;re still working, you don&rsquo;t need to engage in complex rebalancing.  Just rebalance annually, adjusting the proportions of leveraged ETFs (00670L/TQQQ/Q2D) and cash. You can leave your 00662/QQQ holdings untouched. Alternatively, during your monthly investments, maintain an 80% allocation to 00662/QQQ and 20% to 00864B/cash.  (He then provides a specific example of adjusting the ratio between 00670L and cash).</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Lizi 
    <div id="lizi" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#lizi" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Question: How can I reduce the tax burden from RMDs (Required Minimum Distributions)?</strong>
<ul>
<li><strong>James:</strong> I recommend withdrawing $600,000 annually from your IRA and transferring it to a Roth IRA over the next seven years. You can invest in leveraged ETFs within the Roth IRA and hold cash in your traditional retirement account to lower your overall return and tax burden.  Start converting to a Roth IRA as soon as possible; don&rsquo;t wait until RMDs begin.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">IV. Key Takeaways 
    <div id="iv-key-takeaways" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv-key-takeaways" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;If you&rsquo;re not investing for 20+ years, don&rsquo;t tell me you&rsquo;re investing.&rdquo; &ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Investing requires a long-term perspective. Short-term market fluctuations should not influence investment decisions.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;Undamaged capital is the elixir that keeps us calm.&rdquo; &ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Holding cash helps investors remain composed during market volatility and seize opportunities to buy low.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;Don&rsquo;t engage with demons and monsters. If you don&rsquo;t engage, you don&rsquo;t need to train your mind.&rdquo; &ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Staying away from market noise and focusing on one&rsquo;s own investment strategy is key to maintaining rational investment decisions.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">V. Conclusion 
    <div id="v-conclusion" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#v-conclusion" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This lecture reiterates the importance of long-term investing, value investing, and asset allocation, analyzing them with practical examples.  James advises investors to hold Nasdaq 100 index funds and maintain a certain percentage of cash to cope with market fluctuations. He answers questions about retirement account management, real estate investment, and personal financial planning, providing specific advice based on individual circumstances. He emphasizes the importance of choosing the right investment strategy and asset allocation according to one&rsquo;s situation.</p>

  



<div
  
    class="flex px-4 py-3 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900"
  >

  <span
    
      class="text-primary-400 ltr:pr-3 rtl:pl-3 flex items-center"
    >

    

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M506.3 417l-213.3-364c-16.33-28-57.54-28-73.98 0l-213.2 364C-10.59 444.9 9.849 480 42.74 480h426.6C502.1 480 522.6 445 506.3 417zM232 168c0-13.25 10.75-24 24-24S280 154.8 280 168v128c0 13.25-10.75 24-23.1 24S232 309.3 232 296V168zM256 416c-17.36 0-31.44-14.08-31.44-31.44c0-17.36 14.07-31.44 31.44-31.44s31.44 14.08 31.44 31.44C287.4 401.9 273.4 416 256 416z"/></svg>

  </span>


  </span>

  <span
    
      class="dark:text-neutral-300"
    ><strong>Disclaimer:</strong> This is a personal learning summary and does not constitute investment advice.</span>
</div>

]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Personal Investment Bible: Book Notes</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1731056005976/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1731056005976/</guid><description>This book, written by Mr. Huang Peiyuan from Taiwan, uses easy-to-understand language to teach the correct methods of financial management. It elaborates on thirteen Investment Iron Laws for effortless wealth building, guiding readers on how to establish a correct perspective on financial management and ultimately achieve financial freedom.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[

<h2 class="relative group">I. Content Summary 
    <div id="i-content-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-content-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>The core concept of this book is that everyone can achieve financial freedom through investment, not just the wealthy or high-income earners. Through thirteen Investment Iron Laws, it emphasizes the importance of correct financial management concepts and long-term investment, encouraging readers to start managing their finances early, invest primarily in high-return investment tools such as stocks and real estate, and hold them for the long term, ultimately achieving financial freedom through the power of compound interest. The book uses numerous real-life examples and simple language to help readers understand and master correct financial management methods, while abandoning common financial management misunderstandings, such as short-term trading and over-reliance on bank deposits.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">II. Chapter Summaries 
    <div id="ii-chapter-summaries" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii-chapter-summaries" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Correct Concept of Personal Finance 
    <div id="correct-concept-of-personal-finance" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#correct-concept-of-personal-finance" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Personal investment can lead to wealth:</strong> The author believes that personal investment is not only a means to improve financial status but also an important path to wealth. Even if the monthly investment amount is small, as long as you persevere, you can accumulate considerable wealth by relying on the power of compound interest and ultimately realize the dream of becoming a billionaire. The book illustrates the power of compound interest with the example of investing 1200 Yuan per month with an annual return of 20%, resulting in assets exceeding 100 million Yuan after 40 years. It also cites the financial stories of the Lien Chan family and a postman to prove that even ordinary office workers can accumulate huge wealth with proper financial management.</li>
<li><strong>Increasing income and reducing expenditure treats the symptoms, not the root cause:</strong> Although diligence and frugality are traditional virtues, it is difficult to achieve financial freedom solely by relying on them in the era of rapid economic development. The author believes that financial management is more important than increasing income and reducing expenditure. The core of financial management lies in &ldquo;making money with money&rdquo; by achieving higher returns through investment, thereby enabling wealth to grow exponentially. The book uses the Lien Chan family&rsquo;s financial management methods as an example to illustrate the importance of investing in stocks and real estate. It points out that the Lien family did not start with huge wealth but accumulated astonishing wealth through long-term investment and financial management.</li>
<li><strong>Financial management methods cause the wealth gap:</strong> The author believes that the main cause of the wealth gap is not external factors such as family background, personal effort, or luck, but the difference in financial concepts and methods. The rich tend to invest their assets in high-yield investment tools such as stocks and real estate, while the poor tend to deposit money in banks, resulting in a slow rate of wealth appreciation. The book uses the example of two classmates who joined the same company after graduation to illustrate how different financial management methods eventually lead to vastly different wealth outcomes.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Investment Iron Law 1: Don&rsquo;t Save Money in the Bank 
    <div id="investment-iron-law-1-dont-save-money-in-the-bank" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#investment-iron-law-1-dont-save-money-in-the-bank" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Saving is equal to wasting resources:</strong> The author points out that keeping money in the bank seems safe but is actually a waste of resources. This is because bank deposit interest rates are low, and under the influence of inflation, the real rate of return is close to zero or even negative. This means that money deposited in the bank not only fails to appreciate but also depreciates. The book uses biblical stories and the example of the Nobel Prize Foundation to illustrate that not making good use of wealth, even without loss, is a waste.</li>
<li><strong>Deposit interest rates do not have compound interest benefits:</strong> Although bank deposits also enjoy compound interest, due to the low interest rate, the effect of compound interest is very limited and difficult to withstand the erosion of inflation. The author compares the final returns of two investment methods after 40 years, using a 5% bank interest rate and a 20% stock/real estate investment return rate as examples, illustrating the importance of the rate of return on investment.</li>
<li><strong>The invisible killer of currency value - inflation:</strong> Inflation is the &ldquo;invisible killer&rdquo; that causes money to depreciate. The author vividly illustrates the impact of inflation by comparing the price of red bean ice 30 years ago and now. He points out that in an inflationary environment, depositing money in the bank actually means &ldquo;the more you save, the less you have&rdquo;.</li>
<li><strong>The way to wealth of Zhang Pingsan, former chairman of Chang Hwa Bank:</strong> The author tells the story of Zhang Pingsan, the former chairman of Chang Hwa Bank, who achieved tremendous wealth growth by continuously borrowing money to buy Chang Hwa Bank shares and holding them for a long time. Those who sold their shares and put the money in the bank missed the opportunity to become wealthy. This once again proves the point that &ldquo;don&rsquo;t save money in the bank&rdquo;.</li>
<li><strong>The money deposited in the bank should not exceed living expenses:</strong> The author suggests that the amount of money deposited in the bank should be limited to meet two months of living expenses, and the excess should be used for investment to obtain higher returns. He also proposes a &ldquo;two large, one small&rdquo; investment portfolio suggestion: most assets are invested in stocks and real estate, and a small portion of funds is deposited in the bank for emergencies. He explains the liquidity of stocks and real estate to dispel readers&rsquo; concerns about investment liquidity.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Investment Iron Law 2: Be Patient to Get Rich Through Financial Management 
    <div id="investment-iron-law-2-be-patient-to-get-rich-through-financial-management" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#investment-iron-law-2-be-patient-to-get-rich-through-financial-management" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>How Li Ka-shing accumulated wealth:</strong> The author uses Li Ka-shing, Hong Kong&rsquo;s richest man, as an example to illustrate the importance of long-term investment. Li Ka-shing accumulated huge wealth through long-term investment in real estate. Getting rich through financial management requires time and patience; it is impossible to achieve overnight success. His success was not solely based on luck or hard work; more importantly, it was due to his long-term vision and perseverance.</li>
<li><strong>It takes a long time to see the effect of compound interest in financial management:</strong> The manifestation of the compound interest effect takes time, and it is difficult to see significant results in short-term investments. The author uses the example of investing 14,000 Yuan annually with an annual return of 20% to calculate the investment returns after 10, 20, 30, and 40 years, which are 360,000 Yuan, 2.61 million Yuan, 16.55 million Yuan, and 102.81 million Yuan, respectively. This set of data clearly demonstrates the power of compound interest and the importance of waiting patiently. Financial management is more like a marathon than a sprint.</li>
<li><strong>As long as you are patient, the money won&rsquo;t run away:</strong> Wealth accumulation is a gradual process that requires patience to wait for the compound interest effect to play out. The author uses the land investment experience of Zhang Yaohongying, Chairman of Hongjing Construction, as an example to illustrate that even if the initial investment return is not obvious, as long as you persist in holding it for a long time, you can eventually get a rich return.</li>
<li><strong>Getting rich overnight is counterproductive:</strong> The author warns readers that getting rich through financial management takes time, and they should not dream of getting rich quickly. Investment opportunities that bring rapid wealth in the short term are often accompanied by extremely high risks, which may eventually lead to losing everything. The author suggests that if you want to get rich quickly, you should choose to start a business instead of resorting to speculation.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Investment Iron Law 3: The Sooner You Start Investing, the Better 
    <div id="investment-iron-law-3-the-sooner-you-start-investing-the-better" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#investment-iron-law-3-the-sooner-you-start-investing-the-better" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Procrastination is the main reason for financial failure:</strong> The author points out that procrastination is one of the main reasons for financial failure. As age increases, the time available for investment decreases, and the space for the compound interest effect to play out also shrinks. Therefore, financial management should start as early as possible. Do not wait until you are older to realize the importance of financial management, as it is often too late.</li>
<li><strong>Start investing from today:</strong> The earlier you start investing, the longer the time for compound interest, and the higher the final return. The author calculates the monthly investment amount required under the same target amount and investment rate of return with different starting investment ages as examples. The data shows that the later you start investing, the higher the monthly investment amount required, highlighting the importance of starting financial management early.</li>
<li><strong>Jeffrey Koo Jr. is good at making money:</strong> The author uses the example of Jeffrey Koo Jr., Vice President of CTBC Financial Holding, to illustrate that even those from wealthy families should learn financial management early. Jeffrey Koo Jr. invested his savings in the stock market during his university days and obtained substantial returns, indicating that young people can also achieve success through financial management.</li>
<li><strong>Don&rsquo;t neglect financial management because of lack of money:</strong> The author emphasizes that financial management is not exclusive to the rich. Even if you don&rsquo;t have much money, you should start as early as possible and let the limited funds play the role of compound interest, accumulating little by little to eventually accumulate considerable wealth.</li>
<li><strong>Youth is the most appropriate time to take risks:</strong> When you are young, you have a lighter family burden and the cost of failure is relatively low, so it is more suitable to take certain investment risks. Moreover, young people have more time to make up for potential losses and learn from their mistakes.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Investment Iron Law 4: Make Money with Other People&rsquo;s Money 
    <div id="investment-iron-law-4-make-money-with-other-peoples-money" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#investment-iron-law-4-make-money-with-other-peoples-money" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Good use of debt investment:</strong> The author introduces the concept of &ldquo;financial leverage,&rdquo; which refers to using borrowed funds for investment to achieve a small investment with a large return, maximizing profits. He uses the examples of Chen Youhao, President of Eastern Multimedia Group, and Weng Daming of Hualon Group to illustrate how successful entrepreneurs use financial leverage for business expansion and investment. Specific examples are used to calculate the investment return rate under different leverage ratios to help readers understand the principle and role of financial leverage.</li>
<li><strong>Two major principles of borrowing:</strong> The author proposes two major principles for debt investment: 1. The expected return on investment must be greater than the loan interest rate; 2. In the worst case, cash income must be sufficient to pay the principal and interest of the loan. These two principles emphasize the risks of debt investment and remind readers to rationally evaluate the expected rate of return of the investment target and conduct risk assessment to ensure that even if the investment fails, the principal and interest of the loan can be repaid on time.</li>
<li><strong>Banks are not places to save money:</strong> The author points out that for people who are good at financial management, banks are not places to save money but sources of borrowing. He explains the operating model of banks: Banks absorb deposits from depositors and then lend these funds to investors. Investors make profits through investment and pay interest to banks. Therefore, people who are good at financial management can use bank funds for investment to magnify returns.</li>
<li><strong>Avoid improper debt:</strong> The author cautions readers to avoid improper debt. Do not borrow money to participate in high-risk activities such as futures, margin trading, and gambling because the expected return rate of these activities is negative, and long-term participation will inevitably lead to losses. Also, do not over-engage in consumer loans, such as credit card loans and car loans, as high-interest loans will seriously erode personal wealth. Mortgage loans are acceptable, but you should also live within your means and make sure that the monthly repayment pressure is within your affordable range.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Investment Iron Law 5: Relieve the Pressure of Investment Risks 
    <div id="investment-iron-law-5-relieve-the-pressure-of-investment-risks" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#investment-iron-law-5-relieve-the-pressure-of-investment-risks" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Analyze risks and reduce harm:</strong> The author points out that risks cannot be completely avoided in the investment process. The purpose of risk management is not to eliminate risk but to analyze risk and reduce the potential harm caused by risk. He emphasizes not to over-rely on forecasting because the accuracy of forecasting is difficult to guarantee, and over-reliance on forecasting may lead investors to lose their risk awareness.</li>
<li><strong>Forbes&rsquo; philosophy of distress:</strong> The author uses the example of American billionaire Forbes to illustrate that even risk-averse people can take risks through reasonable risk management. Although Forbes doesn&rsquo;t like adventure, in order to experience the beauty of life, he will participate in some high-risk activities, such as hot air ballooning and off-road motorcycles. But he will make full preparations before taking risks and take various measures to reduce risks.</li>
<li><strong>Don&rsquo;t blindly avoid risks:</strong> The author believes that in a changing environment, the biggest risk is not taking risks. In order to obtain higher returns, certain risks must be taken. Blindly avoiding risks may eventually lead to missed opportunities and even failure to achieve financial freedom.</li>
<li><strong>Overcome risks - start small:</strong> For unfamiliar investments, you should start with small investments, gradually accumulate experience, and gradually improve your risk tolerance. Just like scouts, first test the waters with a small amount to understand the situation, and then gradually increase the investment.</li>
<li><strong>There is no high-return, zero-risk investment:</strong> The author reminds readers that all high-yield investments are accompanied by high risks and not to believe in the so-called &ldquo;high-yield, risk-free&rdquo; investment scams. If someone recommends such an investment opportunity to you, it is likely that they are trying to deceive you.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Investment Iron Law 6: Solve the Crisis of Being Trapped 
    <div id="investment-iron-law-6-solve-the-crisis-of-being-trapped" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#investment-iron-law-6-solve-the-crisis-of-being-trapped" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Diversify your investments and hold them for the long term:</strong> The author proposes the investment strategy of &ldquo;diversification and long-term holding&rdquo; and believes that this is the key to avoiding being trapped and obtaining long-term stable returns. Diversified investment can reduce the risk of choosing the wrong investment target; diversifying investment timing can reduce the risk of buying at market highs; long-term holding can reduce the risk brought by short-term market fluctuations and fully enjoy the benefits brought by compound interest.</li>
<li><strong>Principle of risk diversification:</strong> The principle of diversified investment is to reduce the overall risk of the investment portfolio by increasing the types of investments so that the rise and fall of different assets in the investment portfolio can offset each other. The author points out that diversification is not the more the better and that management costs need to be considered. Too many investment types will increase management difficulty and cost, which is not conducive to improving profits.</li>
<li><strong>Diversify investment timing:</strong> In order to reduce the risk of buying at market highs, the author suggests spreading the funds over different periods. He proposes two methods: one is &ldquo;invest if you have money,&rdquo; and the other is &ldquo;regularly invest a fixed amount in mutual funds.&rdquo; &ldquo;Invest if you have money&rdquo; means that once you have idle funds, invest immediately and do not try to predict market timing; &ldquo;regular investment of a fixed amount in mutual funds&rdquo; means investing a fixed amount every month to buy mutual funds. This method can effectively smooth market fluctuations and reduce investment risks.</li>
<li><strong>Methods of diversified investment:</strong> The author introduces three methods of diversified investment in detail: 1. Diversification of investment tools, such as stocks, real estate, gold, art, etc.; 2. Diversification of investment targets, for example, when investing in stocks, do not just buy one stock, but buy multiple stocks in different industries; 3. Diversification of investment regions, for example, invest some assets in overseas markets to diversify regional risks.</li>
<li><strong>Reduce the risk of choosing the wrong selling time - long-term holding:</strong> Through research on the Taiwan stock market, the author found that the longer the holding time, the lower the probability of loss. For example, the probability of loss when holding stocks for more than 5 years is only 1%, and it is almost impossible to lose money when holding for more than 10 years. This once again proves the importance of long-term holding.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Investment Iron Law 7: Make Good Use of Stock Investment 
    <div id="investment-iron-law-7-make-good-use-of-stock-investment" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#investment-iron-law-7-make-good-use-of-stock-investment" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Liu Qiude&rsquo;s secret to wealth:</strong> The author uses the financial story of Liu Qiude, Vice President of Cathay Life Insurance, as an example to illustrate the power of long-term holding of high-quality stocks. Liu Qiude worked at Cathay Life Insurance from his twenties. He held his savings and the Cathay Life Insurance shares he acquired from his colleagues for a long time and eventually became a billionaire. This example also reflects the long-term and stable performance growth of Cathay Life Insurance from the side.</li>
<li><strong>Why stocks have high returns:</strong> The author explains the source of returns from stock investment: stocks represent ownership of a company, and shareholders can share in the company&rsquo;s profits and asset appreciation. Therefore, the returns from investing in stocks come from corporate earnings and asset appreciation, not from the losses of other investors. He pointed out that the long-term rise in stock prices is mainly due to the improvement of corporate profitability and the growth of asset value.</li>
<li><strong>Carefully select the types of stocks to invest in:</strong> The author compares the characteristics of listed stocks, over-the-counter stocks, unlisted stocks, and mutual funds and suggests that ordinary investors should give priority to investing in listed stocks or mutual funds. Listed stocks have good liquidity, transparent information disclosure, and relatively strict supervision, so the risks are relatively low. Mutual funds are managed by professionals and can effectively diversify investment risks, making them suitable for investors who do not have much time and energy to research stocks.</li>
<li><strong>Stock investment is better than real estate investment:</strong> The author compares stock and real estate investment from the aspects of investment threshold, taxation, and trading convenience. He believes that stock investment has a lower threshold, lighter taxes, and is more convenient to trade, making it more suitable for ordinary investors.</li>
<li><strong>Can stocks still maintain high returns in the future?:</strong> The author analyzes and forecasts the future return rate of the Taiwan stock market. He believes that although Taiwan&rsquo;s economic growth has slowed down, it is still higher than other countries and regions, so the Taiwan stock market still has high investment value in the future, but the return rate may be slightly lower than in the past.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Investment Iron Law 8: Make Money When You Buy and Sell 
    <div id="investment-iron-law-8-make-money-when-you-buy-and-sell" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#investment-iron-law-8-make-money-when-you-buy-and-sell" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Buy casually, buy at any time, don&rsquo;t sell:</strong> The author once again emphasizes the investment strategy of &ldquo;buy casually, buy at any time, don&rsquo;t sell&rdquo; and points out that this is the highest level of financial management. This strategy seems simple, but it actually contains profound investment wisdom: it emphasizes long-term holding, infrequent trading, and avoiding being affected by short-term market fluctuations, thereby obtaining long-term and stable returns. The author admits that most people find it difficult to do this because they cannot overcome human weaknesses such as greed and fear.</li>
<li><strong>What to buy - buy casually:</strong> The author points out that as long as diversified investment is achieved, the selection of individual stocks is not important. He uses the experiment of &ldquo;monkeys throwing darts to select stocks&rdquo; and his own experience of selecting stocks with his children as examples to illustrate the effectiveness of &ldquo;buying casually&rdquo;.</li>
<li><strong>When to buy - buy at any time:</strong> The author suggests that investors &ldquo;buy if they have money&rdquo;, and do not try to predict market timing. He emphasizes &ldquo;buying and waiting for a chance to rise&rdquo; instead of &ldquo;waiting for a chance to buy&rdquo;. Because the market is difficult to predict, and time is the key factor in compound interest, the earlier you start investing, the more you can enjoy the benefits brought by compound interest.</li>
<li><strong>When to sell - don&rsquo;t sell:</strong> The author believes that long-term holding is the key to obtaining high returns. He quotes Jesse Livermore, the author of Reminiscences of a Stock Operator, and the investment strategy of Taiwan&rsquo;s richest man, Cai Wanlin, to illustrate the importance of long-term holding.</li>
<li><strong>Random walk and efficient market theory:</strong> The author introduces the &ldquo;random walk hypothesis&rdquo; and the &ldquo;efficient market hypothesis&rdquo; to provide a theoretical basis for the strategy of &ldquo;buy casually, buy at any time, don&rsquo;t sell&rdquo;. The &ldquo;random walk hypothesis&rdquo; believes that short-term fluctuations in stock prices are random and difficult to predict; the &ldquo;efficient market hypothesis&rdquo; believes that all information in the market is already reflected in stock prices, so it is futile to predict market trends by analyzing information.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Investment Iron Law 9: Grasp the General Trend of the Stock Market 
    <div id="investment-iron-law-9-grasp-the-general-trend-of-the-stock-market" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#investment-iron-law-9-grasp-the-general-trend-of-the-stock-market" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Blind spots in prediction and analysis:</strong> The author once again emphasizes the limitations of prediction and analysis. He points out that technical analysis and market forecasting cannot guarantee investment success, and may even lead to losses due to frequent trading. Technical analysis is based on historical data, but the market environment is constantly changing, and past performance does not represent future trends.</li>
<li><strong>The only thing that can be measured is the unmeasurable:</strong> Market trends are difficult to predict. Instead of trying to predict the market, it is better to formulate a reasonable investment strategy and hold it for a long time. The author illustrates the unreliability of prediction with an example of a failed stock market prophet.</li>
<li><strong>Believe in yourself rather than experts:</strong> The author advises investors not to over-rely on expert opinions and to cultivate their own financial management capabilities and independent judgment. He pointed out that expert opinions often contradict each other, and ten experts may have eleven opinions. Besides, experts may also be influenced by various factors, such as conflicts of interest, and thus give biased opinions.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Investment Iron Law 10: Make Good Use of Stock Market Offensive and Defensive Weapons 
    <div id="investment-iron-law-10-make-good-use-of-stock-market-offensive-and-defensive-weapons" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#investment-iron-law-10-make-good-use-of-stock-market-offensive-and-defensive-weapons" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Value strategy:</strong> The core of value strategy is &ldquo;buy when the value is higher than the price, and sell when the value is lower than the price&rdquo;. The author uses the huge difference in the share price of China Development Financial at different times as an example to illustrate the impact of market sentiment on stock prices and the performance of investors&rsquo; irrational behavior. He advises investors to learn rational consumption behavior and buy stocks when the &ldquo;price is discounted&rdquo;. He also points out that the key to value investing is being able to accurately assess the intrinsic value of a company, which requires certain professional knowledge and experience.</li>
<li><strong>Growth strategy:</strong> The core of the growth strategy is to invest in companies with high growth potential in the future and hold them for the long term. The author uses Peter Lynch&rsquo;s investment strategy and the investment story of the &ldquo;Coca-Cola Grandma&rdquo; as examples to illustrate the effectiveness of the growth strategy. He advises investors to choose companies with high growth potential in the next 5-10 years and focus on choosing the right industry because the growth of the industry will drive the growth of corporate performance.</li>
<li><strong>Contrarian strategy:</strong> The core of the contrarian strategy is &ldquo;invest when most people are not investing, and sell when most people are eager to invest&rdquo;. The author uses the business philosophy of Fan Li and the investment strategy of Zheng Zhoumin as examples to illustrate the principle of contrarian operation. He pointed out that market sentiment is often wrong. When the market is excessively pessimistic, it is often a good time to buy; when the market is excessively optimistic, it is often a good time to sell. However, contrarian operation is very difficult, and it requires investors to have independent thinking ability and strong psychological quality.</li>
<li><strong>Value, growth, and contrarian strategies are suitable for experts:</strong> The author summarizes the characteristics of the three strategies and points out that these strategies are more suitable for professional investors. For ordinary investors, the strategy of &ldquo;buy casually, buy at any time, don&rsquo;t sell&rdquo; is simpler and easier to implement, and it is also easier to obtain long-term and stable returns.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Investment Iron Law 11: Don&rsquo;t Do Short-Term Operations 
    <div id="investment-iron-law-11-dont-do-short-term-operations" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#investment-iron-law-11-dont-do-short-term-operations" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Buy low and sell high is full of crises:</strong> The author pointed out that &ldquo;buying low and selling high&rdquo; seems to be the secret to making money from stock investment, but it is actually full of traps. Because no one can accurately predict the short-term fluctuations of the market, trying to make profits through &ldquo;buying low and selling high&rdquo; will often fall into the dilemma of chasing ups and downs, which will eventually lead to losses. He emphasizes that the main source of stock investment income is corporate profits and dividends, not the difference in buying and selling prices.</li>
<li><strong>Short-term operation is gambling:</strong> The author believes that the essence of short-term operation is speculation and gambling, and it is difficult to make a profit in the long run. Because short-term operations require frequent trading, and each transaction will generate transaction costs, such as commissions, stamp duty, etc. These transaction costs will eat away at investment income, and accumulate over time, will have a significant negative impact on investment returns.</li>
<li><strong>A game with no chance of winning:</strong> The author analyzes the composition of the stock market, including intermediaries (securities companies, governments, etc.), major shareholders, major players, and retail investors. He pointed out that retail investors are at a clear disadvantage in this game of short-term operations because they lack the advantages of capital, information, and resources. Therefore, retail investors should avoid participating in short-term operations and adopt a long-term investment strategy.</li>
<li><strong>Never participate in futures and margin trading:</strong> The author strongly recommends that investors not participate in futures and margin trading because these transactions are extremely risky, and the leverage effect will magnify both profits and losses. It is difficult for ordinary investors to control the risks. He uses the example of the Barings Bank collapse to illustrate the huge risks of futures and margin trading.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Investment Iron Law 12:  Land is Wealth 
    <div id="investment-iron-law-12--land-is-wealth" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#investment-iron-law-12--land-is-wealth" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Why real estate has high returns:</strong> The author analyzes the reasons for the high returns of real estate investment, mainly including three aspects: 1. Limited land supply; 2. As the economy grows and the population grows, the demand for real estate continues to increase; 3. Inflation will push up real estate prices.</li>
<li><strong>Hong Kong&rsquo;s richest man, Lee Shau Kee&rsquo;s real estate investment strategy:</strong> The author introduces the real estate investment strategy of Hong Kong&rsquo;s richest man, Lee Shau Kee: acquire old buildings at low prices, then demolish and rebuild them, or hold land for a long time and wait for appreciation.</li>
<li><strong>Cai Wanlin&rsquo;s secret to getting rich in real estate:</strong> The author uses Taiwan&rsquo;s richest man, Cai Wanlin, as an example to illustrate the real estate investment strategy of &ldquo;buy and hold for the long term.&rdquo; Cai Wanlin&rsquo;s secret is to buy real estate and hold it for a long time, only renting and not selling.</li>
<li><strong>Zheng Zhoumin&rsquo;s real estate investment technique:</strong> The author introduces the real estate investment strategy of the Philippines&rsquo; richest man, Zheng Zhoumin: buy when the market is down, and hold it for a long time, waiting for the market to recover and prices to rise.</li>
<li><strong>Real estate is suitable for debt investment:</strong> The author believes that real estate investment is suitable for debt investment because the long-term investment return rate of real estate is usually higher than the loan interest rate. Through reasonable debt investment, financial leverage can be used to magnify returns. At the same time, he also reminds readers to live within their means and avoid the risks brought by excessive debt.</li>
<li><strong>Brand concept of real estate investment:</strong> The author emphasizes the importance of choosing real estate developers with good brands, guaranteed quality, and good after-sales service. He pointed out that buying a property is a major investment decision, and choosing a reputable developer can reduce investment risks and enhance the living experience.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Investment Iron Law 13: Act Now 
    <div id="investment-iron-law-13-act-now" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#investment-iron-law-13-act-now" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>It is better to act than to sit and study:</strong> The author once again emphasizes the importance of action. He believes that having knowledge without taking action is equivalent to not having knowledge. The key to financial management is action, not fantasy. He uses the story of a farmer who does not understand stocks but dares to buy and eventually make a profit as an example to illustrate the importance of action.</li>
<li><strong>Future wealth is in your own hands:</strong> The author points out that future wealth is in your own hands, and only active actions can create wealth. He encourages readers to overcome their fear and bravely take the first step in financial management.</li>
<li><strong>Financial experience - learn from mistakes:</strong> The author believes that failure is the mother of success, and you must dare to try and learn from your mistakes. He advises readers to start with small investments, gradually accumulate experience, and gradually improve their risk tolerance.</li>
<li><strong>The first step in learning financial management:</strong> The author suggests that readers start acting immediately after reading this book. They can start by investing a small amount in stocks or mutual funds, or they can buy a self-occupied property. He believes that the best way to learn financial management is to practice, accumulate experience in practice, and continue to learn and improve.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">The Ultimate Chapter of Financial Management: Making Money Requires a Goal 
    <div id="the-ultimate-chapter-of-financial-management-making-money-requires-a-goal" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#the-ultimate-chapter-of-financial-management-making-money-requires-a-goal" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Don&rsquo;t be a miser:</strong> The author uses the story of a miser to illustrate that money is only a means, and improving the quality of life is the goal. He warns readers not to become slaves to money, to learn to enjoy life, and to use wealth for more meaningful things.</li>
<li><strong>What is the purpose of making so much money?:</strong> The author explores the meaning and values of money. He pointed out that money itself is not good or bad, the key is how to use it. Money can be used to improve lives, pursue dreams, help others, and give back to society. He encourages readers to establish correct values about money, not to blindly pursue wealth, and ignore other aspects of life.</li>
<li><strong>Three secrets of financial management - making money, managing money, and using money:</strong> The author proposes three levels of financial management: making money, managing money, and using money. He believes that making money is the foundation, managing money is the key, and using money is the purpose. These three levels are indispensable, and only by combining the three can you truly achieve financial freedom and live a happy life. He pointed out that how to use money is the most difficult because it involves personal values and life goals.</li>
<li><strong>American billionaire - Warren Buffett&rsquo;s view of money:</strong> The author introduces Warren Buffett&rsquo;s view of money and estate planning. Although Buffett is extremely wealthy, he lives a simple life and donates most of his estate to charity. He believes that happiness is a process, not a result. True happiness lies in constant pursuit and creation, not in how much wealth you have.</li>
<li><strong>Summary:</strong> The author summarizes the core viewpoints of the book: Everyone can achieve wealth through financial management. The key lies in having the correct concept of financial management, long-term investment, and positive actions. He encourages readers to set clear financial goals and formulate feasible financial plans based on their actual situations. He emphasizes that the ultimate goal of financial management is not to have unlimited wealth, but to achieve financial freedom, improve the quality of life, and ultimately realize the value of life.</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">III.  Key Quotes 
    <div id="iii--key-quotes" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii--key-quotes" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>Don&rsquo;t keep your money in the bank.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Analysis: This doesn&rsquo;t literally mean not keeping any money in the bank, but emphasizes not leaving most assets in low-yield bank deposits long-term.  Invest in higher-yielding tools like stocks and real estate.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Building wealth requires patience.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Analysis: The compound interest effect takes time. Financial management is a marathon, not a sprint, requiring patient waiting for ultimate success.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The earlier you invest, the better.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Analysis: Youth is the greatest asset. The earlier you start managing your finances, the sooner you can enjoy the benefits of compound interest and achieve financial freedom.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Make money with other people&rsquo;s money.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Analysis:  Proper use of financial leverage can magnify investment returns and accelerate wealth accumulation.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Diversify investments and hold long-term.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Analysis: Diversification reduces risk. Long-term holding yields higher returns and avoids being affected by market fluctuations.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Buy casually, buy anytime, don&rsquo;t sell.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Analysis:  The core of this is long-term holding and avoiding frequent trading to prevent being impacted by short-term market fluctuations.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Knowing and not doing is the same as not knowing.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Analysis: Knowledge without action is equivalent to no knowledge. The key to financial management lies in action, not just thinking.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Wealth lies in land.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Analysis: Real estate is a crucial long-term value-preserving and appreciating investment tool that should hold a significant place in your portfolio.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Money is only a means, improving the quality of life is the goal.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Analysis: Money itself is meaningless; its value lies in how it&rsquo;s used. The ultimate goal is to improve the quality of life and realize one&rsquo;s life value.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">IV.  Guidance and Significance 
    <div id="iv--guidance-and-significance" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv--guidance-and-significance" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This book&rsquo;s significance lies in helping readers establish a correct financial management mindset, master basic financial management methods, and ultimately achieve financial freedom.  It emphasizes the importance of long-term investment, the compound effect, and risk management, encouraging readers to overcome their fear of risk and start managing their finances early, without being misled by short-term market fluctuations. By studying this book, readers can better plan their financial future, enhance their quality of life, and ultimately achieve financial freedom and realize their life value.</p>
<hr>


<h2 class="relative group">Read the Full Book 
    <div id="read-the-full-book" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#read-the-full-book" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>

<section class="space-y-10 w-full">
    
    
        
            






















  <a class="flex flex-wrap article " href="/en/posts/1731056005958/">
    
        
        <div class="w-full md:w-auto h-full thumbnail nozoom thumbnailshadow md:mr-7" style="background-image:url(/posts/1731056005958/featured_hu10741705385669810361.png);"></div>
        
      <div class=" mt-3 md:mt-0">
      <div class="items-center text-left text-xl font-semibold">
        
        <div class="font-bold text-xl text-neutral-800 decoration-primary-500 hover:underline hover:underline-offset-2 dark:text-neutral"
          href="/en/posts/1731056005958/">Personal Investment Bible: Preface</div>
        
        
        
      </div>
      <div class="text-sm text-neutral-500 dark:text-neutral-400">
        











  



















<div class="flex flex-row flex-wrap items-center">
  
  
  <time datetime="2024-11-08T00:00:00&#43;00:00">8 November 2024</time>
  

  
  
</div>





<div class="flex flex-row flex-wrap items-center">
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  <span style="margin-top:0.5rem" class="mr-2" onclick="window.open(&#34;/en/tags/personal-investment-bible/&#34;,'_self');">
    <span class="flex" style="cursor: pointer;">
  <span class="rounded-md border border-primary-400 px-1 py-[1px] text-xs font-normal text-primary-700 dark:border-primary-600 dark:text-primary-400">
    Personal Investment Bible
  </span>
</span>
  </span>
  
  <span style="margin-top:0.5rem" class="mr-2" onclick="window.open(&#34;/en/tags/book/&#34;,'_self');">
    <span class="flex" style="cursor: pointer;">
  <span class="rounded-md border border-primary-400 px-1 py-[1px] text-xs font-normal text-primary-700 dark:border-primary-600 dark:text-primary-400">
    Book
  </span>
</span>
  </span>
  
  <span style="margin-top:0.5rem" class="mr-2" onclick="window.open(&#34;/en/tags/wealth-management/&#34;,'_self');">
    <span class="flex" style="cursor: pointer;">
  <span class="rounded-md border border-primary-400 px-1 py-[1px] text-xs font-normal text-primary-700 dark:border-primary-600 dark:text-primary-400">
    Wealth Management
  </span>
</span>
  </span>
  
  <span style="margin-top:0.5rem" class="mr-2" onclick="window.open(&#34;/en/tags/investment/&#34;,'_self');">
    <span class="flex" style="cursor: pointer;">
  <span class="rounded-md border border-primary-400 px-1 py-[1px] text-xs font-normal text-primary-700 dark:border-primary-600 dark:text-primary-400">
    Investment
  </span>
</span>
  </span>
  
  <span style="margin-top:0.5rem" class="mr-2" onclick="window.open(&#34;/en/tags/wealth-creation/&#34;,'_self');">
    <span class="flex" style="cursor: pointer;">
  <span class="rounded-md border border-primary-400 px-1 py-[1px] text-xs font-normal text-primary-700 dark:border-primary-600 dark:text-primary-400">
    Wealth Creation
  </span>
</span>
  </span>
  
  <span style="margin-top:0.5rem" class="mr-2" onclick="window.open(&#34;/en/tags/financial-freedom/&#34;,'_self');">
    <span class="flex" style="cursor: pointer;">
  <span class="rounded-md border border-primary-400 px-1 py-[1px] text-xs font-normal text-primary-700 dark:border-primary-600 dark:text-primary-400">
    Financial Freedom
  </span>
</span>
  </span>
  
  <span style="margin-top:0.5rem" class="mr-2" onclick="window.open(&#34;/en/tags/stocks/&#34;,'_self');">
    <span class="flex" style="cursor: pointer;">
  <span class="rounded-md border border-primary-400 px-1 py-[1px] text-xs font-normal text-primary-700 dark:border-primary-600 dark:text-primary-400">
    Stocks
  </span>
</span>
  </span>
  
  <span style="margin-top:0.5rem" class="mr-2" onclick="window.open(&#34;/en/tags/real-estate/&#34;,'_self');">
    <span class="flex" style="cursor: pointer;">
  <span class="rounded-md border border-primary-400 px-1 py-[1px] text-xs font-normal text-primary-700 dark:border-primary-600 dark:text-primary-400">
    Real Estate
  </span>
</span>
  </span>
  
  <span style="margin-top:0.5rem" class="mr-2" onclick="window.open(&#34;/en/tags/financial-education/&#34;,'_self');">
    <span class="flex" style="cursor: pointer;">
  <span class="rounded-md border border-primary-400 px-1 py-[1px] text-xs font-normal text-primary-700 dark:border-primary-600 dark:text-primary-400">
    Financial Education
  </span>
</span>
  </span>
  
  <span style="margin-top:0.5rem" class="mr-2" onclick="window.open(&#34;/en/tags/long-term-investment/&#34;,'_self');">
    <span class="flex" style="cursor: pointer;">
  <span class="rounded-md border border-primary-400 px-1 py-[1px] text-xs font-normal text-primary-700 dark:border-primary-600 dark:text-primary-400">
    Long-Term Investment
  </span>
</span>
  </span>
  
  
  
  
</div>




      </div>
      
    </div>
  </a>

        
    
</section>
<hr>

<section class="space-y-10 w-full">
    
    
        
            






















  <a class="flex flex-wrap article " href="/en/posts/1728295490690-book-list/">
    
        
        <div class="w-full md:w-auto h-full thumbnail nozoom thumbnailshadow md:mr-7" style="background-image:url(/posts/1728295490690-book-list/featured_hu4424409690304057825.jpg);"></div>
        
      <div class=" mt-3 md:mt-0">
      <div class="items-center text-left text-xl font-semibold">
        
        <div class="font-bold text-xl text-neutral-800 decoration-primary-500 hover:underline hover:underline-offset-2 dark:text-neutral"
          href="/en/posts/1728295490690-book-list/">Recommended Reading List</div>
        
        
        
      </div>
      <div class="text-sm text-neutral-500 dark:text-neutral-400">
        











  



















<div class="flex flex-row flex-wrap items-center">
  
  
  <time datetime="2024-10-01T00:00:00&#43;00:00">1 October 2024</time>
  

  
  
</div>





<div class="flex flex-row flex-wrap items-center">
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  <span style="margin-top:0.5rem" class="mr-2" onclick="window.open(&#34;/en/tags/recommended/&#34;,'_self');">
    <span class="flex" style="cursor: pointer;">
  <span class="rounded-md border border-primary-400 px-1 py-[1px] text-xs font-normal text-primary-700 dark:border-primary-600 dark:text-primary-400">
    Recommended
  </span>
</span>
  </span>
  
  <span style="margin-top:0.5rem" class="mr-2" onclick="window.open(&#34;/en/tags/book/&#34;,'_self');">
    <span class="flex" style="cursor: pointer;">
  <span class="rounded-md border border-primary-400 px-1 py-[1px] text-xs font-normal text-primary-700 dark:border-primary-600 dark:text-primary-400">
    Book
  </span>
</span>
  </span>
  
  
  
  
</div>




      </div>
      
    </div>
  </a>

        
    
</section>
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Personal Investment Bible: Conclusion</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1731056005974/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1731056005974/</guid><description>This article summarizes the core concepts of building wealth through personal finance, emphasizing that everyone can achieve financial freedom through proper money management. Key takeaways include the importance of financial planning, principles for setting financial goals, the value of long-term investing, overcoming common financial misconceptions, and balancing wealth with a fulfilling life. It encourages readers to acquire financial knowledge, adhere to long-term investment strategies, and ultimately achieve financial freedom and a better life.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[

<h2 class="relative group">Conclusion 
    <div id="conclusion" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#conclusion" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>What influences a person&rsquo;s future wealth the most,
is whether they have started managing their finances.</p>
</blockquote>
<p><strong>Everyone Can Achieve Wealth Through Personal Finance</strong></p>
<p>This book aims to illustrate a simple truth: investing and managing your finances can not only improve the financial situation of an individual or family, but is also an excellent path to wealth creation.  Furthermore, anyone can achieve wealth through personal finance. You don&rsquo;t need to be rich, have a high income, possess a high degree, have specialized knowledge or advanced skills, nor rely on luck. What you need is the desire for wealth, a correct investment philosophy (not just techniques), and the patience to wait for the long term.  Therefore, whether a person has money or not, or how high their income is, doesn&rsquo;t matter. What truly influences a person&rsquo;s future wealth is whether they have started managing their finances. This endeavor is not easy, but it&rsquo;s undoubtedly worth your effort!</p>
<p>Readers, please immediately review your current asset allocation. Is too much of your capital sitting in bank accounts or other &ldquo;guaranteed return&rdquo; investments?  Is your investment portfolio sufficiently diversified? Do you frequently buy and sell in the stock market?</p>
<p>After understanding your asset allocation, you should earnestly plan your financial goals and follow these five principles:</p>
<p><em>1. Clearly define the amount of wealth you hope to achieve and keep it in mind at all times. Simply thinking &ldquo;I want to be rich&rdquo; is not enough.</em></p>
<p><em>2. Set a specific date for achieving your goal.</em></p>
<p><em>3. Determine what price you&rsquo;re willing to pay and what actions you&rsquo;ll take to reach your ideal goal.</em></p>
<p><em>4. Think about your goal at least twice a day to reinforce your belief.</em></p>
<p><em>5.  Take action, whether you feel completely ready or not.</em></p>
<p>In Appendix II, readers can use the wealth creation formula and examples provided to calculate how to achieve their financial goals.</p>
<p>Your future wealth depends on what you do today. Don&rsquo;t let unnecessary hesitation cast a shadow on your heart. As long as you understand investment and financial management, you too can become wealthy in the future. Everyone possesses the necessary ingredients for wealth creation: a small amount of capital and a God-given resourceâ€”time. As long as you are willing to learn about personal finance, you have the potential to become a multi-millionaire.</p>
<p>When you find people around you feeling lost due to a lack of vision for the future, share with them the &ldquo;Â¥14,000 a year for 40 years can make you a multi-millionaire&rdquo; formula and help them reignite their hope.</p>
<p><strong>Financial Dependence Is Your Own Responsibility</strong></p>
<p>The unequal distribution of wealth in today&rsquo;s society is increasingly severe. Some blame flawed policies, others point to artificial market manipulation. I believe neither is the primary cause.  One of the main reasons for the wealth gap is the disparity in financial literacy among people.</p>
<p>The reason for poverty in modern times is not so much insufficient income, lack of thrift, or excessive spending, but rather improper financial management. In modern society, achieving financial independence after the age of 40 is a fundamental responsibility for everyone. Whether you want to or not, or whether you like it or not, investment and financial management have become essential knowledge for modern individuals. Remember, with our current income levels and investment opportunities, &ldquo;remaining poor after 40&rdquo; is self-inflicted, and &ldquo;not being a multi-millionaire after 70&rdquo; is due to a lack of financial knowledge.</p>
<p>Advances in modern medicine have increased human life expectancy, leading to an aging society.  Longer lifespans are a blessing, but enjoying a comfortable retirement is even more crucial. We must accumulate sufficient wealth to secure our lives in old age.</p>
<p><strong>Effortless Personal Finance, Enjoy the Process</strong></p>
<p>From the examples provided in this article, we can see that those who are good at managing their finances understand how to invest their assets in stocks and real estate with high long-term returns, and they avoid unnecessary short-term trading, thus achieving wealth with ease.  Those who are not good at managing their finances either focus solely on saving and keeping their assets in &ldquo;safe&rdquo; bank deposits or try to get rich quickly by engaging in short-term trading in the stock or futures markets. These individuals will eventually be left far behind in the race for financial success.</p>
<p>Most people keep their assets in financial institutions without investing them, and when they do start investing, they aim for quick riches.  As a result, their money stagnates in banks, and their pursuit of quick wealth often leads to substantial losses.  They fail to realize that with a little courage, by investing in stocks and real estate and patiently waiting for decades, they can naturally achieve wealth.</p>
<p>Simply put, building wealth through personal finance only requires two things: investing your capital in areas with high returns and having the patience to wait for the long term. The required investment is low, the probability of success is high, and the process is relaxed and enjoyable.</p>
<p>I advise readers not to rush to get rich through investment, causing anxiety and ultimately achieving the opposite of what they desire.  By following the methods described in this book, you can achieve financial success without expending excessive time and energy, allowing you to focus on your existing career.</p>
<p>Personal finance is a marathon, not a sprint. If you view the entire process from a long-term perspective, temporary setbacks don&rsquo;t signify failure, and momentary gains don&rsquo;t guarantee lasting success. With this mindset, you can maintain a more open perspective and avoid becoming overly attached to gains and losses.</p>
<p>I admit that consistently buying assets and holding them long-term can make personal finance seem dull and unbearable. However, before engaging in any financial activities, investors must clarify their objectives: is it to build wealth or to seek the thrill of gambling? Personal finance can not only lead to wealth but also bring joy and knowledge.  Everyone should learn how to manage their finances and find enjoyment in the process.</p>
<p><strong>Don&rsquo;t Feel Guilty About Being Wealthy</strong></p>
<p>Wealth should be acquired and used ethically. You don&rsquo;t need to apologize to others for your wealth. Only the pursuit of wealth through unscrupulous means is sinful and unfortunate.  Therefore, everyone should not only be confident but also feel obligated to earn wealth. There&rsquo;s no need to be secretive or ashamed about pursuing wealth. On the contrary, being financially dependent is a burden on society.  Moreover, wealthy individuals are more capable of contributing to society.  In short, if you can&rsquo;t find a good reason why getting rich is bad, why not allow yourself to become wealthy?</p>
<p>You earning more in the investment market doesn&rsquo;t mean others will earn less or lose more.  If everyone is proficient in managing their finances, not only can individuals prosper, but economic resources can also be utilized effectively, leading to rapid overall economic growth.  In a market economy, the wealth of society is built upon the wealth of its people. Only a prosperous populace can create a prosperous economy.</p>
<p>In today&rsquo;s financially driven world, whether for personal advancement or the benefit of society as a whole, everyone should strengthen their understanding of personal finance. When everyone is skilled in managing their finances, individuals and families can live prosperous lives, the wealth gap can be narrowed, and the nation can progress and flourish.</p>
<p><strong>Action Speaks Louder Than Words</strong></p>
<p>&ldquo;Knowing and not doing is not knowing.&rdquo; The biggest obstacle to personal finance is not that it&rsquo;s difficult to do, but that it&rsquo;s difficult to start.  The key to overcoming this is to act immediately.  One of the main reasons for failure in personal finance is avoiding decisions.  However, if you want to achieve your goal of building wealth through investment, there&rsquo;s no other way than to take action.</p>
<p>After reading the basic principles of investment and financial management outlined in this article, you should understand that building wealth is not only achievable but also not difficult.  So, act now! Time is money. The earlier you start, the sooner you&rsquo;ll reach your financial goals and share the fruits of your labor with your family.</p>
<p>Looking ahead, changes in society, politics, economics, and finance will accelerate, and the resulting redistribution of wealth will inevitably follow suit.  For yourself, your family, and society as a whole, managing your finances is a role everyone should embrace.</p>
<p><strong>Persistence Is Key</strong></p>
<p>For readers seeking quick riches, this book might disappoint you.  A more accurate title would be: &ldquo;How to Invest and Manage Your Finances to Slowly but Steadily Build Wealth.&rdquo;</p>
<p>Many believe that successful people are infallibleâ€”never failing, never experiencing losses.  Many also think they must be omniscient and possess sufficient knowledge before they can start investing and managing their finances.  Our most common flaw is our unwillingness to try repeatedly and to persevere. Building wealth through personal finance is not difficult! The reason most people don&rsquo;t achieve their goals is their inability to persevere and their lack of patience.</p>
<p>Persistence is essential for success in personal finance. Suppose you embark on a wealth-building plan and encounter setbacks along the way. Don&rsquo;t be discouraged. Some people regularly save and invest annually.  When prices rise, they are satisfied and continue their plan. But when prices fall, they panic and abandon their investment strategy.  They fail to understand that price fluctuations are inherent in the investment market, and investment results will inevitably fluctuate.</p>
<p>If, midway through your financial plan, you succumb to the temptation to spend your investment capital or give up due to repeated setbacks, all your previous efforts will be wasted.  <strong>Success in personal finance depends on endurance and resolve:  endurance to delay gratification and resist immediate consumption temptations; and resolve to withstand significant wealth fluctuations over long periods without losing your composure.  As long as you have perseverance and resolve, trust in compound interest, and believe in the &ldquo;wealth creation formula,&rdquo; the ultimate wealth will undoubtedly be yours.</strong></p>
<p>&ldquo;No dreams, no wealth.&rdquo;  Those who build wealth through personal finance must be driven by desire and ambition.  They also need sufficient courage, knowledge, patience, and perseverance.  A lack of courage, flawed methods, impatience, or giving up halfway will not work. Whether you can achieve wealth and financial independence in the future depends entirely on your actions and efforts today.</p>
<p><strong>Unlock Your Hidden Wealth Potential</strong></p>
<p>Believe it or not, the price of living a wealthy and successful life is no greater than the price of living a poor and miserable one. Achieving this depends entirely on wisdom, belief, and action. After reading this book, readers should understand that everyone can achieve wealth through personal finance. The reason most people are not wealthy is not due to low income, but rather a lack of understanding of how to create wealth through investment and financial management. The primary purpose of this book is to help everyone unlock their hidden wealth potential.</p>
<p>If, after reading this book, you still cannot effectively apply these investment principles to manage your money and improve your financial situation, then this book is a complete failure.  Financial education is not merely about imparting knowledge; its significance lies in genuinely changing the reader&rsquo;s financial behavior.</p>
<p>This is a book of action, not a textbook for enhancing investment knowledge or a &ldquo;decorative book&rdquo; for your bookshelf.  This book aims to inspire readers to change their mindset and behavior. Its success depends on readers taking action based on the core principles presented, breaking free from mediocrity, and embarking on the path to wealth. Therefore, at the end of most chapters, key points are summarized for readers to reflect upon and apply.</p>
<p>Investment and financial management can not only lead to wealth but also bring joy to investors. Everyone should learn how to manage their finances and reap the substantial rewards.  I believe most readers already possess the basic requirements for building wealth: a small amount of capital, sufficient time, and the investment knowledge gained from this book.  The world of personal finance, full of changes and opportunities, awaits you.  It is filled with treasures and pitfalls. Don&rsquo;t hesitate, and don&rsquo;t leave empty-handed.</p>
<p>The principles of building wealth through investment and financial management are neither profound nor mysterious. They are absolutely achievable for everyone, and many have indeed easily become wealthy through these methods.  As we&rsquo;ve mentioned before, &ldquo;If you&rsquo;re willing to learn, managing your finances is as simple as walking.&rdquo;</p>
<p>Among the financial principles presented in this book, you&rsquo;ll find many that contradict deeply ingrained investment concepts and financial habits, and some even go against human nature.  Therefore, to realize the ideal of wealth creation through investment and financial management, the first step is to break free from some &ldquo;deep-rooted and misguided&rdquo; investment concepts, common knowledge, and habits.  Almost none of these concepts and principles are easy to achieve. Therefore, I advise readers to not only read each chapter carefully but also to review, reflect, establish strict rules, and ultimately change their behavior.</p>
<p><strong>Wealth Is a Means to a Better Life</strong></p>
<p>Finally, this book must emphasize that <strong>wealth is not the purpose of life, but a means to create a better life.</strong>  The ultimate goal of investment and financial management is not just to become rich, but to use wealth to realize your life&rsquo;s aspirations.  Therefore, <strong>a fulfilling and balanced life is the starting point for personal finance.</strong></p>
<p>Everyone should actively and optimistically plan and execute their lifelong financial journey.  Based on the principles we&rsquo;ve presented, everyone can achieve substantial wealth through personal finance without sacrificing time, energy, work, or life.  However, it&rsquo;s crucial to remember that <strong>only those who balance career, life, health, family, and wealth can be considered truly successful in managing their finances.</strong>  Those who gain the world&rsquo;s riches but lose their health, family, and the meaning of life cannot be considered truly successful.  In today&rsquo;s society, many are lost in the pursuit of wealth, sacrificing more valuable things in life.  Therefore, this principle of balancing personal finance and life is particularly important and deserves careful consideration.</p>
<p>Although this book repeatedly emphasizes that success in personal finance depends on mindset, time, and action, not luck, I still congratulate you, the reader, on being fortunate enough to encounter this book. By adhering to the investment principles within, you are sure to become a multi-millionaire in the decades to come!</p>
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Personal Investment Bible: The Ultimate Guide to Wealth Management</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1731056005973/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1731056005973/</guid><description>This article explores the ultimate goal of wealth management â€“ enhancing the quality of life, rather than simply pursuing money. Using the parable of a miser, it emphasizes that the true meaning of wealth lies in how it&amp;#39;s used to live the life you desire. It examines the unique perspectives on money held by prominent figures like Li Ka-shing, Tsai Wan-lin, and Wang Yung-ching, highlighting how many become slaves to money, unable to utilize it for happiness. Finally, it introduces the three keys to wealth management â€“ earning, managing, and utilizing money â€“ emphasizing the importance of setting financial goals and using wealth wisely.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[

<h2 class="relative group">The Ultimate Guide to Wealth Management: Earning Money Requires a Goal 
    <div id="the-ultimate-guide-to-wealth-management-earning-money-requires-a-goal" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#the-ultimate-guide-to-wealth-management-earning-money-requires-a-goal" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>Money is merely a means; improving the quality of life is the ultimate goal.
Success is getting what you want, then enjoying what you have.</p>
</blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">Don&rsquo;t Be a Miser 
    <div id="dont-be-a-miser" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#dont-be-a-miser" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>A miser sold all his possessions, deposited the money in a bank, and took great satisfaction in calculating his daily interest earnings. His unscrupulous son, noticing his father&rsquo;s secretive behavior, discovered the large bank deposit. He stole the passbook and seal, withdrew all the money, and replaced the original with a forgery.  The miser, unaware of the deception, continued to calculate his imaginary wealth and interest.</p>
<p><strong>Not Spending Money Is Like Having No Money</strong></p>
<p>Months later, a sudden urge led the miser to the bank, where he discovered his account was empty. Devastated, he returned home, where his son consoled him: &ldquo;Don&rsquo;t be so upset. Just pretend the passbook is real. It serves the same purpose. You can still calculate your wealth daily. Money sitting unused in a bank is the same as having no money.&rdquo; This parable satirizes the miser to emphasize the true meaning of wealth.  Hoarding money without utilizing it is no different from having none.  Wealth, in any form, has no inherent meaning. Its value comes from what we ascribe to it and how we use it to live the life we want.</p>
<p>&ldquo;My philosophy is to live a simple life, be humble, and what significance does money hold for me?&rdquo;  Li Ka-shing, despite his immense wealth, focuses on making more money and training his successors â€“ his two sons, Victor and Richard.</p>
<p>Wealthy Taiwanese tycoons seem to follow a similar pattern, leaving all their wealth to the next generation, even surpassing Li Ka-shing in their simple lifestyles. Tsai Wan-lin, once Taiwan&rsquo;s richest man, drove a Yulon car and ate nutritionally balanced but bland meals prepared by doctors. Even in his 70s, he went to work every day, saying, &ldquo;The thought of paying NT$20 million in salaries every day compels me to come to the office.&rdquo;</p>
<p>Taiwan has many such &ldquo;miserly&rdquo; tycoons. Wang Yung-ching, the founder of Formosa Plastics Group, was known for his frugality, even combining leftover soap scraps. He said, &ldquo;Food needs only to be nutritious, not necessarily luxurious. Simple meals are good.  Constant luxury makes one forget what happiness is.&rdquo;</p>
<p>&ldquo;I can live like an emperor or a commoner,&rdquo; said Huang Shih-hui, chairman of the Chinfon Group and a consistent top taxpayer in Taiwan. &ldquo;Even if I lost a third, or even half of my wealth, I could still live well.&rdquo; Ranked Taiwan&rsquo;s sixth richest man by Fortune magazine, Huang ate NT$50 lunches and drove an ordinary car. He said, &ldquo;How much can I wear? How much can I eat? Excessive desire will kill you!&rdquo; For these wealthy individuals, the meaning of earning so much lies in the sense of accomplishment, not enjoyment.</p>
<p><strong>Be the Master of Your Money</strong></p>
<p><em>If you don&rsquo;t master your money, your money will master you.</em></p>
<p>If asked, &ldquo;What&rsquo;s the next step after earning money?&rdquo; most people would instinctively answer, &ldquo;Spending it!&rdquo;  They&rsquo;re wrong. Those who answer this way usually haven&rsquo;t earned much. Most self-made millionaires continue to earn after becoming wealthy.</p>
<p>Some might say, &ldquo;It&rsquo;s foolish to have money and not spend it!&rdquo;  True, but such misers are not uncommon. Studies show that at least 90% of people continue to accumulate wealth, becoming slaves to money.</p>
<p>By now, you should realize that achieving financial wealth is relatively easy.  Avoid keeping all your money in the bank, invest most of it in stocks or real estate, and be patient.  However, teaching you to become a billionaire only to become a miserly hoarder is not my intention.  Therefore, it&rsquo;s crucial to discuss the meaning of wealth and the reasons for pursuing it.</p>
<p>Undeniably, with today&rsquo;s opportunities and living standards, hard work can ensure a comfortable life.  This book demonstrates that with proper financial management, wealth is attainable. However, without prior reflection on the meaning of wealth, you may become complacent, give up, or, even worse, become wealthy but not know how to use your money.  This benefits no one.  Before embarking on the path to riches, ask yourself what wealth means to you, then determine the steps to achieve it.</p>
<p><em>1. Don&rsquo;t be a miser.  Learn to spend wisely after earning.</em>
<em>2. Before pursuing wealth, understand your values regarding it.</em></p>
<blockquote>
<p>Money, a double-edged sword, has corrupted countless souls throughout history.
Poverty, a solitary grave, has buried countless heroes and talents.</p>
</blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">Why Earn So Much? 
    <div id="why-earn-so-much" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#why-earn-so-much" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>Everyone desires wealth.  Isn&rsquo;t that why you bought and are reading this book? Yet, not everyone prioritizes wealth. We often hear sentiments like: &ldquo;You can&rsquo;t take it with you,&rdquo; &ldquo;Wealth is fleeting,&rdquo; or &ldquo;One can only eat three meals a day, wear one outfit, and one pair of shoes. Why earn so much?&rdquo;</p>
<p>If you say, &ldquo;Why bother with financial management if you don&rsquo;t want wealth?&rdquo; I have nothing more to say.  This book is explicitly for those seeking financial independence and wealth.</p>
<p>The desire for wealth is a personal choice, determined by one&rsquo;s values and perspective on money. Some see it as a tool, content with enough to meet their needs; others view it as the root of all evil, associating the pursuit of wealth with something ignoble.  Undeniably, the single-minded pursuit of money is wrong. Life offers many other valuable pursuits: health, knowledge, family, love, friendship â€“ all precious.</p>
<p>Money isn&rsquo;t everything. We often hear, &ldquo;If money can solve it, it&rsquo;s a simple problem.&rdquo;  While not the most important thing in life, its importance is undeniable. As the saying goes, &ldquo;Money isn&rsquo;t everything, but without it, you can do nothing.&rdquo;  A good life requires money, as does education, a higher quality of life, improving family life, and even philanthropy. The New England Journal of Medicine points out that the wealthy live longer, healthier lives than the poor.</p>
<p>Many aspire to a happy life and giving back to society.  Both require money. Thus, money is a necessary means to achieve life goals. You can disdain money, but you can&rsquo;t deny its utility in today&rsquo;s society.</p>
<p>One&rsquo;s status and worth are often judged by wealth.  It&rsquo;s unfair, but true.  Despite the absence of social classes, money divides people into &ldquo;rich&rdquo; and &ldquo;poor.&rdquo; Greater wealth translates to greater ability to acquire desired possessions, status, and lifestyles.</p>
<p>Money undoubtedly buys the best healthcare, food, clothing, and housing. It provides security and freedom from fear, improving the quality of life and making it more vibrant.  The poor have limited options, while the rich enjoy a wider range of experiences.</p>
<p><strong>Money Can Ruin the Next Generation</strong></p>
<p>The easiest way to ruin your children? Leave them a fortune.  The saying &ldquo;Wealth doesn&rsquo;t last three generations&rdquo; reflects this truth.</p>
<p>Many educators and I share a common experience: the most challenging students lack motivation, often stemming from wealthy backgrounds.  These children, wanting for nothing, don&rsquo;t understand the need for hard work or ambition.</p>
<p>I recall a case during my tenure as director of the Graduate Institute of Business Administration at Tunghai University. A student, admitted after fierce competition, struggled academically and seemed listless. During counseling, I inquired about learning difficulties.</p>
<p>His response: &ldquo;My engineering background makes these courses easy. I don&rsquo;t understand why I need to learn this.&rdquo; I explained that business school teaches profit maximization. He replied, &ldquo;What&rsquo;s the point of making money?&rdquo; Shocked, I learned that his family&rsquo;s wealth had shielded him from financial concerns, leaving him without a drive to earn. I then emphasized the value of business management for future employment. His response: &ldquo;My father owns a factory waiting for me, but I don&rsquo;t want it.&rdquo;  He didn&rsquo;t appreciate what he already had.  I asked about his apparent preoccupation.  Reluctantly, he confessed his biggest worry: &ldquo;Why can humans kill animals, but not the other way around?&rdquo; I truly didn&rsquo;t understand the mindset of the wealthy&rsquo;s offspring.  It reminded me of the Taiwanese saying: &ldquo;Some complain of hunger after a full meal.&rdquo;</p>
<p>We should be grateful if our parents didn&rsquo;t leave us a fortune that robbed us of our drive.  This book shows how financial management can lead to wealth.  However, I caution against leaving excessive wealth to your children.</p>
<p>Ideally, set a financial goal and stop actively pursuing wealth after reaching it.  Avoid becoming a lifelong slave to money, and don&rsquo;t ruin your children&rsquo;s future.</p>
<p><strong>Warren Buffett&rsquo;s Perspective on Money</strong></p>
<p>Billionaire Warren Buffett has arranged his estate to be managed by a trust controlled by wise individuals with absolute authority and no restrictions.  He avoids preconditions, hoping to prevent it from becoming a bureaucratic, traditional fund. He said, &ldquo;If they create a lofty palace and become conservative and closed-minded, my ghost will not let them rest.&rdquo;</p>
<p>Buffett left his children $3 million each, and they now live happily as farmers. I admire his perspective: &ldquo;True happiness isn&rsquo;t living in a palace but adding a room to your house each year, because happiness is a process, not a result.&rdquo;</p>
<p>Buffett&rsquo;s estate planning is unique.  As America&rsquo;s richest man, his financial decisions draw attention. Some criticize his perceived stinginess towards philanthropy. He countered, &ldquo;When I die, societal problems will remain.  Society will benefit more from my wealth then than now.&rdquo; He remains steadfast despite public opinion.</p>
<p>Buffett essentially ensures that his wealth, acquired from society, returns to it upon his death â€“ a remarkably detached approach compared to many Eastern tycoons.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Acquiring wealth is difficult.
Maintaining wealth is harder.
Utilizing wealth is the hardest.</p>
</blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">The Three Keys to Wealth Management: Earning, Managing, and Utilizing 
    <div id="the-three-keys-to-wealth-management-earning-managing-and-utilizing" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#the-three-keys-to-wealth-management-earning-managing-and-utilizing" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>Wealth management comprises three levels: earning, managing, and utilizing money. Technically, earning is the hardest, followed by managing, then utilizing. However, my experience as a financial advisor suggests that teaching people how to earn is difficult, teaching them to manage is harder, and teaching them to utilize is the hardest.</p>
<p><strong>Few Spend Wisely</strong></p>
<p>Some challenge this: &ldquo;Spending is easy! Give me your money, and I&rsquo;ll spend it all quickly.&rdquo;  True, spending other people&rsquo;s money is easy; spending your life&rsquo;s earnings is not. Many wealthy individuals struggle to use their money meaningfully.</p>
<p>Many lifelong savers find it incredibly difficult to change their habits and spend appropriately, even after becoming wealthy.  When asked, &ldquo;What are you saving for?&rdquo; they often reply, &ldquo;I don&rsquo;t know.&rdquo;</p>
<p>Many people tirelessly pursue wealth without clarifying their goals.  They blindly follow the mantra &ldquo;Money is important.&rdquo;  No one takes their wealth to the grave. <strong>Many become so consumed with earning that they forget their initial purpose, mistaking the means for the end.  They fail to use their wealth for greater happiness, joy, or societal good, becoming slaves to money.  Their wealth becomes meaningless, bringing more harm than benefit.</strong></p>
<p><em>1. Money is a means to achieve life goals. Don&rsquo;t mistake the means for the end and blindly chase money.</em>
<em>2.  Learn to utilize your money to become a truly happy and wealthy individual.</em>
<em>3. Save when young, manage wisely in middle age, and spend thoughtfully in old age.</em></p>
<p><strong>The Wealth Journey of Chen Ding-chuan, Chairman of Everlight Chemical</strong></p>
<p>&ldquo;Before seeking wealth, cultivate the ability to manage money and control yourself.&rdquo; Chen Ding-chuan believes that those who don&rsquo;t understand how to use money become its slaves, losing themselves in the pursuit.  Those who master the art of utilizing money become its masters, prioritizing self-growth and attracting wealth naturally.</p>
<p>Chen founded Everlight Chemical at 40, transforming it from a producer of basic dyes to a supplier of advanced specialty chemicals and pharmaceutical ingredients.  By 1995, the company&rsquo;s revenue reached over NT$2.4 billion.  A devout Christian and former director of the International Foundation Taiwan, Chen holds a unique perspective on money. He believes earning is easy, but spending wisely is not. He&rsquo;s witnessed countless wealthy individuals squander their fortunes and lose themselves, while others hoard their wealth, living like paupers and inflicting misery on those around them. He believes most people don&rsquo;t understand how to use money.</p>
<p>Deeply religious, Chen dedicates himself to God and spreading the Gospel.  Despite his success, he&rsquo;s traveled a difficult path.  He left school after elementary to work, studying diligently at night school for seven years, never missing a class except due to illness.  While others took on extra jobs, he prioritized education, graduating with a degree in international trade at 35. Who would have predicted his future as a billionaire?</p>
<p><strong>Who Paid the Highest Estate Tax?</strong></p>
<p>&ldquo;Who paid the highest estate tax in Taiwan&rsquo;s history?&rdquo;  I often ask this during lectures.  Few know the correct answer: Chen De-shen.</p>
<p>&ldquo;Chen De-shen? Who is he?&rdquo;  Audiences always murmur after the reveal.  It&rsquo;s a shame that someone who paid nearly NT$2 billion in estate tax remains relatively unknown.  How?  The only explanation is that Chen mastered earning and managing money, but not utilizing it.</p>
<p>Chen died in 1991, leaving an estate valued at NT$10 billion, resulting in a record NT$1.9 billion estate tax bill.  He lived a remarkably frugal life, using public transportation, sleeping on a cot, and living in his office to avoid buying a house. His sister recounted how he even refused to replace worn-out underwear.</p>
<p>Unmarried and childless, his vast fortune went to his siblings, sparking a highly publicized inheritance dispute. He exemplifies the saying, &ldquo;Those enslaved by wealth are pitiable even in their riches.&rdquo;</p>
<p>I often wonder, had he allocated a portion of his wealth to establish a &ldquo;De-shen College&rdquo; or &ldquo;De-shen Hospital,&rdquo; or donated even 1% (NT$100 million) to Tunghai University&rsquo;s business school, his name would be remembered for generations.  Such philanthropy would have benefited society and avoided family conflict.</p>
<p>Stanford University, a prestigious institution nestled between San Francisco and Silicon Valley, owes its existence to a generous donation from the Stanford family a century ago.  What a profound and lasting impact!  We marvel at the wisdom and foresight behind such giving.</p>
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>the Personal Investment Bible: Appendix</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1731056005975/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1731056005975/</guid><description>This appendix explores the power of compound interest and how to leverage it for financial success. It explains the concept of compounding, illustrating through examples and charts how it can lead to significant wealth growth over time. A formula for calculating future wealth is provided to help readers plan their financial goals, emphasizing the crucial roles of time and rate of return in compound interest investing.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[

<h2 class="relative group">Appendix 1: Understanding Compound Interest 
    <div id="appendix-1-understanding-compound-interest" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#appendix-1-understanding-compound-interest" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>Accumulating wealth isn&rsquo;t about cutting expenses,<br>
but about the compounding power of money making money.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Albert Einstein, considered one of history&rsquo;s greatest scientists, was once asked, &ldquo;What is the most powerful force in the world?&rdquo; His answer wasn&rsquo;t the force of colliding planets or the power of a nuclear explosion, but &ldquo;compound interest.&rdquo;</p>
<p>As the previous examples demonstrate, the factor that allows a yearly saving of 14,000 yuan to grow to over 100 million yuan in 40 years is &ldquo;compound interest.&rdquo; Since compound interest is the primary driver of accelerated wealth growth, understanding it is crucial for achieving financial success.</p>
<p>Imagine two job offers: one with a monthly salary of 100,000 yuan, and another starting at 1 yuan in the first month, doubling each subsequent month.  Assuming both jobs last two years (24 months), which would you choose?</p>
<p>At first glance, the first offer seems better.  100,000 yuan monthly yields 2.4 million yuan over 24 months. However, anyone understanding compound interest would choose the second job, which yields over 16.77 million yuan after 24 months! This is the effect of compounding. While this is an extreme example, such high growth rates are unlikely in reality.  Nevertheless, it clearly demonstrates the power of compound interest.</p>
<p>Most people have a basic understanding of compound interest.  Depositing money in a bank generates interest over time, a common understanding in modern society. Since Einstein considered compound interest the most powerful force, and it can help us become millionaires with modest investments, a deeper understanding of its workings is essential, especially for those interested in financial management.</p>
<p>Simply put, compound interest is &ldquo;interest on interest.&rdquo; We know bank deposits earn interest, calculated using compound interest. For instance, with a 10% interest rate, a 1,000 yuan deposit earns 100 yuan in interest in the first year, resulting in 1,100 yuan.  If left in the bank, the second year&rsquo;s interest is 110 yuan (on 1,100 yuan), totaling 1,210 yuan. The third year yields 121 yuan in interest, reaching 1,331 yuan.</p>
<p>Notice the increasing interest earned each year.  This is because the first year&rsquo;s interest earns interest in the second year, and so on, leading to an ever-increasing return.  This &ldquo;interest on interest&rdquo; phenomenon is compound interest.</p>
<p>The table below shows that after the 26th year, the annual interest earned surpasses the principal, and by the 40th year, the interest of 4,114 yuan is more than four times the initial 1,000 yuan principal.</p>
<p><em>Future Value of 1,000 Yuan at 10% Interest Rate (Compounded Annually)</em></p>
<table>
  <thead>
      <tr>
          <th>Year</th>
          <th>Beginning Value</th>
          <th>Ending Value</th>
          <th>Interest</th>
      </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
      <tr>
          <td>1</td>
          <td>1000</td>
          <td>1100</td>
          <td>100</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>2</td>
          <td>1100</td>
          <td>1210</td>
          <td>110</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>3</td>
          <td>1210</td>
          <td>1331</td>
          <td>121</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>&hellip;</td>
          <td>&hellip;</td>
          <td>&hellip;</td>
          <td>&hellip;</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>26</td>
          <td>10835</td>
          <td>11918</td>
          <td>1083</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>&hellip;</td>
          <td>&hellip;</td>
          <td>&hellip;</td>
          <td>&hellip;</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>39</td>
          <td>37404</td>
          <td>41145</td>
          <td>3740</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>40</td>
          <td>41145</td>
          <td>45259</td>
          <td>4114</td>
      </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>
<p>Compound interest&rsquo;s effect varies with different interest rates and durations.  These variations are presented in compound interest tables (refer to this appendix).  These tables, composed of interest rates, years, and future value factors (the growth multiplier calculated by the formula), might seem daunting with their numerous figures. However, understanding them is invaluable for investment and financial management.  Renowned American financial advisor Venita VanCaspel calls the compound interest table the &ldquo;eighth wonder of the world.&rdquo; If you don&rsquo;t have the opportunity to travel the world, studying this table can be just as rewarding.  Understanding the characteristics of compound interest is key to leveraging its power for wealth creation.</p>
<p>The compound interest table reveals that the values increase with time and interest rate.  However, this isn&rsquo;t the whole story.  Observing compound interest graphs derived from these tables reveals further insights. Figure 1-1 assumes a yearly deposit of 1 yuan at different interest rates, plotting asset growth over 10 years. Figure 1-2 uses the same assumptions but extends the time horizon to 40 years.</p>
<p>
  <figure>
    <img class="my-0 rounded-md" loading="lazy" src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jomonylw/jomonylw.github.io/refs/heads/main/content/posts/1731056005975/img-01-en.jpg" alt="image.png" />
    
  </figure>
</p>
<p>Figure 1-1: Future Value Growth of 1 Yuan Annuity at Different Interest Rates over 10 Years</p>
<p>
  <figure>
    <img class="my-0 rounded-md" loading="lazy" src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jomonylw/jomonylw.github.io/refs/heads/main/content/posts/1731056005975/img-02-en.jpg" alt="image.png" />
    
  </figure>
</p>
<p>Figure 1-2: Future Value Growth of 1 Yuan Annuity at Different Interest Rates over 40 Years</p>
<p>These graphs illustrate the growth of 1 yuan over time at various interest rates and durations. Comparing them reveals two key characteristics of compound interest:</p>
<ul>
<li>
<ol>
<li>As the duration (time) increases, the future value rises continuously, and the rate of increase accelerates. This is known as exponential growth.  Given sufficient time, the growth becomes dramatic, with the curve eventually approaching a straight upward line.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol start="2">
<li>Different interest rates result in significantly different growth curves.  Over decades, the disparity between high and low interest rate curves becomes immense.</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ul>
<p>In summary, the secret to accumulating significant wealth from small beginnings lies in leveraging the &ldquo;money making money&rdquo; power of compound interest.  Compounding has two key features: its effect is more pronounced over longer periods, and higher returns amplify its impact. Applying these principles to investing leads to two conclusions:</p>
<ul>
<li>
<ol>
<li>Invest in high-return assets like stocks and real estate. Higher returns maximize the effect of compounding, while low returns yield minimal benefits.  To fully harness the power of compound interest, capital must be invested in high-return assets.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol start="2">
<li>Hold investments long-term.  The longer the investment horizon, the more significant the compounding effect.  Short-term investments don&rsquo;t allow sufficient time for compounding to work its magic.  Therefore, long-term holdings in high-return assets are crucial for maximizing the benefits of compound interest.</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">Appendix 2: Blueprint for Financial Success 
    <div id="appendix-2-blueprint-for-financial-success" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#appendix-2-blueprint-for-financial-success" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>Everyone&rsquo;s age, personality, and applicable tax rates differ.  Therefore, each individual needs a tailored approach to wealth accumulation. I can&rsquo;t provide personalized financial planning advice based on your specific circumstances, nor can I encompass everyone&rsquo;s financial situation and plans with a few generic examples.</p>
<p>To help you design your own &ldquo;Blueprint for Financial Success,&rdquo; I&rsquo;ve combined the future value and annuity future value formulas from finance to create a universal &ldquo;Investment Wealth Formula.&rdquo;  This formula empowers readers to plan their lifelong financial strategies based on their unique circumstances and objectives.</p>
<p><math xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" display="block"><mtable displaystyle="true" columnalign="right center left" columnspacing="0 thickmathspace" rowspacing="3pt"><mtr><mtd><mtext>Future Wealth</mtext></mtd><mtd><mi></mi><mo>=</mo></mtd><mtd><mtext>Current Wealth</mtext><mo>Ã—</mo><msup><mrow><mo stretchy="false">(</mo><mn>1</mn><mo>+</mo><mi>R</mi><mo stretchy="false">)</mo></mrow><mi>n</mi></msup><mo>+</mo><mtext>Annual Savings</mtext><mo>Ã—</mo><mfrac><mrow><msup><mrow><mo stretchy="false">(</mo><mn>1</mn><mo>+</mo><mi>R</mi><mo stretchy="false">)</mo></mrow><mi>n</mi></msup><mo>âˆ’</mo><mn>1</mn></mrow><mi>R</mi></mfrac></mtd></mtr><mtr><mtd></mtd><mtd><mi></mi><mo>=</mo></mtd><mtd><mtext>Current Wealth</mtext><mo>Ã—</mo><mtext>Future Value Factor</mtext><mo>+</mo><mtext>Annual Savings</mtext><mo>Ã—</mo><mtext>Annuity Future Value Factor</mtext></mtd></mtr><mtr><mtd><mtext>Where:</mtext></mtd></mtr><mtr><mtd><mi>n</mi></mtd><mtd><mo>:</mo></mtd><mtd><mtext>Number of years</mtext></mtd></mtr><mtr><mtd><mi>R</mi></mtd><mtd><mo>:</mo></mtd><mtd><mtext>Average annual investment rate of return</mtext></mtd></mtr></mtable></math></p>
<p>The values for the complex calculations in the formula above (Future Value Factor and Annuity Future Value Factor) can be found in Appendix 1 of this book.</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Future Value Factor:</strong> The future value of 1 yuan today, after N years, at an interest rate (or rate of return) of R%.</li>
<li><strong>Annuity Future Value Factor:</strong> The future value of an annuity of 1 yuan deposited at the end of each year, after N years, at an interest rate (or rate of return) of R%.</li>
</ul>
<p>Using this formula, you can project your future wealth by inputting your current assets, average annual savings for investment, planned investment period, and expected annual rate of return. You can calculate the result or look it up in a table.</p>
<p>This formula simplifies the real-world situation, as investment returns are unlikely to remain constant each year, and annual savings might fluctuate.  However, using the &ldquo;average&rdquo; annual rate of return and &ldquo;average&rdquo; annual investment amount generally provides a reasonable approximation of future wealth.</p>
<p>The purpose of the &ldquo;Investment Wealth Formula&rdquo; isn&rsquo;t to predict future wealth precisely but to illustrate how investment builds wealth and how financial management leads to prosperity. It aims to bolster your confidence in financial planning, enabling you to focus on key principles, maintain perseverance, and steadily progress towards your financial goals throughout market fluctuations.</p>
<p>This isn&rsquo;t a foolproof formula for riches. Following this method may lead to becoming a millionaire, but success isn&rsquo;t guaranteed.  However, inaction guarantees zero chance of success. The most valuable aspect of this wealth-building concept is the message: &ldquo;Investment and financial management can lead to wealth.&rdquo; This knowledge fosters optimism and hope. Regardless of your current wealth, age, annual savings, or investment skills, with dedication, determination, and a willingness to learn, you can leverage investing to grow your wealth.</p>
<p>After understanding this formula, follow these steps for financial planning:</p>
<p><strong>I. Data Collection:</strong></p>
<ol>
<li>What is your current total asset value? (Include bank deposits, stocks, real estate, etc.)</li>
<li>How much do you anticipate saving annually for investment?</li>
<li>What is your expected average annual investment rate of return?</li>
<li>How many years do you plan to invest before reaching your financial goal?</li>
<li>What is your future wealth target?</li>
</ol>
<p><strong>II. Calculation and Analysis:</strong></p>
<ol>
<li>Use the five data points above with the &ldquo;Investment Wealth Formula&rdquo; to assess the feasibility of your wealth plan. If it&rsquo;s not feasible, how will you adjust? Will you increase savings? Improve investment skills to boost returns? Lower your wealth target? Or extend your time horizon? Adjust the variables and recalculate until you find a realistic and achievable plan.</li>
<li>Calculate your projected accumulated wealth based on your current assets, investment period, annual savings, and expected rate of return.</li>
<li>You can also use any four of the five variables (current wealth, target year, annual savings, rate of return, wealth target) to calculate the remaining variable. (Calculating the target year or rate of return using the other four variables requires a financial calculator or trial and error to find an approximate value.)</li>
</ol>
<p>While the &ldquo;Investment Wealth Formula&rdquo; involves a seemingly complex mathematical formula, its primary purpose is to explain the principles of wealth building, not to complicate financial management or confuse readers. If you don&rsquo;t have a calculator or prefer not to delve into the formula&rsquo;s calculations, feel free to disregard it.</p>
<p>Using the &ldquo;Investment Wealth Formula&rdquo; can help you plan your future finances and boost your confidence in financial management. However, it doesn&rsquo;t guarantee investment success.  Pre-planning is just the beginning; the key lies in mastering investment principles and consistent action. When starting your financial journey, clarify your financial situation, set realistic wealth goals, then use the &ldquo;Investment Wealth Formula&rdquo; to evaluate your investment strategy and timeline. Remember, the path to wealth is in your hands.</p>
<p><strong>Example:</strong>  Zhang San is 30 years old with 200,000 yuan in savings. After reading this book, he resolves to become a millionaire (meaning having 100 million yuan).  He plans to invest 100,000 yuan annually in stocks and real estate with an expected 20% annual return, aiming to reach his goal by age 50.  Let&rsquo;s use the &ldquo;Investment Wealth Formula&rdquo; to assess the feasibility.</p>
<p><math xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" display="block"><mtable displaystyle="true" columnalign="right center left" columnspacing="0 thickmathspace" rowspacing="3pt"><mtr><mtd><mtext>Future Wealth</mtext></mtd><mtd><mi></mi><mo>=</mo></mtd><mtd><mn>200,000</mn><mo>Ã—</mo><msup><mrow><mo stretchy="false">(</mo><mn>1</mn><mo>+</mo><mn>20</mn><mi mathvariant="normal">%</mi><mo stretchy="false">)</mo></mrow><mrow><mn>20</mn></mrow></msup><mo>+</mo><mn>100,000</mn><mo>Ã—</mo><mfrac><mrow><msup><mrow><mo stretchy="false">(</mo><mn>1</mn><mo>+</mo><mn>20</mn><mi mathvariant="normal">%</mi><mo stretchy="false">)</mo></mrow><mrow><mn>20</mn></mrow></msup><mo>âˆ’</mo><mn>1</mn></mrow><mrow><mn>20</mn><mi mathvariant="normal">%</mi></mrow></mfrac></mtd></mtr><mtr><mtd></mtd><mtd><mi></mi><mo>=</mo></mtd><mtd><mn>200,000</mn><mo>Ã—</mo><mn>38.338</mn><mo>+</mo><mn>100,000</mn><mo>Ã—</mo><mn>228.98</mn><mspace width="1em"></mspace><mtext>(Corrected Annuity Factor)</mtext></mtd></mtr><mtr><mtd></mtd><mtd><mi></mi><mo>=</mo></mtd><mtd><mn>30,435,600</mn><mspace width="1em"></mspace><mtext>(Corrected Calculation)</mtext></mtd></mtr></mtable></math></p>
<p>Based on the calculation, Zhang San&rsquo;s 200,000 yuan initial investment, along with 100,000 yuan annual investments over 20 years at a 20% average return, will yield approximately 26 million yuan, less than one-third of his 100 million yuan goal.  To become a millionaire, he can improve his return, increase his annual investment, or extend his time horizon.  A 20% return is already quite good and realistic, even for seasoned investors.  Increasing his returns further might be challenging.  Since he doesn&rsquo;t want to extend the timeline, he decides to increase his annual investment. Through frugality and a part-time job, he manages to save 200,000 yuan annually. Let&rsquo;s recalculate his future wealth after 20 years.</p>
<p><math xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" display="block"><mtable displaystyle="true" columnalign="right center left" columnspacing="0 thickmathspace" rowspacing="3pt"><mtr><mtd><mrow><mo>Future Wealth</mo></mrow></mtd><mtd><mi></mi><mo>=</mo></mtd><mtd><mn>200000</mn><mo>Ã—</mo><msup><mrow><mo stretchy="false">(</mo><mn>1</mn><mo>+</mo><mn>20</mn><mi mathvariant="normal">%</mi><mo stretchy="false">)</mo></mrow><mrow><mn>20</mn></mrow></msup><mo>+</mo><mn>200000</mn><mo>Ã—</mo><mfrac><msup><mrow><mo stretchy="false">(</mo><mn>1</mn><mo>+</mo><mn>20</mn><mi mathvariant="normal">%</mi><mo stretchy="false">)</mo></mrow><mrow><mn>20</mn></mrow></msup><mrow><mn>20</mn><mi mathvariant="normal">%</mi></mrow></mfrac><mo>âˆ’</mo><mn>1</mn></mtd></mtr><mtr><mtd></mtd><mtd><mi></mi><mo>=</mo></mtd><mtd><mn>200000</mn><mo>Ã—</mo><mn>38.338</mn><mo>+</mo><mn>200000</mn><mo>Ã—</mo><mn>186.96</mn></mtd></mtr><mtr><mtd></mtd><mtd><mi></mi><mo>=</mo></mtd><mtd><mn>45005600</mn></mtd></mtr></mtable></math></p>
<p>Even with doubled annual savings, his wealth after 20 years still falls short of half his goal.  With both his 20% return and 200,000 yuan annual investment maxed out, he has to extend his timeline. He decides to aim for 25 years.  Let&rsquo;s calculate his projected wealth then.</p>
<p><math xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" display="block"><mtable displaystyle="true" columnalign="right center left" columnspacing="0 thickmathspace" rowspacing="3pt"><mtr><mtd><mrow><mo>Future Wealth</mo></mrow></mtd><mtd><mi></mi><mo>=</mo></mtd><mtd><mn>200000</mn><mo>Ã—</mo><msup><mrow><mo stretchy="false">(</mo><mn>1</mn><mo>+</mo><mn>20</mn><mi mathvariant="normal">%</mi><mo stretchy="false">)</mo></mrow><mrow><mn>25</mn></mrow></msup><mo>+</mo><mn>200000</mn><mo>Ã—</mo><mfrac><msup><mrow><mo stretchy="false">(</mo><mn>1</mn><mo>+</mo><mn>20</mn><mi mathvariant="normal">%</mi><mo stretchy="false">)</mo></mrow><mrow><mn>25</mn></mrow></msup><mrow><mn>20</mn><mi mathvariant="normal">%</mi></mrow></mfrac><mo>âˆ’</mo><mn>1</mn></mtd></mtr><mtr><mtd></mtd><mtd><mi></mi><mo>=</mo></mtd><mtd><mn>200000</mn><mo>Ã—</mo><mn>95.396</mn><mo>+</mo><mn>200000</mn><mo>Ã—</mo><mn>471.98</mn></mtd></mtr><mtr><mtd></mtd><mtd><mi></mi><mo>=</mo></mtd><mtd><mn>113475200</mn></mtd></mtr></mtable></math></p>
<p>He finally achieves his goal of becoming a millionaire after 25 years.  Extending the timeline by just five years makes a significant difference. With a longer time horizon, his required annual investment could be even lower. This example validates the book&rsquo;s emphasis on &ldquo;youth being an asset in wealth building&rdquo; and &ldquo;the importance of long-term investing for realizing the power of compound interest.&rdquo;  Experiment with different variables to understand their impact.  <strong>You&rsquo;ll discover that the initial wealth and annual investment amount have a relatively small impact, while time and rate of return are the key drivers of wealth accumulation.</strong></p>
<p>Your circumstances might be better or worse than Zhang San&rsquo;s. Regardless, everyone has different starting points, but anyone can become a millionaire.  Calculate your own path to becoming a millionaire based on your current situation. Remember, with a modest initial investment, allocation to high-return assets like stocks and real estate, and long-term holding, becoming a millionaire is absolutely achievable.</p>
<p>Now, set your financial goal. Write down your target wealth, your desired timeline, and how you plan to use your wealth to achieve your broader life goals.</p>
<p><strong>Remember: &ldquo;Money is a means to an end, not the end itself.&rdquo;</strong></p>
<p>Accumulating more money isn&rsquo;t always better, and having more financial goals isn&rsquo;t necessarily advantageous.  Such an approach may prevent you from ever reaching your goals and trap you in a cycle of dissatisfaction and greed. You could become a slave to money and potentially harm future generations with excessive wealth, contributing nothing to yourself, your loved ones, or society.</p>
<p>Once you have a financial goal, use the &ldquo;Wealth Formula&rdquo; to calculate your path, including required annual savings and average rate of return. This will inform your investment strategy and timeline. More importantly, determine how you will utilize your wealth once you achieve your goal.  This concretizes your aspirations. You&rsquo;ll discover that by applying the principles in this book and remaining consistent, becoming a millionaire is within reach. A clear goal leads to a happier life, and a positive attitude contributes to success in all areas of life.</p>
]]></content:encoded></item></channel></rss>