<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Retirement on QQQ Investor</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/tags/retirement/</link><description>Recent content in Retirement on QQQ Investor</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jomonylw.github.io/en/tags/retirement/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>00500 The Balance Between Asset Appreciation and Spending: Spending Should Reflect Your Asset's Capacity</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1737905023775/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1737905023775/</guid><description>This episode mainly discusses the power of compound interest in long-term investing. For example, the final benefits of investing $10,000 at different ages vary greatly. It also addresses questions from students regarding whether retired individuals can use the 80/20 asset allocation strategy for collateralization and related issues.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<lite-youtube videoid="JGxThQ20wak" playlabel="JGxThQ20wak" params=""></lite-youtube>



<h2 class="relative group">I. Current Topic 
    <div id="i-current-topic" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-current-topic" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This episode primarily shares the power of compound interest in long-term investing and discusses whether the 80/20 asset allocation strategy for retirees can be used for collateralization. James uses specific examples and data analysis to emphasize the importance of compound interest in long-term investing and the key issues to consider when using the 80/20 asset allocation for collateralization. For example, while it&rsquo;s possible for retirees to use the 80/20 allocation for collateral, there are many restrictions. For safety, retirees should stick to the 433 allocation for collateralization.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">II. Briefing Content 
    <div id="ii-briefing-content" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii-briefing-content" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">1. Program Suspension Notice and Disclaimer 
    <div id="1-program-suspension-notice-and-disclaimer" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#1-program-suspension-notice-and-disclaimer" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Suspension Notice</strong>: Next Thursday (February 1, 2025) is the fourth day of the Chinese New Year. Considering that everyone may still be celebrating, there will be no program. The program will resume as usual on February 8, 2025.</li>
<li><strong>Disclaimer</strong>: All content shared on the CLEC channel is solely based on James&rsquo;s personal experience. James is not a professional investment advisor and does not provide professional tax advice. Investing involves extremely high risk, so please be cautious. It&rsquo;s important to note that the possibility of your assets being halved (i.e., a 50% drop) can happen at any time.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">2. Learning Materials and Viewing Recommendations 
    <div id="2-learning-materials-and-viewing-recommendations" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#2-learning-materials-and-viewing-recommendations" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Learning Materials</strong>: Newcomers are advised to watch <strong>video 00451</strong> first. We have also compiled a playlist of short videos. The subtitles for the &ldquo;<strong>One Hundred Million Yuan Investment Lecture</strong>&rdquo; series have been re-proofread, including English and various global language versions, making the translation more accurate.</li>
<li><strong>Viewing Recommendations</strong>: James advises everyone to watch the entire video, as the amount of information is large. Asking questions based on watching only parts of the video makes it difficult to get complete and comprehensive answers.</li>
<li><strong>About Groups</strong>: CLEC does not have any groups. The existing groups are organized by enthusiastic students, like the &ldquo;00662&rdquo; group. These groups mainly help new friends answer basic investment questions. However, it&rsquo;s important to note that these groups are not affiliated with CLEC, and James does not participate in any groups.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">3. Investment Strategies and Precautions 
    <div id="3-investment-strategies-and-precautions" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#3-investment-strategies-and-precautions" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Investment Target</strong>: CLEC focuses solely on investing in the Nasdaq 100 Index Fund. There are many instruments worldwide that allow direct investment in the Nasdaq 100 Index Fund, with relevant links provided in CLEC-related videos. For example, the ticker symbol for the Canadian 2x Leveraged Fund has changed. James will explain the specific changes in later videos.</li>
<li><strong>CLEC Video Quantity</strong>: Since 2018, CLEC has accumulated almost 1000 videos, covering content from investment basics to advanced levels.</li>
<li><strong>Investment Philosophy</strong>: Always maintain extreme optimism in investing and believe that the market will always go up.</li>
<li><strong>Prohibited Behaviors</strong>: We have a one-voice policy here. Activities unrelated to investing in the Nasdaq 100 Index Fund are not allowed. For example, recommending insurance, real estate, etc., is prohibited.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">4. Supplementary Remarks on Chen Feng&rsquo;s Sharing 
    <div id="4-supplementary-remarks-on-chen-fengs-sharing" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#4-supplementary-remarks-on-chen-fengs-sharing" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>About Chen Feng</strong>: Chen Feng is a senior and enthusiastic student who has voluntarily started a group and manages it with Nai Xin and others.</li>
<li><strong>Chen Feng&rsquo;s Content</strong>: Recently, Chen Feng shared a three-hour condensed course on YouTube. James provided supplementary remarks on some of the issues:
<ul>
<li><strong>About Long-Term Annualized Returns</strong>: The long-term annualized returns mentioned by Chen Feng are the actual returns after deducting inflation.</li>
<li><strong>About Excel Demonstrations</strong>: In his sharing, Chen Feng used Excel spreadsheets to demonstrate the returns of different asset ratios. Students can check his Excel spreadsheets for more accurate data results. Chen Feng may also add supplements and corrections in the notes of his YouTube video.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Supplementary Explanation</strong>: Chen Feng&rsquo;s sharing was for his group&rsquo;s internal use. While these senior students have understood 99% of James&rsquo;s content, there may still be some non-mainstream or less precise points. Therefore, James made a few supplementary explanations regarding his sharing.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">5. Collateralized Borrowing and Spending Adjustment Strategies 
    <div id="5-collateralized-borrowing-and-spending-adjustment-strategies" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#5-collateralized-borrowing-and-spending-adjustment-strategies" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Usable Funds Ratio for Collateralized Borrowing</strong>: The annual available funds for collateralized borrowing are 2% of retirement reserves (assuming your retirement reserves are 50 times your annual expenses). If your retirement reserves are NT$30 million, the annual available funds are NT$600,000 (NT$30 million * 2% = NT$600,000). This NT$600,000 is fixed. Even if the NT$30 million becomes NT$20 million due to market fluctuations, you can still use NT$600,000. You don&rsquo;t have to worry about a decrease in available funds because of market drop.</li>
<li><strong>Spending Strategy During Market Downturns</strong>: You do not need to reduce spending during a market downturn. You can increase spending during a market upswing. In other words, our annual spending will only increase, not decrease.</li>
<li><strong>Spending Adjustment Strategies</strong>:
<ul>
<li><strong>Upswing Scenario</strong>: For example, with a retirement reserve of NT$30 million, after 5 years, assets increase from NT$30 million to NT$50 million, and the net assets (after deducting debt, including 5 years of expenses, and annual interest, totaling NT$3.22 million) are NT$46.78 million (NT$50 million - NT$3.22 million = NT$46.78 million). At this point, annual available funds can be adjusted to NT$930,000 (NT$46.78 million * 2% = NT$930,000). However, this NT$930,000 includes interest expenses. Assuming the previous loan of NT$3.22 million and a 3% interest rate, the annual interest expense is about NT$100,000, and the actual available funds are NT$830,000 (NT$930,000 - NT$100,000 = NT$830,000).</li>
<li><strong>Downturn Scenario</strong>: There is no need to reduce spending during a market downturn. You can still maintain the peak spending level (e.g., if the peak spending was NT$900,000, you can still maintain NT$900,000 per year even if assets drop to NT$30 million). This allocation strategy is based on a model that assumes a 10-year decline from the peak, which can be fully sustained even under the extreme scenario of a 10-year decline.</li>
<li><strong>Core Principle for Spending Adjustments</strong>: Only increase spending, not decrease it, and it&rsquo;s recommended to adjust it every 5 years to avoid frequent adjustments.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">6. Retirement Asset Allocation and Collateralization Strategies 
    <div id="6-retirement-asset-allocation-and-collateralization-strategies" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#6-retirement-asset-allocation-and-collateralization-strategies" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Retirees who do not utilize collateralization can use an 80/20 asset allocation, i.e., 80% invested in QQQ and 20% in cash.</strong></li>
<li><strong>An 80/20 asset allocation, without collateralization, allows for simple rebalancing yearly without risk of bankruptcy.</strong></li>
<li><strong>If you must utilize the 80/20 asset allocation for collateralization, please be aware:</strong>
<ul>
<li><strong>Absolutely do not use cash to rebalance in the market, cash must only increase, not decrease.</strong></li>
<li><strong>Market downturns may last up to 10 years. If you borrow 2% annually, you will borrow more than 20% in 10 years. If you then invest cash, your total assets may be less than 20%. Therefore, using an 80/20 asset allocation for collateralization is high risk.</strong></li>
<li><strong>A safer approach is still a 433 allocation.</strong></li>
<li><strong>If you must use the 80/20 allocation for collateralization, rebalancing intelligently only during upswing years, that is, can only transfer cash from the prototype fund (QQQ), it is not allowed to transfer cash into QQQ during downswing years, can transfer cash into QQQ during upswing years.</strong></li>
<li><strong>This approach is complex and requires simulation to ensure feasibility.</strong></li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">7. Core Principles for Asset Allocation 
    <div id="7-core-principles-for-asset-allocation" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#7-core-principles-for-asset-allocation" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Whenever making an asset allocation or adjustment, assume that it&rsquo;s the market&rsquo;s highest point.</strong></li>
<li><strong>Spending does not need to be reduced during a 10-year decline, as the allocation strategy has been verified through simulations as feasible.</strong></li>
<li>When assets have risen to a new high (e.g., from NT$30 million to NT$45 million), you can reset the spending amount. Even if the market declines again afterwards, you don&rsquo;t need to reduce spending because it is already close to the bottom, and risk is reduced.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">8. Yuanta Securities Finance Information 
    <div id="8-yuanta-securities-finance-information" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#8-yuanta-securities-finance-information" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Yuanta Securities Finance is an institution that specializes in lending money out. Its interest rates are low (below 3%), and it doesn&rsquo;t experience liquidity shortages like other brokerages or institutions. Its website operation and fund transfers are also convenient.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">9. Risks of Real Estate Investment 
    <div id="9-risks-of-real-estate-investment" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#9-risks-of-real-estate-investment" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Real estate is not a good asset and carries extremely high risks.</strong></li>
<li>Natural disasters like fires and earthquakes can cause the value of real estate to drop to zero. In some countries or regions, you still have to repay the loan even if the house is destroyed.</li>
<li>Real estate involves putting all your eggs in one basket, and the risk is too concentrated. Moreover, real estate depreciates and loses value.</li>
<li><strong>Investments should be diversified. Avoid putting all your assets into real estate.</strong></li>
<li><strong>You should only buy a house if you could afford to buy another one if the first one was destroyed.</strong></li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">10. Information on German Stock Pledge 
    <div id="10-information-on-german-stock-pledge" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#10-information-on-german-stock-pledge" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>See page 30 of the handout. This is information provided by students on German stock pledges. James did not provide a detailed interpretation.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">11. Tax Issues of American Retirement Accounts (Traditional IRA &amp; Roth IRA) 
    <div id="11-tax-issues-of-american-retirement-accounts-traditional-ira--roth-ira" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#11-tax-issues-of-american-retirement-accounts-traditional-ira--roth-ira" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>When the Traditional IRA becomes an inheritance, the heir must withdraw all the funds within 10 years. The principal and appreciation are both taxed, and there are almost no inheritance tax exemptions.</strong></li>
<li><strong>When the Roth IRA becomes an inheritance, the heir has 10 years to withdraw the funds, and neither the principal nor the appreciation is taxed.</strong></li>
<li><strong>Converting Traditional IRA to Roth IRA as soon as possible can effectively reduce the tax burden when RMD (Required Minimum Distribution) occurs.</strong></li>
<li>Many financial planners or accountants do not advise converting all your Traditional IRA to Roth IRA at once because they want to minimize your current year&rsquo;s taxes, rather than focusing on long-term tax planning.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">12. The Value of Life and the Meaning of Wealth 
    <div id="12-the-value-of-life-and-the-meaning-of-wealth" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#12-the-value-of-life-and-the-meaning-of-wealth" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>The value of life lies in learning, thinking, serving others, and growing, not just working and making money.</li>
<li>Money is a tool to help us achieve our life&rsquo;s purpose, enhancing our spiritual energy and fulfilling our dreams.</li>
<li><strong>The ideal state is to have 10 billion dollars in assets but owe the bank 10.1 billion dollars.</strong></li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">III. Q&amp;A Session 
    <div id="iii-qa-session" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii-qa-session" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Angel 
    <div id="angel" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#angel" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing</strong>: Angel is a young man currently studying in the United States. He turns 21 the next day. His parents are very supportive and hardworking, allowing Angel to study in the U.S. without worry. Angel&rsquo;s parents hope he can live a wealthy life, so they advised him to learn investment and financial management with James and promised to give him funds to invest.</li>
<li><strong>Question 1</strong>: If James were 21 again, with his current knowledge and parental support, how would he invest?
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response</strong>: If James were 21 again with his current knowledge and parental support, he would use a 442 allocation to buy in all at once. Additionally, the teacher shared two investment mistakes he made when he was young: investing in real estate, which he bought for 8 million and sold for only 6 million after 10 years, resulting in a significant loss; and selling company stock to buy a car. These two poor decisions resulted in his assets being reduced by half. The teacher used his own example to emphasize: <strong>$100,000 for a young person, with time, compounded at 14% annually, will be $25 million in 60 years; $10,000 for a young person is $2.6 million in the future, so young people should learn to save and invest first and then learn to spend money when the time is right.</strong></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question 2</strong>: Besides human nature, why is it not advisable for someone of my age to put all my money into QQQ, but rather 433 or 442?
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response</strong>: Human nature is the most important factor that must be considered in investment. You cannot exclude the factor of &ldquo;human nature&rdquo;. If you don&rsquo;t consider human nature, then don&rsquo;t invest. For example, investors often overestimate their risk tolerance. Investment should avoid getting yourself into a state of extreme panic. Allocating all your assets to QQQ or half in QQQ and half in cash overestimates your risk tolerance. Although the market will eventually go up in the long term, your assets may fall to extremely low values during a market downswing, for example: from 100 to 80, 70, 60, then finally falling down to 5, 1. During this process, you might have already gone bankrupt and exited, even if you survive until market rise, it no longer has anything to do with you. It’s like playing Russian roulette: a revolver with 6 chambers, and 1 bullet. If the person firing doesn’t die, they will get 10 million; if they do die, they die. You should not participate because of the high reward. You could die. So young people&rsquo;s beta should not exceed 1.2.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Lisa 
    <div id="lisa" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#lisa" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing 1</strong>: Has retired and currently uses a power account as a reserve for daily living. The account balance is usually 0. Money is only used when a large expense happens or an emergency occurs. This practice brings her peace of mind. She doesn&rsquo;t need to keep a lot of cash in her daily account so that she could effectively use cash for investment purposes.</li>
<li><strong>Question 1</strong>: After retiring, I do not want to use leveraged funds (like QLD), but I am worried about a stock market crash. Is it feasible to use the 80/20 (80% in QQQ and 20% in cash) asset allocation strategy?
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response</strong>: Yes, it is feasible. An 80/20 asset allocation, if you don&rsquo;t do collateralization, can do simple rebalancing yearly. Because she is retired, and the funds in her collateralization account have not been used, which is equivalent to her not using collateralization, she can use the 80/20 asset allocation strategy under that circumstance.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Sharing 2</strong>: Has started Roth IRA conversion and plans to complete all the conversion within the next few years when the tax rate is lower.</li>
<li><strong>Question 2</strong>: Some people suggested using up the 32% tax rate, but I cannot mentally accept it, as it may mean paying higher taxes. Is it okay to just use up the 24% tax rate and deal with the rest during RMD time?
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response</strong>: You can complete all the conversions before the RMD age, as long as you finish before RMD, as money cannot be transferred into a Roth IRA after RMD age. Money can only be transferred into a brokerage account, which is not beneficial to inheritance. It is recommended to transfer the funds from the retirement account to a Roth IRA as much as possible, as the Roth IRA&rsquo;s heir does not need to pay taxes within 10 years, while the Traditional IRA&rsquo;s heir needs to pay taxes. Converting early can avoid higher taxes in the future. If you still do the conversion when the market drops, it means your conversion decision is correct. Although you may have to pay as high as 30% tax now during conversion, you can avoid higher taxes in the future in the long run (because your assets will grow significantly over time, so you will have to pay more taxes later).</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">YJ 
    <div id="yj" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#yj" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing 1</strong>: YJ would first like to thank James and the &ldquo;00662&rdquo; group, especially for Chen Feng&rsquo;s sharing and James&rsquo;s supplementation, which make everyone&rsquo;s investment concepts clearer.</li>
<li><strong>Sharing 2</strong>: The Chinese concept of &ldquo;having land is having wealth&rdquo; needs to be updated. In the current era, this &ldquo;land&rdquo; should not be real estate but rather &ldquo;stocks&rdquo;. The old concept of &ldquo;having land is having wealth&rdquo; refers to farmland that can be cultivated and has output, which is similar concept to current day investing in stocks.</li>
<li><strong>Suggestion</strong>: There are no more lectures on the 100 Million Investment topic this year. The 9 situations in the 00005 topic have been simplified into 2 situations. Can there be a &ldquo;00006&rdquo; topic, specifically on the &ldquo;collateralization&rdquo; part, with a simpler presentation?
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response</strong>: &ldquo;Having land is having wealth&rdquo; did not refer to houses in the past, as houses were not valuable in those eras and this term referred to farmlands. Today&rsquo;s &ldquo;having land is having wealth&rdquo; should be changed to &ldquo;having stocks is having wealth&rdquo;, stocks are the true assets. Regarding your suggestion of topic 00006, James believes the existing sharing is already simplified enough. Users using collateralization should use the 433 allocation and make &ldquo;smart rebalancing&rdquo; using 2% of their assets yearly, and there is no need for a more complicated topical presentation.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question 1</strong>: Previously, I sent a message on YouTube mentioning the video 00303 in March 2022, and you suggested to not use TQ (TQQQ) back then. However, two months ago (around November), you replied that a 6TQQ+2U+2Cash strategy can be used with a 6:2:2 allocation. Does this strategy and comparison with the 442 strategy feasible?
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response</strong>: TQQ can be used. The suggestion in previous videos was based on the understanding at the time, so single-asset investment in TQQ was not recommended. However, now, if you have an asset allocation (like 6:2:2, which is 60% in TQQ, 20% in U, and 20% in Cash) and do &ldquo;smart rebalancing&rdquo;, this strategy is viable. Investment strategies and concepts are constantly evolving and improving. Ideas considered impossible in the past may now be proven to be feasible.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Bill 
    <div id="bill" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#bill" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Question</strong>: I previously learned about BOXX as an investment target that is not correlated to the stock market. However, I learned that it&rsquo;s related to blockchain, so there are concerns about its safety, and whether its risk is too high?
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response</strong>: BOXX&rsquo;s operating mechanism is similar to 00864B. As long as its return is trending similarly to the US Federal Funds Rate, its risk is controllable. You should pay serious attention when the return is much higher or lower than the US Federal Funds Rate, as it may indicate some irregular financial operations. BOXX&rsquo;s primary function is to reasonably avoid investment income tax, and it can be used as a short-term investment target.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Henry 
    <div id="henry" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#henry" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Question</strong>: Henry runs his own business and used to have a company 401K. He has stopped it now, and he is not sure whether he should continue contributing into it or put the money designated for company contributions into his investment account.
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response</strong>: The main purpose of a 401K is to save on taxes. If you can do a Roth Solo 401k, you should prioritize it. You can consult your tax consultant or search the web and consult ChatGPT to confirm if you can do a Roth Solo 401k.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Yuqiao 
    <div id="yuqiao" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#yuqiao" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Question</strong>: I am retired and have benefited from this investment method. I want to recommend this investment method to my younger sister in China (who is 50 years old, runs a small business, has a tight budget, and has almost no knowledge of investment). Should I give her investment advice?</li>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response</strong>: Yes, you should. You can be her benefactor. However, she may not accept advice directly. Furthermore, opening an account and the follow-up operations are complex. So, if you really want to help her, you can open an account for her first and invest a small amount of money (such as $1,000 USD for about ¥7,000 to ¥8,000 RMB), tell her that if there are losses, you will bear it, if there are profits, it&rsquo;s hers. You can also co-invest with her proportionally, for example, if she invests ¥100, you can invest ¥100 for her. Once she sees a return, she will then invest automatically.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">IAM 
    <div id="iam" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iam" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing 1</strong>: IAM has recently met a doctor in his 70s. When he was young in his 30s, he trusted brokers and made careless investments. After several failed investments, he not only had real estate and stocks but was also in debt at 40 years old. He had to work to repay his debts even in his 70s. IAM is very grateful he found CLEC in 2022 and avoided going down the same path as the doctor.</li>
<li><strong>Question 1</strong>: James often says &ldquo;slow is fast,&rdquo; and investment should not be rushed. However, everyone&rsquo;s understanding of &ldquo;fast&rdquo; and &ldquo;slow&rdquo; is different. Can you please explain how to measure &ldquo;fast&rdquo; and &ldquo;slow&rdquo; in investing and how to view the concept of &ldquo;40 years is too long&rdquo;?
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response</strong>: Everything has its own rules and timings, like pregnancy and childbirth, which takes ten months and cannot be shortened. The same applies to investing. Wealth growth takes time. You cannot expect to harvest tomorrow what you planted today. It takes 10 years of investment to feel wealthy, 20 years to retire, 30 years to be prosperous, and 40 years to become rich. This requires time, one cannot be hasty. Warren Buffett did not become the world&rsquo;s richest man at 30 or 40, but after 55 years old. Investing requires understanding the essence and rules of time. Do not be impatient. Every thing operates following its rules and timings. It&rsquo;s a rule of nature and cannot be rushed.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question 2</strong>: Why do people haggle over small amounts of money, but at the same time act recklessly like gamblers when it comes to investing?
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response</strong>: This all stems from humanity&rsquo;s &ldquo;loss aversion&rdquo; mentality. People do not like to lose, so they haggle over prices when shopping, but they tend to focus only on the gains and ignore the risks when investing. During investment, people often forget past losses and only think about making more money in the future. This is the gambler&rsquo;s mentality. When shopping, people compare prices since they can lose less and, by nature, they will haggle. In investing, people think that the more they invest, the more they will earn; while ignoring the possibility of losses, hence they will not haggle. It&rsquo;s like if you go to buy a cake, and the owner says the cake is 100, you might haggle and say can it be 90? But if the owner says you buy my cake and tomorrow I&rsquo;ll return 300, you won&rsquo;t haggle anymore, you&rsquo;d think the more expensive, the better.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Mike 
    <div id="mike" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#mike" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing 1</strong>: Shared a story about a CNBC interview with Buffett and Bill Gates: If Buffett and Bill Gates went to McDonald&rsquo;s and they see 1 cent on the ground, what would they do? Buffett would pick it up without hesitation and check if there are any other coins around; and Bill Gates would also pick up that cent. This story illustrates the principles of &ldquo;every little bit counts&rdquo; and &ldquo;compound interest.&rdquo; Even the wealthy do not overlook the importance of &ldquo;saving&rdquo; because when Mike was on a business trip to Microsoft in 1992, Microsoft was already a listed company, and Bill Gates was already very wealthy at that time. One of the employees criticized Bill Gates for using coupons when shopping for groceries. Later, one time, Bill Gates was looking for his coupon when checking out. The person behind him said, don&rsquo;t worry, I will pay, you earn more than this in one minute. However, Bill Gates did not ignore the person behind him, he continued to search for his coupon.</li>
<li><strong>Sharing 2</strong>: Opinions regarding Deep Seek: Recently, AI technology is developing rapidly, with various new technologies and applications emerging, including Deep Seek, which will have a significant impact on QQQ&rsquo;s future. Currently, American technology giants seem to have a &ldquo;big brother&rdquo; mentality, believing that they can win the AI race as long as they invest enough resources. However, historical experience shows that technological leadership does not necessarily win the market, the business model is also important.</li>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response</strong>:</li>
<li>Deep Seek, like many other AI technologies, is still in the early stages, and there will be many uncertainties in the future. But what is certain is that AI will have a profound impact on human society and bring huge opportunities for investors.</li>
<li>Regarding the competition between the US and China in the field of AI, it is still difficult to judge who will ultimately win. The US has advantages in technology and funds, but China also has its own advantages, such as large amounts of data and government support.</li>
<li>AI is not only large language models (LLM), there are many other applications, for example: Tesla&rsquo;s autonomous driving. Tesla&rsquo;s autonomous driving model is already very mature, it can automatically drive out from the parking lot and the driving experience is very smooth, just like a professional driver is driving for you.</li>
<li>AI will not completely replace human jobs but increase our work efficiency. For example, even for translators, you can use AI to improve the efficiency and quality of translation. Therefore, humans need to learn how to utilize AI, not reject it.</li>
<li>Currently, the biggest problem is that many large companies want to introduce AI, but they do not have a clear idea, they do not know whether it needs to be from top down or from bottom-up. James thinks it needs to be from bottom-up, the employees should use them first, so they are accustomed before moving up. But this requires time and because everyone is changing the thinking process of using AI.</li>
<li>AI will cause QQQ&rsquo;s annual returns to be much higher than 14%, or even 20% or 30%. James is very optimistic about this.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Eric 
    <div id="eric" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#eric" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing</strong>: Based in Canada, 35 years old, plans to sell his house and invest the proceeds from the sale. Both he and his wife are currently working.</li>
<li><strong>Question 1</strong>: A plan to invest 20% in cash, 40% in QLD, 40% in QQ for long term investment and do smart rebalancing, is this investment plan correct?
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response</strong>: The plan is correct. Young people who are still working can use a 442 asset allocation, which is 40% in QQQ, 40% in QLD, and 20% in cash, and then do smart rebalancing.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question 2</strong>: Canada has high taxes, and capital gains tax is heavy. What are your suggestions for long-term planning?
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response</strong>: People&rsquo;s destiny is controlled by three factors: the first is fate (DNA); the second is destiny (place of birth); and the third is luck. The place of birth determines one&rsquo;s destiny. Canada, Europe, and Australia are not as good as the US. If financially possible, consider immigrating to the US, not just for yourself but also for your descendants.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Hao Qing 
    <div id="hao-qing" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#hao-qing" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing 1</strong>:
<ul>
<li><strong>Event 1</strong>: Shared two experiences of encountering potential &ldquo;scams&rdquo;. One time was meeting someone on a highway who claimed to be from Dubai, needing help. This person was dressed neatly, drove a BMW, and claimed to have run out of gas and had no money or was robbed. This person wore gold and asked Hao Qing for help, claiming that he could give his gold to Hao Qing. Hao Qing gave him 40 yuan, but he wanted more. Hao Qing felt that something was wrong, and so did not give any more. The second time, he encountered the same person on the road again, so he called the police.</li>
<li><strong>Event 2</strong>: A colleague&rsquo;s relative, an 80-year-old, was scammed for 600,000 yuan. This old person did not believe what nearby people said about it being a scam, and believed that since he raised his children for so many years, it was not unfilial to ask them for money to invest and everyone was stopping him. When going to the bank, the bank employees also told him that it was a scam. The police also came to give him risk warnings that the money could not be transferred, but this old person still did not believe it and was scammed for 600,000 yuan.</li>
<li><strong>Personal Views</strong>: Hao Qing thinks that he is a kind-hearted person. When he sees someone in trouble, he will help to the best of his ability. However, he will be more careful when it comes to money. Also, there are now many scams and the success rate for solving them is extremely low. He is not sure if it&rsquo;s the government&rsquo;s problem or individual&rsquo;s problem.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Sharing 2</strong>: While discussing &ldquo;US-China trade&rdquo; with colleagues, his colleagues think that China may devalue the renminbi to deal with the US tariffs. He does not agree with this point of view but does not know how to explain it.</li>
<li><strong>Questions</strong>: How should we view the three problems of &ldquo;scams&rdquo;, &ldquo;Taiwan policy&rdquo;, and “RMB devaluation”?
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response</strong>:
<ul>
<li><strong>About Scams:</strong> The US does not care because the US thinks that if you are scammed, it means you are stupid. Furthermore, the person that Hao Qing encountered is technically not breaking a legal law, even if you report, it is useless. All the police can do is to chase him away. Why are there scams? It&rsquo;s because of &ldquo;poverty&rdquo;. When it&rsquo;s difficult to earn money through normal ways, &ldquo;scamming&rdquo; becomes a way to get rich quickly. So, you still need to start from the systems, and education aspect.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>About Taiwan policies</strong>: The US has completely free capitalism where the market determines prices. When prices increase, wages increase, which will then increase interest rates and suppress inflation, ultimately creating a positive economic cycle. Taiwan&rsquo;s policies, to a certain degree, hinders this positive economic cycle.</li>
<li><strong>Regarding the RMB devaluation expectations</strong>: This problem is complex and interlinked. It cannot be simply solved via devaluation.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Martin 
    <div id="martin" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#martin" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing</strong>: Previously talked with James about the DPC open-source model, and he is also involved in the implementation of his company&rsquo;s AI project. Therefore, he would like to share and communicate with everyone.</li>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response</strong>: Okay, you can come and share it with us next time.</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">IV. Key Insights 
    <div id="iv-key-insights" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv-key-insights" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>When investing, you need to see results. You want to see results like Buffett&rsquo;s. Of course, everyone&rsquo;s level is different. When you feel you are living a prosperous life, you will also need 40 years. You cannot be hasty.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>This point explains the importance of &ldquo;time&rdquo; and the power of &ldquo;compound interest&rdquo; in long-term investing.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The value of life lies in learning, thinking, serving others, and growing, not just working and making money.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>This point emphasizes that the meaning of life lies in continuous learning, growth, and serving society, not just the pursuit of material wealth.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>You also need an appropriate amount of time to grow wealth to a certain extent. Therefore, you need to recognize that time exists first.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>This emphasizes that wealth accumulation requires time and patience, and one should not take any shortcuts.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>What do you do when everything is destroyed? You need a way out.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>Whether you&rsquo;re investing or doing anything else, you have to consider if this thing fails, and whether you have a way out. Or whether you can bear the losses caused by that failure.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Today if you buy a Tesla car but you&rsquo;re afraid of it getting scratched, you&rsquo;re afraid of washing it. After washing it, you&rsquo;re afraid to drive it. Every time you drive it out, you&rsquo;re afraid of people wanting to borrow it, or when your daughter wants to borrow it, you&rsquo;d always say no and no. You&rsquo;re a slave to wealth. It&rsquo;s okay to drive. I have insurance. If it is crashed I can buy a new one. This is wealth. Therefore, don&rsquo;t be a slave to your assets, never be.  It&rsquo;s better not to buy it, instead of buying it and then using up your mental energy over it. We should not spend any mental energy on material things. This is very important. This is the key to happiness.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>We should not be slaves to &ldquo;wealth,&rdquo; and should not be controlled by &ldquo;material things.&rdquo; If something affects your mood, do not buy it because you cannot afford it.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>People&rsquo;s destiny is controlled by three factors: The first is fate (DNA); the second is destiny (place of birth); and the third is luck.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>The place of birth determines destiny. If you are born in the United States, you have the American destiny; if you are born in Taiwan, you have the Taiwan destiny; if you are born in Australia, you have the Australian destiny.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>I am still going to tell everyone that we are going to be very wealthy, so when you want to immigrate you have to think twice. If it&rsquo;s me, I&rsquo;d rather spend 800,000 USD to immigrate to the US instead of using less money to immigrate to Canada, Europe, or the NSW. Because the destinies are different. Look at the world&rsquo;s top ten companies, and nine are from the US. Only one is TSMC from China, but TSMC is also cultivated in the US. To say it bluntly, all the world&rsquo;s top ten companies were founded by Americans, this is fate.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>When considering immigration, one should think not only for themselves but also the fate of future generations.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>An 80/20 allocation without collateralization can do simple rebalancing yearly without risk of bankruptcy.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>Retirees that do not do collateralization may utilize an 80/20 asset allocation where 80% is invested in QQQ and 20% is kept in cash, and can do simple rebalancing without risk of bankruptcy.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The US does not care about scams, they don&rsquo;t even care about the 0-dollar purchase scams, so why would they care about scams? Therefore, there is a cost accounting issue. If a country wants to be strong, it needs strong cost accounting. What do you want? Right and wrong is about competing, and everyone needs to know that prosperity is a key, and poverty is a disease. Being poor for an emerging country is a disease, if one is poor it&rsquo;s a disease.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>The United States is strong due to its sound system and market economy.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Always maintain extreme optimism in investing and believe that the market will always go up.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>Maintain an optimistic attitude throughout the investment process.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>AI may not necessarily solely rely on computing power. It can also rely on the human brain.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>This point explains that in the development of AI, in addition to computing power, the human brain can also play an important role.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">V. Summary 
    <div id="v-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#v-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This episode mainly focused on discussions surrounding compound interest, asset allocation, and various social phenomena. James emphasized the power of &ldquo;compound interest&rdquo; and the importance of &ldquo;time&rdquo; in long-term investing. He also provided detailed answers and specific operational suggestions regarding asset allocation strategies for retirees, particularly addressing the question of whether an 80/20 allocation is suitable for collateralization. Furthermore, he incorporated current events to share his perspectives on social phenomena such as US-China trade, AI development, and scams, pointing out that &ldquo;wealth&rdquo; is a key factor in a nation&rsquo;s strength. Overall, this episode was packed with information, offering specific guidance on investment strategies along with profound reflections on life, wealth, and social issues, making it worthy of repeated study.</p>

  



<div
  
    class="flex px-4 py-3 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900"
  >

  <span
    
      class="text-primary-400 ltr:pr-3 rtl:pl-3 flex items-center"
    >

    

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M506.3 417l-213.3-364c-16.33-28-57.54-28-73.98 0l-213.2 364C-10.59 444.9 9.849 480 42.74 480h426.6C502.1 480 522.6 445 506.3 417zM232 168c0-13.25 10.75-24 24-24S280 154.8 280 168v128c0 13.25-10.75 24-23.1 24S232 309.3 232 296V168zM256 416c-17.36 0-31.44-14.08-31.44-31.44c0-17.36 14.07-31.44 31.44-31.44s31.44 14.08 31.44 31.44C287.4 401.9 273.4 416 256 416z"/></svg>

  </span>


  </span>

  <span
    
      class="dark:text-neutral-300"
    >Disclaimer: This article is solely for personal study notes and does not constitute any investment advice.</span>
</div>

]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>00496 Global Markets and the Tech Wave: How to Seize Opportunities for Wealth Growth Amidst Volatility. The Philosophy of Financial Freedom: From Personalized Investing to Exploring Life's Values</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1735482278058/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1735482278058/</guid><description>At the end of 2024, with market fluctuations, Teacher James shared his insights on the current economic situation, financial markets, and investment strategies. In addition, several students asked questions online, covering asset allocation, business operations, health and wellness, tax planning, stock leveraging, and other areas.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Part One
<lite-youtube videoid="9F1rAWjCGX8" playlabel="9F1rAWjCGX8" params=""></lite-youtube>
</p>
<p>Part Two
<lite-youtube videoid="oPb4m81Nv24" playlabel="oPb4m81Nv24" params=""></lite-youtube>
</p>


<h2 class="relative group">I. Main Topic of the Session 
    <div id="i-main-topic-of-the-session" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-main-topic-of-the-session" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>Investment mindset and strategy adjustments amidst year-end market volatility, along with comprehensive reflections on personal life and financial health.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">II. Presentation Content 
    <div id="ii-presentation-content" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii-presentation-content" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Market Volatility and Investment Mindset 
    <div id="market-volatility-and-investment-mindset" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#market-volatility-and-investment-mindset" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>The only constant in the market is volatility. Investors should ignore market fluctuations, international situations, market analysis, financial reports, and economic situations, and focus on long-term investment.</li>
<li>Disclaimer: The content of the COC investment and financial management channel is for educational purposes only and does not constitute investment advice. Investment involves high risks, and proper asset allocation is necessary.</li>
<li>Newcomers should watch the YouTube episode 00451 &ldquo;Investment Lecture Worth 100 Million&rdquo; and also find related content on Bilibili and podcasts.</li>
<li>Investing requires independent thinking. Do not blindly follow advice or join any groups to avoid being deceived.</li>
<li>The Nasdaq 100 index fund is recommended as the only focused fund, with others being supplementary.</li>
<li>The handout includes information on Nasdaq 100 index funds worldwide, including leveraged funds, and information on retirement accounts in various regions, with content continuously updated.</li>
<li>The &ldquo;Investment Lecture Worth 100 Million&rdquo; video is the most important. Investors should always be extremely optimistic; the market will eventually rise and reach new highs.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">UK and European Financial Information 
    <div id="uk-and-european-financial-information" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#uk-and-european-financial-information" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Showcasing information provided by a UK friend regarding UK investments, loans, retirement accounts, ETFs, and insurance companies, particularly information on 2x leveraged funds on the PEA website.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">US-China Trade War and Globalization 
    <div id="us-china-trade-war-and-globalization" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#us-china-trade-war-and-globalization" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Issues like the US-China trade war and tariffs do not affect technological advancements and the innovation of American companies, thus having little impact on index investing.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Risks and Returns of Leveraged Funds 
    <div id="risks-and-returns-of-leveraged-funds" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#risks-and-returns-of-leveraged-funds" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>The risk of a 2x leveraged fund is not simply double, and the return is not twice the annualized rate of return, but approximately 1.4 times.</li>
<li>The annualized return of QQQ over 20 years is 14%, while QLD&rsquo;s is 19.6%. QLD&rsquo;s total return over 20 years is 2.6 times that of QQQ, far exceeding double.</li>
<li>Combining leveraged funds with cash can reduce risk and increase returns.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Investment Wisdom and Market Essence 
    <div id="investment-wisdom-and-market-essence" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#investment-wisdom-and-market-essence" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>The market is always smarter than individual investors. Stock picking and timing the market are futile.</li>
<li>In a bull market, many &ldquo;gurus&rdquo; emerge, but they disappear when the market falls; this is a market norm.</li>
<li>Controlling the major stocks on Wall Street means controlling the world.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Investment Sharing and Personal Insights 
    <div id="investment-sharing-and-personal-insights" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#investment-sharing-and-personal-insights" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Investment sharers need to provide clear, diverse, and universally applicable investment methods and benefit from them.</li>
<li>Buffett&rsquo;s investment philosophy emphasizes long-term investment, perfecting the investment system.</li>
<li>Understanding the essence of finance, economics, accounting, and logic helps resist external interference and adhere to index investing.</li>
<li>Asset allocation is simplified into two types: 433 (conservative) and 442 (aggressive), pursuing safety rather than high returns, with cash being a safe asset.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Finance and Monetary Theory 
    <div id="finance-and-monetary-theory" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#finance-and-monetary-theory" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>The foundation of capitalism is currency. Understanding monetary theory is crucial to understanding finance, investment, and the economy.</li>
<li>The status of the US dollar as the world&rsquo;s reserve currency determines the subordinate status of other countries, especially those holding large amounts of US dollar foreign exchange reserves.</li>
<li>China and other emerging countries are trying to break away from their dependence on the US dollar to escape US control.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Life&rsquo;s Meaning and Happiness 
    <div id="lifes-meaning-and-happiness" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#lifes-meaning-and-happiness" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>The happiest thing in life is giving. Happiness is a human right. Sharing and giving energy on a spiritual level can bring more happiness than material things.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Extremes of Capitalism and Social Issues 
    <div id="extremes-of-capitalism-and-social-issues" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#extremes-of-capitalism-and-social-issues" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Capitalism will lead to an expansion of the wealth gap. The development of robots will make spiritual education even more important.</li>
<li>Systemic discrimination exists in society, leading to a vicious cycle of poverty. Our goal is to help eliminate poverty as much as possible.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">US Accounting System and Social Phenomena 
    <div id="us-accounting-system-and-social-phenomena" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#us-accounting-system-and-social-phenomena" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>The US accounting system is very complete. Phenomena like &ldquo;zero-dollar shopping&rdquo; are the result of accounting costs and leftist thinking, and there is no need to over-interpret them.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Wealth and Government Relations 
    <div id="wealth-and-government-relations" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#wealth-and-government-relations" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Wealthy individuals escape government control by paying taxes, while the poor are trapped.</li>
<li>Legitimate tax avoidance is an important topic.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Personalization of Diet and Asset Allocation 
    <div id="personalization-of-diet-and-asset-allocation" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#personalization-of-diet-and-asset-allocation" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Both diet and asset allocation should be customized according to individual circumstances and cannot be generalized.</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">III. Q&amp;A Session 
    <div id="iii-qa-session" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii-qa-session" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Zhang Yong 
    <div id="zhang-yong" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#zhang-yong" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing</strong>: The chaos in the domestic insurance industry, where banks lure customers into buying insurance with high commissions, is even linked to the performance evaluations of customer managers. Many customers do not understand investments and choose low-yield or even risky insurance products to preserve their capital. He also shared a case of a friend who was defrauded of over 1.7 million in a romance scam, illustrating the complexity of the domestic financial environment.
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s comment</strong>: The US financial system strictly separates life insurance from other financial businesses, and there is no such thing as banks selling insurance. The financial supervision in China and Taiwan is problematic. Banks should focus on deposit and loan business and should not be involved in insurance and investment. This chaos will ultimately harm the interests of emerging countries.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question</strong>: Does Teacher James share content each week based on reflections on the same theme, or does he summarize viewpoints from reading many books?
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s reply</strong>: In addition to reading a lot of books, more importantly, independent thinking and critical thinking are involved. The formation of monetary theory stems from thinking about the nature of capitalism, and the content of the handouts mostly comes from students&rsquo; questions and his own reflections. This information is endless. To be an excellent sharer, one needs to have basic knowledge, thinking ability, and originality.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Xiao Cai 
    <div id="xiao-cai" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#xiao-cai" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing 1</strong>: Took over the family food business ten years ago when the company&rsquo;s assets and liabilities were zero. After ten years of operation, the company turned a profit, and its current value (including real estate) is about 300 million NTD. Over the past decade, he distributed about 200 million NTD of revenue to his family, retaining 100 million NTD for loan purposes. Currently, he has invested 80 million in 00662 (a 2x leveraged Nasdaq 100 index ETF) and 20 million in 00631L (Taiwan&rsquo;s 50 Positive 2 ETF).
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s comment</strong>: None</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question 1</strong>: The bank will allocate a loan of 60 million NTD on January 1st. Should this fund be used to buy 00662 all at once, or should he wait for a 20% market drop before buying? Also, if the market crashes and 00662 and 00631L go to zero, how will he deal with it?
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s reply</strong>: If the market goes to zero, the company can still make loan payments. The worst-case scenario is that the land is auctioned off, and he can still get tens of millions. Since the worst has been considered, how to buy the 60 million is not important. If it were me, I would buy it all on Monday. If you choose to wait for a 20% drop before buying, you can follow your plan and inform everyone when you buy.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question 2</strong>: How to maintain good health?
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s reply</strong>: Regular comprehensive physical examinations are necessary. I have been doing annual check-ups since my thirties. Wellness, like asset allocation, needs to be personalized. The advice I can give everyone now is to eat well, sleep well, and don&rsquo;t worry. What to eat specifically, what exercises to do, etc., need to be decided according to personal circumstances and cannot be given a unified recommendation.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question 3</strong>: What are your views on Taiwan&rsquo;s politics and how to support political parties?
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s reply</strong>: Regarding politics and religious beliefs, everyone has different positions and viewpoints. Discussing these issues in the classroom is meaningless and fruitless. It is recommended that students do not discuss these topics in the classroom and keep their opinions to themselves.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question 4</strong>: How to preserve assets in response to potential cross-strait issues? He currently has about 200 million NTD in assets in Taiwan and a house worth 8 million in Vietnam. How should he allocate his assets?
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s reply</strong>: If you can&rsquo;t sleep due to worries about cross-strait issues, it&rsquo;s recommended to immigrate as soon as possible. If you choose to stay in Taiwan, you need to make some decisions, such as whether to close the company. If the 40 employees are causing you distress, consider closing the company and compensating them. Life decisions should be decisive, not prolonged. Be responsible for your own happiness.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Additional question</strong>: How to get rid of the shackles of the family business?
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s reply</strong>: You have managed the company very well. The choice is your life. Do whatever makes you happy. If the family business makes you unhappy, shut it down and give the employees a good severance package. Consider your own life, not your father&rsquo;s. If your father&rsquo;s business is no longer your concern, and it&rsquo;s not bringing you happiness, then let it go.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Repeated emphasis</strong>: Believes that apart from investment and financial management, health is the most important asset in life, and cited the example of &ldquo;Yu (Yuan) Lingqi&rdquo; to emphasize the importance of regular health check-ups, hoping the channel will pay more attention to health issues.
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s reply</strong>: Health is very important. Everyone&rsquo;s health condition is different, and it is impossible to provide a unified recommendation. Everyone needs to pay attention to and manage their health according to their own situation.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Lare 
    <div id="lare" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#lare" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Question</strong>: Based in Canada, unable to leverage stocks. If income decreases in a certain year, and the tax rate drops from 32% to 24%, is it worth selling some stocks to increase income to the 32% tax bracket to improve the future cost basis?
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s reply</strong>: It is not recommended to sell stocks because selling incurs taxes. Canada&rsquo;s tax system is very unfavorable for stock investments. When immigrating, consider future generations and choose countries with development prospects. In Canada, you can consider using an IB account for loans, but this will face inheritance tax issues, possibly up to 40%. Therefore, when planning estates, minimize assets in IB accounts. In the long run, trusts can be used to avoid taxes. It is currently not recommended to sell stocks for short-term tax benefits. Consider selling after retirement when income is lower.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Additional explanation</strong>: IB accounts have a low financing ratio for Canadian stocks, only up to 50%.
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s addition</strong>: You can borrow 40% first, and add more if needed. But ultimately, there will still be inheritance tax issues.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Terry 
    <div id="terry" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#terry" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Question 1</strong>: How to transfer taxable accounts or retirement accounts to tax-free accounts, such as Roth IRA? What are the specific steps?
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s reply</strong>: If it&rsquo;s within the same brokerage, such as Charles Schwab, you can fill out a form online directly. If it&rsquo;s at different brokerages, you need to contact the brokerage to obtain and fill out a form. For specific steps, you can refer to the previously released video &ldquo;Investment and Financial Management Tips 26: How to Transfer from a Traditional Taxable Account to a Roth IRA Online at 722.&rdquo;</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question 2</strong>: What is your view on Crypto, and will QQQ include Crypto companies in the future?
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s reply</strong>: I don&rsquo;t know much about Crypto and am not sure if it will exist forever, so I won&rsquo;t answer.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">IM 
    <div id="im" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#im" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing</strong>: Through learning, I realized that my investment was too risky, and emergency funds should not all be invested in QQQ. Now I have withdrawn 36 months of emergency funds back to the Money Market Fund. When starting with small funds, one should focus on their main job and increase income sources. After investing in index funds, my mindset changed, and I began to focus on the importance of timing. Therefore, I started to focus on diet, fitness, and learning from the experiences of long-lived people around me. In addition, I learned from investing to avoid risks, such as giving up dangerous activities like diving.
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s comment</strong>: It is wise to learn from the experiences of others. Being overly aggressive is human nature, but it is important to realize and correct it in time. It is wrong to increase positions when the market is rising and to be fearful when it is falling. It should be the other way around. Emergency funds should not be added to.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question</strong>: How to judge whether you are being too adventurous? For example, increasing the leverage ratio of asset allocation from 1.0 to 1.8 when stocks are rising.
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s reply</strong>: This is also a necessary evil. Now that you realize it&rsquo;s not right, you can start to retreat, or when it rises, you buy in, and when it falls, you get scared. Oh, what to do? Then start to retreat. Once you have learned, don&rsquo;t do it again. So, as Buffett said, when others are greedy, you should be fearful, and when others are fearful, you should be greedy. That&rsquo;s the right pace. So, when you want to increase your position in the future, it should be when others are fearful. That&rsquo;s how I do it. This emergency fund should not be increased. Regardless of whether the market is rising or falling, you should not add to this cervical spine disease. How could you add to it? This is not allowed. Then, if you use our asset allocation, when the market falls, you automatically buy in for one year, and when the market rises, you automatically withdraw from the leveraged fund. This is passive, and this has already achieved the practice of being greedy when others are fearful and being fearful when others are greedy.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Patty 
    <div id="patty" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#patty" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Question</strong>: The relationship between the asset-backed ratio and cash reserves. If asset-backed financing is carried out, how to ensure that the cash on hand is greater than the pledged amount? For example, with assets of 1 million, allocated according to the 721 ratio, 200,000 is pledged, but 100,000 in cash cannot be moved. Is it necessary to balance for one or two years to accumulate 200,000 in cash before making a pledge?
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s reply</strong>: You cannot borrow 200,000 all at once; you can only borrow 2% per year. When conducting asset-backed financing, the asset allocation should be 433, not 721. Borrow 2% each year and conduct &ldquo;smart rebalancing.&rdquo; Even if the market falls, you will not be forced to liquidate. The cash ratio may be lower than the loan ratio in extreme cases (such as a continuous 10-year decline), but since the total asset value is still greater than the debt, there will be no problem.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Mike 
    <div id="mike" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#mike" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing</strong>: A friend&rsquo;s experience. The friend took over his father&rsquo;s family business and eventually had health problems due to overwork. He later sold the company for over 600 million and invested the funds in QQQ. He is now very happy.
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s comment</strong>: None</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question 1</strong>: Regarding 401k and RMD. Previously, company stock was placed in a 401k, and now it has a high value, facing the RMD issue. After Trump takes office, is it possible to abolish RMD and change it to a 15% capital gains tax?
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s reply</strong>: This possibility is extremely slim. The government is unlikely to give up the tax revenue brought by RMD.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question 2</strong>: Regarding the Debt to Equity Ratio of companies. It is found that there are large differences in the debt-to-equity ratios of Buffett and many technology companies. Is this related to the nature of the industry? For example, the debt-to-equity ratio of software companies is usually low, while that of hardware companies like Apple is high. So, for individuals, is it a healthy level to control the debt-to-equity ratio at 0.2?
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s reply</strong>: The higher the debt-to-equity ratio, the higher the ROE usually is, but this needs to be based on healthy debt. Healthy debt refers to debt that can be repaid through its own operating activities, such as credit, stock-backed loans (under safe circumstances), and mortgages (that can be repaid). Apple&rsquo;s debt-to-equity ratio is high because it borrows a lot of money to pay dividends and places assets overseas. In addition, it has a large amount of accounts payable. Therefore, it cannot be simply considered that a high debt-to-equity ratio is bad. It is necessary to analyze the nature and safety of the debt specifically.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question 3</strong>: What are your thoughts on the Jetson Orin product launched by Nvidia? This product is mainly for the personal AI market, is cheap, can use ChatGPT to generate code, and runs locally, thereby creating your own AI database.
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s reply</strong>: I don&rsquo;t know much about this product. Our AI is mainly trained using ChatGPT as a personal assistant. Currently, I don&rsquo;t use other devices for personal AI.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">IV. Highlighted Quotes 
    <div id="iv-highlighted-quotes" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv-highlighted-quotes" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>The only constant in the market is volatility.
&ndash; Teacher James</p></blockquote>
<p>This viewpoint emphasizes the normality of market fluctuations. Investors should be mentally prepared and not be affected by short-term market fluctuations.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Investing requires independent thinking. Do not blindly follow advice or join any groups to avoid being deceived.
&ndash; Teacher James</p></blockquote>
<p>This viewpoint emphasizes the importance of independent thinking in investing. Investors should make investment decisions based on their own judgment rather than blindly following others&rsquo; opinions or joining unreliable investment groups.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The happiest thing in life is giving. Happiness is a human right. Sharing and giving energy on a spiritual level can bring more happiness than material things.
&ndash; Teacher James</p></blockquote>
<p>This viewpoint emphasizes that spiritual pursuits are more important than material ones. Giving and sharing can bring greater happiness.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>If you, as a commercial bank, do lending well, then focus on lending. Deposits are 2%. Then your lending is 3.5%, 4%. You just make that 2% difference. This is what a commercial bank should do. Commerce should not touch insurance.
&ndash; Teacher James</p></blockquote>
<p>This viewpoint points out that commercial banks should focus on deposit and loan business instead of being involved in areas like insurance, which not only violates financial regulations but also harms the interests of customers.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Happiness is a human right. If you are alive, you should be happy. If you live so miserably, why bother?
&ndash; Teacher James</p></blockquote>
<p>This viewpoint reminds everyone to pursue happiness and not sacrifice their happiness for money or other goals.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Impotence is also a kind of strength because accepting one&rsquo;s own impotence and acknowledging one&rsquo;s own impotence is also a kind of strength.
&ndash; Teacher James</p></blockquote>
<p>This viewpoint expresses a broad-minded attitude towards life. Acknowledging one&rsquo;s limitations is not a bad thing; instead, it can make one more relaxed.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The truly wealthy are those who foresee a future eternally disconnected from government oversight, swiftly settling their dues to escape the clutches of authority.
&ndash; Teacher James</p></blockquote>
<p>This perspective highlights how affluent individuals utilize legitimate tax avoidance strategies to minimize governmental control over their wealth.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Learning from the experiences of others is a wise approach.
&ndash; IM</p></blockquote>
<p>This viewpoint emphasizes the importance of learning and drawing lessons from others&rsquo; experiences, which can help us avoid making the same mistakes.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>When others are greedy, you should be fearful; when others are fearful, you should be greedy.
&ndash; Teacher James, quoting Buffett</p></blockquote>
<p>This is a very important principle in investing, namely, contrarian thinking, staying calm when the market is frenzied and looking for opportunities when the market is panicking.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Just be happy. There&rsquo;s nothing to it, nothing to fight for, no particular meaning, nothing that grand or great.
&ndash; Teacher James</p></blockquote>
<p>This viewpoint expresses a detached attitude towards life. Don&rsquo;t put too much pressure on yourself; learn to enjoy life.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Don&rsquo;t wait until it&rsquo;s too late, leaving no time for regrets.
&ndash; Teacher James</p></blockquote>
<p>Drawing on investment principles, this perspective underscores the importance of early health screenings, urging not to wait until problems arise before regretting, echoing Xiao Cai&rsquo;s shared viewpoint.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>We investors are always extremely optimistic. Market fluctuations should be ignored. The market will eventually rise and always reach new highs.
&ndash; Teacher James</p></blockquote>
<p>This viewpoint emphasizes the optimistic attitude towards the long-term trend of the market and the neglect of short-term fluctuations, demonstrating the proper mindset for long-term investors.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">V. Summary 
    <div id="v-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#v-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>The content of this episode of the investment and financial management channel is rich. Teacher James not only shared his views on the current market and investment strategies but also answered the practical questions of many students, involving asset allocation, business operations, health and wellness, tax planning, and other aspects. In addition, he also emphasized the importance of happiness and health, as well as investment concepts such as independent thinking, long-term investment, and reasonable tax avoidance. In summary, the content of this episode provides valuable guidance and inspiration for investors, helping everyone make wise decisions in a complex market environment and have a healthier and happier life.</p>

  



<div
  
    class="flex px-4 py-3 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900"
  >

  <span
    
      class="text-primary-400 ltr:pr-3 rtl:pl-3 flex items-center"
    >

    

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M506.3 417l-213.3-364c-16.33-28-57.54-28-73.98 0l-213.2 364C-10.59 444.9 9.849 480 42.74 480h426.6C502.1 480 522.6 445 506.3 417zM232 168c0-13.25 10.75-24 24-24S280 154.8 280 168v128c0 13.25-10.75 24-23.1 24S232 309.3 232 296V168zM256 416c-17.36 0-31.44-14.08-31.44-31.44c0-17.36 14.07-31.44 31.44-31.44s31.44 14.08 31.44 31.44C287.4 401.9 273.4 416 256 416z"/></svg>

  </span>


  </span>

  <span
    
      class="dark:text-neutral-300"
    ><strong>Disclaimer:</strong> This article is only a personal study note and does not constitute any investment advice.</span>
</div>

]]></content:encoded></item></channel></rss>