<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Index Funds on QQQ Investor</title>
    <link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/tags/index-funds/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Index Funds on QQQ Investor</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jomonylw.github.io/en/tags/index-funds/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>00496 Global Markets and the Tech Wave: How to Seize Opportunities for Wealth Growth Amidst Volatility. The Philosophy of Financial Freedom: From Personalized Investing to Exploring Life&#39;s Values</title>
      <link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1735482278058/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1735482278058/</guid>
      <description>At the end of 2024, with market fluctuations, Teacher James shared his insights on the current economic situation, financial markets, and investment strategies. In addition, several students asked questions online, covering asset allocation, business operations, health and wellness, tax planning, stock leveraging, and other areas.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Part One
<lite-youtube videoid="9F1rAWjCGX8" playlabel="9F1rAWjCGX8" params=""></lite-youtube>
</p>
<p>Part Two
<lite-youtube videoid="oPb4m81Nv24" playlabel="oPb4m81Nv24" params=""></lite-youtube>
</p>


<h2 class="relative group">I. Main Topic of the Session 
    <div id="i-main-topic-of-the-session" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-main-topic-of-the-session" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>Investment mindset and strategy adjustments amidst year-end market volatility, along with comprehensive reflections on personal life and financial health.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">II. Presentation Content 
    <div id="ii-presentation-content" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii-presentation-content" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Market Volatility and Investment Mindset 
    <div id="market-volatility-and-investment-mindset" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#market-volatility-and-investment-mindset" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>The only constant in the market is volatility. Investors should ignore market fluctuations, international situations, market analysis, financial reports, and economic situations, and focus on long-term investment.</li>
<li>Disclaimer: The content of the COC investment and financial management channel is for educational purposes only and does not constitute investment advice. Investment involves high risks, and proper asset allocation is necessary.</li>
<li>Newcomers should watch the YouTube episode 00451 &ldquo;Investment Lecture Worth 100 Million&rdquo; and also find related content on Bilibili and podcasts.</li>
<li>Investing requires independent thinking. Do not blindly follow advice or join any groups to avoid being deceived.</li>
<li>The Nasdaq 100 index fund is recommended as the only focused fund, with others being supplementary.</li>
<li>The handout includes information on Nasdaq 100 index funds worldwide, including leveraged funds, and information on retirement accounts in various regions, with content continuously updated.</li>
<li>The &ldquo;Investment Lecture Worth 100 Million&rdquo; video is the most important. Investors should always be extremely optimistic; the market will eventually rise and reach new highs.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">UK and European Financial Information 
    <div id="uk-and-european-financial-information" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#uk-and-european-financial-information" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Showcasing information provided by a UK friend regarding UK investments, loans, retirement accounts, ETFs, and insurance companies, particularly information on 2x leveraged funds on the PEA website.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">US-China Trade War and Globalization 
    <div id="us-china-trade-war-and-globalization" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#us-china-trade-war-and-globalization" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Issues like the US-China trade war and tariffs do not affect technological advancements and the innovation of American companies, thus having little impact on index investing.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Risks and Returns of Leveraged Funds 
    <div id="risks-and-returns-of-leveraged-funds" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#risks-and-returns-of-leveraged-funds" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>The risk of a 2x leveraged fund is not simply double, and the return is not twice the annualized rate of return, but approximately 1.4 times.</li>
<li>The annualized return of QQQ over 20 years is 14%, while QLD&rsquo;s is 19.6%. QLD&rsquo;s total return over 20 years is 2.6 times that of QQQ, far exceeding double.</li>
<li>Combining leveraged funds with cash can reduce risk and increase returns.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Investment Wisdom and Market Essence 
    <div id="investment-wisdom-and-market-essence" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#investment-wisdom-and-market-essence" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>The market is always smarter than individual investors. Stock picking and timing the market are futile.</li>
<li>In a bull market, many &ldquo;gurus&rdquo; emerge, but they disappear when the market falls; this is a market norm.</li>
<li>Controlling the major stocks on Wall Street means controlling the world.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Investment Sharing and Personal Insights 
    <div id="investment-sharing-and-personal-insights" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#investment-sharing-and-personal-insights" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Investment sharers need to provide clear, diverse, and universally applicable investment methods and benefit from them.</li>
<li>Buffett&rsquo;s investment philosophy emphasizes long-term investment, perfecting the investment system.</li>
<li>Understanding the essence of finance, economics, accounting, and logic helps resist external interference and adhere to index investing.</li>
<li>Asset allocation is simplified into two types: 433 (conservative) and 442 (aggressive), pursuing safety rather than high returns, with cash being a safe asset.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Finance and Monetary Theory 
    <div id="finance-and-monetary-theory" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#finance-and-monetary-theory" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>The foundation of capitalism is currency. Understanding monetary theory is crucial to understanding finance, investment, and the economy.</li>
<li>The status of the US dollar as the world&rsquo;s reserve currency determines the subordinate status of other countries, especially those holding large amounts of US dollar foreign exchange reserves.</li>
<li>China and other emerging countries are trying to break away from their dependence on the US dollar to escape US control.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Life&rsquo;s Meaning and Happiness 
    <div id="lifes-meaning-and-happiness" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#lifes-meaning-and-happiness" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>The happiest thing in life is giving. Happiness is a human right. Sharing and giving energy on a spiritual level can bring more happiness than material things.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Extremes of Capitalism and Social Issues 
    <div id="extremes-of-capitalism-and-social-issues" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#extremes-of-capitalism-and-social-issues" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Capitalism will lead to an expansion of the wealth gap. The development of robots will make spiritual education even more important.</li>
<li>Systemic discrimination exists in society, leading to a vicious cycle of poverty. Our goal is to help eliminate poverty as much as possible.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">US Accounting System and Social Phenomena 
    <div id="us-accounting-system-and-social-phenomena" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#us-accounting-system-and-social-phenomena" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>The US accounting system is very complete. Phenomena like &ldquo;zero-dollar shopping&rdquo; are the result of accounting costs and leftist thinking, and there is no need to over-interpret them.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Wealth and Government Relations 
    <div id="wealth-and-government-relations" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#wealth-and-government-relations" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Wealthy individuals escape government control by paying taxes, while the poor are trapped.</li>
<li>Legitimate tax avoidance is an important topic.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Personalization of Diet and Asset Allocation 
    <div id="personalization-of-diet-and-asset-allocation" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#personalization-of-diet-and-asset-allocation" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Both diet and asset allocation should be customized according to individual circumstances and cannot be generalized.</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">III. Q&amp;A Session 
    <div id="iii-qa-session" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii-qa-session" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Zhang Yong 
    <div id="zhang-yong" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#zhang-yong" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing</strong>: The chaos in the domestic insurance industry, where banks lure customers into buying insurance with high commissions, is even linked to the performance evaluations of customer managers. Many customers do not understand investments and choose low-yield or even risky insurance products to preserve their capital. He also shared a case of a friend who was defrauded of over 1.7 million in a romance scam, illustrating the complexity of the domestic financial environment.
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s comment</strong>: The US financial system strictly separates life insurance from other financial businesses, and there is no such thing as banks selling insurance. The financial supervision in China and Taiwan is problematic. Banks should focus on deposit and loan business and should not be involved in insurance and investment. This chaos will ultimately harm the interests of emerging countries.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question</strong>: Does Teacher James share content each week based on reflections on the same theme, or does he summarize viewpoints from reading many books?
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s reply</strong>: In addition to reading a lot of books, more importantly, independent thinking and critical thinking are involved. The formation of monetary theory stems from thinking about the nature of capitalism, and the content of the handouts mostly comes from students&rsquo; questions and his own reflections. This information is endless. To be an excellent sharer, one needs to have basic knowledge, thinking ability, and originality.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Xiao Cai 
    <div id="xiao-cai" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#xiao-cai" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing 1</strong>: Took over the family food business ten years ago when the company&rsquo;s assets and liabilities were zero. After ten years of operation, the company turned a profit, and its current value (including real estate) is about 300 million NTD. Over the past decade, he distributed about 200 million NTD of revenue to his family, retaining 100 million NTD for loan purposes. Currently, he has invested 80 million in 00662 (a 2x leveraged Nasdaq 100 index ETF) and 20 million in 00631L (Taiwan&rsquo;s 50 Positive 2 ETF).
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s comment</strong>: None</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question 1</strong>: The bank will allocate a loan of 60 million NTD on January 1st. Should this fund be used to buy 00662 all at once, or should he wait for a 20% market drop before buying? Also, if the market crashes and 00662 and 00631L go to zero, how will he deal with it?
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s reply</strong>: If the market goes to zero, the company can still make loan payments. The worst-case scenario is that the land is auctioned off, and he can still get tens of millions. Since the worst has been considered, how to buy the 60 million is not important. If it were me, I would buy it all on Monday. If you choose to wait for a 20% drop before buying, you can follow your plan and inform everyone when you buy.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question 2</strong>: How to maintain good health?
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s reply</strong>: Regular comprehensive physical examinations are necessary. I have been doing annual check-ups since my thirties. Wellness, like asset allocation, needs to be personalized. The advice I can give everyone now is to eat well, sleep well, and don&rsquo;t worry. What to eat specifically, what exercises to do, etc., need to be decided according to personal circumstances and cannot be given a unified recommendation.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question 3</strong>: What are your views on Taiwan&rsquo;s politics and how to support political parties?
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s reply</strong>: Regarding politics and religious beliefs, everyone has different positions and viewpoints. Discussing these issues in the classroom is meaningless and fruitless. It is recommended that students do not discuss these topics in the classroom and keep their opinions to themselves.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question 4</strong>: How to preserve assets in response to potential cross-strait issues? He currently has about 200 million NTD in assets in Taiwan and a house worth 8 million in Vietnam. How should he allocate his assets?
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s reply</strong>: If you can&rsquo;t sleep due to worries about cross-strait issues, it&rsquo;s recommended to immigrate as soon as possible. If you choose to stay in Taiwan, you need to make some decisions, such as whether to close the company. If the 40 employees are causing you distress, consider closing the company and compensating them. Life decisions should be decisive, not prolonged. Be responsible for your own happiness.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Additional question</strong>: How to get rid of the shackles of the family business?
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s reply</strong>: You have managed the company very well. The choice is your life. Do whatever makes you happy. If the family business makes you unhappy, shut it down and give the employees a good severance package. Consider your own life, not your father&rsquo;s. If your father&rsquo;s business is no longer your concern, and it&rsquo;s not bringing you happiness, then let it go.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Repeated emphasis</strong>: Believes that apart from investment and financial management, health is the most important asset in life, and cited the example of &ldquo;Yu (Yuan) Lingqi&rdquo; to emphasize the importance of regular health check-ups, hoping the channel will pay more attention to health issues.
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s reply</strong>: Health is very important. Everyone&rsquo;s health condition is different, and it is impossible to provide a unified recommendation. Everyone needs to pay attention to and manage their health according to their own situation.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Lare 
    <div id="lare" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#lare" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Question</strong>: Based in Canada, unable to leverage stocks. If income decreases in a certain year, and the tax rate drops from 32% to 24%, is it worth selling some stocks to increase income to the 32% tax bracket to improve the future cost basis?
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s reply</strong>: It is not recommended to sell stocks because selling incurs taxes. Canada&rsquo;s tax system is very unfavorable for stock investments. When immigrating, consider future generations and choose countries with development prospects. In Canada, you can consider using an IB account for loans, but this will face inheritance tax issues, possibly up to 40%. Therefore, when planning estates, minimize assets in IB accounts. In the long run, trusts can be used to avoid taxes. It is currently not recommended to sell stocks for short-term tax benefits. Consider selling after retirement when income is lower.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Additional explanation</strong>: IB accounts have a low financing ratio for Canadian stocks, only up to 50%.
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s addition</strong>: You can borrow 40% first, and add more if needed. But ultimately, there will still be inheritance tax issues.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Terry 
    <div id="terry" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#terry" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Question 1</strong>: How to transfer taxable accounts or retirement accounts to tax-free accounts, such as Roth IRA? What are the specific steps?
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s reply</strong>: If it&rsquo;s within the same brokerage, such as Charles Schwab, you can fill out a form online directly. If it&rsquo;s at different brokerages, you need to contact the brokerage to obtain and fill out a form. For specific steps, you can refer to the previously released video &ldquo;Investment and Financial Management Tips 26: How to Transfer from a Traditional Taxable Account to a Roth IRA Online at 722.&rdquo;</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question 2</strong>: What is your view on Crypto, and will QQQ include Crypto companies in the future?
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s reply</strong>: I don&rsquo;t know much about Crypto and am not sure if it will exist forever, so I won&rsquo;t answer.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">IM 
    <div id="im" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#im" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing</strong>: Through learning, I realized that my investment was too risky, and emergency funds should not all be invested in QQQ. Now I have withdrawn 36 months of emergency funds back to the Money Market Fund. When starting with small funds, one should focus on their main job and increase income sources. After investing in index funds, my mindset changed, and I began to focus on the importance of timing. Therefore, I started to focus on diet, fitness, and learning from the experiences of long-lived people around me. In addition, I learned from investing to avoid risks, such as giving up dangerous activities like diving.
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s comment</strong>: It is wise to learn from the experiences of others. Being overly aggressive is human nature, but it is important to realize and correct it in time. It is wrong to increase positions when the market is rising and to be fearful when it is falling. It should be the other way around. Emergency funds should not be added to.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question</strong>: How to judge whether you are being too adventurous? For example, increasing the leverage ratio of asset allocation from 1.0 to 1.8 when stocks are rising.
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s reply</strong>: This is also a necessary evil. Now that you realize it&rsquo;s not right, you can start to retreat, or when it rises, you buy in, and when it falls, you get scared. Oh, what to do? Then start to retreat. Once you have learned, don&rsquo;t do it again. So, as Buffett said, when others are greedy, you should be fearful, and when others are fearful, you should be greedy. That&rsquo;s the right pace. So, when you want to increase your position in the future, it should be when others are fearful. That&rsquo;s how I do it. This emergency fund should not be increased. Regardless of whether the market is rising or falling, you should not add to this cervical spine disease. How could you add to it? This is not allowed. Then, if you use our asset allocation, when the market falls, you automatically buy in for one year, and when the market rises, you automatically withdraw from the leveraged fund. This is passive, and this has already achieved the practice of being greedy when others are fearful and being fearful when others are greedy.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Patty 
    <div id="patty" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#patty" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Question</strong>: The relationship between the asset-backed ratio and cash reserves. If asset-backed financing is carried out, how to ensure that the cash on hand is greater than the pledged amount? For example, with assets of 1 million, allocated according to the 721 ratio, 200,000 is pledged, but 100,000 in cash cannot be moved. Is it necessary to balance for one or two years to accumulate 200,000 in cash before making a pledge?
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s reply</strong>: You cannot borrow 200,000 all at once; you can only borrow 2% per year. When conducting asset-backed financing, the asset allocation should be 433, not 721. Borrow 2% each year and conduct &ldquo;smart rebalancing.&rdquo; Even if the market falls, you will not be forced to liquidate. The cash ratio may be lower than the loan ratio in extreme cases (such as a continuous 10-year decline), but since the total asset value is still greater than the debt, there will be no problem.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Mike 
    <div id="mike" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#mike" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing</strong>: A friend&rsquo;s experience. The friend took over his father&rsquo;s family business and eventually had health problems due to overwork. He later sold the company for over 600 million and invested the funds in QQQ. He is now very happy.
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s comment</strong>: None</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question 1</strong>: Regarding 401k and RMD. Previously, company stock was placed in a 401k, and now it has a high value, facing the RMD issue. After Trump takes office, is it possible to abolish RMD and change it to a 15% capital gains tax?
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s reply</strong>: This possibility is extremely slim. The government is unlikely to give up the tax revenue brought by RMD.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question 2</strong>: Regarding the Debt to Equity Ratio of companies. It is found that there are large differences in the debt-to-equity ratios of Buffett and many technology companies. Is this related to the nature of the industry? For example, the debt-to-equity ratio of software companies is usually low, while that of hardware companies like Apple is high. So, for individuals, is it a healthy level to control the debt-to-equity ratio at 0.2?
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s reply</strong>: The higher the debt-to-equity ratio, the higher the ROE usually is, but this needs to be based on healthy debt. Healthy debt refers to debt that can be repaid through its own operating activities, such as credit, stock-backed loans (under safe circumstances), and mortgages (that can be repaid). Apple&rsquo;s debt-to-equity ratio is high because it borrows a lot of money to pay dividends and places assets overseas. In addition, it has a large amount of accounts payable. Therefore, it cannot be simply considered that a high debt-to-equity ratio is bad. It is necessary to analyze the nature and safety of the debt specifically.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question 3</strong>: What are your thoughts on the Jetson Orin product launched by Nvidia? This product is mainly for the personal AI market, is cheap, can use ChatGPT to generate code, and runs locally, thereby creating your own AI database.
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s reply</strong>: I don&rsquo;t know much about this product. Our AI is mainly trained using ChatGPT as a personal assistant. Currently, I don&rsquo;t use other devices for personal AI.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">IV. Highlighted Quotes 
    <div id="iv-highlighted-quotes" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv-highlighted-quotes" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>The only constant in the market is volatility.
&ndash; Teacher James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This viewpoint emphasizes the normality of market fluctuations. Investors should be mentally prepared and not be affected by short-term market fluctuations.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Investing requires independent thinking. Do not blindly follow advice or join any groups to avoid being deceived.
&ndash; Teacher James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This viewpoint emphasizes the importance of independent thinking in investing. Investors should make investment decisions based on their own judgment rather than blindly following others&rsquo; opinions or joining unreliable investment groups.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The happiest thing in life is giving. Happiness is a human right. Sharing and giving energy on a spiritual level can bring more happiness than material things.
&ndash; Teacher James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This viewpoint emphasizes that spiritual pursuits are more important than material ones. Giving and sharing can bring greater happiness.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>If you, as a commercial bank, do lending well, then focus on lending. Deposits are 2%. Then your lending is 3.5%, 4%. You just make that 2% difference. This is what a commercial bank should do. Commerce should not touch insurance.
&ndash; Teacher James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This viewpoint points out that commercial banks should focus on deposit and loan business instead of being involved in areas like insurance, which not only violates financial regulations but also harms the interests of customers.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Happiness is a human right. If you are alive, you should be happy. If you live so miserably, why bother?
&ndash; Teacher James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This viewpoint reminds everyone to pursue happiness and not sacrifice their happiness for money or other goals.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Impotence is also a kind of strength because accepting one&rsquo;s own impotence and acknowledging one&rsquo;s own impotence is also a kind of strength.
&ndash; Teacher James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This viewpoint expresses a broad-minded attitude towards life. Acknowledging one&rsquo;s limitations is not a bad thing; instead, it can make one more relaxed.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The truly wealthy are those who foresee a future eternally disconnected from government oversight, swiftly settling their dues to escape the clutches of authority.
&ndash; Teacher James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This perspective highlights how affluent individuals utilize legitimate tax avoidance strategies to minimize governmental control over their wealth.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Learning from the experiences of others is a wise approach.
&ndash; IM</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This viewpoint emphasizes the importance of learning and drawing lessons from others&rsquo; experiences, which can help us avoid making the same mistakes.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>When others are greedy, you should be fearful; when others are fearful, you should be greedy.
&ndash; Teacher James, quoting Buffett</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This is a very important principle in investing, namely, contrarian thinking, staying calm when the market is frenzied and looking for opportunities when the market is panicking.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Just be happy. There&rsquo;s nothing to it, nothing to fight for, no particular meaning, nothing that grand or great.
&ndash; Teacher James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This viewpoint expresses a detached attitude towards life. Don&rsquo;t put too much pressure on yourself; learn to enjoy life.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Don&rsquo;t wait until it&rsquo;s too late, leaving no time for regrets.
&ndash; Teacher James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Drawing on investment principles, this perspective underscores the importance of early health screenings, urging not to wait until problems arise before regretting, echoing Xiao Cai&rsquo;s shared viewpoint.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>We investors are always extremely optimistic. Market fluctuations should be ignored. The market will eventually rise and always reach new highs.
&ndash; Teacher James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This viewpoint emphasizes the optimistic attitude towards the long-term trend of the market and the neglect of short-term fluctuations, demonstrating the proper mindset for long-term investors.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">V. Summary 
    <div id="v-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#v-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>The content of this episode of the COC investment and financial management channel is rich. Teacher James not only shared his views on the current market and investment strategies but also answered the practical questions of many students, involving asset allocation, business operations, health and wellness, tax planning, and other aspects. In addition, he also emphasized the importance of happiness and health, as well as investment concepts such as independent thinking, long-term investment, and reasonable tax avoidance. In summary, the content of this episode provides valuable guidance and inspiration for investors, helping everyone make wise decisions in a complex market environment and have a healthier and happier life.</p>

  



<div
  
    class="flex px-4 py-3 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900"
  >

  <span
    
      class="text-primary-400 ltr:pr-3 rtl:pl-3 flex items-center"
    >

    

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M506.3 417l-213.3-364c-16.33-28-57.54-28-73.98 0l-213.2 364C-10.59 444.9 9.849 480 42.74 480h426.6C502.1 480 522.6 445 506.3 417zM232 168c0-13.25 10.75-24 24-24S280 154.8 280 168v128c0 13.25-10.75 24-23.1 24S232 309.3 232 296V168zM256 416c-17.36 0-31.44-14.08-31.44-31.44c0-17.36 14.07-31.44 31.44-31.44s31.44 14.08 31.44 31.44C287.4 401.9 273.4 416 256 416z"/></svg>

  </span>


  </span>

  <span
    
      class="dark:text-neutral-300"
    ><strong>Disclaimer:</strong> This article is only a personal study note and does not constitute any investment advice.</span>
</div>

]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>00495 Market Highs and Lows Don&#39;t Exist: The Only Truth in Long-Term Investing; The Privilege of the Rich and the Secret of Asset Appreciation</title>
      <link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1734846063547/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1734846063547/</guid>
      <description>In this session, James shares his year-end rebalancing strategy, investment philosophy, 433 asset allocation plan, and answers questions from students regarding QQQ, leveraged ETFs, ETNs, real estate, personal finance, and CLEC short video production.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<lite-youtube videoid="TCfozoZu0Hw" playlabel="TCfozoZu0Hw" params=""></lite-youtube>



<h2 class="relative group">I. Main Topic 
    <div id="i-main-topic" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-main-topic" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This session focuses on year-end investment strategies. James emphasizes the importance of rebalancing and delves into investment philosophy, asset allocation, handling market fluctuations, and other practical investment tips. The core message is: adopt a long-term investment approach, adhere to the &ldquo;buy whenever you have money, never sell&rdquo; strategy, and implement a suitable asset allocation and rebalancing plan based on individual circumstances.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">II. Briefing Content 
    <div id="ii-briefing-content" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii-briefing-content" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Year-End Rebalancing and Asset Allocation 
    <div id="year-end-rebalancing-and-asset-allocation" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#year-end-rebalancing-and-asset-allocation" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Importance of Rebalancing:</strong> James stresses the importance of rebalancing at the end or beginning of the year. He recommends passive rebalancing, which means rebalancing when the market is performing well, to avoid panic selling during market downturns. He points out that many investors are reluctant to rebalance during market rallies, hoping to earn more, but end up succumbing to losses during declines and selling at the bottom, resulting in greater losses.</li>
<li><strong>Pledging Stocks for Tax Payment:</strong> He advises individuals with pledged stocks to borrow money for tax payments instead of selling the stocks to avoid increasing capital gains tax and to better utilize their funds. He emphasizes that under the premise of sound asset allocation and risk management, the borrowed money can be used flexibly.</li>
<li><strong>Real Estate Investment:</strong>  James advises against buying real estate, believing it restricts personal freedom. He uses the example of a friend in the Bay Area selling their property to support this viewpoint, pointing out the high holding costs of real estate, including property taxes, maintenance fees, and insurance, which can put significant financial pressure on individuals.</li>
<li><strong>Children&rsquo;s Education and Wealth Perspective:</strong> He suggests parents support their children&rsquo;s choices, believing that happiness is more important than wealth. Children shouldn&rsquo;t live for the sake of glorifying their family but should pursue happiness, serve others, and do what they love.</li>
<li><strong>433 Asset Allocation Plan:</strong> James recommends the 433 asset allocation plan (40% QQQ, 30% TQQQ, 30% Cash) for the general public, adjustable based on individual circumstances. For retirees who are not pledging stocks, he suggests an 80/20 allocation (80% index funds, 20% cash). For investors unfamiliar with or averse to leveraged ETFs, he recommends 100% investment in QQQ or 00662.</li>
<li><strong>Taiwan&rsquo;s Investment Environment Advantage:</strong> James highly praises Taiwan&rsquo;s investment environment, believing it possesses cutting-edge financial tools, tax-free policies, and low interest rates, making it an ideal place for investment. He encourages Taiwanese investors to leverage this advantage.</li>
<li><strong>Mid-Life Investment Strategy:</strong> He advises middle-aged individuals, even with modest incomes, to persist in monthly investments, accumulating wealth gradually for retirement. He illustrates the returns of monthly investments of 5,000 and 10,000 at retirement with specific examples.</li>
<li><strong>Advantages of Nasdaq 100 Index Funds:</strong> James explains the rationale for investing in QQQ, stating that its constituent companies have strong profitability, focus on technology and innovation, and align with long-term human development trends. He also points out that the constituent companies of the Nasdaq 100 index have stronger profitability compared to the S&amp;P 500.</li>
<li><strong>Investment Philosophy:</strong>  He advocates for the &ldquo;buy whenever you have money, never sell&rdquo; strategy, ignoring short-term fluctuations and believing in the long-term upward trajectory of the market. He emphasizes that the purpose of investment is wealth appreciation, not short-term gains, and criticizes the drawbacks of short-term trading.</li>
<li><strong>The Difference Between the Rich and the Poor:</strong> James points out that the rich possess assets and credit, which they can use to &ldquo;print money&rdquo; through leverage for rapid wealth growth.  The poor, lacking investment knowledge, keep their money in banks, missing out on wealth growth opportunities. He uses the example of Warren Buffett issuing bonds to illustrate how the rich utilize credit for investment.</li>
<li><strong>Three Contributions of Investors:</strong>  First, allocating capital to the most efficient companies, promoting technological advancement; second, helping the government invest idle foreign exchange reserves; third, helping the poor activate their funds, maximizing their social value.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Other Investment Advice and Opinions 
    <div id="other-investment-advice-and-opinions" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#other-investment-advice-and-opinions" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Don&rsquo;t blindly trust the investment advice of financial advisors and banks, as they have profit motives and may recommend products beneficial to themselves, not necessarily to investors.</li>
<li>Don&rsquo;t believe in investment recommendations from so-called &ldquo;group leaders&rdquo; or random individuals. Think independently, make your own decisions, and be responsible for your investments.</li>
<li>Focus on investing in broad-market passive funds in the US, such as the Nasdaq 100 Index Fund (QQQ) and the S&amp;P 500 Index Fund (SPY). He provides codes for investing in Nasdaq 100 index funds globally.</li>
<li>Avoid investing in unfamiliar assets like Bitcoin. Focus on core investment strategies to avoid distractions.</li>
<li>Don&rsquo;t overemphasize short-term market fluctuations and various news. Maintain an optimistic mindset and firmly believe in the long-term upward trend of the market.</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">III. Q&amp;A Session 
    <div id="iii-qa-session" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii-qa-session" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Zhang Yong 
    <div id="zhang-yong" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#zhang-yong" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Expresses gratitude to James, shares his 15-year experience in the insurance industry, reflects on some existing problems within the industry, such as promoting low-yield financial insurance, and expresses admiration for the simplicity and effectiveness of the CLEC investment philosophy and how it can change his and his family&rsquo;s financial future. He also shares his desire to help friends and family learn the CLEC investment philosophy but acknowledges the challenges in promotion.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s comments: Affirms Zhang Yong&rsquo;s sharing and thanks Dr. Lao Chai for the recommendation. Emphasizes the power of word-of-mouth marketing and encourages Zhang Yong to continue promoting the CLEC investment philosophy.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Mike 
    <div id="mike" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#mike" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Shares a discussion with friends in Taiwan about QQQ&rsquo;s component stock adjustments and rebalancing mechanism, mentioning the Matthew effect and the idea that the strong get stronger. He also expresses surprise at the relatively small total market capitalization of QQQ.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s comments: Suggests focusing on long-term performance rather than short-term fluctuations and explains that QQQ&rsquo;s smaller market cap is due to the relatively low number of people who understand and invest in it.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 1:  The impact of QQQ component adjustments and rebalancing mechanisms on investments, and whether one should invest in the smaller 90 companies.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s reply:  Advises focusing on long-term performance and volatility, not short-term component adjustments. QQQ&rsquo;s adjustment mechanism ensures the inclusion of the best companies, illustrated by the performance of Mega 7 and MAGS. Points out the &ldquo;stronger get stronger&rdquo; phenomenon among large companies and explains QQQ&rsquo;s rebalancing mechanism.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2: James&rsquo;s methods, tools, and experience in creating short videos, and the application of AI technology.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s reply: Details the short video production process, including writing scripts, using speech recognition software, text-to-video conversion, and subtitle generation. He shares his experience with AI tools, emphasizing the importance of personal creation and the limitations of AI in emotional expression. Mentions using tools like speech recognition software, PowerDirector, and some Chinese and Taiwanese video production software.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Hui 
    <div id="hui" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#hui" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question 1:  FNGS has performed better than QQQ. Can FNGS replace QQQ?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s reply: No, because FNGS has excessive volatility and higher risk, illustrated by the 2000 tech bubble.  Emphasizes that asset allocation should consider volatility and maximum drawdown, not just performance. In the long run, QQQ offers better stability.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2: XLG has lower volatility than QQQ and decent returns.  Is it suitable for allocation?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s reply: No, because XLG&rsquo;s long-term performance is inferior to QQQ. He provides a performance comparison of QQQ and XLG from 2006 to the present, showing QQQ&rsquo;s significantly higher returns. Emphasizes focusing on long-term performance and avoiding investments with poor long-term track records despite low short-term volatility. Investments with less than 30 years of market history are not worth discussing.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Ethan 
    <div id="ethan" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ethan" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Shares his two-year experience learning and promoting the CLEC investment philosophy in China, highlighting the positive impact and challenges. He suggests domestic investors consider opening accounts in Hong Kong to invest in QQQ and shares the advantages of investing in Hong Kong.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s comments: Affirms Ethan&rsquo;s sharing and promotional efforts, agrees with his suggestion of opening accounts in Hong Kong, and adds to the advantages, such as access to leveraged ETFs and money market funds, making the 433 asset allocation plan more comprehensive.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Ling 
    <div id="ling" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ling" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Shares her experience and understanding of the CLEC investment philosophy and how she applies it to life, such as educating her children.  She shares a childhood story of collecting shells for money and her desire for investment.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s comments: Acknowledges Ling&rsquo;s sharing and praises her proactive approach.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question: How to pledge stocks after retirement?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s reply: Explains the process of pledging stocks after retirement and emphasizes the importance of asset allocation.  Suggests the 433 asset allocation plan, adjusted according to the value of the pledged stocks. Explains how to calculate borrowing limits based on the value of pledged stocks and how to add collateral.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Martin 
    <div id="martin" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#martin" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Shares his investment experience and observations in Europe and expresses envy for the US investment environment. Mentions issues such as strict regulations and heavy tax burdens in Europe.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s comments: Agrees with Martin&rsquo;s viewpoint, analyzes the disadvantages of the European investment environment, such as high taxes and restrictions on the tech industry, and explains his focus on the US market. Points out that European socialist ideology and wealth expropriation are detrimental to capital accumulation and economic development.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Ying 
    <div id="ying" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ying" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Reflects on some mistakes in his investment journey, such as missing a year of market gains for a 5% fixed deposit interest rate, and shares his experience and insights on all-in investing in QQQ and TQQQ, and how he persuaded his wife to start investing.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s comments: Affirms Ying&rsquo;s sharing and reiterates the &ldquo;buy whenever you have money, never sell&rdquo; strategy and the all-in investment philosophy. Points out the importance of overcoming human weaknesses for investment success.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Pamela 
    <div id="pamela" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#pamela" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Shares the story of her neighbor being scammed by an accountant, reminding everyone to be cautious of investment risks and not to trust others blindly, even friends or professionals.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s comments: Agrees with Pamela&rsquo;s point, emphasizes the importance of improving one&rsquo;s financial literacy, and advises against over-reliance on financial advisors and accountants.  Points out that an accountant&rsquo;s responsibility is tax filing, not financial planning, so investors should not solely rely on their investment advice.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Nick 
    <div id="nick" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#nick" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Shares his investment experience in Canada, recommends HQU, the Canadian equivalent of QQQ, and discusses using IBKR&rsquo;s margin account. Highlights the challenges of investing in Canada and how to utilize IBKR for leverage.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s comments: Thanks Macro for sharing and suggests that IBKR&rsquo;s margin account might be an option for investors in countries without stock pledging.  Recommends that investors from other countries try and provide feedback on their experience with IBKR&rsquo;s margin account.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Julie 
    <div id="julie" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#julie" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question 1: Will pledging stocks affect mortgage refinancing?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s reply: No, stock pledging does not appear on credit reports and will not affect mortgage refinancing rates. He advises Julie to pledge her stocks as soon as possible and not wait for interest rates to decline, as future interest rate movements are unpredictable.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2: How to use TQQQ for investment and how to balance returns and risks? How to invest the money set aside for property taxes?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s reply: Suggests the 433 asset allocation plan, adjustable based on individual circumstances.  Emphasizes the importance of Beta management and recommends holding leveraged ETFs in retirement accounts. He advises against investing property tax money in TQQQ, recommending instead to keep it in cash or money market funds for unexpected needs.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Other Q&amp;A 
    <div id="other-qa" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#other-qa" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>James answers audience questions on topics such as 20-year investment returns, Warren Buffett&rsquo;s cash holdings, account selection for funds, short video production, the impact of FNG&rsquo;s bankruptcy on QQQ, simulating investments in the top ten stocks, stock pledging in Taiwan, 50/25/25 asset allocation, money market fund selection, leveraged ETF investment ratios, investment time horizons, and investment options in Canada.</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">IV. Key Takeaways 
    <div id="iv-key-takeaways" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv-key-takeaways" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>Buy whenever you have money, never sell.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This is James&rsquo;s consistent investment philosophy and the core strategy of CLEC.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Taiwan is a country with well-equipped weapons and cheap bullets.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>James praises Taiwan&rsquo;s investment environment, believing its financial tools, tax benefits, and low interest rates are highly advantageous for investors.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The most important thing in life is happiness.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>James emphasizes that the meaning of life lies in happiness, not in working and making money for its own sake.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>AI creations lack warmth.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>James shares his experience using AI tools for short video production, highlighting the limitations of AI in conveying emotions.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>You can be a benefactor to others, but whether they benefit depends on their destiny and fate.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>James shares his understanding of wealth and life, believing that an individual&rsquo;s wealth accumulation is influenced by destiny, fate, and luck, in addition to hard work.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The market has no peak, only higher highs; the market has no bottom, only a perpetual absence of a top or bottom.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>James emphasizes the long-term upward trend of the market and advises against trying to predict market tops and bottoms.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">V. Summary 
    <div id="v-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#v-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This session covered year-end rebalancing strategies, investment philosophy, the 433 asset allocation plan, CLEC short video production methods, and addressed various questions from students. James emphasized the importance of long-term investing and encouraged participants to create a reasonable asset allocation and rebalancing plan based on their individual circumstances, ignore short-term market fluctuations, and adhere to the &ldquo;buy whenever you have money, never sell&rdquo; principle.  During the Q&amp;A, students shared their investment experiences and concerns, raising questions about investment environments in different countries and specific investment products.  James provided professional guidance and advice, helping students better understand and apply the CLEC investment philosophy.</p>

  



<div
  
    class="flex px-4 py-3 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900"
  >

  <span
    
      class="text-primary-400 ltr:pr-3 rtl:pl-3 flex items-center"
    >

    

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M506.3 417l-213.3-364c-16.33-28-57.54-28-73.98 0l-213.2 364C-10.59 444.9 9.849 480 42.74 480h426.6C502.1 480 522.6 445 506.3 417zM232 168c0-13.25 10.75-24 24-24S280 154.8 280 168v128c0 13.25-10.75 24-23.1 24S232 309.3 232 296V168zM256 416c-17.36 0-31.44-14.08-31.44-31.44c0-17.36 14.07-31.44 31.44-31.44s31.44 14.08 31.44 31.44C287.4 401.9 273.4 416 256 416z"/></svg>

  </span>


  </span>

  <span
    
      class="dark:text-neutral-300"
    ><strong>Disclaimer:</strong> This article is for personal learning notes only and does not constitute any investment advice.</span>
</div>

]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Millionaire Teacher: Book Notes</title>
      <link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1728295541698/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1728295541698/</guid>
      <description>Andrew Hallam, the author of this book, started investing at the age of 19 and achieved millionaire status within 17 years on a teacher&amp;#39;s salary. He shares nine financial principles that anyone can learn, yet few are taught in school. Through real-life stories and personal experiences, he guides readers on how to avoid common investment pitfalls and achieve financial freedom using the simplest, safest, and most effective methods.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[

<h2 class="relative group">I. Summary 
    <div id="i-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This book reveals a financial secret that everyone can learn but is rarely taught in school: <strong>You don&rsquo;t have to be a finance expert or a high-income earner to achieve financial freedom; prudent spending and rational investing are all it takes, even on a modest income.</strong></p>
<p>The author, Andrew Hallam, is a high school English teacher who started investing at age 19 and became a millionaire by age 38. He distilled his years of investment experience and wisdom he garnered from numerous financial wizards into nine simple and actionable principles. Supported by factual cases and personal anecdotes, he guides readers step-by-step towards financial freedom.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">II. Chapter Summaries 
    <div id="ii-chapter-summaries" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii-chapter-summaries" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Lesson One: Spend Like You Want to Grow Rich 
    <div id="lesson-one-spend-like-you-want-to-grow-rich" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#lesson-one-spend-like-you-want-to-grow-rich" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Distinguish between &ldquo;wants&rdquo; and &ldquo;needs&rdquo;</strong>: Spend rationally, control unnecessary expenses, and avoid over-reliance on credit cards. Invest the money you save.
<ul>
<li>Example: In his youth, the author lived an extremely frugal life to pay off his student loans as quickly as possible, succeeding within a year and subsequently investing all his income.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>How to buy a car for less</strong>: Opt for low-mileage, easy-to-resell used cars instead of blindly pursuing luxury vehicles.
<ul>
<li>Example: The author purchased low-mileage used Japanese cars in his youth and sold them for the same or even higher price after a few years, turning a small profit.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Buying a house: It&rsquo;s not about the down payment, but the interest rate</strong>:  Consider whether you can still afford the mortgage if the interest rate doubles to prevent financial strain due to rising rates.</li>
<li><strong>Start strong, don&rsquo;t rely on a &ldquo;rich dad&rdquo;</strong>:  Excessive financial support from parents can hinder a child&rsquo;s ability to create wealth independently. Teach them financial knowledge and skills, letting them learn how to earn, save, and invest on their own.
<ul>
<li>Example: Studies show that accountants who received financial assistance from their parents had 43% less average wealth than their self-made counterparts.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>You don&rsquo;t have to live like a pauper, but spend like a millionaire</strong>: Frugality does not equate to a lower quality of life. It&rsquo;s about investing the money you save, allowing it to work for you instead of the other way around.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Lesson Two: Use the Greatest Investment Ally You Have 
    <div id="lesson-two-use-the-greatest-investment-ally-you-have" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#lesson-two-use-the-greatest-investment-ally-you-have" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Leverage compound interest to accelerate wealth accumulation</strong>: The earlier you start investing, the longer the time horizon for compound interest to work its magic, leading to faster wealth growth.
<ul>
<li>Example: Investing $45 per month for 40 years yields significantly higher returns than investing $800 per month for only 25 years.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Buffett&rsquo;s &ldquo;Noah&rsquo;s Ark Principle&rdquo;</strong>: Invest early, just like Noah built the ark, don&rsquo;t wait for the &ldquo;flood&rdquo; to arrive before taking action.</li>
<li><strong>What to do when you get paid</strong>:  Keep track of your monthly expenses, calculate the amount available for investment, and transfer that money to your investment account on payday to avoid running out of funds at the end of the month.
<ul>
<li>Example: A couple the author knew, both teachers, realized their wasteful spending habits after tracking their expenses for three months. They subsequently allocated more money to investment, tripling their investment amount within two years.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>The stock market doesn&rsquo;t believe in tears, but it believes in time</strong>:  In the long run, the stock market rises with corporate earnings growth. Therefore, be patient and don&rsquo;t be intimidated by short-term market fluctuations. The author&rsquo;s stock market investments from 1990 had increased tenfold by 2016.
<ul>
<li>Example: Using Willy Wonka&rsquo;s chocolate factory as an analogy, the author explains the fundamentals of stocks, share prices, dividends, and the stock market in a simple and engaging way, highlighting the substantial returns from long-term investment.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Lesson Three: Small Fees Pack Big Punches 
    <div id="lesson-three-small-fees-pack-big-punches" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#lesson-three-small-fees-pack-big-punches" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Index funds: the secret to effortless wealth generation</strong>: Index funds track a specific market index, holding all or most of the stocks in that index to achieve the same return as the market. Their advantages lie in low costs, risk diversification, and stable returns.</li>
<li><strong>&ldquo;The Oracle of Omaha&rdquo; buys index funds</strong>:  Investment gurus like Warren Buffett, Paul Samuelson, and Daniel Kahneman all recommend index funds because they provide market-average returns at the lowest cost, outperforming the vast majority of actively managed funds over the long term.
<ul>
<li>Example: Buffett suggests putting 90% of one&rsquo;s funds into an ultra-low-cost S&amp;P 500 index fund.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>78% of active fund returns go to the advisors&rsquo; pockets</strong>:  The high fees (management fees, transaction costs, commissions, etc.) of actively managed funds will eat up most of the investors&rsquo; gains. Generally, their returns underperform index funds over the long run.
<ul>
<li>Example: The author&rsquo;s wife could have earned an extra $20,000 if she had invested in index funds instead of actively managed funds, as recommended by her financial advisor, over the past five years.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Don&rsquo;t bother picking &ldquo;top actively managed funds&rdquo;</strong>: There is no reliable method to consistently pick actively managed funds that will outperform index funds. Even if a fund has a history of exceptional performance, it doesn&rsquo;t guarantee future success. Their returns tend to revert to the average or lower in the long run.
<ul>
<li>Example: Investors in Morningstar&rsquo;s five-star-rated funds often experience lower long-term returns compared to index fund investors.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>&ldquo;International citizens&rdquo; should opt for index funds</strong>:  Actively managed funds are significantly more expensive outside of the US. Therefore, &ldquo;international citizens&rdquo; should choose index funds to lower their investment costs.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Lesson Four: Conquer the Enemy in the Mirror 
    <div id="lesson-four-conquer-the-enemy-in-the-mirror" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#lesson-four-conquer-the-enemy-in-the-mirror" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Stay rational, earn 10% returns even in a bear market</strong>: Don&rsquo;t let fear and greed dictate your investment decisions. Don&rsquo;t panic sell in a falling market or chase rising prices in a bull market. Stick to regular investment and buy more cheap stocks in a bear market to achieve higher returns in the long run.
<ul>
<li>Example: During the 2008-2009 financial crisis, investors who steadily invested in index funds at the lows ultimately reaped higher returns.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Don&rsquo;t try to time the market</strong>:  No one can accurately predict short-term market trends; don&rsquo;t try to beat the market by timing it. Market timing often causes you to miss the best investment opportunities, leading to lower investment returns.</li>
<li><strong>Earning 150%? Be wary of tech stocks</strong>:  Don&rsquo;t be fooled by high-growth, high-valuation stocks. Stock prices eventually revert to the level justified by corporate earnings. Blindly chasing hot stocks can easily lead to losing your entire investment.
<ul>
<li>Example: The dot-com bubble burst in 1999, causing countless investors to suffer heavy losses. The author himself lost nearly half of his money due to investing in Nortel Networks stock.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Falling stocks: a buying opportunity</strong>:  A bear market is the best time to invest. Seize the opportunity to buy more cheap stocks when prices are low. In the long run, stocks rise with corporate earnings growth.</li>
<li><strong>Young people should be excited when stocks rebound</strong>: Young investors have more time to allow compound interest to work its magic. They should actually hope for market declines to buy more low-priced stocks. Over the long term, stocks bought at a discount offer higher returns.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Lesson Five: Build Mountains of Money with a Responsible Portfolio 
    <div id="lesson-five-build-mountains-of-money-with-a-responsible-portfolio" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#lesson-five-build-mountains-of-money-with-a-responsible-portfolio" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Buy bonds as insurance for your stocks</strong>:  Bonds offer lower returns than stocks but have lower volatility, reducing the overall risk of your portfolio. They act as a buffer when the stock market falls.
<ul>
<li><strong>Short-term bonds: a safe haven for your money</strong>:  Short-term bonds are less sensitive to interest rate fluctuations and are more suitable as a &ldquo;safety cushion&rdquo; for your portfolio.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Adjusting your portfolio to profit from market crashes</strong>:  Determine the appropriate mix of stocks and bonds based on your age and risk tolerance. Rebalance your portfolio regularly (e.g., review it annually), selling bonds to buy stocks in a down market and selling stocks to buy bonds in a bull market.
<ul>
<li>Example: Before the 2008 financial crisis, the author created a portfolio with a 35% bond allocation. During the downturn, he consistently increased his stock holdings. Consequently, he achieved higher returns when the market rebounded.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>&ldquo;Globalize&rdquo; your investment</strong>: Don&rsquo;t limit yourself to the domestic market. Diversify your investments across the globe to further reduce risk and access a wider range of opportunities.</li>
<li><strong>&ldquo;Lazy portfolio&rdquo;: adjust once a year for annual returns</strong>:  Allocate your portfolio equally between stocks and bonds, rebalance once a year. This simple strategy delivers impressive long-term returns without demanding excessive time or effort.
<ul>
<li>Example: Following the &ldquo;Lazy Portfolio&rdquo; strategy allowed investors to achieve positive returns even during the 2008 financial crisis.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Lesson Six: Sample a &ldquo;Round-the-World&rdquo; Ticket to Indexing 
    <div id="lesson-six-sample-a-round-the-world-ticket-to-indexing" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#lesson-six-sample-a-round-the-world-ticket-to-indexing" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>ETFs: Access Global Markets with One Account</strong>:  Exchange-traded funds (ETFs) offer a convenient way to invest in index funds. They are traded on stock exchanges like individual stocks and cover a wide array of global markets.
<ul>
<li><strong>How to buy ETFs?:</strong> The author details the steps involved in buying ETFs: opening a brokerage account, finding the ETF ticker symbol, determining the price per share, and setting the investment amount, etc.</li>
<li><strong>Limit orders vs. market orders:</strong> The author explains these two common ETF order types and recommends using limit orders to avoid losses due to price fluctuations.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>US Indexes: Strategic Allocation for Optimal Returns</strong>:  For US investors, a portfolio split equally between a US stock market index, a global stock market index, and a US bond market index, with annual rebalancing, is recommended for stable long-term returns.
<ul>
<li>Example: The author&rsquo;s friend, Chris, following this approach, grew his portfolio by 73.09% in 10 years despite experiencing the 2008-2009 financial crisis.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Canadian Indexes: Minimize Costs for Maximum Returns</strong>:  Canadians can build a low-cost, diversified global portfolio using TD Bank&rsquo;s &ldquo;e-Series&rdquo; index funds or ETFs.
<ul>
<li>The author uses personal anecdotes to illustrate that Canadian financial advisors are more inclined to recommend actively managed funds while overlooking low-cost index funds.</li>
<li>He uses the example of Air Force Technician, Felix, to demonstrate how investors can build a low-cost, diversified portfolio through TD&rsquo;s &ldquo;e-Series&rdquo; index funds.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>UK Indexes: Avoid High Fees, Optimize your Portfolio</strong>:  UK investors should be wary of high-fee index funds. Building a diversified portfolio using low-cost index funds or ETFs provided by Vanguard or iShares is recommended.
<ul>
<li>The author cites Virgin Money as an example to demonstrate how high fees and tracking errors can significantly affect index fund returns.</li>
<li>He then uses the case of software engineer, Paul, to illustrate how investors can utilize iShares and Vanguard ETFs to build a low-cost, diversified portfolio.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Australian Indexes: Multi-Asset Portfolios, Lower Fees with Higher Investments</strong>:  Australians can opt for Vanguard&rsquo;s multi-asset LifeStrategy funds or utilize platforms like Stockspot and Ignition Wealth to build ETF portfolios.
<ul>
<li>The author shares the story of Andy, a software developer, who uses the Nabtrade brokerage platform to buy ETFs and create a diversified index fund portfolio.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Singapore indexes: Low cost, smart allocation</strong>:  Singaporean investors should also be cautious of high-fee index funds. Building a diversified portfolio using low-cost ETFs offered by Vanguard is recommended, but it&rsquo;s important to avoid ETFs traded on US exchanges to avert US estate taxes.
<ul>
<li>The author utilizes the example of &ldquo;Fundsupermart&rsquo;s&rdquo; &ldquo;S&amp;P 500 index&rdquo; fund to illustrate how high fees significantly impact long-term investment returns.</li>
<li>He further uses the case of a professor couple to show how investors can construct a diversified portfolio using ETFs traded on Singaporean and Canadian exchanges, thus avoiding US estate taxes.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Lesson Seven: No, You Don&rsquo;t Have to Invest on Your Own 
    <div id="lesson-seven-no-you-dont-have-to-invest-on-your-own" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#lesson-seven-no-you-dont-have-to-invest-on-your-own" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Why do index investors lag behind the index?:</strong> Many investors fall prey to their emotions, making irrational decisions during market fluctuations, or are swayed by investment predictions, ultimately hindering their returns.
<ul>
<li>Example: Some investors panic sell during market downturns and chase rising prices in a bull market, resulting in returns far lower than the index itself.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>US Robo-Advisors: Let the Smart Investors &ldquo;Win&rdquo; Effortlessly</strong>: Robo-advisor platforms can help investors create and manage low-cost index fund portfolios, rebalancing them regularly, and preventing investors from damaging their accounts.
<ul>
<li>Example: Vanguard&rsquo;s Target Retirement Funds offer a one-stop solution at a very low cost, suitable for those who prefer a hands-off approach to investment.
<ul>
<li>The author uses his wife as an example to highlight the advantages of Vanguard Target Retirement Funds: achieving positive returns even without investment knowledge.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Vanguard&rsquo;s Comprehensive Financial Advisory Services:</strong> Vanguard provides comprehensive financial planning services at a low cost, making it a good option for investors seeking professional advice.</li>
<li><strong>Investment Guidance Training Services:</strong> Mark Zoril of PlanVision offers training services that guide investors to open low-cost brokerage accounts and build their own index fund portfolios.</li>
<li><strong>Investment Enhancement Services:</strong> Scott Burns of AssetBuilder provides investment enhancement services, using Dimensional Fund Advisors (DFA) index funds to help investors build a &ldquo;Lazy Portfolio&rdquo;.
<ul>
<li>The author elaborates on DFA&rsquo;s investment philosophy: pursuing excess returns through small-cap and value stocks.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Betterment, Rebalance IRA, SigFig, and Wealthfront:</strong> These companies also offer robo-advisory services, building and managing portfolios consisting of index funds or ETFs for investors.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Canadian Robo-Advisors: Lower Cost and More Targeted:</strong> Robo-advisor platforms in Canada, such as WealthBar and Wealthsimple, offer lower-cost, personalized services, tailoring portfolios to suit client risk tolerance and investment goals.
<ul>
<li>The author uses personal experiences to demonstrate that Canadian bank advisors still favor actively managed funds over low-cost index funds.</li>
<li><strong>Tangerine:</strong> Tangerine bank provides Canadian investors with a financial product that encompasses a diversified index fund portfolio. Low cost makes it suitable for those who prefer to invest small sums regularly.
<ul>
<li>The author uses 19-year-old Katie as an example to show how young people can leverage Tangerine&rsquo;s investment products for regular investing.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>WealthBar:</strong> WealthBar offers Canadian investors five portfolio management solutions and provides comprehensive financial planning based on their risk tolerance.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>UK Robo-Advisors: Diversified Index Fund Baskets</strong>: UK robo-advisor platforms, like Nutmeg, construct diverse index fund portfolios for investors, rebalancing regularly, although their fees are comparatively higher.</li>
<li><strong>Australian Robo-Advisors: Increasing Competition and Falling Fees</strong>: The Australian robo-advisor market is highly competitive with decreasing fees. Platforms like Stockspot and Ignition Wealth offer low-cost, personalized ETF portfolio management services.</li>
<li><strong>Singapore Robo-Advisors: Avoid &ldquo;Suicidal&rdquo; Asset Allocation:</strong>  Singapore&rsquo;s robo-advisory market is nascent. Investors should opt for companies that don&rsquo;t utilize ETFs traded on US exchanges to avoid US estate tax liabilities.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Lesson Eight: Peek Inside A Pilferers Playbook 
    <div id="lesson-eight-peek-inside-a-pilferers-playbook" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#lesson-eight-peek-inside-a-pilferers-playbook" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Identifying Financial Advisors&rsquo; Tricks:</strong> Financial advisors use various tactics to persuade investors to buy actively managed funds, such as claiming that &ldquo;index funds are more dangerous during downturns&rdquo; or that &ldquo;index funds can only achieve average returns,&rdquo; both of which are misleading.
<ul>
<li>Examples:  When the author and his friend sought advice from financial advisors, they were aggressively steered towards actively managed funds without mention of their high fees or lower returns. One advisor even claimed index funds were riskier and that actively managed funds were better suited for navigating bear markets.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Index Fund Returns Outshine &ldquo;Financial Elites&rdquo;</strong>: Even seasoned investment professionals like pension fund managers struggle to beat index fund returns. Many pension funds have started shifting towards indexed investments, allocating a significant portion of their funds to index funds.
<ul>
<li>Example: A study by US consulting firm FutureMetrics revealed that less than 30% of large corporate pension funds outperformed a diversified portfolio holding 60% S&amp;P 500 index and 40% corporate bond index.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Don&rsquo;t Accidentally Become a &ldquo;Second-Rate Investor&rdquo;</strong>:  Don&rsquo;t be fooled by financial advisors&rsquo; sales pitches. Trust the data and facts - index funds are the most reliable way to profit in the stock market. Advisors&rsquo; interests are often at odds with those of their clients; they prioritize commission income over investor returns.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Lesson Nine: Avoid Seduction 
    <div id="lesson-nine-avoid-seduction" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#lesson-nine-avoid-seduction" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Stock Picking Scams: Do their stock recommendations really work?:</strong>  Investment newsletter predictions are often inaccurate, and their recommended stocks are likely to lead to financial ruin. Their primary goal is to attract subscribers, not to help investors make money.
<ul>
<li>Example: The author invested in stocks recommended by &ldquo;The Gilder Technology Report&rdquo; and suffered significant losses.  The author of that report continues to publish similar reports, using the lure of high past returns to attract investors.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Investing in Emerging Markets: Don&rsquo;t be fooled by GDP</strong>: High economic growth does not necessarily translate into high stock market returns. Be cautious when investing in emerging markets. They are more volatile and risky, and their long-term returns may not surpass developed markets.
<ul>
<li>Example: While China&rsquo;s GDP grew rapidly from 2008 to 2016, its stock market performance was lackluster, with investors in a large-cap Chinese stock ETF experiencing a 30% loss.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>&ldquo;Gold speculation&rdquo;: It&rsquo;s not investing</strong>: Gold has a low long-term return rate with high price volatility, making it unsuitable for long-term investment. &ldquo;Gold speculators&rdquo; attempt to profit from price differences by buying low and selling high, a risky strategy that cannot guarantee stable long-term returns.
<ul>
<li>Example: $1 worth of gold purchased in 1801 would only be worth $73 in 2016, whereas a $1 investment in the US stock market during the same period would turn into $16.24 million.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Investment Magazines: The Untold Truth</strong>:  Investment magazines rely heavily on advertising revenue, leading them to cater to their advertisers rather than prioritize investors&rsquo; needs. They often recommend high-fee actively managed funds while neglecting low-cost index funds.
<ul>
<li>Example: In April 2009, &ldquo;SmartMoney&rdquo; magazine recommended bond funds and gold, ignoring the investment opportunity presented by low-priced stocks amidst the financial crisis.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Hedge Funds: Picking the Pockets of the Rich</strong>: Hedge funds charge exorbitant fees and carry significant risks, with long-term returns that are often no better, and sometimes even worse, than index funds. Their reported performance is often skewed by &ldquo;survivorship bias&rdquo; and &ldquo;backfill bias.&rdquo;
<ul>
<li>Example: Hedge funds struggle to achieve an average annual compounded return of even 1%.  Only one out of the top 20 largest hedge funds has outperformed the S&amp;P 500 index.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Don&rsquo;t buy currency-hedged ETFs</strong>: Currency-hedged ETFs  aim to eliminate the impact of exchange rate fluctuations on investment returns. However, the hedging mechanism itself incurs costs, decreasing a portfolio&rsquo;s returns.
<ul>
<li>Example: Research indicates that non-currency-hedged ETFs generally outperform their currency-hedged counterparts over the long term.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Don&rsquo;t fall for smart beta funds</strong>: These hybrid funds fall somewhere between active and index funds, attempting to achieve excess returns with specific strategies. Their effectiveness is debated, and their fees are generally higher.
<ul>
<li>Example:  Studies show that the market capitalization growth of smart beta funds has been primarily due to valuation increases, not corporate earnings growth, suggesting potential decreases in future returns.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Don&rsquo;t blindly buy into small-cap stocks</strong>:  Small-cap stocks, those of smaller companies, offer high growth potential, but also carry higher risk. Investing in them requires careful consideration and risk tolerance; avoid chasing high returns blindly.</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">III. Key Quotes 
    <div id="iii-key-quotes" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii-key-quotes" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>You don&rsquo;t have to be a financial expert; even with a moderate income, you can achieve financial freedom through prudent spending and rational investing.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This encapsulates the core message of the book:  financial management and investment are not exclusive to the wealthy; ordinary people can also achieve financial freedom through learning and practical application.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Time is money.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This emphasizes that time is our most valuable asset. The earlier you start investing, the longer the time horizon for compound interest to work its magic, leading to faster wealth accumulation.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>A successful investor should follow two principles: the first is to never lose money and the second is to never forget the first principle.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This quote highlights the importance of risk management and capital preservation in investing.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The investor&rsquo;s task is to focus on the horse, not the jockey.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This means that investors should prioritize a company&rsquo;s intrinsic value over the fund manager&rsquo;s individual ability. Over the long run, a company&rsquo;s profitability is the most important factor determining its stock price.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>If you plan to live off hamburgers for the rest of your life, but you don&rsquo;t own any cattle, would you want beef prices to go up or down?</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Buffett used this analogy to illustrate that stocks represent ownership in a company. When share prices fall, long-term investors should view it as an opportunity to buy more shares.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The most insidious devil is the high cost associated with holding certain actively managed funds.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This quote emphasizes that investment costs are one of the most important factors affecting investment returns. Choosing low-cost index funds maximizes gains.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>How much you can accumulate in your lifetime depends not on how much you can earn, but on how you invest. Money finds people more effectively than people find money. Let your money work for you, not the other way around.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Buffett stresses the importance of investment and financial management, pointing out that wealth accumulation relies not only on income but also on how you manage and invest your money.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Too much money can harm investment returns.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This seemingly paradoxical statement highlights a critical principle: avoid over-diversification and the blind pursuit of high returns. Concentrating your investments in a few high-quality assets and holding them for the long term often yields better results.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>In stock investing, luck inevitably plays a role, but in the long run, good luck and bad luck offset each other. For sustained success, skills and sound principles are essential.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This emphasizes that the key to successful investing lies in mastering the correct investment philosophy and principles and adhering to them in the long term, rather than relying on luck.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Let time and money work for you; you just need to sit back and wait for the results.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This emphasizes the power of long-term investment and compound interest. By choosing the right investment method and being patient, significant returns will follow.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">IV. Practical Implications 
    <div id="iv-practical-implications" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv-practical-implications" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This book&rsquo;s key takeaways include:</p>
<ol>
<li><strong>Developing a sound financial mindset</strong>: Understand the importance of thrift, control unnecessary spending, and invest your savings.</li>
<li><strong>Mastering simple and effective investment methods</strong>: Learn to leverage compound interest, start investing early, choose low-cost index funds, and commit to long-term investments. Avoid being swayed by short-term market volatility.</li>
<li><strong>Avoiding common investment pitfalls</strong>:  Be wary of financial advisors&rsquo; sales tactics, don&rsquo;t blindly trust investment predictions or stock recommendations, and avoid being lured by the promise of high returns.</li>
<li><strong>Developing financial independence</strong>: Learn basic financial knowledge and skills, don&rsquo;t rely solely on financial advisors, and learn to make investment decisions independently.</li>
</ol>
<hr>

<section class="space-y-10 w-full">
    
    
        
            






















  <a class="flex flex-wrap article " href="/en/posts/1728295490690-book-list/">
    
        
        <div class="w-full md:w-auto h-full thumbnail nozoom thumbnailshadow md:mr-7" style="background-image:url(/posts/1728295490690-book-list/featured_hu4424409690304057825.jpg);"></div>
        
      <div class=" mt-3 md:mt-0">
      <div class="items-center text-left text-xl font-semibold">
        
        <div class="font-bold text-xl text-neutral-800 decoration-primary-500 hover:underline hover:underline-offset-2 dark:text-neutral"
          href="/en/posts/1728295490690-book-list/">Recommended Reading List</div>
        
        
        
      </div>
      <div class="text-sm text-neutral-500 dark:text-neutral-400">
        











  



















<div class="flex flex-row flex-wrap items-center">
  
  
  <time datetime="2024-10-01T00:00:00&#43;00:00">1 October 2024</time>
  

  
  
</div>





<div class="flex flex-row flex-wrap items-center">
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  <span style="margin-top:0.5rem" class="mr-2" onclick="window.open(&#34;/en/tags/recommended/&#34;,'_self');">
    <span class="flex" style="cursor: pointer;">
  <span class="rounded-md border border-primary-400 px-1 py-[1px] text-xs font-normal text-primary-700 dark:border-primary-600 dark:text-primary-400">
    Recommended
  </span>
</span>
  </span>
  
  <span style="margin-top:0.5rem" class="mr-2" onclick="window.open(&#34;/en/tags/book/&#34;,'_self');">
    <span class="flex" style="cursor: pointer;">
  <span class="rounded-md border border-primary-400 px-1 py-[1px] text-xs font-normal text-primary-700 dark:border-primary-600 dark:text-primary-400">
    Book
  </span>
</span>
  </span>
  
  
  
  
</div>




      </div>
      
    </div>
  </a>

        
    
</section>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>00485 Buying a house will only make you poor. Investing makes you rich. Borrowing money to keep your assets growing is the way to become wealthy</title>
      <link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1728259977859/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1728259977859/</guid>
      <description>This episode focuses on investment philosophy, strategies to avoid scams, and the impact of China&amp;#39;s newest economic policies on the global market. James reiterates the importance of long-term investment in index funds, specifically QQQ, and advises investors to control their emotions and resist market volatility. He uses real-life examples and data to illustrate the concept of borrowing for consumption, investing for asset growth, and analyzes China&amp;#39;s recent economic stimulus policies, viewing them as a positive sign for global economic recovery. </description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<lite-youtube videoid="zJdXwFaec2c" playlabel="zJdXwFaec2c" params=""></lite-youtube>



<h2 class="relative group">I. Main Topic 
    <div id="i-main-topic" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-main-topic" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This episode primarily discusses proper investment philosophy, ways to avoid investment traps, and the implications of China&rsquo;s latest economic policies for the global market. James emphasizes the importance of long-term investment in index funds, particularly QQQ, and reminds investors to maintain emotional control and not be swayed by market fluctuations. He uses specific examples and data to illustrate the concept of &ldquo;borrow for consumption, invest for asset growth,&rdquo; while also analyzing China&rsquo;s recently introduced series of economic stimulus policies, believing them to be a positive signal for a global economic recovery.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">II. Briefing Content 
    <div id="ii-briefing-content" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii-briefing-content" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<ul>
<li><strong>Investment Philosophy:</strong>
<ul>
<li>Emotions are the biggest enemy in investing. You need to avoid being influenced by news and information, stay rational, and refrain from chasing rising or falling markets.</li>
<li>Investing requires a long-term perspective, aiming for a timeframe of 40 years or more. Warren Buffett acquired 99% of his wealth after the age of 50, demonstrating that patience is key to wealth creation.</li>
<li>Choose investment targets that are consistently stable and provide high returns. Index funds are the best option, especially QQQ, which boasts a long-term annualized return of 14%.</li>
<li>Adhere to the &ldquo;never sell&rdquo; strategy to allow assets to continue appreciating. Avoid selling stocks unless absolutely necessary.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Scam Avoidance Guide:</strong>
<ul>
<li>Be wary of various investment traps. Do not trust any projects that guarantee high returns, especially those that require you to sell existing assets for new investments.</li>
<li>Do not readily believe any investment or financial management information received via phone, text messages, or online platforms. Any information involving bank accounts or government departments must be verified through official channels.</li>
<li>Be cautious of aggressive sales tactics from financial institutions. Stick to your investment plan and avoid being lured by various fancy financial products.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Regarding Real Estate Investment:</strong>
<ul>
<li>James advises against homeownership for average working individuals, believing it turns them into &ldquo;mortgage slaves&rdquo; burdened with heavy loan pressure, hindering wealth accumulation.</li>
<li>He advocates for a &ldquo;rent instead of buy&rdquo; approach, suggesting using a stock pledge loan to rent high-quality housing at lower interest rates, then investing the saved funds for higher returns.</li>
<li>Consider purchasing real estate only when your assets reach a certain scale and you can comfortably afford the payment.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>New Trends in China&rsquo;s Economy:</strong>
<ul>
<li>The People&rsquo;s Bank of China recently introduced a series of potent fiscal policies, including reserve requirement ratio and interest rate cuts, injecting funds into banks, and encouraging stock purchases, to stimulate economic growth.</li>
<li>These policies will contribute positively to stabilizing China&rsquo;s real estate market, boosting consumer confidence, and promoting global economic recovery.</li>
<li>Investors should pay attention to developments in the Chinese market and seize new investment opportunities.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">III. Q&amp;A Session 
    <div id="iii-qa-session" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii-qa-session" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p><strong>IM:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Through conversations with individuals of different age groups, IM discovered that most people have insufficient awareness of long-term savings and are often constrained by mortgages and other factors. By comparing the returns of index funds in different countries and regions with those of fixed deposits and pensions, IM illustrated the advantages of long-term investment in index funds.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>INGYNYING:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: INGYNYING&rsquo;s mother wanted to sell all her assets to purchase a house but, after persuasion, realized that this would lead to losing opportunities for asset appreciation. Many of INGYNYING&rsquo;s friends are afraid of change, preferring to endure the hardships of their current situation rather than attempt new investment methods.</li>
<li>Question: How to convince family members to accept new investment concepts?</li>
<li>James&rsquo; answer: Utilize data and case studies for illustration, such as comparing the long-term returns of fixed deposits and index funds, and sharing success stories of investors. It&rsquo;s also important to respect family members&rsquo; choices and refrain from forcing them to accept new ideas.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Allen:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Questions:  Should someone with assets worth 50 times their annual living expenses use their salary to pay for a car? How can a couple combine their stock accounts for collateral purposes?</li>
<li>James&rsquo; answer: It is recommended to utilize Tesla&rsquo;s official website loan to purchase a vehicle, then use funds from a stock pledge loan to repay the car loan. Dedicate your salary entirely to investment. Couples can combine their accounts through a joint account for collateral, sharing the limit, while their accounts remain individually managed.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Eric:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Question: Eric&rsquo;s mother is visiting the US and is concerned about medical expenses. How should this be  handled?</li>
<li>James&rsquo; answer:  Purchasing travel insurance is advised, but excessive worry is unnecessary. Most non-emergency situations can be treated back home. If encountering extremely high medical costs, attempting negotiation with the hospital or seeking alternative solutions is possible. Due to the specific circumstances of foreign nationality and lack of income, the hospital may choose not to pursue the medical expenses.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Dean:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Dean purchased a new car using Tesla&rsquo;s website loan and a stock pledge loan, conserving a significant amount of capital. Learning about investing boosted Dean&rsquo;s confidence to decline a high-paying job and choose to stay home with their child.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Michael:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Questions: How to secure a loan from Tesla&rsquo;s official website for a car purchase? Can funds from 401k or IRA accounts be used for collateral? What are the options if QQQ is not available in their company&rsquo;s 401k plan?</li>
<li>James&rsquo; answer: To apply for a car loan through Tesla&rsquo;s website, choose the desired model and configuration, click &ldquo;Order Now&rdquo;, and select &ldquo;Finance&rdquo;. Funds in retirement accounts cannot be used as collateral; it is recommended to transfer part of those funds to a brokerage account for collateral purposes.  Alternative options include choosing an S&amp;P 500 index fund or inquiring with the company about the possibility of Blockage Link to invest in QQQ.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>EVA:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Question: As a single, middle-aged woman with limited savings, how to balance work and investment? Should selling the house be considered for investment purposes?</li>
<li>James&rsquo; answer: Continue working diligently while consistently making monthly investments. Even small amounts will accumulate over 8-9 years, reaching the threshold for collateral, allowing you to leverage and accelerate wealth growth. Selling a house for investment is an option but requires careful consideration based on personal circumstances.  If renting is more cost-effective, choose to rent and allocate the funds to investments yielding higher returns.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Jenny:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Questions:  Any knowledge regarding the latest Roth SEP IRA policy?</li>
<li>James&rsquo; answer: The policy information is quite recent, and the accuracy of the $69,000 limit requires verification. Consulting with professionals like a financial advisor at Chase or Lisa is recommended. As it is a new product, not all institutions may offer it.</li>
<li>Sharing: Jenny shared a personal experience of being scammed, reminding everyone to exercise caution and avoid trusting any investment information, particularly those spread through unofficial channels.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Haoqing:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Haoqing relayed the experiences of close friends falling victim to scams, lamenting that scam tactics are constantly evolving and are hard to guard against, even for highly educated individuals.</li>
<li>Question: How can investment concepts be better conveyed to people around us to prevent them from being deceived? Is there a need to explain professional investment knowledge?</li>
<li>James&rsquo; answer: Avoid explaining intricate investment knowledge; simply emphasize the core principle of long-term investment in index funds. Excessive professional details may confuse them, making them more susceptible to being misled by other investment information and ultimately falling prey to scams.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Jason:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Recounted an NFT scam incident encountered on Clubhouse, warning everyone to be wary of risks in the cryptocurrency world. Expressed gratitude toward James&rsquo; investment philosophy for helping them avoid such traps.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Amy:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Amy shared personal encounters with scams, including impersonations of government departments and courier companies. She emphasized the importance of relying only on written communication and ignoring any investment information delivered through phone calls or text messages. Amy suggested that, when in doubt, contact official channels for clarification.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Becky:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Suggestion: Avoid answering calls from unfamiliar numbers, set up spam filters, and use a less important email address when necessary to share personal information to minimize the risk of scams.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Mike:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Question: What are your thoughts on China&rsquo;s most recent economic policies? Are they sustainable?</li>
<li>James&rsquo; answer: The People&rsquo;s Bank of China has introduced powerful policies that are having a positive impact on economic confidence. Investors should keep an eye on these developments. Although the policies appear to be heading in a positive direction, their sustainability remains to be seen.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Julia:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Question:  Any updates on the Roth SEP IRA policy? Are there any financial institutions already offering related products?</li>
<li>James&rsquo; answer: The policy information is fairly new, and the $69,000 limit&rsquo;s accuracy is debatable. Consulting with a professional is advised. Being a new product, not all institutions might offer it yet.</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">IV. Noteworthy Points 
    <div id="iv-noteworthy-points" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv-noteworthy-points" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>You have enough money when you have enough.&quot;
&ndash; Many people</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Many individuals believe that having just enough to get by is sufficient. This is a mistaken notion, as money is never truly enough. True financial freedom lies in possessing the power of choice  going wherever you want, doing whatever you desire  instead of being constrained by finances.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;Never borrow money for investments.&rdquo;
&ndash; Many people</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Many believe that borrowing for investment is unwise; however, this viewpoint is overly cautious. True investors, like Warren Buffett, skillfully leverage debt. Following the principle of &ldquo;borrow for consumption, invest for asset growth&rdquo;, the correct approach is to use borrowed money for expenses and personal money for investment. This enables rapid wealth accumulation.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>All investment information received through phone calls, text messages, or online platforms is not trustworthy.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Nowadays, numerous scams operate through these channels. It&rsquo;s crucial to exercise caution and avoid blindly believing any financial advice or information. Anything involving bank accounts or government departments must be verified through official sources. Additionally, seeking guidance from qualified professionals is essential.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Investment must be consistently stable over the long term, which is why index funds are the only viable option.&quot;
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Within the complex investment landscape, index funds stand out as a few reliable options capable of offering consistent stability and high returns. Index funds are like living organisms; they will never die, whereas all individual stocks will eventually disappear within a century.  If you&rsquo;re looking for generational wealth, index funds are the way to go.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">V. Summary 
    <div id="v-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#v-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This episode is packed with valuable information and insights. It not only reiterates the importance of long-term index fund investment but also offers practical tips on scam prevention and provides an in-depth analysis of China&rsquo;s newest economic policies.  It is recommended to apply this knowledge to your investment practices and strive for financial freedom.</p>

  



<div
  
    class="flex px-4 py-3 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900"
  >

  <span
    
      class="text-primary-400 ltr:pr-3 rtl:pl-3 flex items-center"
    >

    

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M506.3 417l-213.3-364c-16.33-28-57.54-28-73.98 0l-213.2 364C-10.59 444.9 9.849 480 42.74 480h426.6C502.1 480 522.6 445 506.3 417zM232 168c0-13.25 10.75-24 24-24S280 154.8 280 168v128c0 13.25-10.75 24-23.1 24S232 309.3 232 296V168zM256 416c-17.36 0-31.44-14.08-31.44-31.44c0-17.36 14.07-31.44 31.44-31.44s31.44 14.08 31.44 31.44C287.4 401.9 273.4 416 256 416z"/></svg>

  </span>


  </span>

  <span
    
      class="dark:text-neutral-300"
    ><strong>Disclaimer:</strong> This article serves solely as personal study notes and does not constitute any investment advice.</span>
</div>

]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>00482 Investing in Humanity&#39;s Future: How to Harness the Power of Long-Term Investing, Grow Your Capital, and Make Time and Money Work for You?</title>
      <link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1728285089799/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1728285089799/</guid>
      <description>This session explored the essence of capitalism, critiquing the current financial education system and delving into a brainless investment strategy.  It emphasized the importance of asset allocation, achieving true financial freedom, and discussed topics like raising children with a sense of responsibility and finding one&amp;#39;s purpose in life.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<lite-youtube videoid="zQO1A-pLj6M" playlabel="zQO1A-pLj6M" params=""></lite-youtube>



<h2 class="relative group">I. Main Topic 
    <div id="i-main-topic" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-main-topic" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This session focused on the nature of capitalism and a brainless investment strategy. James criticized the current financial education system for &ldquo;enslaving&rdquo; the masses, arguing that it&rsquo;s designed to create workers, not capitalists. He stressed the importance of asset allocation and understanding the true meaning of wealth to achieve financial freedom in a capitalist society.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">II. Briefing Content 
    <div id="ii-briefing-content" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii-briefing-content" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<ul>
<li><strong>The Essence of Capitalism:</strong> James likened capitalism to a massive AI, with complex and opaque operating mechanisms that can easily lead to confusion. He argued that capitalism is not inherently evil but a tool, the key being the user&rsquo;s mindset and approach. Similar to the emergence of AI, capitalism also evolved from simple buy-and-sell relationships, its complexity making it difficult to predict and understand.</li>
<li><strong>Brainless Investing Strategy:</strong> &ldquo;Buy when you have money, and never sell.&rdquo;  He emphasized index fund investing, particularly the Nasdaq-100 index fund (QQQ), as the core investment vehicle. He opposed over-diversification, believing that focusing on the US market is more effective due to its fairness, justice, and openness.</li>
<li><strong>The Importance of Asset Allocation:</strong> Asset allocation is the core of investing, and it&rsquo;s crucial to develop a suitable strategy based on individual circumstances. James provided relevant links and video resources to help the audience learn more. A safe and sound asset allocation should be able to cope with market fluctuations, ensuring that even if the market drops to zero, one can still maintain their lifestyle for many years.  He highlighted the concept of &ldquo;being able to live comfortably for over a decade regardless of market fluctuations.&rdquo;</li>
<li><strong>The True Meaning of Financial Freedom:</strong> True financial freedom is not just about possessing wealth but also about &ldquo;knowing how to spend.&rdquo; This means understanding one&rsquo;s asset situation and knowing how much can be freely spent annually and monthly.  He emphasized the concept of &ldquo;knowing what to spend and spending it freely when desired.&rdquo;</li>
<li><strong>Parenting and Responsibility:</strong> He encouraged young people to have children and cultivate their sense of responsibility and financial awareness from a young age, enabling them to be self-reliant. He shared his experience of educating his daughter, emphasizing the importance of letting children bear the consequences of their actions, starting with small things.</li>
<li><strong>The Meaning of Learning:</strong> The purpose of learning is not just for monetary gain but for ultimate enlightenment. One should absorb knowledge like a sponge, cultivate thinking abilities, and ultimately reach the state of &ldquo;decreasing knowledge to gain wisdom.&rdquo; He used the example of martial arts manuals to illustrate that learning is a process from having something to having nothing.</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">III. Q&amp;A Session 
    <div id="iii-qa-session" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii-qa-session" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p><strong>YJ:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Sharing:  Discussed the lack of financial education in Asia, using the moon analogy to illustrate the differences between Eastern and Western education. Mentioned the inspirational Jewish financial education book, <em>Talmud</em>.</li>
<li>Question: How to educate children about finances from a young age.</li>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: Cultivate children&rsquo;s sense of responsibility from an early age, let them understand the meaning of wealth, and encourage them to start financial planning and investment early.  Avoid the negative views on money held by older generations.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Ying Nuo:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Sharing:  Shared the enlightenment gained after learning James&rsquo;s investment philosophy and how they implemented a simple asset allocation strategy, feeling secure and stable.</li>
<li>Question: Question about the pledging ratio.</li>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: Corrected the concept of the pledging ratio, emphasizing that retirees should pledge or borrow 2% of their total assets for living expenses, and young people should choose QQQ for better growth potential.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>IM:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Sharing:  Shared the simplicity and convenience of ETF investing, along with experiences sharing investment philosophies with friends and their views on having children.</li>
<li>Question:  Whether one should &ldquo;know too much&rdquo; in investing and life, and whether concerns about the future and AI would affect the willingness to have children.</li>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: Affirmed the importance of learning, but emphasized the need to learn to subtract, filtering out unimportant knowledge and information. &ldquo;Gaining knowledge daily, losing wisdom daily.&rdquo;  Encouraged young people not to be afraid of having children, sharing his understanding of the meaning of life - &ldquo;The meaning of life lies in creating the next generation of life in the universe.&rdquo;</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Chang An:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Sharing:  Shared news about a government department in China buying Nasdaq funds and becoming the largest shareholder.</li>
<li>Question: The implications of this action and its connection to US-China relations.</li>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: Affirmed the investment behavior of the government department, believing it to be the correct way to manage finances, and encouraged other government departments to learn from it.  He believed that governments should also engage in asset allocation.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Sam:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Shared entrepreneurial experiences and reflections on blind expansion, as well as personal confusion about retirement and future life.</li>
<li>Question: Preparing for retirement but feeling lost about the future state of life and unsure how to prepare.</li>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: Retirement is not the only option, listen to your inner voice, and find a lifestyle that makes you happy.  Don&rsquo;t over-plan the future; things will work out. He also suggested that Sam think about streamlining company processes, improving efficiency, and making employees happier at work.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Jason:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Sharing:  Examples of young people staying at home after graduating from university.</li>
<li>Question: How to help young people find meaning in life.</li>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: Cultivate children&rsquo;s sense of responsibility from an early age and let them learn to be self-reliant. Parents should not over-pamper their children, let them take responsibility, and encourage them to enter society and serve others.  He used his own daughter as an example to illustrate how to cultivate children&rsquo;s sense of responsibility from a young age.</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">IV. Key Takeaways 
    <div id="iv-key-takeaways" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv-key-takeaways" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>Spending money is moral.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Spending money should not be seen as negative; knowing how to spend and being willing to spend is the only way to truly enjoy the freedom that wealth brings. Also emphasized taking advantage of credit card benefits, points, etc.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The more we know, the greater the risks we don&rsquo;t know.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>As our knowledge increases, we need to be more cautious in identifying and assessing potential unknown risks. The real risk is the unknown risk.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The class of those who know and those who don&rsquo;t.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>There is a disparity in information and knowledge in capitalist society, leading to class differentiation between those who know and those who don&rsquo;t. Wealth and capital are concentrated in the hands of a few.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>I may not know where I&rsquo;m sailing, but I know there are some paths I can no longer take.
&ndash; Sam</p>
</blockquote>
<p>On the road of life, clarifying what you don&rsquo;t want is more important than knowing what you want.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">V. Conclusion 
    <div id="v-conclusion" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#v-conclusion" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This session covered investment philosophy, life philosophy, parenting experiences, and more. James, with his unique perspective and sharp language, criticized the shortcomings of the current financial education system, proposed a &ldquo;brainless investing&rdquo; strategy, and emphasized the importance of asset allocation and &ldquo;knowing how to spend.&rdquo;  He also discussed topics such as how to cultivate children&rsquo;s sense of responsibility and finding one&rsquo;s purpose in life, encouraging the audience to actively think about the meaning of life and contribute to society.</p>

  



<div
  
    class="flex px-4 py-3 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900"
  >

  <span
    
      class="text-primary-400 ltr:pr-3 rtl:pl-3 flex items-center"
    >

    

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M506.3 417l-213.3-364c-16.33-28-57.54-28-73.98 0l-213.2 364C-10.59 444.9 9.849 480 42.74 480h426.6C502.1 480 522.6 445 506.3 417zM232 168c0-13.25 10.75-24 24-24S280 154.8 280 168v128c0 13.25-10.75 24-23.1 24S232 309.3 232 296V168zM256 416c-17.36 0-31.44-14.08-31.44-31.44c0-17.36 14.07-31.44 31.44-31.44s31.44 14.08 31.44 31.44C287.4 401.9 273.4 416 256 416z"/></svg>

  </span>


  </span>

  <span
    
      class="dark:text-neutral-300"
    ><strong>Disclaimer:</strong> This article is only for personal learning notes and does not constitute any investment advice.</span>
</div>

]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>00479 Three Easy Examples of Getting Rich, The Power of Starting Early and Compound Interest</title>
      <link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1728391134352/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1728391134352/</guid>
      <description>In this session, James reiterates the importance of long-term index fund investing, illustrating the power of compounding interest with multiple examples. He also explains how to avoid common investment pitfalls to achieve financial freedom.  Additionally, James addresses audience questions on asset allocation, real estate investment, trusts, and children&amp;#39;s education funds.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<lite-youtube videoid="1VSo2I6xqG0" playlabel="1VSo2I6xqG0" params=""></lite-youtube>



<h2 class="relative group">I. Main Topic 
    <div id="i-main-topic" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-main-topic" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This session focuses on long-term index fund investing. The core message is: hold index funds firmly, ignore market fluctuations, maintain a proper asset allocation, and leverage the compounding effect of time to achieve financial freedom.  James also warns against investment scams and emphasizes avoiding unnecessary risks, while offering advice on investing in children&rsquo;s education funds.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">II. Presentation Summary 
    <div id="ii-presentation-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii-presentation-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<ul>
<li><strong>Advantages of Index Funds:</strong> Long-term index fund investing eliminates the need to follow short-term market fluctuations, international affairs, financial reports, and economic data.  Focus on asset allocation and consistent investment.</li>
<li><strong>The Power of Compounding:</strong> James uses several examples to illustrate the magic of compounding:  A monthly investment of 1000 TWD can grow to 17.3 million TWD in 40 years; a lump-sum investment of 100,000 TWD can reach 18.8 million TWD in 40 years;  starting early is crucial, as a 10-year delay significantly impacts final returns; one share of QQQ at 500 USD will become 25,000 USD in 30 years and 94,000 USD in 40 years.</li>
<li><strong>Safe Asset Allocation:</strong> Asset allocation is more critical than any market commentary. James recommends deleveraging and reducing debt for those nearing retirement, holding a larger cash position.  For younger individuals with stable income, leveraging can be considered. He suggests using a beta of 1.0 as a benchmark, reducing beta when the market is overheated, and increasing it back to 1.0 during market downturns.  For cash allocation, he references Buffett and suggests a sample allocation (Scenario 3): 40% index funds, 30% 2x leveraged funds, and 30% cash.</li>
<li><strong>Beware of Investment Scams:</strong>  Don&rsquo;t trust investment information from unknown accounts or websites. Choose legitimate financial institutions.</li>
<li><strong>Don&rsquo;t Give Money Directly to Children:</strong> James uses personal anecdotes and case studies to caution against putting assets directly in children&rsquo;s names, as this may discourage their initiative or cause family conflicts.  However, investing children&rsquo;s &ldquo;lucky money&rdquo; (red envelopes) for them is recommended as an educational fund.</li>
<li><strong>Risks of Real Estate Investment:</strong> James reiterates his advice against early homeownership for young people, arguing that real estate is illiquid, high-risk, and ties up capital that could be used for other investments.  He highlights the added risk in Taiwan, where mortgage debt remains even after foreclosure.</li>
<li><strong>Recommended Learning Resources:</strong> He recommends a YouTube channel called &ldquo;&rdquo; (What&rsquo;s Worth Reading) for valuable content on value investing.</li>
<li><strong>Emergency Fund:</strong> Maintain a cash reserve equivalent to six months of living expenses in a money market fund account. Investing this emergency fund in stocks is not recommended.</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">III. Q&amp;A Session 
    <div id="iii-qa-session" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii-qa-session" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p><strong>Jeff:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Shares:  Highlights misconceptions about investing held by two listeners and emphasizes the importance of carefully studying James&rsquo;s lecture notes, particularly the chart on page two.</li>
<li>James&rsquo;s response:  Affirms Jeff&rsquo;s points and re-emphasizes the importance of a solid investment philosophy to avoid being swayed by market noise.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Cat:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Shares: A listener holding 35 million TWD in 00662 still finds the 2% withdrawal rate insufficient. Discusses the spending needs and inheritance considerations of single individuals.</li>
<li>James&rsquo;s response: Different indices have different volatility and dividend yields, requiring adjustments to withdrawal rates. For higher withdrawals, consider ETFs with higher dividend yields, such as 0056, which yields around 4-5%.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>H:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Question:  High rental costs for young people, should they buy a house?  Mortgages offer tax deductions, while renting does not.  Concerned about insufficient funds for leveraged investing.</li>
<li>James&rsquo;s response:  Recommends watching the &ldquo;30 Years of Different Destinies&rdquo; video, which analyzes the pros and cons of renting versus buying.  Young people should prioritize investing in index funds to build wealth through compounding and consider buying a house later.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Yonglin:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Question: Should money be invested in children&rsquo;s names for long-term holding?  Should a mortgage-free house be sold to invest in index funds after retirement?</li>
<li>James&rsquo;s response:  Advises against putting money directly in children&rsquo;s names.  Retirees should deleverage, and selling a mortgage-free house to invest in index funds is a viable option.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Mike:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Shares: Success story of investing his children&rsquo;s education fund in QQQ.  Gives the example of Taoyuan Language in Taiwan, suggesting potential leveraged investment through real estate mortgages.</li>
<li>Question: How to establish a family trust and manage generational wealth like the Rockefeller family?</li>
<li>James&rsquo;s response:  Recommends contacting Lisa for trust advice when assets reach a certain level and age. For now, focus on investing. Trusts can be considered around 70-80 years old. Single individuals or those without children should rely on trusts, appointing guardians and executors.  Those with children can consider Trust 2.0, with the bank as executor and children as supervisors.  Family foundations managed by professional institutions are also an option.  Recommends the Walmart family&rsquo;s living trust as a model.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Becky, Jessie, and Other Participants:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Becky: Difficulties of renting at an older age.</li>
<li>Jessie: How to balance saving for an emergency fund, paying off a mortgage, and investing simultaneously.</li>
<li>Other Participants: Questions about real estate investment, cash management, insurance, Bitcoin, and Japanese government bonds.</li>
<li>James&rsquo;s response:  Addresses each question and reiterates his investment philosophy.  For example, young people should avoid real estate and insurance due to high risks; long-term bonds and municipal bonds are not suitable for emergency funds.</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">IV. Key Takeaways 
    <div id="iv-key-takeaways" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv-key-takeaways" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>Time is the source of all power.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>James uses examples like the evolution of Earth&rsquo;s ecosystem and human evolution to illustrate the power of time and emphasize the importance of long-term investing.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Don&rsquo;t casually help others with money.  People will resent you for it for a lifetime.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Cautions against testing human nature with money and emphasizes setting boundaries with financial assistance.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The earlier you invest, the better.  Keep enough emergency funds. The earlier you invest, the lower the risk.
&ndash; Jeff</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Emphasizes the importance of early investing and maintaining an emergency fund.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Laugh a little; how long a scammer can scam is determined by the fool.
&ndash; Mike</p>
</blockquote>
<p>A cynical comment on the prevalence of scammers and a reminder to stay vigilant.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">V. Conclusion 
    <div id="v-conclusion" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#v-conclusion" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>The core message of this session remains long-term index fund investing. James uses clear language and vivid examples to reiterate the power of compounding and the importance of starting early. He also addresses audience questions on asset allocation, real estate, trusts, emergency funds, and children&rsquo;s education funds, sharing advice on avoiding common investment traps and achieving financial freedom.  He further recommends learning resources and provides commentary on social phenomena.</p>

  



<div
  
    class="flex px-4 py-3 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900"
  >

  <span
    
      class="text-primary-400 ltr:pr-3 rtl:pl-3 flex items-center"
    >

    

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M506.3 417l-213.3-364c-16.33-28-57.54-28-73.98 0l-213.2 364C-10.59 444.9 9.849 480 42.74 480h426.6C502.1 480 522.6 445 506.3 417zM232 168c0-13.25 10.75-24 24-24S280 154.8 280 168v128c0 13.25-10.75 24-23.1 24S232 309.3 232 296V168zM256 416c-17.36 0-31.44-14.08-31.44-31.44c0-17.36 14.07-31.44 31.44-31.44s31.44 14.08 31.44 31.44C287.4 401.9 273.4 416 256 416z"/></svg>

  </span>


  </span>

  <span
    
      class="dark:text-neutral-300"
    ><strong>Disclaimer:</strong> This document is for personal learning notes only and does not constitute any investment advice.</span>
</div>

]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>00478 Invest Immediately and Hold Long-Term: Key Strategies for Achieving Financial Freedom</title>
      <link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1728479738630/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1728479738630/</guid>
      <description>This episode focuses on risk control and investment mindset. James reiterates the importance of asset allocation, especially during market volatility. He explains in detail how to allocate assets in different scenarios and how to maintain a positive investment mindset. In addition, James answers questions from the audience regarding insurance and financial products, Apple Vision Pro, the role of Wall Street, and 401K accounts. </description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<lite-youtube videoid="neKoOJhqK3c" playlabel="neKoOJhqK3c" params=""></lite-youtube>



<h2 class="relative group">I. Main Topic 
    <div id="i-main-topic" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-main-topic" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>During periods of market volatility, investors should prioritize risk control and maintain a positive and optimistic mindset. By establishing a rational asset allocation strategy, such as holding cash, index funds, and leveraged funds, and selecting an appropriate allocation plan based on individual circumstances, investors can effectively mitigate market risks and ensure survival even in extreme situations.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">II. Briefing Content 
    <div id="ii-briefing-content" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii-briefing-content" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<ol>
<li>
<p><strong>Investment Objective:</strong> Identify high-quality investment targets, such as market-capitalization-weighted index funds, and hold them for the long term. Avoid chasing high-return investment targets, as excessive volatility may lead to an inability to hold, ultimately hindering returns.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Risk Control:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Do not overestimate your risk tolerance, as market downturns often exceed expectations.</li>
<li>Selling leads to permanent losses; the only mistake in the market is selling.</li>
<li>Investing is a process that goes against human nature, requiring the overcoming of fear and greed.</li>
<li>Always ensure survival in extreme market conditions, meaning possessing sufficient cash flow to sustain living expenses.</li>
<li>Holding cash is crucial for mitigating risks.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Investment Mindset:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Investors should remain perpetually optimistic, believing that the market will eventually rise.</li>
<li>Be patient, as wealth accumulation takes time.</li>
<li>Do not be swayed by short-term market fluctuations; adhere to a long-term investment strategy.</li>
<li>Do not attempt to predict the market, and ignore market noise.</li>
<li>Keep investing simple: buy when you have money and hold for the long term; avoid excessive trading.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Asset Allocation:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>The highest guiding principle of asset allocation is: you can still survive under extreme market conditions.</li>
<li>Retirees need to hold more cash and can utilize leveraged funds to enhance returns while reducing risks.</li>
<li>Employed individuals can choose different asset allocation plans based on their circumstances, but ensure a certain proportion of cash holdings.</li>
<li>Do not alter your asset allocation based on market ups and downs, as this constitutes short-term trading behavior.</li>
<li>Asset allocation needs to be adjusted based on individual situations. For example, when significant events like retirement or purchasing a house occur, reassessment and adjustment of the asset allocation plan are necessary.</li>
<li>Leverage initially carries higher risk, which gradually decreases as the market rises.</li>
<li>It is recommended that retirement accounts comprise at least 30% of total assets to effectively avoid taxes during rebalancing.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Market Efficiency:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>The market is efficient; it&rsquo;s nearly impossible to find opportunities for consistent excess returns.</li>
<li>Do not readily believe investment strategies claiming to achieve excess returns, as they are often unsustainable.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>The Role of Wall Street:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Wall Street&rsquo;s primary roles are to provide liquidity and investment products, establish the framework for investment transactions, and lower the barriers to entry, allowing ordinary investors to participate.</li>
<li>Investors need to understand how Wall Street operates to avoid falling into its traps.</li>
<li>Market makers are a crucial part of Wall Street. They profit by providing bid-ask spreads while also offering liquidity to the market.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ol>


<h2 class="relative group">III. Q&amp;A Session 
    <div id="iii-qa-session" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii-qa-session" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p><strong>IM:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Black swan events remind us that people are forgetful, easily becoming optimistic during market upswings and panicking during downturns.</li>
<li>Question: How to control optimism and avoid overconfidence leading to bankruptcy?</li>
<li>James&rsquo;s response: Remember the highest guiding principle of asset allocation, ensuring survival under extreme conditions. Cash is the lifeline for survival.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Sunny:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Question: How to persuade people around me not to purchase insurance and financial products?</li>
<li>James&rsquo;s response: By calculating the annualized return rate of insurance products and comparing it with the return rates of other investment products, you can demonstrate that insurance and financial products offer lower returns. You can compare the return rates of insurance products with the long-term returns of index funds and point out that the income source for insurance companies and insurance agents is the premiums paid by customers.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Jason:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Experienced Apple Vision Pro and found its spatial computing capabilities impressive, but currently, it has limited functionality and applications, along with a high price tag.</li>
<li>Question: If investing is so simple, what is the role of Wall Street experts?</li>
<li>James&rsquo;s response: Wall Street&rsquo;s role primarily lies in providing liquidity, investment products, and the trading infrastructure, lowering the barriers to entry, enabling ordinary investors to participate in the market. Market makers are an essential component of Wall Street, making profits by providing bid-ask spreads while also offering liquidity to the market.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Brian:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Question: How can employed individuals utilize the asset allocation plan in Scenario 9?</li>
<li>James&rsquo;s response: Scenario 9 is suitable for retired individuals with loans. If you are employed and have substantial loans, such as a mortgage, you need to adjust the plan based on your circumstances. For example, pay off a portion of the loan before proceeding with asset allocation. Moreover, leverage carries higher risk initially, which gradually decreases as the market rises.</li>
<li>Question: How to allocate and rebalance assets between a 401K account and a Roth IRA account?</li>
<li>James&rsquo;s response: It&rsquo;s recommended that retirement accounts comprise at least 30% of total assets for effective tax avoidance during rebalancing. Due to the limited investment options within a 401K account, direct purchase of QQQ may not be possible. You can use similar alternatives or transfer funds to a Roth IRA account for more flexibility.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Yingying:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Question: What&rsquo;s the difference between QQQ and QQQM?</li>
<li>James&rsquo;s response: The market is efficient. There won&rsquo;t be a significant difference in the long-term returns of QQQ and QQQM. Choose QQQ, which has lower fees.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Grace:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Question: Should I convert 0066 to 00670L during a market downturn?</li>
<li>James&rsquo;s response: Do not change your asset allocation based on market fluctuations, as this constitutes short-term trading behavior.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Using Fatality:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s response: Charles Schwab is recommended because it is both a brokerage and a bank, offering higher security. Fidelity only has brokerage services and lacks a banking license, potentially facing risks during financial crises.</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">IV. Key Insights 
    <div id="iv-key-insights" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv-key-insights" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>The highest guiding principle of investing is: you can still survive under extreme market conditions.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Under any circumstances, ensure that you have sufficient cash flow to sustain your living expenses. This is the bottom line of investing.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Where are Wall Street&rsquo;s yachts? Where are the clients&rsquo; yachts?
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This vividly illustrates Wall Street&rsquo;s profit model, reminding investors to be wary of its various fees and traps.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Look down upon the poor and favor the rich.
&ndash; Zero seven&rsquo;s teacher</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This phrase reveals the harsh reality of Wall Street in the past and reflects the inequality of investment opportunities.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The market is efficient; you cannot have excess profits.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This emphasizes the efficient market hypothesis, reminding investors not to seek easy opportunities for excess returns.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">V. Conclusion 
    <div id="v-conclusion" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#v-conclusion" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This episode reiterates the importance of risk control and investment mindset, providing a detailed explanation of how to allocate assets under different circumstances and how to perceive the market and the role of Wall Street. Through interactive Q&amp;A with the audience, James addresses various investment-related questions and offers practical advice.</p>

  



<div
  
    class="flex px-4 py-3 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900"
  >

  <span
    
      class="text-primary-400 ltr:pr-3 rtl:pl-3 flex items-center"
    >

    

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M506.3 417l-213.3-364c-16.33-28-57.54-28-73.98 0l-213.2 364C-10.59 444.9 9.849 480 42.74 480h426.6C502.1 480 522.6 445 506.3 417zM232 168c0-13.25 10.75-24 24-24S280 154.8 280 168v128c0 13.25-10.75 24-23.1 24S232 309.3 232 296V168zM256 416c-17.36 0-31.44-14.08-31.44-31.44c0-17.36 14.07-31.44 31.44-31.44s31.44 14.08 31.44 31.44C287.4 401.9 273.4 416 256 416z"/></svg>

  </span>


  </span>

  <span
    
      class="dark:text-neutral-300"
    ><strong>Disclaimer:</strong> This article is for personal learning notes only and does not constitute any investment advice.</span>
</div>

]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
