<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Investing on QQQ Investor</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/tags/investing/</link><description>Recent content in Investing on QQQ Investor</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jomonylw.github.io/en/tags/investing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>00500 The Balance Between Asset Appreciation and Spending: Spending Should Reflect Your Asset's Capacity</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1737905023775/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1737905023775/</guid><description>This episode mainly discusses the power of compound interest in long-term investing. For example, the final benefits of investing $10,000 at different ages vary greatly. It also addresses questions from students regarding whether retired individuals can use the 80/20 asset allocation strategy for collateralization and related issues.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<lite-youtube videoid="JGxThQ20wak" playlabel="JGxThQ20wak" params=""></lite-youtube>



<h2 class="relative group">I. Current Topic 
    <div id="i-current-topic" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-current-topic" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This episode primarily shares the power of compound interest in long-term investing and discusses whether the 80/20 asset allocation strategy for retirees can be used for collateralization. James uses specific examples and data analysis to emphasize the importance of compound interest in long-term investing and the key issues to consider when using the 80/20 asset allocation for collateralization. For example, while it&rsquo;s possible for retirees to use the 80/20 allocation for collateral, there are many restrictions. For safety, retirees should stick to the 433 allocation for collateralization.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">II. Briefing Content 
    <div id="ii-briefing-content" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii-briefing-content" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">1. Program Suspension Notice and Disclaimer 
    <div id="1-program-suspension-notice-and-disclaimer" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#1-program-suspension-notice-and-disclaimer" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Suspension Notice</strong>: Next Thursday (February 1, 2025) is the fourth day of the Chinese New Year. Considering that everyone may still be celebrating, there will be no program. The program will resume as usual on February 8, 2025.</li>
<li><strong>Disclaimer</strong>: All content shared on the CLEC channel is solely based on James&rsquo;s personal experience. James is not a professional investment advisor and does not provide professional tax advice. Investing involves extremely high risk, so please be cautious. It&rsquo;s important to note that the possibility of your assets being halved (i.e., a 50% drop) can happen at any time.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">2. Learning Materials and Viewing Recommendations 
    <div id="2-learning-materials-and-viewing-recommendations" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#2-learning-materials-and-viewing-recommendations" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Learning Materials</strong>: Newcomers are advised to watch <strong>video 00451</strong> first. We have also compiled a playlist of short videos. The subtitles for the &ldquo;<strong>One Hundred Million Yuan Investment Lecture</strong>&rdquo; series have been re-proofread, including English and various global language versions, making the translation more accurate.</li>
<li><strong>Viewing Recommendations</strong>: James advises everyone to watch the entire video, as the amount of information is large. Asking questions based on watching only parts of the video makes it difficult to get complete and comprehensive answers.</li>
<li><strong>About Groups</strong>: CLEC does not have any groups. The existing groups are organized by enthusiastic students, like the &ldquo;00662&rdquo; group. These groups mainly help new friends answer basic investment questions. However, it&rsquo;s important to note that these groups are not affiliated with CLEC, and James does not participate in any groups.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">3. Investment Strategies and Precautions 
    <div id="3-investment-strategies-and-precautions" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#3-investment-strategies-and-precautions" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Investment Target</strong>: CLEC focuses solely on investing in the Nasdaq 100 Index Fund. There are many instruments worldwide that allow direct investment in the Nasdaq 100 Index Fund, with relevant links provided in CLEC-related videos. For example, the ticker symbol for the Canadian 2x Leveraged Fund has changed. James will explain the specific changes in later videos.</li>
<li><strong>CLEC Video Quantity</strong>: Since 2018, CLEC has accumulated almost 1000 videos, covering content from investment basics to advanced levels.</li>
<li><strong>Investment Philosophy</strong>: Always maintain extreme optimism in investing and believe that the market will always go up.</li>
<li><strong>Prohibited Behaviors</strong>: We have a one-voice policy here. Activities unrelated to investing in the Nasdaq 100 Index Fund are not allowed. For example, recommending insurance, real estate, etc., is prohibited.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">4. Supplementary Remarks on Chen Feng&rsquo;s Sharing 
    <div id="4-supplementary-remarks-on-chen-fengs-sharing" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#4-supplementary-remarks-on-chen-fengs-sharing" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>About Chen Feng</strong>: Chen Feng is a senior and enthusiastic student who has voluntarily started a group and manages it with Nai Xin and others.</li>
<li><strong>Chen Feng&rsquo;s Content</strong>: Recently, Chen Feng shared a three-hour condensed course on YouTube. James provided supplementary remarks on some of the issues:
<ul>
<li><strong>About Long-Term Annualized Returns</strong>: The long-term annualized returns mentioned by Chen Feng are the actual returns after deducting inflation.</li>
<li><strong>About Excel Demonstrations</strong>: In his sharing, Chen Feng used Excel spreadsheets to demonstrate the returns of different asset ratios. Students can check his Excel spreadsheets for more accurate data results. Chen Feng may also add supplements and corrections in the notes of his YouTube video.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Supplementary Explanation</strong>: Chen Feng&rsquo;s sharing was for his group&rsquo;s internal use. While these senior students have understood 99% of James&rsquo;s content, there may still be some non-mainstream or less precise points. Therefore, James made a few supplementary explanations regarding his sharing.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">5. Collateralized Borrowing and Spending Adjustment Strategies 
    <div id="5-collateralized-borrowing-and-spending-adjustment-strategies" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#5-collateralized-borrowing-and-spending-adjustment-strategies" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Usable Funds Ratio for Collateralized Borrowing</strong>: The annual available funds for collateralized borrowing are 2% of retirement reserves (assuming your retirement reserves are 50 times your annual expenses). If your retirement reserves are NT$30 million, the annual available funds are NT$600,000 (NT$30 million * 2% = NT$600,000). This NT$600,000 is fixed. Even if the NT$30 million becomes NT$20 million due to market fluctuations, you can still use NT$600,000. You don&rsquo;t have to worry about a decrease in available funds because of market drop.</li>
<li><strong>Spending Strategy During Market Downturns</strong>: You do not need to reduce spending during a market downturn. You can increase spending during a market upswing. In other words, our annual spending will only increase, not decrease.</li>
<li><strong>Spending Adjustment Strategies</strong>:
<ul>
<li><strong>Upswing Scenario</strong>: For example, with a retirement reserve of NT$30 million, after 5 years, assets increase from NT$30 million to NT$50 million, and the net assets (after deducting debt, including 5 years of expenses, and annual interest, totaling NT$3.22 million) are NT$46.78 million (NT$50 million - NT$3.22 million = NT$46.78 million). At this point, annual available funds can be adjusted to NT$930,000 (NT$46.78 million * 2% = NT$930,000). However, this NT$930,000 includes interest expenses. Assuming the previous loan of NT$3.22 million and a 3% interest rate, the annual interest expense is about NT$100,000, and the actual available funds are NT$830,000 (NT$930,000 - NT$100,000 = NT$830,000).</li>
<li><strong>Downturn Scenario</strong>: There is no need to reduce spending during a market downturn. You can still maintain the peak spending level (e.g., if the peak spending was NT$900,000, you can still maintain NT$900,000 per year even if assets drop to NT$30 million). This allocation strategy is based on a model that assumes a 10-year decline from the peak, which can be fully sustained even under the extreme scenario of a 10-year decline.</li>
<li><strong>Core Principle for Spending Adjustments</strong>: Only increase spending, not decrease it, and it&rsquo;s recommended to adjust it every 5 years to avoid frequent adjustments.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">6. Retirement Asset Allocation and Collateralization Strategies 
    <div id="6-retirement-asset-allocation-and-collateralization-strategies" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#6-retirement-asset-allocation-and-collateralization-strategies" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Retirees who do not utilize collateralization can use an 80/20 asset allocation, i.e., 80% invested in QQQ and 20% in cash.</strong></li>
<li><strong>An 80/20 asset allocation, without collateralization, allows for simple rebalancing yearly without risk of bankruptcy.</strong></li>
<li><strong>If you must utilize the 80/20 asset allocation for collateralization, please be aware:</strong>
<ul>
<li><strong>Absolutely do not use cash to rebalance in the market, cash must only increase, not decrease.</strong></li>
<li><strong>Market downturns may last up to 10 years. If you borrow 2% annually, you will borrow more than 20% in 10 years. If you then invest cash, your total assets may be less than 20%. Therefore, using an 80/20 asset allocation for collateralization is high risk.</strong></li>
<li><strong>A safer approach is still a 433 allocation.</strong></li>
<li><strong>If you must use the 80/20 allocation for collateralization, rebalancing intelligently only during upswing years, that is, can only transfer cash from the prototype fund (QQQ), it is not allowed to transfer cash into QQQ during downswing years, can transfer cash into QQQ during upswing years.</strong></li>
<li><strong>This approach is complex and requires simulation to ensure feasibility.</strong></li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">7. Core Principles for Asset Allocation 
    <div id="7-core-principles-for-asset-allocation" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#7-core-principles-for-asset-allocation" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Whenever making an asset allocation or adjustment, assume that it&rsquo;s the market&rsquo;s highest point.</strong></li>
<li><strong>Spending does not need to be reduced during a 10-year decline, as the allocation strategy has been verified through simulations as feasible.</strong></li>
<li>When assets have risen to a new high (e.g., from NT$30 million to NT$45 million), you can reset the spending amount. Even if the market declines again afterwards, you don&rsquo;t need to reduce spending because it is already close to the bottom, and risk is reduced.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">8. Yuanta Securities Finance Information 
    <div id="8-yuanta-securities-finance-information" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#8-yuanta-securities-finance-information" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Yuanta Securities Finance is an institution that specializes in lending money out. Its interest rates are low (below 3%), and it doesn&rsquo;t experience liquidity shortages like other brokerages or institutions. Its website operation and fund transfers are also convenient.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">9. Risks of Real Estate Investment 
    <div id="9-risks-of-real-estate-investment" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#9-risks-of-real-estate-investment" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Real estate is not a good asset and carries extremely high risks.</strong></li>
<li>Natural disasters like fires and earthquakes can cause the value of real estate to drop to zero. In some countries or regions, you still have to repay the loan even if the house is destroyed.</li>
<li>Real estate involves putting all your eggs in one basket, and the risk is too concentrated. Moreover, real estate depreciates and loses value.</li>
<li><strong>Investments should be diversified. Avoid putting all your assets into real estate.</strong></li>
<li><strong>You should only buy a house if you could afford to buy another one if the first one was destroyed.</strong></li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">10. Information on German Stock Pledge 
    <div id="10-information-on-german-stock-pledge" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#10-information-on-german-stock-pledge" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>See page 30 of the handout. This is information provided by students on German stock pledges. James did not provide a detailed interpretation.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">11. Tax Issues of American Retirement Accounts (Traditional IRA &amp; Roth IRA) 
    <div id="11-tax-issues-of-american-retirement-accounts-traditional-ira--roth-ira" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#11-tax-issues-of-american-retirement-accounts-traditional-ira--roth-ira" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>When the Traditional IRA becomes an inheritance, the heir must withdraw all the funds within 10 years. The principal and appreciation are both taxed, and there are almost no inheritance tax exemptions.</strong></li>
<li><strong>When the Roth IRA becomes an inheritance, the heir has 10 years to withdraw the funds, and neither the principal nor the appreciation is taxed.</strong></li>
<li><strong>Converting Traditional IRA to Roth IRA as soon as possible can effectively reduce the tax burden when RMD (Required Minimum Distribution) occurs.</strong></li>
<li>Many financial planners or accountants do not advise converting all your Traditional IRA to Roth IRA at once because they want to minimize your current year&rsquo;s taxes, rather than focusing on long-term tax planning.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">12. The Value of Life and the Meaning of Wealth 
    <div id="12-the-value-of-life-and-the-meaning-of-wealth" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#12-the-value-of-life-and-the-meaning-of-wealth" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>The value of life lies in learning, thinking, serving others, and growing, not just working and making money.</li>
<li>Money is a tool to help us achieve our life&rsquo;s purpose, enhancing our spiritual energy and fulfilling our dreams.</li>
<li><strong>The ideal state is to have 10 billion dollars in assets but owe the bank 10.1 billion dollars.</strong></li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">III. Q&amp;A Session 
    <div id="iii-qa-session" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii-qa-session" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Angel 
    <div id="angel" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#angel" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing</strong>: Angel is a young man currently studying in the United States. He turns 21 the next day. His parents are very supportive and hardworking, allowing Angel to study in the U.S. without worry. Angel&rsquo;s parents hope he can live a wealthy life, so they advised him to learn investment and financial management with James and promised to give him funds to invest.</li>
<li><strong>Question 1</strong>: If James were 21 again, with his current knowledge and parental support, how would he invest?
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response</strong>: If James were 21 again with his current knowledge and parental support, he would use a 442 allocation to buy in all at once. Additionally, the teacher shared two investment mistakes he made when he was young: investing in real estate, which he bought for 8 million and sold for only 6 million after 10 years, resulting in a significant loss; and selling company stock to buy a car. These two poor decisions resulted in his assets being reduced by half. The teacher used his own example to emphasize: <strong>$100,000 for a young person, with time, compounded at 14% annually, will be $25 million in 60 years; $10,000 for a young person is $2.6 million in the future, so young people should learn to save and invest first and then learn to spend money when the time is right.</strong></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question 2</strong>: Besides human nature, why is it not advisable for someone of my age to put all my money into QQQ, but rather 433 or 442?
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response</strong>: Human nature is the most important factor that must be considered in investment. You cannot exclude the factor of &ldquo;human nature&rdquo;. If you don&rsquo;t consider human nature, then don&rsquo;t invest. For example, investors often overestimate their risk tolerance. Investment should avoid getting yourself into a state of extreme panic. Allocating all your assets to QQQ or half in QQQ and half in cash overestimates your risk tolerance. Although the market will eventually go up in the long term, your assets may fall to extremely low values during a market downswing, for example: from 100 to 80, 70, 60, then finally falling down to 5, 1. During this process, you might have already gone bankrupt and exited, even if you survive until market rise, it no longer has anything to do with you. It’s like playing Russian roulette: a revolver with 6 chambers, and 1 bullet. If the person firing doesn’t die, they will get 10 million; if they do die, they die. You should not participate because of the high reward. You could die. So young people&rsquo;s beta should not exceed 1.2.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Lisa 
    <div id="lisa" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#lisa" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing 1</strong>: Has retired and currently uses a power account as a reserve for daily living. The account balance is usually 0. Money is only used when a large expense happens or an emergency occurs. This practice brings her peace of mind. She doesn&rsquo;t need to keep a lot of cash in her daily account so that she could effectively use cash for investment purposes.</li>
<li><strong>Question 1</strong>: After retiring, I do not want to use leveraged funds (like QLD), but I am worried about a stock market crash. Is it feasible to use the 80/20 (80% in QQQ and 20% in cash) asset allocation strategy?
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response</strong>: Yes, it is feasible. An 80/20 asset allocation, if you don&rsquo;t do collateralization, can do simple rebalancing yearly. Because she is retired, and the funds in her collateralization account have not been used, which is equivalent to her not using collateralization, she can use the 80/20 asset allocation strategy under that circumstance.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Sharing 2</strong>: Has started Roth IRA conversion and plans to complete all the conversion within the next few years when the tax rate is lower.</li>
<li><strong>Question 2</strong>: Some people suggested using up the 32% tax rate, but I cannot mentally accept it, as it may mean paying higher taxes. Is it okay to just use up the 24% tax rate and deal with the rest during RMD time?
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response</strong>: You can complete all the conversions before the RMD age, as long as you finish before RMD, as money cannot be transferred into a Roth IRA after RMD age. Money can only be transferred into a brokerage account, which is not beneficial to inheritance. It is recommended to transfer the funds from the retirement account to a Roth IRA as much as possible, as the Roth IRA&rsquo;s heir does not need to pay taxes within 10 years, while the Traditional IRA&rsquo;s heir needs to pay taxes. Converting early can avoid higher taxes in the future. If you still do the conversion when the market drops, it means your conversion decision is correct. Although you may have to pay as high as 30% tax now during conversion, you can avoid higher taxes in the future in the long run (because your assets will grow significantly over time, so you will have to pay more taxes later).</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">YJ 
    <div id="yj" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#yj" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing 1</strong>: YJ would first like to thank James and the &ldquo;00662&rdquo; group, especially for Chen Feng&rsquo;s sharing and James&rsquo;s supplementation, which make everyone&rsquo;s investment concepts clearer.</li>
<li><strong>Sharing 2</strong>: The Chinese concept of &ldquo;having land is having wealth&rdquo; needs to be updated. In the current era, this &ldquo;land&rdquo; should not be real estate but rather &ldquo;stocks&rdquo;. The old concept of &ldquo;having land is having wealth&rdquo; refers to farmland that can be cultivated and has output, which is similar concept to current day investing in stocks.</li>
<li><strong>Suggestion</strong>: There are no more lectures on the 100 Million Investment topic this year. The 9 situations in the 00005 topic have been simplified into 2 situations. Can there be a &ldquo;00006&rdquo; topic, specifically on the &ldquo;collateralization&rdquo; part, with a simpler presentation?
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response</strong>: &ldquo;Having land is having wealth&rdquo; did not refer to houses in the past, as houses were not valuable in those eras and this term referred to farmlands. Today&rsquo;s &ldquo;having land is having wealth&rdquo; should be changed to &ldquo;having stocks is having wealth&rdquo;, stocks are the true assets. Regarding your suggestion of topic 00006, James believes the existing sharing is already simplified enough. Users using collateralization should use the 433 allocation and make &ldquo;smart rebalancing&rdquo; using 2% of their assets yearly, and there is no need for a more complicated topical presentation.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question 1</strong>: Previously, I sent a message on YouTube mentioning the video 00303 in March 2022, and you suggested to not use TQ (TQQQ) back then. However, two months ago (around November), you replied that a 6TQQ+2U+2Cash strategy can be used with a 6:2:2 allocation. Does this strategy and comparison with the 442 strategy feasible?
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response</strong>: TQQ can be used. The suggestion in previous videos was based on the understanding at the time, so single-asset investment in TQQ was not recommended. However, now, if you have an asset allocation (like 6:2:2, which is 60% in TQQ, 20% in U, and 20% in Cash) and do &ldquo;smart rebalancing&rdquo;, this strategy is viable. Investment strategies and concepts are constantly evolving and improving. Ideas considered impossible in the past may now be proven to be feasible.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Bill 
    <div id="bill" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#bill" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Question</strong>: I previously learned about BOXX as an investment target that is not correlated to the stock market. However, I learned that it&rsquo;s related to blockchain, so there are concerns about its safety, and whether its risk is too high?
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response</strong>: BOXX&rsquo;s operating mechanism is similar to 00864B. As long as its return is trending similarly to the US Federal Funds Rate, its risk is controllable. You should pay serious attention when the return is much higher or lower than the US Federal Funds Rate, as it may indicate some irregular financial operations. BOXX&rsquo;s primary function is to reasonably avoid investment income tax, and it can be used as a short-term investment target.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Henry 
    <div id="henry" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#henry" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Question</strong>: Henry runs his own business and used to have a company 401K. He has stopped it now, and he is not sure whether he should continue contributing into it or put the money designated for company contributions into his investment account.
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response</strong>: The main purpose of a 401K is to save on taxes. If you can do a Roth Solo 401k, you should prioritize it. You can consult your tax consultant or search the web and consult ChatGPT to confirm if you can do a Roth Solo 401k.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Yuqiao 
    <div id="yuqiao" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#yuqiao" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Question</strong>: I am retired and have benefited from this investment method. I want to recommend this investment method to my younger sister in China (who is 50 years old, runs a small business, has a tight budget, and has almost no knowledge of investment). Should I give her investment advice?</li>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response</strong>: Yes, you should. You can be her benefactor. However, she may not accept advice directly. Furthermore, opening an account and the follow-up operations are complex. So, if you really want to help her, you can open an account for her first and invest a small amount of money (such as $1,000 USD for about ¥7,000 to ¥8,000 RMB), tell her that if there are losses, you will bear it, if there are profits, it&rsquo;s hers. You can also co-invest with her proportionally, for example, if she invests ¥100, you can invest ¥100 for her. Once she sees a return, she will then invest automatically.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">IAM 
    <div id="iam" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iam" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing 1</strong>: IAM has recently met a doctor in his 70s. When he was young in his 30s, he trusted brokers and made careless investments. After several failed investments, he not only had real estate and stocks but was also in debt at 40 years old. He had to work to repay his debts even in his 70s. IAM is very grateful he found CLEC in 2022 and avoided going down the same path as the doctor.</li>
<li><strong>Question 1</strong>: James often says &ldquo;slow is fast,&rdquo; and investment should not be rushed. However, everyone&rsquo;s understanding of &ldquo;fast&rdquo; and &ldquo;slow&rdquo; is different. Can you please explain how to measure &ldquo;fast&rdquo; and &ldquo;slow&rdquo; in investing and how to view the concept of &ldquo;40 years is too long&rdquo;?
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response</strong>: Everything has its own rules and timings, like pregnancy and childbirth, which takes ten months and cannot be shortened. The same applies to investing. Wealth growth takes time. You cannot expect to harvest tomorrow what you planted today. It takes 10 years of investment to feel wealthy, 20 years to retire, 30 years to be prosperous, and 40 years to become rich. This requires time, one cannot be hasty. Warren Buffett did not become the world&rsquo;s richest man at 30 or 40, but after 55 years old. Investing requires understanding the essence and rules of time. Do not be impatient. Every thing operates following its rules and timings. It&rsquo;s a rule of nature and cannot be rushed.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question 2</strong>: Why do people haggle over small amounts of money, but at the same time act recklessly like gamblers when it comes to investing?
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response</strong>: This all stems from humanity&rsquo;s &ldquo;loss aversion&rdquo; mentality. People do not like to lose, so they haggle over prices when shopping, but they tend to focus only on the gains and ignore the risks when investing. During investment, people often forget past losses and only think about making more money in the future. This is the gambler&rsquo;s mentality. When shopping, people compare prices since they can lose less and, by nature, they will haggle. In investing, people think that the more they invest, the more they will earn; while ignoring the possibility of losses, hence they will not haggle. It&rsquo;s like if you go to buy a cake, and the owner says the cake is 100, you might haggle and say can it be 90? But if the owner says you buy my cake and tomorrow I&rsquo;ll return 300, you won&rsquo;t haggle anymore, you&rsquo;d think the more expensive, the better.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Mike 
    <div id="mike" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#mike" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing 1</strong>: Shared a story about a CNBC interview with Buffett and Bill Gates: If Buffett and Bill Gates went to McDonald&rsquo;s and they see 1 cent on the ground, what would they do? Buffett would pick it up without hesitation and check if there are any other coins around; and Bill Gates would also pick up that cent. This story illustrates the principles of &ldquo;every little bit counts&rdquo; and &ldquo;compound interest.&rdquo; Even the wealthy do not overlook the importance of &ldquo;saving&rdquo; because when Mike was on a business trip to Microsoft in 1992, Microsoft was already a listed company, and Bill Gates was already very wealthy at that time. One of the employees criticized Bill Gates for using coupons when shopping for groceries. Later, one time, Bill Gates was looking for his coupon when checking out. The person behind him said, don&rsquo;t worry, I will pay, you earn more than this in one minute. However, Bill Gates did not ignore the person behind him, he continued to search for his coupon.</li>
<li><strong>Sharing 2</strong>: Opinions regarding Deep Seek: Recently, AI technology is developing rapidly, with various new technologies and applications emerging, including Deep Seek, which will have a significant impact on QQQ&rsquo;s future. Currently, American technology giants seem to have a &ldquo;big brother&rdquo; mentality, believing that they can win the AI race as long as they invest enough resources. However, historical experience shows that technological leadership does not necessarily win the market, the business model is also important.</li>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response</strong>:</li>
<li>Deep Seek, like many other AI technologies, is still in the early stages, and there will be many uncertainties in the future. But what is certain is that AI will have a profound impact on human society and bring huge opportunities for investors.</li>
<li>Regarding the competition between the US and China in the field of AI, it is still difficult to judge who will ultimately win. The US has advantages in technology and funds, but China also has its own advantages, such as large amounts of data and government support.</li>
<li>AI is not only large language models (LLM), there are many other applications, for example: Tesla&rsquo;s autonomous driving. Tesla&rsquo;s autonomous driving model is already very mature, it can automatically drive out from the parking lot and the driving experience is very smooth, just like a professional driver is driving for you.</li>
<li>AI will not completely replace human jobs but increase our work efficiency. For example, even for translators, you can use AI to improve the efficiency and quality of translation. Therefore, humans need to learn how to utilize AI, not reject it.</li>
<li>Currently, the biggest problem is that many large companies want to introduce AI, but they do not have a clear idea, they do not know whether it needs to be from top down or from bottom-up. James thinks it needs to be from bottom-up, the employees should use them first, so they are accustomed before moving up. But this requires time and because everyone is changing the thinking process of using AI.</li>
<li>AI will cause QQQ&rsquo;s annual returns to be much higher than 14%, or even 20% or 30%. James is very optimistic about this.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Eric 
    <div id="eric" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#eric" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing</strong>: Based in Canada, 35 years old, plans to sell his house and invest the proceeds from the sale. Both he and his wife are currently working.</li>
<li><strong>Question 1</strong>: A plan to invest 20% in cash, 40% in QLD, 40% in QQ for long term investment and do smart rebalancing, is this investment plan correct?
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response</strong>: The plan is correct. Young people who are still working can use a 442 asset allocation, which is 40% in QQQ, 40% in QLD, and 20% in cash, and then do smart rebalancing.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question 2</strong>: Canada has high taxes, and capital gains tax is heavy. What are your suggestions for long-term planning?
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response</strong>: People&rsquo;s destiny is controlled by three factors: the first is fate (DNA); the second is destiny (place of birth); and the third is luck. The place of birth determines one&rsquo;s destiny. Canada, Europe, and Australia are not as good as the US. If financially possible, consider immigrating to the US, not just for yourself but also for your descendants.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Hao Qing 
    <div id="hao-qing" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#hao-qing" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing 1</strong>:
<ul>
<li><strong>Event 1</strong>: Shared two experiences of encountering potential &ldquo;scams&rdquo;. One time was meeting someone on a highway who claimed to be from Dubai, needing help. This person was dressed neatly, drove a BMW, and claimed to have run out of gas and had no money or was robbed. This person wore gold and asked Hao Qing for help, claiming that he could give his gold to Hao Qing. Hao Qing gave him 40 yuan, but he wanted more. Hao Qing felt that something was wrong, and so did not give any more. The second time, he encountered the same person on the road again, so he called the police.</li>
<li><strong>Event 2</strong>: A colleague&rsquo;s relative, an 80-year-old, was scammed for 600,000 yuan. This old person did not believe what nearby people said about it being a scam, and believed that since he raised his children for so many years, it was not unfilial to ask them for money to invest and everyone was stopping him. When going to the bank, the bank employees also told him that it was a scam. The police also came to give him risk warnings that the money could not be transferred, but this old person still did not believe it and was scammed for 600,000 yuan.</li>
<li><strong>Personal Views</strong>: Hao Qing thinks that he is a kind-hearted person. When he sees someone in trouble, he will help to the best of his ability. However, he will be more careful when it comes to money. Also, there are now many scams and the success rate for solving them is extremely low. He is not sure if it&rsquo;s the government&rsquo;s problem or individual&rsquo;s problem.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Sharing 2</strong>: While discussing &ldquo;US-China trade&rdquo; with colleagues, his colleagues think that China may devalue the renminbi to deal with the US tariffs. He does not agree with this point of view but does not know how to explain it.</li>
<li><strong>Questions</strong>: How should we view the three problems of &ldquo;scams&rdquo;, &ldquo;Taiwan policy&rdquo;, and “RMB devaluation”?
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response</strong>:
<ul>
<li><strong>About Scams:</strong> The US does not care because the US thinks that if you are scammed, it means you are stupid. Furthermore, the person that Hao Qing encountered is technically not breaking a legal law, even if you report, it is useless. All the police can do is to chase him away. Why are there scams? It&rsquo;s because of &ldquo;poverty&rdquo;. When it&rsquo;s difficult to earn money through normal ways, &ldquo;scamming&rdquo; becomes a way to get rich quickly. So, you still need to start from the systems, and education aspect.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>About Taiwan policies</strong>: The US has completely free capitalism where the market determines prices. When prices increase, wages increase, which will then increase interest rates and suppress inflation, ultimately creating a positive economic cycle. Taiwan&rsquo;s policies, to a certain degree, hinders this positive economic cycle.</li>
<li><strong>Regarding the RMB devaluation expectations</strong>: This problem is complex and interlinked. It cannot be simply solved via devaluation.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Martin 
    <div id="martin" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#martin" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing</strong>: Previously talked with James about the DPC open-source model, and he is also involved in the implementation of his company&rsquo;s AI project. Therefore, he would like to share and communicate with everyone.</li>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response</strong>: Okay, you can come and share it with us next time.</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">IV. Key Insights 
    <div id="iv-key-insights" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv-key-insights" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>When investing, you need to see results. You want to see results like Buffett&rsquo;s. Of course, everyone&rsquo;s level is different. When you feel you are living a prosperous life, you will also need 40 years. You cannot be hasty.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>This point explains the importance of &ldquo;time&rdquo; and the power of &ldquo;compound interest&rdquo; in long-term investing.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The value of life lies in learning, thinking, serving others, and growing, not just working and making money.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>This point emphasizes that the meaning of life lies in continuous learning, growth, and serving society, not just the pursuit of material wealth.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>You also need an appropriate amount of time to grow wealth to a certain extent. Therefore, you need to recognize that time exists first.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>This emphasizes that wealth accumulation requires time and patience, and one should not take any shortcuts.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>What do you do when everything is destroyed? You need a way out.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>Whether you&rsquo;re investing or doing anything else, you have to consider if this thing fails, and whether you have a way out. Or whether you can bear the losses caused by that failure.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Today if you buy a Tesla car but you&rsquo;re afraid of it getting scratched, you&rsquo;re afraid of washing it. After washing it, you&rsquo;re afraid to drive it. Every time you drive it out, you&rsquo;re afraid of people wanting to borrow it, or when your daughter wants to borrow it, you&rsquo;d always say no and no. You&rsquo;re a slave to wealth. It&rsquo;s okay to drive. I have insurance. If it is crashed I can buy a new one. This is wealth. Therefore, don&rsquo;t be a slave to your assets, never be.  It&rsquo;s better not to buy it, instead of buying it and then using up your mental energy over it. We should not spend any mental energy on material things. This is very important. This is the key to happiness.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>We should not be slaves to &ldquo;wealth,&rdquo; and should not be controlled by &ldquo;material things.&rdquo; If something affects your mood, do not buy it because you cannot afford it.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>People&rsquo;s destiny is controlled by three factors: The first is fate (DNA); the second is destiny (place of birth); and the third is luck.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>The place of birth determines destiny. If you are born in the United States, you have the American destiny; if you are born in Taiwan, you have the Taiwan destiny; if you are born in Australia, you have the Australian destiny.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>I am still going to tell everyone that we are going to be very wealthy, so when you want to immigrate you have to think twice. If it&rsquo;s me, I&rsquo;d rather spend 800,000 USD to immigrate to the US instead of using less money to immigrate to Canada, Europe, or the NSW. Because the destinies are different. Look at the world&rsquo;s top ten companies, and nine are from the US. Only one is TSMC from China, but TSMC is also cultivated in the US. To say it bluntly, all the world&rsquo;s top ten companies were founded by Americans, this is fate.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>When considering immigration, one should think not only for themselves but also the fate of future generations.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>An 80/20 allocation without collateralization can do simple rebalancing yearly without risk of bankruptcy.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>Retirees that do not do collateralization may utilize an 80/20 asset allocation where 80% is invested in QQQ and 20% is kept in cash, and can do simple rebalancing without risk of bankruptcy.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The US does not care about scams, they don&rsquo;t even care about the 0-dollar purchase scams, so why would they care about scams? Therefore, there is a cost accounting issue. If a country wants to be strong, it needs strong cost accounting. What do you want? Right and wrong is about competing, and everyone needs to know that prosperity is a key, and poverty is a disease. Being poor for an emerging country is a disease, if one is poor it&rsquo;s a disease.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>The United States is strong due to its sound system and market economy.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Always maintain extreme optimism in investing and believe that the market will always go up.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>Maintain an optimistic attitude throughout the investment process.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>AI may not necessarily solely rely on computing power. It can also rely on the human brain.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>This point explains that in the development of AI, in addition to computing power, the human brain can also play an important role.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">V. Summary 
    <div id="v-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#v-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This episode mainly focused on discussions surrounding compound interest, asset allocation, and various social phenomena. James emphasized the power of &ldquo;compound interest&rdquo; and the importance of &ldquo;time&rdquo; in long-term investing. He also provided detailed answers and specific operational suggestions regarding asset allocation strategies for retirees, particularly addressing the question of whether an 80/20 allocation is suitable for collateralization. Furthermore, he incorporated current events to share his perspectives on social phenomena such as US-China trade, AI development, and scams, pointing out that &ldquo;wealth&rdquo; is a key factor in a nation&rsquo;s strength. Overall, this episode was packed with information, offering specific guidance on investment strategies along with profound reflections on life, wealth, and social issues, making it worthy of repeated study.</p>

  



<div
  
    class="flex px-4 py-3 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900"
  >

  <span
    
      class="text-primary-400 ltr:pr-3 rtl:pl-3 flex items-center"
    >

    

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M506.3 417l-213.3-364c-16.33-28-57.54-28-73.98 0l-213.2 364C-10.59 444.9 9.849 480 42.74 480h426.6C502.1 480 522.6 445 506.3 417zM232 168c0-13.25 10.75-24 24-24S280 154.8 280 168v128c0 13.25-10.75 24-23.1 24S232 309.3 232 296V168zM256 416c-17.36 0-31.44-14.08-31.44-31.44c0-17.36 14.07-31.44 31.44-31.44s31.44 14.08 31.44 31.44C287.4 401.9 273.4 416 256 416z"/></svg>

  </span>


  </span>

  <span
    
      class="dark:text-neutral-300"
    >Disclaimer: This article is solely for personal study notes and does not constitute any investment advice.</span>
</div>

]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>00495 Market Highs and Lows Don't Exist: The Only Truth in Long-Term Investing; The Privilege of the Rich and the Secret of Asset Appreciation</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1734846063547/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1734846063547/</guid><description>In this session, James shares his year-end rebalancing strategy, investment philosophy, 433 asset allocation plan, and answers questions from students regarding QQQ, leveraged ETFs, ETNs, real estate, personal finance, and CLEC short video production.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<lite-youtube videoid="TCfozoZu0Hw" playlabel="TCfozoZu0Hw" params=""></lite-youtube>



<h2 class="relative group">I. Main Topic 
    <div id="i-main-topic" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-main-topic" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This session focuses on year-end investment strategies. James emphasizes the importance of rebalancing and delves into investment philosophy, asset allocation, handling market fluctuations, and other practical investment tips. The core message is: adopt a long-term investment approach, adhere to the &ldquo;buy whenever you have money, never sell&rdquo; strategy, and implement a suitable asset allocation and rebalancing plan based on individual circumstances.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">II. Briefing Content 
    <div id="ii-briefing-content" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii-briefing-content" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Year-End Rebalancing and Asset Allocation 
    <div id="year-end-rebalancing-and-asset-allocation" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#year-end-rebalancing-and-asset-allocation" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Importance of Rebalancing:</strong> James stresses the importance of rebalancing at the end or beginning of the year. He recommends passive rebalancing, which means rebalancing when the market is performing well, to avoid panic selling during market downturns. He points out that many investors are reluctant to rebalance during market rallies, hoping to earn more, but end up succumbing to losses during declines and selling at the bottom, resulting in greater losses.</li>
<li><strong>Pledging Stocks for Tax Payment:</strong> He advises individuals with pledged stocks to borrow money for tax payments instead of selling the stocks to avoid increasing capital gains tax and to better utilize their funds. He emphasizes that under the premise of sound asset allocation and risk management, the borrowed money can be used flexibly.</li>
<li><strong>Real Estate Investment:</strong>  James advises against buying real estate, believing it restricts personal freedom. He uses the example of a friend in the Bay Area selling their property to support this viewpoint, pointing out the high holding costs of real estate, including property taxes, maintenance fees, and insurance, which can put significant financial pressure on individuals.</li>
<li><strong>Children&rsquo;s Education and Wealth Perspective:</strong> He suggests parents support their children&rsquo;s choices, believing that happiness is more important than wealth. Children shouldn&rsquo;t live for the sake of glorifying their family but should pursue happiness, serve others, and do what they love.</li>
<li><strong>433 Asset Allocation Plan:</strong> James recommends the 433 asset allocation plan (40% QQQ, 30% TQQQ, 30% Cash) for the general public, adjustable based on individual circumstances. For retirees who are not pledging stocks, he suggests an 80/20 allocation (80% index funds, 20% cash). For investors unfamiliar with or averse to leveraged ETFs, he recommends 100% investment in QQQ or 00662.</li>
<li><strong>Taiwan&rsquo;s Investment Environment Advantage:</strong> James highly praises Taiwan&rsquo;s investment environment, believing it possesses cutting-edge financial tools, tax-free policies, and low interest rates, making it an ideal place for investment. He encourages Taiwanese investors to leverage this advantage.</li>
<li><strong>Mid-Life Investment Strategy:</strong> He advises middle-aged individuals, even with modest incomes, to persist in monthly investments, accumulating wealth gradually for retirement. He illustrates the returns of monthly investments of 5,000 and 10,000 at retirement with specific examples.</li>
<li><strong>Advantages of Nasdaq 100 Index Funds:</strong> James explains the rationale for investing in QQQ, stating that its constituent companies have strong profitability, focus on technology and innovation, and align with long-term human development trends. He also points out that the constituent companies of the Nasdaq 100 index have stronger profitability compared to the S&amp;P 500.</li>
<li><strong>Investment Philosophy:</strong>  He advocates for the &ldquo;buy whenever you have money, never sell&rdquo; strategy, ignoring short-term fluctuations and believing in the long-term upward trajectory of the market. He emphasizes that the purpose of investment is wealth appreciation, not short-term gains, and criticizes the drawbacks of short-term trading.</li>
<li><strong>The Difference Between the Rich and the Poor:</strong> James points out that the rich possess assets and credit, which they can use to &ldquo;print money&rdquo; through leverage for rapid wealth growth.  The poor, lacking investment knowledge, keep their money in banks, missing out on wealth growth opportunities. He uses the example of Warren Buffett issuing bonds to illustrate how the rich utilize credit for investment.</li>
<li><strong>Three Contributions of Investors:</strong>  First, allocating capital to the most efficient companies, promoting technological advancement; second, helping the government invest idle foreign exchange reserves; third, helping the poor activate their funds, maximizing their social value.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Other Investment Advice and Opinions 
    <div id="other-investment-advice-and-opinions" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#other-investment-advice-and-opinions" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Don&rsquo;t blindly trust the investment advice of financial advisors and banks, as they have profit motives and may recommend products beneficial to themselves, not necessarily to investors.</li>
<li>Don&rsquo;t believe in investment recommendations from so-called &ldquo;group leaders&rdquo; or random individuals. Think independently, make your own decisions, and be responsible for your investments.</li>
<li>Focus on investing in broad-market passive funds in the US, such as the Nasdaq 100 Index Fund (QQQ) and the S&amp;P 500 Index Fund (SPY). He provides codes for investing in Nasdaq 100 index funds globally.</li>
<li>Avoid investing in unfamiliar assets like Bitcoin. Focus on core investment strategies to avoid distractions.</li>
<li>Don&rsquo;t overemphasize short-term market fluctuations and various news. Maintain an optimistic mindset and firmly believe in the long-term upward trend of the market.</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">III. Q&amp;A Session 
    <div id="iii-qa-session" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii-qa-session" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Zhang Yong 
    <div id="zhang-yong" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#zhang-yong" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Expresses gratitude to James, shares his 15-year experience in the insurance industry, reflects on some existing problems within the industry, such as promoting low-yield financial insurance, and expresses admiration for the simplicity and effectiveness of the CLEC investment philosophy and how it can change his and his family&rsquo;s financial future. He also shares his desire to help friends and family learn the CLEC investment philosophy but acknowledges the challenges in promotion.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s comments: Affirms Zhang Yong&rsquo;s sharing and thanks Dr. Lao Chai for the recommendation. Emphasizes the power of word-of-mouth marketing and encourages Zhang Yong to continue promoting the CLEC investment philosophy.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Mike 
    <div id="mike" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#mike" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Shares a discussion with friends in Taiwan about QQQ&rsquo;s component stock adjustments and rebalancing mechanism, mentioning the Matthew effect and the idea that the strong get stronger. He also expresses surprise at the relatively small total market capitalization of QQQ.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s comments: Suggests focusing on long-term performance rather than short-term fluctuations and explains that QQQ&rsquo;s smaller market cap is due to the relatively low number of people who understand and invest in it.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 1:  The impact of QQQ component adjustments and rebalancing mechanisms on investments, and whether one should invest in the smaller 90 companies.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s reply:  Advises focusing on long-term performance and volatility, not short-term component adjustments. QQQ&rsquo;s adjustment mechanism ensures the inclusion of the best companies, illustrated by the performance of Mega 7 and MAGS. Points out the &ldquo;stronger get stronger&rdquo; phenomenon among large companies and explains QQQ&rsquo;s rebalancing mechanism.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2: James&rsquo;s methods, tools, and experience in creating short videos, and the application of AI technology.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s reply: Details the short video production process, including writing scripts, using speech recognition software, text-to-video conversion, and subtitle generation. He shares his experience with AI tools, emphasizing the importance of personal creation and the limitations of AI in emotional expression. Mentions using tools like speech recognition software, PowerDirector, and some Chinese and Taiwanese video production software.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Hui 
    <div id="hui" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#hui" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question 1:  FNGS has performed better than QQQ. Can FNGS replace QQQ?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s reply: No, because FNGS has excessive volatility and higher risk, illustrated by the 2000 tech bubble.  Emphasizes that asset allocation should consider volatility and maximum drawdown, not just performance. In the long run, QQQ offers better stability.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2: XLG has lower volatility than QQQ and decent returns.  Is it suitable for allocation?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s reply: No, because XLG&rsquo;s long-term performance is inferior to QQQ. He provides a performance comparison of QQQ and XLG from 2006 to the present, showing QQQ&rsquo;s significantly higher returns. Emphasizes focusing on long-term performance and avoiding investments with poor long-term track records despite low short-term volatility. Investments with less than 30 years of market history are not worth discussing.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Ethan 
    <div id="ethan" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ethan" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Shares his two-year experience learning and promoting the CLEC investment philosophy in China, highlighting the positive impact and challenges. He suggests domestic investors consider opening accounts in Hong Kong to invest in QQQ and shares the advantages of investing in Hong Kong.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s comments: Affirms Ethan&rsquo;s sharing and promotional efforts, agrees with his suggestion of opening accounts in Hong Kong, and adds to the advantages, such as access to leveraged ETFs and money market funds, making the 433 asset allocation plan more comprehensive.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Ling 
    <div id="ling" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ling" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Shares her experience and understanding of the CLEC investment philosophy and how she applies it to life, such as educating her children.  She shares a childhood story of collecting shells for money and her desire for investment.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s comments: Acknowledges Ling&rsquo;s sharing and praises her proactive approach.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question: How to pledge stocks after retirement?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s reply: Explains the process of pledging stocks after retirement and emphasizes the importance of asset allocation.  Suggests the 433 asset allocation plan, adjusted according to the value of the pledged stocks. Explains how to calculate borrowing limits based on the value of pledged stocks and how to add collateral.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Martin 
    <div id="martin" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#martin" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Shares his investment experience and observations in Europe and expresses envy for the US investment environment. Mentions issues such as strict regulations and heavy tax burdens in Europe.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s comments: Agrees with Martin&rsquo;s viewpoint, analyzes the disadvantages of the European investment environment, such as high taxes and restrictions on the tech industry, and explains his focus on the US market. Points out that European socialist ideology and wealth expropriation are detrimental to capital accumulation and economic development.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Ying 
    <div id="ying" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ying" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Reflects on some mistakes in his investment journey, such as missing a year of market gains for a 5% fixed deposit interest rate, and shares his experience and insights on all-in investing in QQQ and TQQQ, and how he persuaded his wife to start investing.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s comments: Affirms Ying&rsquo;s sharing and reiterates the &ldquo;buy whenever you have money, never sell&rdquo; strategy and the all-in investment philosophy. Points out the importance of overcoming human weaknesses for investment success.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Pamela 
    <div id="pamela" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#pamela" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Shares the story of her neighbor being scammed by an accountant, reminding everyone to be cautious of investment risks and not to trust others blindly, even friends or professionals.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s comments: Agrees with Pamela&rsquo;s point, emphasizes the importance of improving one&rsquo;s financial literacy, and advises against over-reliance on financial advisors and accountants.  Points out that an accountant&rsquo;s responsibility is tax filing, not financial planning, so investors should not solely rely on their investment advice.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Nick 
    <div id="nick" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#nick" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Shares his investment experience in Canada, recommends HQU, the Canadian equivalent of QQQ, and discusses using IBKR&rsquo;s margin account. Highlights the challenges of investing in Canada and how to utilize IBKR for leverage.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s comments: Thanks Macro for sharing and suggests that IBKR&rsquo;s margin account might be an option for investors in countries without stock pledging.  Recommends that investors from other countries try and provide feedback on their experience with IBKR&rsquo;s margin account.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Julie 
    <div id="julie" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#julie" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question 1: Will pledging stocks affect mortgage refinancing?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s reply: No, stock pledging does not appear on credit reports and will not affect mortgage refinancing rates. He advises Julie to pledge her stocks as soon as possible and not wait for interest rates to decline, as future interest rate movements are unpredictable.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2: How to use TQQQ for investment and how to balance returns and risks? How to invest the money set aside for property taxes?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s reply: Suggests the 433 asset allocation plan, adjustable based on individual circumstances.  Emphasizes the importance of Beta management and recommends holding leveraged ETFs in retirement accounts. He advises against investing property tax money in TQQQ, recommending instead to keep it in cash or money market funds for unexpected needs.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Other Q&amp;A 
    <div id="other-qa" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#other-qa" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>James answers audience questions on topics such as 20-year investment returns, Warren Buffett&rsquo;s cash holdings, account selection for funds, short video production, the impact of FNG&rsquo;s bankruptcy on QQQ, simulating investments in the top ten stocks, stock pledging in Taiwan, 50/25/25 asset allocation, money market fund selection, leveraged ETF investment ratios, investment time horizons, and investment options in Canada.</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">IV. Key Takeaways 
    <div id="iv-key-takeaways" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv-key-takeaways" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>Buy whenever you have money, never sell.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>This is James&rsquo;s consistent investment philosophy and the core strategy of CLEC.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Taiwan is a country with well-equipped weapons and cheap bullets.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>James praises Taiwan&rsquo;s investment environment, believing its financial tools, tax benefits, and low interest rates are highly advantageous for investors.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The most important thing in life is happiness.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>James emphasizes that the meaning of life lies in happiness, not in working and making money for its own sake.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>AI creations lack warmth.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>James shares his experience using AI tools for short video production, highlighting the limitations of AI in conveying emotions.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>You can be a benefactor to others, but whether they benefit depends on their destiny and fate.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>James shares his understanding of wealth and life, believing that an individual&rsquo;s wealth accumulation is influenced by destiny, fate, and luck, in addition to hard work.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The market has no peak, only higher highs; the market has no bottom, only a perpetual absence of a top or bottom.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>James emphasizes the long-term upward trend of the market and advises against trying to predict market tops and bottoms.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">V. Summary 
    <div id="v-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#v-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This session covered year-end rebalancing strategies, investment philosophy, the 433 asset allocation plan, CLEC short video production methods, and addressed various questions from students. James emphasized the importance of long-term investing and encouraged participants to create a reasonable asset allocation and rebalancing plan based on their individual circumstances, ignore short-term market fluctuations, and adhere to the &ldquo;buy whenever you have money, never sell&rdquo; principle.  During the Q&amp;A, students shared their investment experiences and concerns, raising questions about investment environments in different countries and specific investment products.  James provided professional guidance and advice, helping students better understand and apply the CLEC investment philosophy.</p>

  



<div
  
    class="flex px-4 py-3 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900"
  >

  <span
    
      class="text-primary-400 ltr:pr-3 rtl:pl-3 flex items-center"
    >

    

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M506.3 417l-213.3-364c-16.33-28-57.54-28-73.98 0l-213.2 364C-10.59 444.9 9.849 480 42.74 480h426.6C502.1 480 522.6 445 506.3 417zM232 168c0-13.25 10.75-24 24-24S280 154.8 280 168v128c0 13.25-10.75 24-23.1 24S232 309.3 232 296V168zM256 416c-17.36 0-31.44-14.08-31.44-31.44c0-17.36 14.07-31.44 31.44-31.44s31.44 14.08 31.44 31.44C287.4 401.9 273.4 416 256 416z"/></svg>

  </span>


  </span>

  <span
    
      class="dark:text-neutral-300"
    ><strong>Disclaimer:</strong> This article is for personal learning notes only and does not constitute any investment advice.</span>
</div>

]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Personal Investment Bible: Conclusion</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1731056005974/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1731056005974/</guid><description>This article summarizes the core concepts of building wealth through personal finance, emphasizing that everyone can achieve financial freedom through proper money management. Key takeaways include the importance of financial planning, principles for setting financial goals, the value of long-term investing, overcoming common financial misconceptions, and balancing wealth with a fulfilling life. It encourages readers to acquire financial knowledge, adhere to long-term investment strategies, and ultimately achieve financial freedom and a better life.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[

<h2 class="relative group">Conclusion 
    <div id="conclusion" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#conclusion" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>What influences a person&rsquo;s future wealth the most,
is whether they have started managing their finances.</p></blockquote>
<p><strong>Everyone Can Achieve Wealth Through Personal Finance</strong></p>
<p>This book aims to illustrate a simple truth: investing and managing your finances can not only improve the financial situation of an individual or family, but is also an excellent path to wealth creation.  Furthermore, anyone can achieve wealth through personal finance. You don&rsquo;t need to be rich, have a high income, possess a high degree, have specialized knowledge or advanced skills, nor rely on luck. What you need is the desire for wealth, a correct investment philosophy (not just techniques), and the patience to wait for the long term.  Therefore, whether a person has money or not, or how high their income is, doesn&rsquo;t matter. What truly influences a person&rsquo;s future wealth is whether they have started managing their finances. This endeavor is not easy, but it&rsquo;s undoubtedly worth your effort!</p>
<p>Readers, please immediately review your current asset allocation. Is too much of your capital sitting in bank accounts or other &ldquo;guaranteed return&rdquo; investments?  Is your investment portfolio sufficiently diversified? Do you frequently buy and sell in the stock market?</p>
<p>After understanding your asset allocation, you should earnestly plan your financial goals and follow these five principles:</p>
<p><em>1. Clearly define the amount of wealth you hope to achieve and keep it in mind at all times. Simply thinking &ldquo;I want to be rich&rdquo; is not enough.</em></p>
<p><em>2. Set a specific date for achieving your goal.</em></p>
<p><em>3. Determine what price you&rsquo;re willing to pay and what actions you&rsquo;ll take to reach your ideal goal.</em></p>
<p><em>4. Think about your goal at least twice a day to reinforce your belief.</em></p>
<p><em>5.  Take action, whether you feel completely ready or not.</em></p>
<p>In Appendix II, readers can use the wealth creation formula and examples provided to calculate how to achieve their financial goals.</p>
<p>Your future wealth depends on what you do today. Don&rsquo;t let unnecessary hesitation cast a shadow on your heart. As long as you understand investment and financial management, you too can become wealthy in the future. Everyone possesses the necessary ingredients for wealth creation: a small amount of capital and a God-given resource—time. As long as you are willing to learn about personal finance, you have the potential to become a multi-millionaire.</p>
<p>When you find people around you feeling lost due to a lack of vision for the future, share with them the &ldquo;¥14,000 a year for 40 years can make you a multi-millionaire&rdquo; formula and help them reignite their hope.</p>
<p><strong>Financial Dependence Is Your Own Responsibility</strong></p>
<p>The unequal distribution of wealth in today&rsquo;s society is increasingly severe. Some blame flawed policies, others point to artificial market manipulation. I believe neither is the primary cause.  One of the main reasons for the wealth gap is the disparity in financial literacy among people.</p>
<p>The reason for poverty in modern times is not so much insufficient income, lack of thrift, or excessive spending, but rather improper financial management. In modern society, achieving financial independence after the age of 40 is a fundamental responsibility for everyone. Whether you want to or not, or whether you like it or not, investment and financial management have become essential knowledge for modern individuals. Remember, with our current income levels and investment opportunities, &ldquo;remaining poor after 40&rdquo; is self-inflicted, and &ldquo;not being a multi-millionaire after 70&rdquo; is due to a lack of financial knowledge.</p>
<p>Advances in modern medicine have increased human life expectancy, leading to an aging society.  Longer lifespans are a blessing, but enjoying a comfortable retirement is even more crucial. We must accumulate sufficient wealth to secure our lives in old age.</p>
<p><strong>Effortless Personal Finance, Enjoy the Process</strong></p>
<p>From the examples provided in this article, we can see that those who are good at managing their finances understand how to invest their assets in stocks and real estate with high long-term returns, and they avoid unnecessary short-term trading, thus achieving wealth with ease.  Those who are not good at managing their finances either focus solely on saving and keeping their assets in &ldquo;safe&rdquo; bank deposits or try to get rich quickly by engaging in short-term trading in the stock or futures markets. These individuals will eventually be left far behind in the race for financial success.</p>
<p>Most people keep their assets in financial institutions without investing them, and when they do start investing, they aim for quick riches.  As a result, their money stagnates in banks, and their pursuit of quick wealth often leads to substantial losses.  They fail to realize that with a little courage, by investing in stocks and real estate and patiently waiting for decades, they can naturally achieve wealth.</p>
<p>Simply put, building wealth through personal finance only requires two things: investing your capital in areas with high returns and having the patience to wait for the long term. The required investment is low, the probability of success is high, and the process is relaxed and enjoyable.</p>
<p>I advise readers not to rush to get rich through investment, causing anxiety and ultimately achieving the opposite of what they desire.  By following the methods described in this book, you can achieve financial success without expending excessive time and energy, allowing you to focus on your existing career.</p>
<p>Personal finance is a marathon, not a sprint. If you view the entire process from a long-term perspective, temporary setbacks don&rsquo;t signify failure, and momentary gains don&rsquo;t guarantee lasting success. With this mindset, you can maintain a more open perspective and avoid becoming overly attached to gains and losses.</p>
<p>I admit that consistently buying assets and holding them long-term can make personal finance seem dull and unbearable. However, before engaging in any financial activities, investors must clarify their objectives: is it to build wealth or to seek the thrill of gambling? Personal finance can not only lead to wealth but also bring joy and knowledge.  Everyone should learn how to manage their finances and find enjoyment in the process.</p>
<p><strong>Don&rsquo;t Feel Guilty About Being Wealthy</strong></p>
<p>Wealth should be acquired and used ethically. You don&rsquo;t need to apologize to others for your wealth. Only the pursuit of wealth through unscrupulous means is sinful and unfortunate.  Therefore, everyone should not only be confident but also feel obligated to earn wealth. There&rsquo;s no need to be secretive or ashamed about pursuing wealth. On the contrary, being financially dependent is a burden on society.  Moreover, wealthy individuals are more capable of contributing to society.  In short, if you can&rsquo;t find a good reason why getting rich is bad, why not allow yourself to become wealthy?</p>
<p>You earning more in the investment market doesn&rsquo;t mean others will earn less or lose more.  If everyone is proficient in managing their finances, not only can individuals prosper, but economic resources can also be utilized effectively, leading to rapid overall economic growth.  In a market economy, the wealth of society is built upon the wealth of its people. Only a prosperous populace can create a prosperous economy.</p>
<p>In today&rsquo;s financially driven world, whether for personal advancement or the benefit of society as a whole, everyone should strengthen their understanding of personal finance. When everyone is skilled in managing their finances, individuals and families can live prosperous lives, the wealth gap can be narrowed, and the nation can progress and flourish.</p>
<p><strong>Action Speaks Louder Than Words</strong></p>
<p>&ldquo;Knowing and not doing is not knowing.&rdquo; The biggest obstacle to personal finance is not that it&rsquo;s difficult to do, but that it&rsquo;s difficult to start.  The key to overcoming this is to act immediately.  One of the main reasons for failure in personal finance is avoiding decisions.  However, if you want to achieve your goal of building wealth through investment, there&rsquo;s no other way than to take action.</p>
<p>After reading the basic principles of investment and financial management outlined in this article, you should understand that building wealth is not only achievable but also not difficult.  So, act now! Time is money. The earlier you start, the sooner you&rsquo;ll reach your financial goals and share the fruits of your labor with your family.</p>
<p>Looking ahead, changes in society, politics, economics, and finance will accelerate, and the resulting redistribution of wealth will inevitably follow suit.  For yourself, your family, and society as a whole, managing your finances is a role everyone should embrace.</p>
<p><strong>Persistence Is Key</strong></p>
<p>For readers seeking quick riches, this book might disappoint you.  A more accurate title would be: &ldquo;How to Invest and Manage Your Finances to Slowly but Steadily Build Wealth.&rdquo;</p>
<p>Many believe that successful people are infallible—never failing, never experiencing losses.  Many also think they must be omniscient and possess sufficient knowledge before they can start investing and managing their finances.  Our most common flaw is our unwillingness to try repeatedly and to persevere. Building wealth through personal finance is not difficult! The reason most people don&rsquo;t achieve their goals is their inability to persevere and their lack of patience.</p>
<p>Persistence is essential for success in personal finance. Suppose you embark on a wealth-building plan and encounter setbacks along the way. Don&rsquo;t be discouraged. Some people regularly save and invest annually.  When prices rise, they are satisfied and continue their plan. But when prices fall, they panic and abandon their investment strategy.  They fail to understand that price fluctuations are inherent in the investment market, and investment results will inevitably fluctuate.</p>
<p>If, midway through your financial plan, you succumb to the temptation to spend your investment capital or give up due to repeated setbacks, all your previous efforts will be wasted.  <strong>Success in personal finance depends on endurance and resolve:  endurance to delay gratification and resist immediate consumption temptations; and resolve to withstand significant wealth fluctuations over long periods without losing your composure.  As long as you have perseverance and resolve, trust in compound interest, and believe in the &ldquo;wealth creation formula,&rdquo; the ultimate wealth will undoubtedly be yours.</strong></p>
<p>&ldquo;No dreams, no wealth.&rdquo;  Those who build wealth through personal finance must be driven by desire and ambition.  They also need sufficient courage, knowledge, patience, and perseverance.  A lack of courage, flawed methods, impatience, or giving up halfway will not work. Whether you can achieve wealth and financial independence in the future depends entirely on your actions and efforts today.</p>
<p><strong>Unlock Your Hidden Wealth Potential</strong></p>
<p>Believe it or not, the price of living a wealthy and successful life is no greater than the price of living a poor and miserable one. Achieving this depends entirely on wisdom, belief, and action. After reading this book, readers should understand that everyone can achieve wealth through personal finance. The reason most people are not wealthy is not due to low income, but rather a lack of understanding of how to create wealth through investment and financial management. The primary purpose of this book is to help everyone unlock their hidden wealth potential.</p>
<p>If, after reading this book, you still cannot effectively apply these investment principles to manage your money and improve your financial situation, then this book is a complete failure.  Financial education is not merely about imparting knowledge; its significance lies in genuinely changing the reader&rsquo;s financial behavior.</p>
<p>This is a book of action, not a textbook for enhancing investment knowledge or a &ldquo;decorative book&rdquo; for your bookshelf.  This book aims to inspire readers to change their mindset and behavior. Its success depends on readers taking action based on the core principles presented, breaking free from mediocrity, and embarking on the path to wealth. Therefore, at the end of most chapters, key points are summarized for readers to reflect upon and apply.</p>
<p>Investment and financial management can not only lead to wealth but also bring joy to investors. Everyone should learn how to manage their finances and reap the substantial rewards.  I believe most readers already possess the basic requirements for building wealth: a small amount of capital, sufficient time, and the investment knowledge gained from this book.  The world of personal finance, full of changes and opportunities, awaits you.  It is filled with treasures and pitfalls. Don&rsquo;t hesitate, and don&rsquo;t leave empty-handed.</p>
<p>The principles of building wealth through investment and financial management are neither profound nor mysterious. They are absolutely achievable for everyone, and many have indeed easily become wealthy through these methods.  As we&rsquo;ve mentioned before, &ldquo;If you&rsquo;re willing to learn, managing your finances is as simple as walking.&rdquo;</p>
<p>Among the financial principles presented in this book, you&rsquo;ll find many that contradict deeply ingrained investment concepts and financial habits, and some even go against human nature.  Therefore, to realize the ideal of wealth creation through investment and financial management, the first step is to break free from some &ldquo;deep-rooted and misguided&rdquo; investment concepts, common knowledge, and habits.  Almost none of these concepts and principles are easy to achieve. Therefore, I advise readers to not only read each chapter carefully but also to review, reflect, establish strict rules, and ultimately change their behavior.</p>
<p><strong>Wealth Is a Means to a Better Life</strong></p>
<p>Finally, this book must emphasize that <strong>wealth is not the purpose of life, but a means to create a better life.</strong>  The ultimate goal of investment and financial management is not just to become rich, but to use wealth to realize your life&rsquo;s aspirations.  Therefore, <strong>a fulfilling and balanced life is the starting point for personal finance.</strong></p>
<p>Everyone should actively and optimistically plan and execute their lifelong financial journey.  Based on the principles we&rsquo;ve presented, everyone can achieve substantial wealth through personal finance without sacrificing time, energy, work, or life.  However, it&rsquo;s crucial to remember that <strong>only those who balance career, life, health, family, and wealth can be considered truly successful in managing their finances.</strong>  Those who gain the world&rsquo;s riches but lose their health, family, and the meaning of life cannot be considered truly successful.  In today&rsquo;s society, many are lost in the pursuit of wealth, sacrificing more valuable things in life.  Therefore, this principle of balancing personal finance and life is particularly important and deserves careful consideration.</p>
<p>Although this book repeatedly emphasizes that success in personal finance depends on mindset, time, and action, not luck, I still congratulate you, the reader, on being fortunate enough to encounter this book. By adhering to the investment principles within, you are sure to become a multi-millionaire in the decades to come!</p>
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>The Most Important Thing: Book Notes</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1729341470274/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1729341470274/</guid><description>This book, by renowned investor Howard Marks, summarizes his investment experience, explaining his investment philosophy and analyzing key factors such as market environment, investor psychology, and risk control, aiming to help investors achieve above-market investment performance.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[

<h2 class="relative group">I. Summary 
    <div id="i-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>The core idea of this book is how to achieve investment returns that surpass the market average. The author argues that achieving this goal requires &ldquo;second-level thinking,&rdquo; which is deeper and more comprehensive than the thinking of ordinary investors. He emphasizes contrarian investing, being greedy when others are fearful, and fearful when others are greedy. The book elaborates on important concepts such as market efficiency, value assessment, risk identification and control, cyclical and pendulum awareness, investor psychology, and diversified investment. It also provides a wealth of practical experience and case studies, aiming to help investors establish a sound thinking framework and control the impact of emotions on investment decisions.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">II. Chapter Summaries 
    <div id="ii-chapter-summaries" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii-chapter-summaries" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<ol>
<li>
<p><strong>Second-Level Thinking:</strong> To outperform the market, one must engage in second-level thinking, which requires investors to think more deeply and comprehensively, not being satisfied with simple conclusions, but considering various possibilities, probabilities, market consensus, and their own cognitive biases. For example, first-level thinking might conclude, &ldquo;This is a good company, so I should buy it,&rdquo; while second-level thinking would consider, &ldquo;While it&rsquo;s a good company, has the market already overreacted, pushing the price too high?&rdquo;</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Understanding Market Efficiency and Its Limitations:</strong> Markets are not perfectly efficient; there are opportunities for mispricing. However, due to the large number of investors competing, beating the market remains very difficult. Markets are efficient at incorporating information, but they don&rsquo;t always interpret that information correctly. Investors should focus on relatively inefficient markets, such as those that are less followed, have opaque information, or are controversial.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Value Assessment:</strong> The foundation of value investing is accurate estimation of intrinsic value, which requires considering factors such as a company&rsquo;s financial position, management capabilities, profitability, competitive advantages, and future growth prospects. The author emphasizes that value investing focuses more on present value, while growth investing emphasizes future value, but both require considering the future.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>The Relationship Between Price and Value:</strong> Successful investing is not about &ldquo;buying good things,&rdquo; but about &ldquo;buying things well,&rdquo; which means buying at a price below intrinsic value. Price is influenced by value, psychology, and technical factors. Investors need to understand the relationship between these three to make sound investment decisions. Buying a good company at a high price can still lead to losses, while buying a lower-quality asset at a low price can yield high returns.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Understanding Risk:</strong> Risk is not volatility, but the possibility of permanent loss of capital. It&rsquo;s crucial to understand the various forms of risk, such as failing to meet objectives, underperformance, career risk, and liquidity risk. Risk is subjective and difficult to quantify, depending on the investor&rsquo;s specific circumstances and goals.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Recognizing Risk:</strong> Risk often increases when market optimism is high and prices are inflated. Be wary of the &ldquo;no risk&rdquo; narrative and recognize signs of an overheated market, such as high P/E ratios, narrow credit spreads, and loose credit conditions.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Controlling Risk:</strong> Risk control is more important than taking risks. Control risk through diversification, limiting risk exposure, adhering to a margin of safety, and avoiding excessive leverage. The results of risk control are often invisible because they manifest in losses avoided.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Focusing on Cycles:</strong> Everything is cyclical. Recognize the inevitability of cyclical fluctuations and look for opportunities at cyclical extremes. The author uses the credit cycle as an example to illustrate how cycles are self-correcting and how investors can find opportunities within them.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Pendulum Awareness:</strong> Investor psychology swings like a pendulum between optimism and pessimism, greed and fear. Recognize the patterns of this swing and act contrarianly at extremes. Market extremes often represent turning points and opportunities.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Resisting Negative Influences:</strong> Resist the influence of negative emotions such as greed, fear, herd mentality, envy, and ego on investment decisions. Recognizing the existence of these psychological factors and striving to overcome them is crucial for making rational investment decisions.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Contrarian Investing:</strong> Be greedy when others are fearful, and fearful when others are greedy. Contrarian investing is not simply doing the opposite of the crowd; it requires independent thinking and judgment, as well as a deep understanding of value. Contrarian investing can be lonely and unsettling but is key to achieving superior returns.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Finding Bargains:</strong> Bargains often appear in unpopular and unfavored assets, such as those with apparent flaws, misunderstood by the market, or overlooked.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Waiting Patiently for Opportunities:</strong> Don&rsquo;t chase opportunities; wait patiently for them to come to you. Investors should be like baseball hitters, waiting for the perfect pitch instead of swinging blindly.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Recognizing the Limitations of Forecasting:</strong> Predicting the future is very difficult. Recognize the limitations of forecasting and focus on knowable factors, such as company fundamentals and industry trends.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Understanding Your Position in the Cycle:</strong> Understand your position within the market cycle and adjust your investment strategy accordingly. Investors can assess market conditions by observing investor behavior, the credit environment, and valuation levels.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Appreciating the Role of Luck:</strong> Investment outcomes are influenced by luck. Distinguish between skill and luck, and avoid being blinded by short-term success. Investors should focus on long-term performance and analyze the sources of returns, rather than just focusing on short-term gains.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Diversification:</strong> Diversification is an important risk management tool, but understand correlations and avoid ineffective diversification. True diversification means holding assets that behave differently under different market conditions.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Avoiding Mistakes:</strong> Avoiding major mistakes is more important than pursuing great success. Identify and avoid various types of errors, such as analytical errors, psychological errors, and failure to recognize cycles and market sentiment.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>The Significance of Value Creation:</strong> Value creation requires superior investment skill. Understand alpha and beta, and strive for asymmetric investment performance, meaning achieving higher returns when the market rises and suffering fewer losses when the market falls.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Reasonable Expectations:</strong> Set reasonable return expectations and avoid being misled by unrealistic expectations. Excessively high return expectations are often accompanied by excessive risk. Understand how returns are generated and the conditions required to achieve objectives.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>The Most Important Thing:</strong> Summarizes the core ideas of the book, emphasizing the importance of value assessment, risk control, contrarian investing, and psychological factors. Successful investing requires comprehensive consideration of these factors and the development of a complete investment framework.</p>
</li>
</ol>


<h2 class="relative group">III. Key Takeaways 
    <div id="iii-key-takeaways" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii-key-takeaways" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;There&rsquo;s a certain irony in the investing world: What&rsquo;s obvious to everyone else is likely to be wrong.&rdquo;</p></blockquote>
<p>Insight:  Consensus views often lead to average results, at best.  Superior returns require non-consensus views that prove to be correct.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;Remember, your goal in investing isn&rsquo;t to earn average returns; you want to do better than average.&rdquo;</p></blockquote>
<p>Insight:  Complacency is the enemy of superior performance.  Strive to exceed benchmarks, not simply match them.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;The widespread belief that there&rsquo;s no risk is the biggest risk of all.&rdquo;</p></blockquote>
<p>Insight:  When markets are universally optimistic, risk is often at its highest because prices don&rsquo;t reflect potential problems.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;Only when the tide goes out do you discover who&rsquo;s been swimming naked.&rdquo;</p></blockquote>
<p>Insight: Adverse market conditions reveal the weaknesses in portfolios and investment strategies that were hidden during favorable periods.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;It takes greatest courage, but provides the greatest profit, to buy when others are despondently selling and to sell when others are greedily buying.&rdquo;</p></blockquote>
<p>Insight: Contrarian investing is difficult because it requires going against the crowd, but it offers the potential for the highest rewards.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;One of the great things about investing is that you don&rsquo;t have to make a lot of good decisions to do well. What&rsquo;s essential is avoiding bad decisions.&rdquo;</p></blockquote>
<p>Insight:  Preserving capital is paramount.  Avoiding significant losses has a greater impact on long-term returns than occasional big wins.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;An investor needs do very few things right as long as he avoids big mistakes.&rdquo;</p></blockquote>
<p>Insight:  Risk management and capital preservation are the cornerstones of successful investing.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">IV. Practical Application 
    <div id="iv-practical-application" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv-practical-application" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This book provides a comprehensive investment framework to help investors:</p>
<ol>
<li><strong>Establish a sound investment philosophy:</strong> Emphasizes the importance of value investing, contrarian investing, and risk control.</li>
<li><strong>Improve investment skills:</strong> Learn how to assess value, identify risks, control emotions, and construct portfolios.</li>
<li><strong>Cultivate a healthy investment mindset:</strong> Remain rational, objective, patient, and think independently, avoiding being swayed by market sentiment.</li>
<li><strong>Achieve better investment performance:</strong> By applying the methods and techniques discussed in the book, improve the quality of investment decisions and ultimately achieve above-market returns.</li>
</ol>

  



<div
  
    class="flex px-4 py-3 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900"
  >

  <span
    
      class="text-primary-400 ltr:pr-3 rtl:pl-3 flex items-center"
    >

    

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 640 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M172.5 131.1C228.1 75.51 320.5 75.51 376.1 131.1C426.1 181.1 433.5 260.8 392.4 318.3L391.3 319.9C381 334.2 361 337.6 346.7 327.3C332.3 317 328.9 297 339.2 282.7L340.3 281.1C363.2 249 359.6 205.1 331.7 177.2C300.3 145.8 249.2 145.8 217.7 177.2L105.5 289.5C73.99 320.1 73.99 372 105.5 403.5C133.3 431.4 177.3 435 209.3 412.1L210.9 410.1C225.3 400.7 245.3 404 255.5 418.4C265.8 432.8 262.5 452.8 248.1 463.1L246.5 464.2C188.1 505.3 110.2 498.7 60.21 448.8C3.741 392.3 3.741 300.7 60.21 244.3L172.5 131.1zM467.5 380C411 436.5 319.5 436.5 263 380C213 330 206.5 251.2 247.6 193.7L248.7 192.1C258.1 177.8 278.1 174.4 293.3 184.7C307.7 194.1 311.1 214.1 300.8 229.3L299.7 230.9C276.8 262.1 280.4 306.9 308.3 334.8C339.7 366.2 390.8 366.2 422.3 334.8L534.5 222.5C566 191 566 139.1 534.5 108.5C506.7 80.63 462.7 76.99 430.7 99.9L429.1 101C414.7 111.3 394.7 107.1 384.5 93.58C374.2 79.2 377.5 59.21 391.9 48.94L393.5 47.82C451 6.731 529.8 13.25 579.8 63.24C636.3 119.7 636.3 211.3 579.8 267.7L467.5 380z"/></svg>

  </span>


  </span>

  <span
    
      class="dark:text-neutral-300"
    ><strong>Related Reading:</strong>  Howard Marks&rsquo; investment memos: <a href="https://www.oaktreecapital.com/insights/memos" target="_blank"><strong>Archived Memos</strong></a></span>
</div>

<hr>

<section class="space-y-10 w-full">
    
    
</section>
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Just Keep Buying: Book Notes</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1728914740948/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1728914740948/</guid><description>This book answers the most common questions in the field of personal finance and investing. From saving to investing, it provides practical tips to teach you how to increase your income, invest in income-producing assets, manage your finances more wisely, and live a richer life.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[

<h2 class="relative group">I. Content Summary 
    <div id="i-content-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-content-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This book is divided into two parts: saving and investing. The <strong>saving</strong> section covers all aspects of saving money, including how much to save, how to save more, and how to spend money without guilt. The <strong>investing</strong> section covers many aspects of making money with money, including why you should invest, what you should invest in, and how often you should invest. The author answers the most common questions in the field of personal finance and investing, with each chapter exploring a topic in depth and providing practical tips.  Using a large amount of data and empirical research as evidence, the author arrives at reliable ways to save money and build wealth.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">II. Chapter Summary 
    <div id="ii-chapter-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii-chapter-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Chapter 1. Where Should You Start? 
    <div id="chapter-1-where-should-you-start" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chapter-1-where-should-you-start" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>The poor should focus on saving, and the rich should focus on investing.</p>
<ul>
<li>Recent graduates should focus on increasing their income and savings rate, rather than obsessing over investment decisions, because the growth rate of savings far exceeds the growth rate of investment.</li>
<li>People who have accumulated a certain amount of wealth should spend more time thinking about the details of their investment plan.</li>
<li>The author proposes a &ldquo;Save-Invest continuum&rdquo; concept to help you determine your current financial focus: calculate your expected savings and expected investment growth. Focus on whichever is greater.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chapter 2. How Much Should You Save? 
    <div id="chapter-2-how-much-should-you-save" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chapter-2-how-much-should-you-save" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>You probably need to save less than you think.</p>
<ul>
<li>Many saving recommendations are based on false assumptions: that people&rsquo;s incomes are stable and that everyone has the ability to achieve the same savings rate.</li>
<li>In fact, incomes become more unstable over time, and the biggest determinant of an individual&rsquo;s savings rate is their income level.</li>
<li>The best saving advice is: <strong>save what you can save.</strong></li>
<li>A large body of evidence suggests that retirees generally don&rsquo;t spend enough, with many even increasing their financial assets after retirement.</li>
<li>Today&rsquo;s younger generation is not creating wealth any slower than previous generations, so there is no need to worry too much about running out of money after retirement.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chapter 3. How to Save More Money? 
    <div id="chapter-3-how-to-save-more-money" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chapter-3-how-to-save-more-money" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>The biggest lie in personal finance: you can get rich just by saving.</p>
<ul>
<li>The effectiveness of reducing spending is limited. For low-income people, spending is already at its lowest level, making it difficult to reduce further. The author uses data from the U.S. Bureau of Labor Statistics Consumer Expenditure Survey to support this point.</li>
<li>Increasing income is more effective than reducing spending because as income increases, spending does not necessarily increase proportionately (diminishing marginal utility). The author calls this the &ldquo;law of the stomach.&rdquo;</li>
<li>Five ways to increase your income:
<ul>
<li>Sell your time/expertise: easy to do, but not scalable.</li>
<li>Sell a skill/service: higher income, but takes time to develop skills.</li>
<li>Teach: easy to scale, but highly competitive.</li>
<li>Sell a product: scalable, but requires a lot of upfront investment and ongoing marketing efforts.</li>
<li>Climb the career ladder: traditional but effective, can gain skills, experience and stable income growth.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>The most reliable way to get rich is: <strong>Increase your income and invest in income-producing assets.</strong></li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chapter 4. How to Spend Money Without Guilt? 
    <div id="chapter-4-how-to-spend-money-without-guilt" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chapter-4-how-to-spend-money-without-guilt" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Most financial advice uses guilt to make you question your spending decisions, causing you to be overly nervous about spending money.</li>
<li>Two tips to help you make financial decisions without worry and spend money without guilt:
<ul>
<li>The 2x rule: When you splurge, invest the same amount of money in income-producing assets or donate it to charity. For example, if you want to buy a pair of $400 shoes, buy $400 worth of stock at the same time.</li>
<li>Focus on maximizing satisfaction: Think about whether your purchase can bring autonomy, mastery, and purpose, thereby increasing your long-term satisfaction. For example, a daily latte might allow you to do your job better.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>The only right way to spend money is: <strong>the way that works for you</strong>. Think about what you want to get out of life, and make spending decisions accordingly. Research from the University of Cambridge shows that the more your spending patterns match your psychological state, the higher your life satisfaction, and this effect is greater than the happiness brought by your total income.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chapter 5. How Much Lifestyle Inflation Is Harmless? 
    <div id="chapter-5-how-much-lifestyle-inflation-is-harmless" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chapter-5-how-much-lifestyle-inflation-is-harmless" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Lifestyle inflation refers to the increase in spending that follows an increase in one&rsquo;s income.</li>
<li>Some lifestyle inflation is enjoyable, but too much lifestyle inflation will lead to having to delay retirement.</li>
<li>The author simulates the retirement plans of two investors with different savings rates after salary increases to arrive at these conclusions:
<ul>
<li>The lower your current savings rate, the higher your lifestyle inflation can be without affecting your original retirement plan.</li>
<li>The author recommends saving at least 50% of your future raises, a rule that is simple, practical, and suitable for most people.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chapter 6. Should You Go Into Debt? 
    <div id="chapter-6-should-you-go-into-debt" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chapter-6-should-you-go-into-debt" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>Debt is not necessarily good or bad, it depends on how you use it.</p>
<ul>
<li>Debt as a form of risk mitigation: Some people, even with savings, keep credit card debt as a strategy to reduce the risk of future funding shortages.</li>
<li>Debt as a behavioral pillar of forced savings: Some people use debt as a behavioral pillar to force themselves to save.</li>
<li>The two most useful types of debt:
<ul>
<li>To reduce risk: for example, keeping cash on hand for emergencies or fixing housing costs.</li>
<li>To earn a return higher than the cost of borrowing: for example, by taking out education loans, business loans, or mortgages to generate higher returns. The author uses data to demonstrate that getting a college degree is often worthwhile.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Debt can also have non-financial costs, such as psychological stress and health problems, so non-mortgage financial debt should be avoided as much as possible.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chapter 7. Should You Rent or Buy? 
    <div id="chapter-7-should-you-rent-or-buy" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chapter-7-should-you-rent-or-buy" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>The point of buying a home is not whether to buy it, but when to buy it.</p>
<ul>
<li>In addition to the mortgage, there are a number of one-time and ongoing costs associated with buying a home, such as down payment, closing costs, taxes, maintenance, and insurance. The author details these costs, concluding that buying a home is only cost-effective if the buyer intends to live in it for the long term.</li>
<li>In the short term, buying a home is riskier than renting, but in the long term, renters face greater long-term risks such as rent fluctuations, housing instability, and moving costs.</li>
<li>In the United States, the long-term return on  homeownership as an investment is not ideal, far lower than the stock market. The author uses the example of his grandparents buying a home to illustrate this point.</li>
<li>The right time to buy a home is when you:
<ul>
<li>plan to stay in that location for at least ten years;</li>
<li>have a stable personal and professional life;</li>
<li>can afford a 20% down payment and keep your debt-to-income ratio below 43%. The author recommends, if possible, to make a 20% down payment and buy a larger home in one step, because the transaction costs are lower in the long run.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chapter 8. How to Save For a Down Payment (and Other Big Purchases)? 
    <div id="chapter-8-how-to-save-for-a-down-payment-and-other-big-purchases" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chapter-8-how-to-save-for-a-down-payment-and-other-big-purchases" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>Why the length of time you save matters?</p>
<ul>
<li>Short-term saving for less than two years: Holding <strong>cash</strong> is the best option, as it has the lowest risk.</li>
<li>Long-term saving for more than two years: Investing in <strong>bonds</strong> is preferable to holding cash because bond returns can offset the effects of inflation. The author compares cash and bonds using two examples: &ldquo;Save $1,000 per month with a goal of $24,000&rdquo; and &ldquo;Save $1,000 per month with a goal of $60,000&rdquo;.</li>
<li>Longer-term saving for more than three years: You can choose to invest in <strong>stocks</strong>, but the risk is higher and you need to choose an appropriate portfolio based on your own risk tolerance. The author uses data to show that stocks have much higher long-term returns than bonds, but also greater volatility.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chapter 9. When Can You Retire? 
    <div id="chapter-9-when-can-you-retire" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chapter-9-when-can-you-retire" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>There&rsquo;s more to consider than just money when it comes to retirement.</p>
<ul>
<li>The 4% rule: When your retirement savings reach 25 times your expected annual expenses, you can retire.
<ul>
<li>You can withdraw 4% of your investment assets (half bonds and half stocks) in the first year of retirement, and increase the amount withdrawn by 3% each year to keep up with inflation.</li>
<li>If you have a pension or other guaranteed income, you only need to save 25 times your &ldquo;annual excess spending&rdquo; (expected annual expenses less future guaranteed income).</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>The crossover point rule: The point at which your monthly investment income is greater than your monthly expenses, you have reached the &ldquo;crossover point&rdquo; and achieved financial freedom.
<ul>
<li>&ldquo;Crossover Assets&rdquo; = Monthly Expenses / Monthly Investment Return.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Retirement is much more than just a financial decision, it&rsquo;s a lifestyle decision. You need to think about what you want to do and how you want to live after retirement. The author uses the examples of several celebrities to illustrate the confusion and emptiness that can exist after early retirement.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chapter 10. Why You Should Invest? 
    <div id="chapter-10-why-you-should-invest" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chapter-10-why-you-should-invest" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>Three reasons to make your money grow.</p>
<ul>
<li>Save for your future self: Investing allows you to have a pool of resources to draw from as you age. Human lifespans are increasing, and the concept of &ldquo;retirement&rdquo; has emerged accordingly. To ensure quality of life after retirement, it is necessary to invest in advance.</li>
<li>Fight inflation and maintain the purchasing power of your wealth: Investing can offset the impact of inflation and maintain or increase your purchasing power. The author uses data to show that investing can effectively combat the effects of inflation.</li>
<li>Replace your human capital with financial capital: Investing can turn your diminishing human capital into financial capital that can continue to generate returns. The author illustrates this with the example of professional athletes.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chapter 11. What Should You Invest In? 
    <div id="chapter-11-what-should-you-invest-in" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chapter-11-what-should-you-invest-in" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>There is no single right way to get rich.</p>
<ul>
<li>The author lists a variety of income-producing assets, including:
<ul>
<li>Stocks: One of the most reliable ways to build wealth over the long term, easy to own and trade, with low maintenance costs, but highly volatile and valuations easily influenced by market sentiment.</li>
<li>Bonds: Low volatility, safe principal, and helpful in rebalancing portfolios, but returns are generally lower than stocks, especially in a low interest rate environment.</li>
<li>Investment real estate: Returns are higher than stocks or bonds, especially when using leverage, but require more effort to manage and are difficult to diversify.</li>
<li>Real Estate Investment Trusts (REITs): Provide access to real estate investment income without needing to manage it yourself, but are more volatile and highly correlated with stocks and other risky assets during stock market crashes.</li>
<li>Farmland: Low correlation with stocks and bonds, low volatility, inflation-resistant, but low liquidity, higher fees, and requires &ldquo;accredited investor&rdquo; status to participate.</li>
<li>Small businesses/franchises/angel investing: Potential for high returns and the more effort you put in, the greater the return, but requires a significant time commitment and has a high failure rate.</li>
<li>Royalties: Can generate stable income that is uncorrelated with traditional financial assets, but sellers incur high fees and public taste changes are unpredictable.</li>
<li>Your own products: 100% ownership, personal satisfaction and achievement, can create a valuable brand, but very labor-intensive and no guarantee of return.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>The author also contrasts the characteristics of income-producing and non-income-producing assets (e.g., gold, cryptocurrency, art, etc.) and their respective advantages and disadvantages.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chapter 12. Why You Shouldn&rsquo;t Buy Individual Stocks? 
    <div id="chapter-12-why-you-shouldnt-buy-individual-stocks" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chapter-12-why-you-shouldnt-buy-individual-stocks" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>Why underperforming the market is the least of your worries?</p>
<ul>
<li>Most people (even professionals) can&rsquo;t beat the market. Data from the SPIVA report shows that active funds tend to underperform index funds over the long term.</li>
<li>Only a very small percentage of individual stocks outperform in the long run. Bessembinder&rsquo;s research indicates that since 1926, only 4% of stocks have generated returns that exceed U.S. Treasury bonds.</li>
<li>Even stocks that outperform are not always winners. West&rsquo;s statistical analysis suggests that many companies will disappear within a decade.</li>
<li>Choosing individual stocks is emotionally draining and stressful. The author uses the example of his friend Darren investing in GameStop stock to detail the emotional rollercoaster of stock trading.</li>
<li>It&rsquo;s hard to tell if you&rsquo;re really good at picking stocks. The link between stock picking decisions and outcomes is not significant, making it difficult to assess your stock picking skills. Even if you have performed well in the past, there is no guarantee that you will continue to do so in the future.</li>
<li>The risk of holding a concentrated position in a single stock is that the return is lower than the market. The author uses data on U.S. stock performance since 1963 to show that the median return of individual stocks is lower than that of index funds.</li>
<li>The author suggests buying index funds or ETFs to earn market average returns, which can lead to higher returns and less stress during the investment process.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chapter 13. How Early Should You Start Investing? 
    <div id="chapter-13-how-early-should-you-start-investing" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chapter-13-how-early-should-you-start-investing" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>Why buying early is better than buying late?</p>
<ul>
<li>Most markets tend to go up most of the time, so investing early allows for a longer period of compounding growth.</li>
<li>The author compares two investment strategies:
<ul>
<li>Buy now: Put all the money you can invest in immediately.</li>
<li>Average in: Invest the money you can invest in batches.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Conclusion: The <strong>buy now</strong> strategy is generally better than the average-in strategy. The author uses U.S. stock market data from 1997 to 2020, as well as U.S. stock market data from 1920 to 2020, to respectively prove this conclusion. The same results hold when testing other types of assets.</li>
<li>For risk-averse investors, you can choose to invest in a lower risk portfolio. For example, change an 80% stock / 20% bond portfolio to a 60% stock / 40% bond portfolio.</li>
<li>Even if market valuations are high, the buy now strategy is still better than the average in strategy. The author compares the two strategies using CAPE percentile categories, and the results show that the buy now strategy is still superior even during periods of high valuations.</li>
<li>For investors concerned about the risk of a lump sum investment, you can take a longer time to gradually adjust to your target asset allocation.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chapter 14. Why You Shouldn&rsquo;t Wait to Buy the Dip? 
    <div id="chapter-14-why-you-shouldnt-wait-to-buy-the-dip" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chapter-14-why-you-shouldnt-wait-to-buy-the-dip" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>Even God can&rsquo;t beat dollar-cost averaging.</p>
<ul>
<li>The buy the dip strategy only works if the market is about to have a big drop and you can accurately predict when it will happen.</li>
<li>Big market drops don&rsquo;t happen that often, so the buy the dip strategy has a small chance of beating dollar-cost averaging. The author simulates the two strategies using U.S. stock market data from between 1920 and 1980. The results show that in all forty-year investment periods, the buy-the-dip strategy underperformed dollar-cost averaging more than 70% of the time.</li>
<li>Even with perfect information, the buy the dip strategy often loses to dollar-cost averaging because the market may continue to rise while you miss out on compounding growth. The author simulates the two strategies using U.S. stock market data from 1975 onward, again proving this conclusion.</li>
<li>Even if the predicted time of the market bottom is off by only two months, the long-term investment performance of the buy-the-dip strategy still loses to dollar-cost averaging.</li>
<li>Conclusion: <strong>you should invest as early as possible and as often as possible</strong>.</li>
<li>Investment returns are heavily influenced by time, and the power of strategy is far less than the power of market change.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chapter 15. Why Does Investing Involve Luck? 
    <div id="chapter-15-why-does-investing-involve-luck" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chapter-15-why-does-investing-involve-luck" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>And why you shouldn&rsquo;t care.</p>
<ul>
<li>The year you were born influences your investment returns because markets fluctuate unpredictably. The author illustrates this with data on 10-, 20-, and 30-year investment returns in the U.S. stock market since 1910.</li>
<li>The sequence of investment returns also affects your final return because you invest more money in the later stages of your investment, so later returns are more important. The author illustrates the impact of return sequence with two cases of 20-year investment horizons with the same annualized return but in reverse order.</li>
<li>How to mitigate bad luck:
<ul>
<li>Hold low-risk assets (such as bonds) for the long term to diversify risk.</li>
<li>Withdraw less money during market downturns.</li>
<li>Consider getting a part-time job to supplement your income.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chapter 16. Why You Shouldn&rsquo;t Fear Market Volatility? 
    <div id="chapter-16-why-you-shouldnt-fear-market-volatility" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chapter-16-why-you-shouldnt-fear-market-volatility" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>The price of admission for successful investing.</p>
<ul>
<li>Avoiding too many market declines can limit your upside.</li>
<li>Using the analogy of a &ldquo;market genie&rdquo; that tells you the maximum intra-year drawdown for the coming year, the author simulates different risk aversion strategies. The conclusion is that if you want to maximize long-term wealth, you should accept some degree of intra-year market decline (0% to 15%) and avoid large intra-year market declines (greater than 15%).</li>
<li>Buying a diversified portfolio of income-producing assets over the long term is one of the best ways to combat market volatility as it rears its ugly head.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chapter 17. How to Buy During a Crisis? 
    <div id="chapter-17-how-to-buy-during-a-crisis" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chapter-17-how-to-buy-during-a-crisis" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>Why you should keep your cool when the market panics?</p>
<ul>
<li>Market crashes are opportunities to buy because every dollar you invest at this point will earn a higher return after the market recovers. The author uses the 1929 U.S. stock market crash as an example to illustrate the excess returns of investing at the bottom of the market.</li>
<li>The more the market falls, the higher the return you need to make up for the loss. The author illustrates this with a simple mathematical formula and chart.</li>
<li>Even if the market takes a long time to recover, buying during a crisis is still a good decision because you can earn a decent annualized return while you wait. The author proves this conclusion using examples of the U.S. stock market falling 30% and 50% between 1920 and 2020.</li>
<li>Most stock markets trend upwards most of the time, and even if a prolonged downturn occurs, the likelihood of losing money is significantly reduced if you make regular investments as most investors do, rather than a single lump sum investment. The author illustrates this with the example of the Japanese stock market.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chapter 18. When Should You Sell? 
    <div id="chapter-18-when-should-you-sell" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chapter-18-when-should-you-sell" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>About rebalancing, concentrated positions, and the purpose of investing.</p>
<ul>
<li>Three situations where you should consider selling an investment asset:
<ul>
<li>Rebalancing your portfolio.</li>
<li>Getting rid of a concentrated (or consistently losing) investment position.</li>
<li>Meeting your financial needs.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>You should have a plan in place before you consider selling investment assets to avoid emotional decisions.</li>
<li>Selling gradually (or selling later) is generally better than selling immediately, because in the long run, the market tends to go up.</li>
<li>Regularly rebalancing your portfolio can reduce risk, but it generally reduces returns. The author simulates two strategies, annual rebalancing and never rebalancing, using a portfolio of 60% stocks/40% bonds, and compares the returns and maximum drawdowns after 30 years.</li>
<li>Accumulative rebalancing is a better way to rebalance by buying asset classes that are underweight over time to avoid incurring tax liabilities. The author uses the same portfolio to simulate a strategy of adding investments each month, demonstrating that this strategy can effectively reduce the maximum drawdown.</li>
<li>For investors holding large concentrated positions, it is advisable to sell some of the assets to reduce risk and meet their own living needs. Selling strategies can range from selling a portion on a regular basis to selling based on price levels, as long as it is decided in advance.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chapter 19. Where Should Your Investments Be Held? 
    <div id="chapter-19-where-should-your-investments-be-held" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chapter-19-where-should-your-investments-be-held" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>On taxes, traditional 401(k) vs. Roth 401(k), and why you might not want to maximize your 401(k).</p>
<ul>
<li>Tax policy in the United States is constantly changing, and financial management should also be adjusted according to tax policy. The author reviews the history of income tax in the United States to illustrate this point.</li>
<li>When choosing between a traditional 401(k) and a Roth 401(k), the most important factor is whether your effective income tax rate is higher now (during your working years) or later (in retirement).</li>
<li>The author favors traditional 401(k)s because they offer more flexibility and allow you to convert funds to a Roth IRA when tax rates are lower, such as when you are in business school or on maternity leave.</li>
<li>Roth 401(k)s may be a better option for high savers because they can enjoy greater total tax deferral benefits. The author illustrates this with the example of Sally and Sam.</li>
<li>Using a retirement savings account to invest can avoid capital gains taxes, which can lead to significant long-term gains. The author uses simulated data to compare the returns of three approaches: tax-free accounts, accounts taxed once on capital gains, and accounts taxed annually on capital gains. The author also explains the impact of compounding on investment returns.</li>
<li>Maximizing your 401(k) may not be the best option because 401(k) plan fees may offset the tax benefits. The author suggests that you should at least increase your personal contributions to the point where you can receive the maximum employer match. For any contributions beyond that, you need to take into account the 401(k)&rsquo;s expense ratio and your own need for liquidity.</li>
<li>When allocating assets, it is advisable to place high-growth assets (e.g. stocks) in tax-advantaged accounts and low-growth assets (e.g. bonds) in taxable accounts.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chapter 20. Why Will You Never Feel Rich? 
    <div id="chapter-20-why-will-you-never-feel-rich" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chapter-20-why-will-you-never-feel-rich" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>You might already be rich, so why not?</p>
<ul>
<li>People can always find someone richer than themselves, so it&rsquo;s hard to feel content. The author illustrates people&rsquo;s sense of relative wealth by telling the story of Powerball lottery winner Jack Whittaker, and the story of his friend John.</li>
<li>If you compare yourself to people around the world, you may find that you are much richer than you think. For example, if your net worth is over $4,210, you are wealthier than half the world; if your net worth is over $93,170, you are in the top 10% of the world&rsquo;s wealth.</li>
<li>Don&rsquo;t let feelings of relative wealth affect your happiness and appreciate the wealth you have.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chapter 21. The Most Important Asset 
    <div id="chapter-21-the-most-important-asset" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chapter-21-the-most-important-asset" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>Why you can never get more of this asset.</p>
<ul>
<li>Time is your most important asset, and how you use your time will have a huge impact on your future life. The author tells the story of Dashrath Manjhi, an Indian villager who carved a road through a mountain, to illustrate the power of time.</li>
<li>In your younger years, you should prioritize career development because that&rsquo;s when your income grows the fastest. The author uses his own experience to illustrate the importance of making the right career choices early on.</li>
<li>Don&rsquo;t sacrifice your time in pursuit of money, because you can never buy more time with money.</li>
<li>People&rsquo;s happiness tends to follow a U-shaped curve as they age, overestimating their future happiness in their youth, being more pessimistic in middle age, and feeling pleasantly surprised in old age.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Conclusion. The Just Keep Buying Rules 
    <div id="conclusion-the-just-keep-buying-rules" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#conclusion-the-just-keep-buying-rules" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>How to win the time traveler&rsquo;s game?</p>
<ul>
<li>The author summarizes 21 financial guidelines to help you succeed on your financial journey, these guidelines are called the &ldquo;Just Keep Buying Rules&rdquo;:
<ol>
<li>The poor should focus on saving, and the rich should focus on investing.</li>
<li>Save what you can save.</li>
<li>Focus on income, not expenses.</li>
<li>Use the &ldquo;2x rule&rdquo; to eliminate spending guilt.</li>
<li>Save at least 50% of your future raises and bonuses.</li>
<li>Debt is not necessarily a good thing or a bad thing, it depends on how you use it.</li>
<li>Only buy a house when the timing is right.</li>
<li>Use cash when saving for large purchases.</li>
<li>There&rsquo;s more to retirement than just money.</li>
<li>Invest to accumulate financial capital to replace your diminishing human capital.</li>
<li>Think like an owner and buy income-producing assets.</li>
<li>Don&rsquo;t buy individual stocks.</li>
<li>Buy fast, sell slow.</li>
<li>Invest as early and as often as possible.</li>
<li>Investing is not just about the cards you have, it&rsquo;s also about how you play them.</li>
<li>Don&rsquo;t be afraid when volatility inevitably comes.</li>
<li>Market crashes are usually opportunities to buy.</li>
<li>Use your money for the life you need before risking it for the life you want.</li>
<li>Think twice before maximizing your 401(k).</li>
<li>You&rsquo;ll never feel rich, and that&rsquo;s okay.</li>
<li>Time is your most important asset.</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">III. Quotes 
    <div id="iii-quotes" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii-quotes" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>The surest way to get rich is to increase your income and invest in income-producing assets.</p></blockquote>
<p>Analysis: Instead of blindly pursuing saving, it is better to focus your energy on increasing your income and investing in assets that can generate income; this is a more reliable path to financial freedom.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The only right way to spend money is the way that works for you.</p></blockquote>
<p>Analysis: Everyone&rsquo;s values, life goals, and preferences are different, so their financial management style should also be personalized. Don&rsquo;t blindly follow the crowd; find a spending pattern that suits you in order to achieve true happiness.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Time is your most important asset.</p></blockquote>
<p>Analysis: Time is a non-renewable resource. We should cherish time and spend it on the most valuable things. Investing early is not only about accumulating wealth, but also about buying back more time and freedom.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">IV. Guiding Significance 
    <div id="iv-guiding-significance" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv-guiding-significance" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<ul>
<li><strong>Establishing the right financial mindset:</strong> This book helps us understand the essence of personal finance and how to develop a sound savings and investment plan, avoiding common financial pitfalls.</li>
<li><strong>Enhancing personal competitiveness:</strong> The book emphasizes the importance of increasing income and encourages us to continuously learn and improve our personal skills to gain greater career development space.</li>
<li><strong>Balancing life and wealth:</strong> The author reminds us that wealth is not the only goal in life. We should focus on the quality of life and the realization of personal values while pursuing wealth.</li>
<li><strong>Viewing investment rationally:</strong> This book emphasizes the importance of long-term investing and warns investors not to blindly chase short-term gains or be intimidated by market volatility. Only rationality and patience can ultimately lead to success.</li>
</ul>

  



<div
  
    class="flex px-4 py-3 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900"
  >

  <span
    
      class="text-primary-400 ltr:pr-3 rtl:pl-3 flex items-center"
    >

    

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 640 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M172.5 131.1C228.1 75.51 320.5 75.51 376.1 131.1C426.1 181.1 433.5 260.8 392.4 318.3L391.3 319.9C381 334.2 361 337.6 346.7 327.3C332.3 317 328.9 297 339.2 282.7L340.3 281.1C363.2 249 359.6 205.1 331.7 177.2C300.3 145.8 249.2 145.8 217.7 177.2L105.5 289.5C73.99 320.1 73.99 372 105.5 403.5C133.3 431.4 177.3 435 209.3 412.1L210.9 410.1C225.3 400.7 245.3 404 255.5 418.4C265.8 432.8 262.5 452.8 248.1 463.1L246.5 464.2C188.1 505.3 110.2 498.7 60.21 448.8C3.741 392.3 3.741 300.7 60.21 244.3L172.5 131.1zM467.5 380C411 436.5 319.5 436.5 263 380C213 330 206.5 251.2 247.6 193.7L248.7 192.1C258.1 177.8 278.1 174.4 293.3 184.7C307.7 194.1 311.1 214.1 300.8 229.3L299.7 230.9C276.8 262.1 280.4 306.9 308.3 334.8C339.7 366.2 390.8 366.2 422.3 334.8L534.5 222.5C566 191 566 139.1 534.5 108.5C506.7 80.63 462.7 76.99 430.7 99.9L429.1 101C414.7 111.3 394.7 107.1 384.5 93.58C374.2 79.2 377.5 59.21 391.9 48.94L393.5 47.82C451 6.731 529.8 13.25 579.8 63.24C636.3 119.7 636.3 211.3 579.8 267.7L467.5 380z"/></svg>

  </span>


  </span>

  <span
    
      class="dark:text-neutral-300"
    ><strong>Further Reading</strong>: Check out the author, <strong>Nick Maggiulli</strong>&rsquo;s blog: <a href="https://ofdollarsanddata.com/" target="_blank"><strong>Of Dollars And Data</strong></a></span>
</div>

<hr>

<section class="space-y-10 w-full">
    
    
        
            






















  <a class="flex flex-wrap article " href="/en/posts/1728295490690-book-list/">
    
        
        <div class="w-full md:w-auto h-full thumbnail nozoom thumbnailshadow md:mr-7" style="background-image:url(/posts/1728295490690-book-list/featured_hu_a14921d8ab66af4e.jpg);"></div>
        
      <div class=" mt-3 md:mt-0">
      <div class="items-center text-left text-xl font-semibold">
        
        <div class="font-bold text-xl text-neutral-800 decoration-primary-500 hover:underline hover:underline-offset-2 dark:text-neutral"
          href="/en/posts/1728295490690-book-list/">Recommended Reading List</div>
        
        
        
      </div>
      <div class="text-sm text-neutral-500 dark:text-neutral-400">
        











  



















<div class="flex flex-row flex-wrap items-center">
  
  
  <time datetime="2024-10-01T00:00:00&#43;00:00">1 October 2024</time>
  

  
  
</div>





<div class="flex flex-row flex-wrap items-center">
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  <span style="margin-top:0.5rem" class="mr-2" onclick="window.open(&#34;/en/tags/recommended/&#34;,'_self');">
    <span class="flex" style="cursor: pointer;">
  <span class="rounded-md border border-primary-400 px-1 py-[1px] text-xs font-normal text-primary-700 dark:border-primary-600 dark:text-primary-400">
    Recommended
  </span>
</span>
  </span>
  
  <span style="margin-top:0.5rem" class="mr-2" onclick="window.open(&#34;/en/tags/book/&#34;,'_self');">
    <span class="flex" style="cursor: pointer;">
  <span class="rounded-md border border-primary-400 px-1 py-[1px] text-xs font-normal text-primary-700 dark:border-primary-600 dark:text-primary-400">
    Book
  </span>
</span>
  </span>
  
  
  
  
</div>




      </div>
      
    </div>
  </a>

        
    
</section>
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>How to Invest in NASDAQ 100</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1728723295012-invest-qqq/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1728723295012-invest-qqq/</guid><description>a description</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="qqq-tradingview">
    <script>
        const container = document.getElementById('qqq-tradingview');
        const script = document.createElement('script');
        script.type = 'text/javascript';
        script.src = 'https://s3.tradingview.com/external-embedding/embed-widget-mini-symbol-overview.js';  // 加载TradingView库
        script.async = true; //  异步加载，不阻塞页面渲染
        script.textContent = `{"symbol": "NASDAQ:NDX",
                                "width": "100%",
                                "height": "220",
                                "locale": "EN",
                                "dateRange": "ALL",
                                "colorTheme": "dark",
                                "isTransparent": true,
                                "autosize": true}`;
        container.appendChild(script);  //  将 <script> 标签添加到容器中
    </script>
</div>


<h2 class="relative group">North America 
    <div id="north-america" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#north-america" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">United States 
    <div id="united-states" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#united-states" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<table>
  <thead>
      <tr>
          <th>Ticker</th>
          <th>Product Name</th>
          <th>Remarks</th>
      </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
      <tr>
          <td><strong>QQQ</strong></td>
          <td>Invesco QQQ Trust</td>
          <td></td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td><strong>QQQM</strong></td>
          <td>Invesco NASDAQ 100 ETF</td>
          <td></td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>QLD</td>
          <td>ProShares Ultra QQQ</td>
          <td>2x</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>TQQQ</td>
          <td>ProShares UltraPro QQQ</td>
          <td>3x</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>PSQ</td>
          <td>ProShares Short QQQ</td>
          <td>-1x</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>QID</td>
          <td>ProShares UltraShort QQQ</td>
          <td>-2x</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>SQQQ</td>
          <td>ProShares UltraPro Short QQQ</td>
          <td>-3x</td>
      </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>


<h3 class="relative group">Canada 
    <div id="canada" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#canada" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<table>
  <thead>
      <tr>
          <th>Ticker</th>
          <th>Product Name</th>
          <th>Remarks</th>
      </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
      <tr>
          <td>XQQ</td>
          <td>iShares NASDAQ 100 (CAD Hedged)</td>
          <td></td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>QQC</td>
          <td>Invesco NASDAQ 100 Index Fund</td>
          <td></td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>HQU</td>
          <td>BetaPro NASDAQ-100 2x Daily Bull</td>
          <td>2x</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>HQD</td>
          <td>BetaPro NASDAQ-100 2x Daily Bear</td>
          <td>-2x</td>
      </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>


<h2 class="relative group">Asia 
    <div id="asia" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#asia" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">China 
    <div id="china" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#china" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<table>
  <thead>
      <tr>
          <th>Ticker</th>
          <th>Product Name</th>
          <th>Remarks</th>
      </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
      <tr>
          <td>159941</td>
          <td>GF Fund NASDAQ-100 ETF</td>
          <td></td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>513100</td>
          <td>Cathay NASDAQ-100 ETF</td>
          <td></td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>513300</td>
          <td>ChinaAMC NASDAQ-100 ETF</td>
          <td></td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>159513</td>
          <td>Dacheng NASDAQ-100 ETF</td>
          <td></td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>159632</td>
          <td>HuaAn NASDAQ-100 ETF</td>
          <td></td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>159501</td>
          <td>Harvest NASDAQ-100 ETF</td>
          <td></td>
      </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>


<h3 class="relative group">Hong Kong, China 
    <div id="hong-kong-china" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#hong-kong-china" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<table>
  <thead>
      <tr>
          <th>Ticker</th>
          <th>Product Name</th>
          <th>Remarks</th>
      </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
      <tr>
          <td>02834</td>
          <td>iShares NASDAQ 100</td>
          <td></td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>03034</td>
          <td>CSOP NASDAQ 100</td>
          <td></td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>07266</td>
          <td>FL 2X CSOP NASDAQ 100</td>
          <td>2x</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>07261</td>
          <td>FL 2X ChinaAMC NASDAQ 100</td>
          <td>2x</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>07568</td>
          <td>FI 2X Inverse CSOP NASDAQ 100</td>
          <td>-2x</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>07522</td>
          <td>FI 2X Inverse ChinaAMC NASDAQ 100</td>
          <td>-2x</td>
      </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>


<h3 class="relative group">Taiwan, China 
    <div id="taiwan-china" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#taiwan-china" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<table>
  <thead>
      <tr>
          <th>Ticker</th>
          <th>Product Name</th>
          <th>Remarks</th>
      </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
      <tr>
          <td>00662</td>
          <td>Fubon NASDAQ 100</td>
          <td></td>
      </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>


<h3 class="relative group">India 
    <div id="india" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#india" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<table>
  <thead>
      <tr>
          <th>Ticker</th>
          <th>Product Name</th>
          <th>Remarks</th>
      </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
      <tr>
          <td>N100</td>
          <td>Motilal Oswal MOSt Shares NASDAQ 100</td>
          <td></td>
      </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>


<h3 class="relative group">Japan 
    <div id="japan" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#japan" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<table>
  <thead>
      <tr>
          <th>Ticker</th>
          <th>Product Name</th>
          <th>Remarks</th>
      </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
      <tr>
          <td>2569</td>
          <td>Listed Index Fund US Equity (NASDAQ100) Currency Hedged</td>
          <td></td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>1545</td>
          <td>NEXT FUNDS NASDAQ-100</td>
          <td></td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>2568</td>
          <td>Listed Index Fund US Equity (NASDAQ100) No Currency Hedging</td>
          <td></td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>2631</td>
          <td>MUKAM MAXIS NASDAQ100 ETF</td>
          <td></td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>2842</td>
          <td>iFreeETF NASDAQ100 Inverse</td>
          <td>-1x</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>2869</td>
          <td>iFreeETF NASDAQ100 Leveraged (2x)</td>
          <td>2x</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>2870</td>
          <td>iFreeETF NASDAQ100 Double Inverse (-2x)</td>
          <td>-2x</td>
      </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>


<h3 class="relative group">South Korea 
    <div id="south-korea" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#south-korea" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<table>
  <thead>
      <tr>
          <th>Ticker</th>
          <th>Product Name</th>
          <th>Remarks</th>
      </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
      <tr>
          <td>379810</td>
          <td>Samsung KODEX US NASDAQ100 Total Return</td>
          <td></td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>409820</td>
          <td>SAMSUNG KODEX US NASDAQ100 Leverage (SYNTH H)</td>
          <td></td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>367380</td>
          <td>KIM KINDEX NASDAQ100</td>
          <td></td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>368590</td>
          <td>KB KBSTAR US NASDAQ100</td>
          <td></td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>133690</td>
          <td>Mirae Asset TIGER NASDAQ 100 ETF</td>
          <td></td>
      </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>


<h2 class="relative group">Europe 
    <div id="europe" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#europe" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Germany 
    <div id="germany" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#germany" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<table>
  <thead>
      <tr>
          <th>Ticker</th>
          <th>Product Name</th>
          <th>Remarks</th>
      </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
      <tr>
          <td>NDXEX</td>
          <td>iShares NASDAQ-100 UCITS ETF</td>
          <td></td>
      </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>


<h3 class="relative group">United Kingdom 
    <div id="united-kingdom" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#united-kingdom" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<table>
  <thead>
      <tr>
          <th>Ticker</th>
          <th>Product Name</th>
          <th>Remarks</th>
      </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
      <tr>
          <td>CNDX</td>
          <td>iShares NASDAQ 100 UCITS ETF</td>
          <td></td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>EQQQ</td>
          <td>INVESCO MARKETS III PLC INVESCO EQQQ NASDAQ 100 UCITS ETF</td>
          <td></td>
      </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>


<h3 class="relative group">France 
    <div id="france" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#france" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<table>
  <thead>
      <tr>
          <th>Ticker</th>
          <th>Product Name</th>
          <th>Remarks</th>
      </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
      <tr>
          <td>USTE</td>
          <td>Lyxor UCITS Nasdaq-100 D-EUR</td>
          <td></td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>PUST</td>
          <td>Lyxor PEA Nasdaq 100 C</td>
          <td></td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>PANX</td>
          <td>Amundi ETF PEA Nasdaq-100 UCITS</td>
          <td></td>
      </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>


<h3 class="relative group">Austria 
    <div id="austria" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#austria" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<table>
  <thead>
      <tr>
          <th>Ticker</th>
          <th>Product Name</th>
          <th>Remarks</th>
      </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
      <tr>
          <td>EXXT</td>
          <td>iShares NASDAQ-100 UCITS</td>
          <td></td>
      </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>


<h3 class="relative group">Hungary 
    <div id="hungary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#hungary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<table>
  <thead>
      <tr>
          <th>Ticker</th>
          <th>Product Name</th>
          <th>Remarks</th>
      </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
      <tr>
          <td>DE0A0F.</td>
          <td>iShares NASDAQ-100 UCITS</td>
          <td></td>
      </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>


<h3 class="relative group">Switzerland 
    <div id="switzerland" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#switzerland" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<table>
  <thead>
      <tr>
          <th>Ticker</th>
          <th>Product Name</th>
          <th>Remarks</th>
      </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
      <tr>
          <td>CSNDX</td>
          <td>iShares Nasdaq 100 UCITS</td>
          <td></td>
      </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>


<h2 class="relative group">South America 
    <div id="south-america" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#south-america" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Brazil 
    <div id="brazil" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#brazil" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<table>
  <thead>
      <tr>
          <th>Ticker</th>
          <th>Product Name</th>
          <th>Remarks</th>
      </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
      <tr>
          <td>NASD11</td>
          <td>Trend ETF Nasdaq 100 Fundo de Índice</td>
          <td></td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>QQQI11</td>
          <td>Buena Vista Nasdaq-100 High Income</td>
          <td></td>
      </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>


<h2 class="relative group">Africa 
    <div id="africa" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#africa" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">South Africa 
    <div id="south-africa" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#south-africa" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<table>
  <thead>
      <tr>
          <th>Ticker</th>
          <th>Product Name</th>
          <th>Remarks</th>
      </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
      <tr>
          <td>STXNDQJ</td>
          <td>Satrix Nasdaq 100 Feeder Portfolio</td>
          <td></td>
      </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>


<h2 class="relative group">Oceania 
    <div id="oceania" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#oceania" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Australia 
    <div id="australia" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#australia" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<table>
  <thead>
      <tr>
          <th>Ticker</th>
          <th>Product Name</th>
          <th>Remarks</th>
      </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
      <tr>
          <td>NDQ</td>
          <td>Betashares Nasdaq 100</td>
          <td></td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>HNDQ</td>
          <td>BetaShares NASDAQ 100 ETF - Currency Hedged</td>
          <td></td>
      </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>


<h2 class="relative group">Middle East 
    <div id="middle-east" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#middle-east" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Israel 
    <div id="israel" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#israel" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<table>
  <thead>
      <tr>
          <th>Ticker</th>
          <th>Product Name</th>
          <th>Remarks</th>
      </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
      <tr>
          <td>MTFF96</td>
          <td>MTF Sal (4A) Nasdaq 100 Currency Hedged</td>
          <td></td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>MTFF95</td>
          <td>MTF Sal (4D) Nasdaq 100</td>
          <td></td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>KSMF83</td>
          <td>KSM 4A NASDAQ 100 Currency Hedged</td>
          <td></td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>HRLF49</td>
          <td>Harel Sal 4A NASDAQ 100 Currency Hedged</td>
          <td></td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>HRLF217</td>
          <td>Harel Sal (E) 3 Time Lvrg Nasdaq 100 Mnth CH (6A)</td>
          <td>3x</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>KSMF115</td>
          <td>KSM 6D Short Leveraged NASDAQ 100 x3 Monthly</td>
          <td>-3x</td>
      </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>
<hr>
<img src="https://www.uscreditcardguide.com/wp-content/uploads/ibkr-300x203.png" alt="ibkr" style="display: block; margin: 0 auto; border-radius: 6px;">


<h2 class="relative group">Interactive Brokers (IBKR) 
    <div id="interactive-brokers-ibkr" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#interactive-brokers-ibkr" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p><a href="https://www.interactivebrokers.com/en/general/about/ibkr-fact-sheet.php" target="_blank">Interactive Brokers LLC (IBKR)</a>, a US-based online brokerage firm, is the largest online broker in the United States. Founded in 1977 by Thomas Peterffy in the US, Interactive Brokers Group has its headquarters in Greenwich, Connecticut. The company went public in 2007 and is listed on the Nasdaq Stock Market under the ticker symbol <a href="https://www.nasdaq.com/market-activity/stocks/ibkr" target="_blank"><strong>IBKR</strong></a>.</p>
<p>Interactive Brokers Group affiliates provide automated trade execution and custody of securities, commodities and foreign exchange around the clock on over 150 markets in 27 currencies, from a single integrated platform, to clients from over 200 countries and territories. We service individual investors, hedge funds, proprietary trading groups, financial advisors and introducing brokers. Our four decades of focus on technology and automation have enabled us to equip our clients with a uniquely sophisticated platform to manage their investment portfolios. We strive to provide our clients with advantageous execution prices and trading, risk and portfolio management tools, research facilities and investment products, all at low or no cost, positioning them to achieve superior returns on investments. For the sixth consecutive year, Barron&rsquo;s ranked Interactive Brokers #1 with 5 out of 5 stars in its June 9, 2023, Best Online Brokers Review.</p>
<ul>
<li>IBG LLC was founded by its Chairman, Thomas Peterffy. Over the last 47 years, it has grown internally to become a major securities firm with equity capital of 15.2 billion .</li>
<li>Interactive Brokers&rsquo; headquarters is in Greenwich Connecticut, and it has 2,950+ employees in its offices in the United States, Switzerland, Canada, Hong Kong, United Kingdom, Australia, Japan, Hungary, Russia, India, China, Luxembourg, Ireland, Singapore and Estonia. IBKR is regulated by the SEC, FINRA, SFA and other regulatory agencies around the world.</li>
<li>IBKR is among the largest electronic brokers based on daily average revenue trades (DARTs) executing 2,634,000 trades per day.</li>
<li>Interactive Brokers Group has consistently been at the <a href="https://www.interactivebrokers.com/en/general/about/about.php" target="_blank">forefront of trading innovation</a>, starting with the invention of the first floor-based handheld computer in 1983.</li>
<li>Standard &amp; Poor&rsquo;s issues investment grade ratings to both <a href="https://www.interactivebrokers.com/download/IBG_SandP-Rating-06-2022.pdf" target="_blank">IBG LLC</a> and <a href="https://www.interactivebrokers.com/download/IBG_SandP-Rating-06-2022.pdf" target="_blank">IB LLC (IBKR)</a>.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Referral Link for Account Opening 
    <div id="referral-link-for-account-opening" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#referral-link-for-account-opening" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://ibkr.com/referral/zumou900" target="_blank">Interactive Brokers (IBKR)</a></li>
</ul>

  



<div
  
    class="flex px-4 py-3 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900"
  >

  <span
    
      class="text-primary-400 ltr:pr-3 rtl:pl-3 flex items-center"
    >

    

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M256 0C114.6 0 0 114.6 0 256s114.6 256 256 256s256-114.6 256-256S397.4 0 256 0zM256 128c17.67 0 32 14.33 32 32c0 17.67-14.33 32-32 32S224 177.7 224 160C224 142.3 238.3 128 256 128zM296 384h-80C202.8 384 192 373.3 192 360s10.75-24 24-24h16v-64H224c-13.25 0-24-10.75-24-24S210.8 224 224 224h32c13.25 0 24 10.75 24 24v88h16c13.25 0 24 10.75 24 24S309.3 384 296 384z"/></svg>

  </span>


  </span>

  <span
    
      class="dark:text-neutral-300"
    >For every $100 in assets (cash or other assets) you deposit in your account after opening an account using <strong>the link above</strong>, you&rsquo;ll receive $1 worth of IBKR stock, up to a maximum value of $1,000. The average balance must be maintained for at least one year for the stock to vest.  <a href="https://www.ibtws.com/en/trading/referral-member-to-member.php" target="_blank">(Official Instructions)</a></span>
</div>

]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Early Retirement Extreme: Book Notes</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1728390192272/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1728390192272/</guid><description>This book offers an unconventional philosophical and practical guide to financial independence and early retirement, encouraging readers to break free from the traditional &amp;#39;work-consume&amp;#39; cycle. By cultivating diverse skills, reducing consumption, and investing wisely, readers can achieve financial independence within a few years and live a more free and balanced life. The book also delves into how &amp;#39;the system&amp;#39; influences individual decisions and how to escape its constraints.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[

<h2 class="relative group">I. Summary 
    <div id="i-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This book&rsquo;s core is to guide readers in constructing a mindset of financial independence and encourage them to challenge and break free from the constraints of societal &ldquo;systems.&rdquo; The author argues that modern society, through education, careers, consumerism, and other means, &ldquo;locks&rdquo; people into a preset track, making them work and consume continuously to maintain the system&rsquo;s operation. This book encourages readers to break this cycle by cultivating diverse skills, reducing dependence on a single income and material possessions, and ultimately achieving financial independence and early retirement to pursue a more meaningful life.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">II. Chapter Summaries 
    <div id="ii-chapter-summaries" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii-chapter-summaries" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<ul>
<li><strong>About the Book:</strong> Explains the purpose and core ideas, emphasizing that it&rsquo;s a philosophical book about strategy, aiming to help readers build a framework for financial independence.</li>
<li><strong>A Different Thinking Framework:</strong> Challenges the traditional &ldquo;work-consume&rdquo; model and society&rsquo;s pursuit of material possessions, status, and happiness. It encourages readers to think like a &ldquo;Renaissance person&rdquo; by developing diverse skills and points out the challenges of implementing change.</li>
<li><strong>Locked In:</strong> Delves into how modern people are &ldquo;locked in&rdquo; by consumerism, social norms, and &ldquo;the system.&rdquo; It analyzes how &ldquo;the system,&rdquo; through education, careers, advertising, media, etc., influences individual decisions, limits choices, and creates dependencies.  The book encourages readers to break free from the limitations of &ldquo;the system&rdquo; and re-examine their lifestyles and values. (Example: The allegory of Plato&rsquo;s Cave, illustrating how people are trapped in limited cognition and experience, mistaking shadows for reality).</li>
<li><strong>Degrees of Economic Freedom:</strong> Introduces four economic states: Salaryman, Wage Earner, Businessman, and Renaissance Person. It analyzes their financial characteristics, strengths, weaknesses, and interactions with &ldquo;the system.&rdquo;  The concepts of financial coupling and job dependence are emphasized.</li>
<li><strong>The Renaissance Ideal:</strong> Explains the versatility and independence of the &ldquo;Renaissance person&rdquo; and contrasts it with the modern &ldquo;system&rsquo;s&rdquo; emphasis on specialization.
<ul>
<li><strong>Human Capital and Necessary Personal Assets:</strong> Details the specific meanings and goals of seven areas of competence, emphasizing how these competencies help individuals break free from dependence on &ldquo;the system.&rdquo;</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Strategies, Tactics, and Guiding Principles:</strong> Provides strategic and tactical guidance for achieving financial independence.</li>
<li><strong>Tactical Principles:</strong> Offers more specific action guidelines, such as how to identify needs and wants, how to build a modular lifestyle, and how to maximize the use of existing resources.</li>
<li><strong>Economic and Financial Foundations:</strong> Explains the cash flow cycle and how to make money work for you instead of working for money through saving and investing.</li>
<li><strong>Financial Independence and Investing:</strong> Discusses important financial ratios and investment strategies, emphasizing the importance of understanding investment principles and risk management.  (Formulas: N=log[(1)/(1- (Po)/(p)(i)/(1+i))]/log(1+i) and P = (1+0.03/12)/(0.03/12) p = 401 р)</li>
<li><strong>The Renaissance Lifestyle:</strong>  Explores how to implement the Renaissance ideal in aspects such as food, clothing, shelter, transportation, health, relationships, etc., contrasting it with the modern consumerist lifestyle. Emphasizes how reducing dependence on products and services provided by &ldquo;the system&rdquo; can lower living costs and improve quality of life. (Examples: how to replace car ownership with walking, cycling, or other methods, how to repair and maintain items oneself, and how to reduce expenses through socializing and sharing resources).</li>
<li><strong>Conclusion:</strong>  Summarizes the core ideas and encourages readers to break free from the constraints of &ldquo;the system&rdquo; to live more free and autonomous lives.</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">III. Key Quotes 
    <div id="iii-key-quotes" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii-key-quotes" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>Independence is not something you have; it&rsquo;s something you are.</p></blockquote>
<p>Insight:  Independence is a way of thinking and behaving, not a state of being.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>You cannot solve a problem with the same mindset that created it.</p></blockquote>
<p>Insight: Achieving financial independence requires a shift from a consumerist mindset to a creative problem-solving approach.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Be the change that you wish to see in the world.</p></blockquote>
<p>Insight: Instead of complaining about the system, change yourself and your actions, and influence others by example.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The best prison has invisible bars.</p></blockquote>
<p>Insight: Modern society subtly confines us through social norms, consumerism, and the education system, making us unconsciously comply.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">IV.  Guidance 
    <div id="iv--guidance" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv--guidance" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This book provides a perspective that goes beyond traditional financial advice, helping readers re-examine their lifestyles, values, and relationship with societal &ldquo;systems.&rdquo; It encourages readers to achieve financial independence and early retirement through:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Critical thinking:</strong> Question social norms and consumerism to avoid being manipulated by &ldquo;the system.&rdquo;</li>
<li><strong>Developing diverse skills:</strong> Increase self-worth and competitiveness, and reduce dependence on a single income source.</li>
<li><strong>Smart consumption:</strong> Avoid unnecessary expenses and allocate resources to more valuable areas.</li>
<li><strong>Long-term planning and investing:</strong> Prepare for the future and make money work for you.</li>
<li><strong>Building a resilient lifestyle:</strong> Reduce dependence on the external environment and &ldquo;the system&rdquo; and increase the ability to adapt to change.</li>
<li><strong>Pursuing personal growth and self-realization:</strong> Live a more meaningful, autonomous, and free life.</li>
</ul>
<p>In conclusion, this book encourages readers to undertake a profound self-reflection and lifestyle transformation to ultimately break free from the constraints of &ldquo;the system&rdquo; and achieve financial independence and true freedom.
<br/>

  



<div
  
    class="flex px-4 py-3 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900"
  >

  <span
    
      class="text-primary-400 ltr:pr-3 rtl:pl-3 flex items-center"
    >

    

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512">
<path fill="currentColor" d="M288 32c0-17.7-14.3-32-32-32s-32 14.3-32 32V274.7l-73.4-73.4c-12.5-12.5-32.8-12.5-45.3 0s-12.5 32.8 0 45.3l128 128c12.5 12.5 32.8 12.5 45.3 0l128-128c12.5-12.5 12.5-32.8 0-45.3s-32.8-12.5-45.3 0L288 274.7V32zM64 352c-35.3 0-64 28.7-64 64v32c0 35.3 28.7 64 64 64H448c35.3 0 64-28.7 64-64V416c0-35.3-28.7-64-64-64H346.5l-45.3 45.3c-25 25-65.5 25-90.5 0L165.5 352H64zM432 456c-13.3 0-24-10.7-24-24s10.7-24 24-24s24 10.7 24 24s-10.7 24-24 24z"/></svg>
  </span>


  </span>

  <span
    
      class="dark:text-neutral-300"
    ><strong>Download:</strong> <a href="https://github.com/TianmingLi/early_retirement_extreme_cn/blob/main/src/earlyretirementextreme.pdf" target="_blank">Early Retirement Extreme</a></span>
</div>

<br/>
<a id="github-ca5909c42993317bda43c57784488179" target="_blank" href="https://github.com/TianmingLi/early_retirement_extreme_cn" class="cursor-pointer">
  <div
    class="w-full md:w-auto pt-3 p-5 border border-neutral-200 dark:border-neutral-700 border rounded-md shadow-2xl">

    <div class="flex items-center">
      <span class="text-2xl text-neutral-800 dark:text-neutral" style="margin-right:10px;">
        

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 496 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M165.9 397.4c0 2-2.3 3.6-5.2 3.6-3.3.3-5.6-1.3-5.6-3.6 0-2 2.3-3.6 5.2-3.6 3-.3 5.6 1.3 5.6 3.6zm-31.1-4.5c-.7 2 1.3 4.3 4.3 4.9 2.6 1 5.6 0 6.2-2s-1.3-4.3-4.3-5.2c-2.6-.7-5.5.3-6.2 2.3zm44.2-1.7c-2.9.7-4.9 2.6-4.6 4.9.3 2 2.9 3.3 5.9 2.6 2.9-.7 4.9-2.6 4.6-4.6-.3-1.9-3-3.2-5.9-2.9zM244.8 8C106.1 8 0 113.3 0 252c0 110.9 69.8 205.8 169.5 239.2 12.8 2.3 17.3-5.6 17.3-12.1 0-6.2-.3-40.4-.3-61.4 0 0-70 15-84.7-29.8 0 0-11.4-29.1-27.8-36.6 0 0-22.9-15.7 1.6-15.4 0 0 24.9 2 38.6 25.8 21.9 38.6 58.6 27.5 72.9 20.9 2.3-16 8.8-27.1 16-33.7-55.9-6.2-112.3-14.3-112.3-110.5 0-27.5 7.6-41.3 23.6-58.9-2.6-6.5-11.1-33.3 2.6-67.9 20.9-6.5 69 27 69 27 20-5.6 41.5-8.5 62.8-8.5s42.8 2.9 62.8 8.5c0 0 48.1-33.6 69-27 13.7 34.7 5.2 61.4 2.6 67.9 16 17.7 25.8 31.5 25.8 58.9 0 96.5-58.9 104.2-114.8 110.5 9.2 7.9 17 22.9 17 46.4 0 33.7-.3 75.4-.3 83.6 0 6.5 4.6 14.4 17.3 12.1C428.2 457.8 496 362.9 496 252 496 113.3 383.5 8 244.8 8zM97.2 352.9c-1.3 1-1 3.3.7 5.2 1.6 1.6 3.9 2.3 5.2 1 1.3-1 1-3.3-.7-5.2-1.6-1.6-3.9-2.3-5.2-1zm-10.8-8.1c-.7 1.3.3 2.9 2.3 3.9 1.6 1 3.6.7 4.3-.7.7-1.3-.3-2.9-2.3-3.9-2-.6-3.6-.3-4.3.7zm32.4 35.6c-1.6 1.3-1 4.3 1.3 6.2 2.3 2.3 5.2 2.6 6.5 1 1.3-1.3.7-4.3-1.3-6.2-2.2-2.3-5.2-2.6-6.5-1zm-11.4-14.7c-1.6 1-1.6 3.6 0 5.9 1.6 2.3 4.3 3.3 5.6 2.3 1.6-1.3 1.6-3.9 0-6.2-1.4-2.3-4-3.3-5.6-2z"/></svg>

  </span>


      </span>
      <div
        id="github-ca5909c42993317bda43c57784488179-full_name"
        class="m-0 font-bold text-xl text-neutral-800 decoration-primary-500 hover:underline hover:underline-offset-2 dark:text-neutral">
        TianmingLi/early_retirement_extreme_cn
      </div>
    </div>

    <p id="github-ca5909c42993317bda43c57784488179-description" class="m-0 mt-2 text-md text-neutral-800 dark:text-neutral">
      Early Retirement Extreme 中文翻译 Renaissance &amp; Liberty
    </p>

    <div class="m-0 mt-2 flex items-center">

      <span class="mr-1 inline-block h-3 w-3 rounded-full"
        style="background-color: #e34c26"></span>
      <div class="m-0 mr-5 text-md text-neutral-800 dark:text-neutral">
         HTML 
      </div>

      <span class="text-md mr-1 text-neutral-800 dark:text-neutral">
        

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 576 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M287.9 0C297.1 0 305.5 5.25 309.5 13.52L378.1 154.8L531.4 177.5C540.4 178.8 547.8 185.1 550.7 193.7C553.5 202.4 551.2 211.9 544.8 218.2L433.6 328.4L459.9 483.9C461.4 492.9 457.7 502.1 450.2 507.4C442.8 512.7 432.1 513.4 424.9 509.1L287.9 435.9L150.1 509.1C142.9 513.4 133.1 512.7 125.6 507.4C118.2 502.1 114.5 492.9 115.1 483.9L142.2 328.4L31.11 218.2C24.65 211.9 22.36 202.4 25.2 193.7C28.03 185.1 35.5 178.8 44.49 177.5L197.7 154.8L266.3 13.52C270.4 5.249 278.7 0 287.9 0L287.9 0zM287.9 78.95L235.4 187.2C231.9 194.3 225.1 199.3 217.3 200.5L98.98 217.9L184.9 303C190.4 308.5 192.9 316.4 191.6 324.1L171.4 443.7L276.6 387.5C283.7 383.7 292.2 383.7 299.2 387.5L404.4 443.7L384.2 324.1C382.9 316.4 385.5 308.5 391 303L476.9 217.9L358.6 200.5C350.7 199.3 343.9 194.3 340.5 187.2L287.9 78.95z"/></svg>
  </span>


      </span>
      <div id="github-ca5909c42993317bda43c57784488179-stargazers" class="m-0 mr-5 text-md text-neutral-800 dark:text-neutral">
        111
      </div>

      <span class="text-md mr-1 text-neutral-800 dark:text-neutral">
        

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 448 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M80 104c13.3 0 24-10.7 24-24s-10.7-24-24-24S56 66.7 56 80s10.7 24 24 24zm80-24c0 32.8-19.7 61-48 73.3V192c0 17.7 14.3 32 32 32H304c17.7 0 32-14.3 32-32V153.3C307.7 141 288 112.8 288 80c0-44.2 35.8-80 80-80s80 35.8 80 80c0 32.8-19.7 61-48 73.3V192c0 53-43 96-96 96H256v70.7c28.3 12.3 48 40.5 48 73.3c0 44.2-35.8 80-80 80s-80-35.8-80-80c0-32.8 19.7-61 48-73.3V288H144c-53 0-96-43-96-96V153.3C19.7 141 0 112.8 0 80C0 35.8 35.8 0 80 0s80 35.8 80 80zm208 24c13.3 0 24-10.7 24-24s-10.7-24-24-24s-24 10.7-24 24s10.7 24 24 24zM248 432c0-13.3-10.7-24-24-24s-24 10.7-24 24s10.7 24 24 24s24-10.7 24-24z"/></svg>
  </span>


      </span>
      <div id="github-ca5909c42993317bda43c57784488179-forks" class="m-0 mr-5 text-md text-neutral-800 dark:text-neutral">
        26
      </div>

    </div>

  </div>
  <script>
    fetch("https://api.github.com/repos/TianmingLi/early_retirement_extreme_cn", {
      headers: new Headers({
        'User-agent': 'Mozilla/4.0 Custom User Agent'
      })
    })
      .then(response => response.json())
      .then(data => {
        document.getElementById('github-ca5909c42993317bda43c57784488179-full_name').innerHTML = data.full_name;
        document.getElementById('github-ca5909c42993317bda43c57784488179-description').innerHTML = data.description;
        document.getElementById('github-ca5909c42993317bda43c57784488179-stargazers').innerHTML = data.stargazers_count;
        document.getElementById('github-ca5909c42993317bda43c57784488179-forks').innerHTML = data.forks;
      })
      .catch(error => console.error(error))
  </script>
</a></p>
<hr>

<section class="space-y-10 w-full">
    
    
        
            






















  <a class="flex flex-wrap article " href="/en/posts/1728295490690-book-list/">
    
        
        <div class="w-full md:w-auto h-full thumbnail nozoom thumbnailshadow md:mr-7" style="background-image:url(/posts/1728295490690-book-list/featured_hu_a14921d8ab66af4e.jpg);"></div>
        
      <div class=" mt-3 md:mt-0">
      <div class="items-center text-left text-xl font-semibold">
        
        <div class="font-bold text-xl text-neutral-800 decoration-primary-500 hover:underline hover:underline-offset-2 dark:text-neutral"
          href="/en/posts/1728295490690-book-list/">Recommended Reading List</div>
        
        
        
      </div>
      <div class="text-sm text-neutral-500 dark:text-neutral-400">
        











  



















<div class="flex flex-row flex-wrap items-center">
  
  
  <time datetime="2024-10-01T00:00:00&#43;00:00">1 October 2024</time>
  

  
  
</div>





<div class="flex flex-row flex-wrap items-center">
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  <span style="margin-top:0.5rem" class="mr-2" onclick="window.open(&#34;/en/tags/recommended/&#34;,'_self');">
    <span class="flex" style="cursor: pointer;">
  <span class="rounded-md border border-primary-400 px-1 py-[1px] text-xs font-normal text-primary-700 dark:border-primary-600 dark:text-primary-400">
    Recommended
  </span>
</span>
  </span>
  
  <span style="margin-top:0.5rem" class="mr-2" onclick="window.open(&#34;/en/tags/book/&#34;,'_self');">
    <span class="flex" style="cursor: pointer;">
  <span class="rounded-md border border-primary-400 px-1 py-[1px] text-xs font-normal text-primary-700 dark:border-primary-600 dark:text-primary-400">
    Book
  </span>
</span>
  </span>
  
  
  
  
</div>




      </div>
      
    </div>
  </a>

        
    
</section>
]]></content:encoded></item></channel></rss>