<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Leveraged ETFs on QQQ Investor</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/tags/leveraged-etfs/</link><description>Recent content in Leveraged ETFs on QQQ Investor</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jomonylw.github.io/en/tags/leveraged-etfs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>00511 Risk and Cash Are the Real Starting Points for Investing</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1744504450104/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1744504450104/</guid><description>In this episode, James emphasizes that in any market environment, the primary consideration for investing is having sufficient cash reserves, followed by holding index funds for the long term. He discusses risk tolerance, asset allocation models (such as 433 and 424), the principles for using leveraged funds, and caution regarding paid groups and conflicts of interest. Students share their experiences and questions regarding market volatility, tax planning, retirement preparation, and more.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<lite-youtube videoid="xmD_sz5rYlU" playlabel="xmD_sz5rYlU" params=""></lite-youtube>



<h2 class="relative group">I. Current Theme 
    <div id="i-current-theme" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-current-theme" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>The core viewpoint of this episode emphasizes that investment decisions should be <strong>independent of market volatility</strong>, with <strong>sufficient cash reserves</strong> serving as the first step and cornerstone of investment planning. After determining the cash level based on individual risk tolerance and living needs, then proceed with long-term (15+ years) investment in index funds (especially the Nasdaq 100). Beta is a result of asset allocation, not the starting point. At the same time, be wary of various risks in investment, especially cognitive risks and behavioral biases, and remain vigilant about conflicts of interest in financial services.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">II. Briefing Content 
    <div id="ii-briefing-content" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii-briefing-content" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Market Volatility and Long-Term Perspective 
    <div id="market-volatility-and-long-term-perspective" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#market-volatility-and-long-term-perspective" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Market fluctuations are normal. Having experienced multiple major crashes (2000, 2008, 2020, 2022), the current volatility is relatively mild.</li>
<li>In the long run, most of the current concerns will &ldquo;leave no trace.&rdquo; Don&rsquo;t panic over short-term events. Time is the best medicine, but people are prone to repeating mistakes (old habits die hard).</li>
<li>Investing is a long-term matter (15+ years), and dips are buying opportunities. James has been investing for 40 years and has never &ldquo;seen&rdquo; a market crash, only buying opportunities.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Core Investment Principles 
    <div id="core-investment-principles" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#core-investment-principles" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Focus on Doing the Right Things:</strong> The core is &ldquo;Han Xin Counts Soldiers&rdquo; (i.e., using affordable and safe borrowing, such as mortgages and credit lines, for investment), putting borrowed money into the market, but with sufficient cash reserves.</li>
<li><strong>Investment Targets:</strong> Only invest in the Nasdaq 100 index fund (such as QQQ, 00662, 513100, etc.), as it represents human growth and innovation and has a self-evolving mechanism of survival of the fittest. Related materials are linked on page 10 of the handout. It is mentioned that HXQ and other Nasdaq 100-based funds may outperform QQQ in certain periods.</li>
<li><strong>Long-Term Holding:</strong> Holding for 15+ years after purchase is key, &ldquo;never selling.&rdquo; Only inaction can lead to wealth, not frequent trading.</li>
<li><strong>Stay Optimistic:</strong> Investment is based on confidence in the long-term development of humanity.</li>
<li><strong>Independent Learning:</strong> Investment requires self-study, understanding the reasons behind the strategy and the then-current market environment, and not blindly following.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Asset Allocation: Cash First 
    <div id="asset-allocation-cash-first" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#asset-allocation-cash-first" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Primary Question:</strong> The first step in investing is not what to buy, but <strong>how much cash needs to be retained</strong> to live securely and cope with emergencies. This is the most important thing.</li>
<li><strong>Cash Needs Determine Allocation:</strong>
<ul>
<li><strong>Young People:</strong> First, prepare an emergency fund (e.g., NT$400,000/CNY100,000), and only invest surplus funds.</li>
<li><strong>Asset Allocation Model Examples:</strong>
<ul>
<li><strong>433 (Beta 1.0):</strong> 40% Index + 30% Leverage + 30% Cash. Requires 30% Cash &gt; Emergency Fund (e.g., NT$400,000), requiring total assets of NT$1.33 million to implement.</li>
<li><strong>424 (Beta 0.8):</strong> 40% Index + 20% Leverage + 40% Cash. Requires 40% Cash &gt; Emergency Fund (e.g., NT$400,000), requiring total assets of NT$1 million to implement. Illustrates that reducing Beta can lower the funding threshold.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>High-Net-Worth Individuals:</strong> The principle is the same, determine the cash ratio according to personal comfort (potentially millions of RMB or hundreds of thousands of USD).</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Beta is the Result, Not the Goal:</strong> First determine cash needs and risk tolerance, naturally forming the allocation ratio, and finally calculate the Beta value as a measurement tool. Don&rsquo;t set a target Beta from the beginning.</li>
<li><strong>Allocation Irrelevant Factors:</strong> Asset allocation is <strong>unrelated</strong> to age, fund size, or market level, only related to how to prevent accidents and how much accident can be tolerated.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Risk Management and Cognition 
    <div id="risk-management-and-cognition" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#risk-management-and-cognition" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Risk Tolerance:</strong>
<ul>
<li>Young people have less experience, so risk tolerance may not be high, and should not blindly pursue high Beta (e.g., 442).</li>
<li>Wealthy people are usually more conservative, pursuing stability rather than extreme returns (Beta 0.5 may be sufficient).</li>
<li>Conclusion: Taking risks beyond your tolerance is foolish. Investment is like eating spicy food, do what you can handle.</li>
<li>Recommendation: Start conservatively. If you believe you can tolerate Beta 1.2, start with 1.0; if you believe you can tolerate 1.0, start with 0.8.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Leveraged Fund Usage Principles:</strong> The ratio of leveraged funds should not exceed the ratio of cash or the ratio of the original fund. This suggests that a 442 allocation (40% Index + 40% Leverage + 20% Cash) is not suitable for most people.</li>
<li><strong>Behavioral Biases:</strong> Retail investors often feel sad when the market falls (regret buying early) and also sad when the market rises (regret not going all-in). The correct allocation should achieve &ldquo;happy when it rises, comfortable when it falls,&rdquo; maintaining &ldquo;immovability.&rdquo;</li>
<li><strong>Individual Stock Risk:</strong> No company lasts forever (examples: Intel, Kodak, Blackberry), individual stock risk is high. Index funds mitigate individual stock risk through a mechanism of survival of the fittest.</li>
<li><strong>Borrowing Risk:</strong>
<ul>
<li><strong>Safe Borrowing:</strong> Mortgages, credit lines (Han Xin Counts Soldiers), assuming income can cover monthly payments, unrelated to market fluctuations.</li>
<li><strong>Dangerous Borrowing:</strong> Margin trading, stock-pledged reinvestment. Market declines can lead to forced liquidation or even bankruptcy. <strong>These operations are strictly prohibited.</strong></li>
<li>James&rsquo;s pledge loan: Based on holding cash far exceeding debt, ensuring absolute security.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Specific Funds Use Risk:</strong> Money earmarked for short-term use (e.g., down payment on a house) within a short period (e.g., 3 years) <strong>absolutely cannot</strong> be invested in the stock market. Someone recently defaulted because of this.</li>
<li><strong>Tax Risk:</strong> Tax planning is very important and can affect significant wealth. Rules need to be carefully studied (e.g., the application of the U.S. Wash Sale Rule across accounts).</li>
<li><strong>Spending Ability Mindset:</strong> True &ldquo;affordability&rdquo; means being able to easily repurchase an item if it breaks down, as in James&rsquo;s example of replacing a juicer. Large expenditures (e.g., buying a house) should also have this mindset, otherwise the risk is too high.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Be Wary of Paid Services and Conflicts of Interest 
    <div id="be-wary-of-paid-services-and-conflicts-of-interest" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#be-wary-of-paid-services-and-conflicts-of-interest" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Firmly Do Not Charge:</strong> James emphasizes that his services are free because charging easily creates conflicts of interest. His YouTube channel also does not have monetization enabled.</li>
<li><strong>Warning Signals:</strong> Be highly vigilant about any paid groups, paid recommendations, or financial services that charge commissions or kickbacks (e.g., account opening, buying funds). Mentions feedback that some groups may be transferring benefits through financial service referrals.</li>
<li><strong>Harm of Conflicts of Interest:</strong> Those who charge may recommend unsuitable or even harmful products/strategies for commissions.</li>
<li><strong>Self-Protection:</strong> Learn independently, compare multiple sources, understand financial products yourself, and do not easily trust introductions. Be especially wary of &ldquo;pits&rdquo; introduced by acquaintances.</li>
<li><strong>U.S. Regulations:</strong> The U.S. prohibits paying commissions to referrers for financial product recommendations (account opening rewards are usually given to the account opener themselves) to prevent conflicts of interest. Regulations may vary in other regions.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Other Suggestions 
    <div id="other-suggestions" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#other-suggestions" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Emergency Fund:</strong> Do not use the emergency fund to buy the dip. Survival is the most important thing.</li>
<li><strong>Regular Investment:</strong> Buy index funds immediately with new income (e.g., salary).</li>
<li><strong>Financial Literacy:</strong> Financial intelligence requires learning, there are no shortcuts. Be wary of the &ldquo;get rich quick&rdquo; mentality. Discuss with his daughter the mindset of speculators: it may be &ldquo;greed,&rdquo; it may be &ldquo;poverty,&rdquo; or it may be &ldquo;not wanting to get rich slowly.&rdquo;</li>
<li><strong>Video Viewing:</strong> New friends are advised to watch video #451, then start from #398 (January 2023) and watch in order.</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">III. Q&amp;A Session 
    <div id="iii-qa-session" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii-qa-session" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">CAD 
    <div id="cad" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#cad" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing:
<ol>
<li>Observed that regardless of wealth, some people are keen on short-term trading, possibly due to addictive pleasure or a sense of accomplishment. Poor people may say they need quick returns, while rich people may enjoy the process.</li>
<li>Emphasized the strict prohibition of margin trading or stock-pledged reinvestment. Recently, with the market decline, someone was forced to liquidate and even became indebted because of it. Compared this to his own use of credit lines/mortgages for investment, stating that as long as he can afford the monthly payments, the market decline does not affect his survival.</li>
<li>Mentioned a senior who was forced to liquidate due to margin calls during the Kuo Wan-Jung incident (Taiwan stock market historical event) and has been in debt ever since, warning future generations.</li>
<li><strong>Important Reminder:</strong> When observing an investment portfolio, you should pay attention to the <strong>fluctuation range of the overall assets</strong> rather than just staring at the leveraged portion with the biggest decline, which helps manage emotions.</li>
</ol>
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Comment: Agreed. Explained the risk of illiquidity under the Taiwan stock market&rsquo;s limit-down mechanism, compared to the U.S. market. Re-emphasized the danger of margin/pledge reinvestment. Explained that while he uses pledge loans, he holds cash far exceeding his debt to ensure security. Criticized putting house-buying money into the stock market as ignoring risk.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">BG 
    <div id="bg" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#bg" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing:
<ol>
<li>Agreed that money management (cash ratio, position control) takes precedence over buying and selling signals.</li>
<li>Money management should start from oneself (capital amount, risk tolerance willingness).</li>
<li>Backtesting is not just to verify signals, but also to understand the money drawdown of the strategy under historical market conditions, to adjust positions to suit one&rsquo;s own tolerance.</li>
<li>Under the buy-and-hold strategy, investment funds must be strictly separated from living funds to avoid affecting long-term investment plans and mentality due to living needs.</li>
</ol>
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Comment: Distinguished between strategy (long-term goals, cash planning, asset class allocation) and tactics (specific buying and selling points, short-term adjustments). Emphasized that tactics should not interfere with strategy, for example, one should not liquidate due to market panic or use the emergency fund to buy the dip.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Rui 
    <div id="rui" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#rui" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing:
<ol>
<li>Thanked James for solving many investment confusions (cash first, the use of leverage, asset allocation, etc.) through learning videos.</li>
<li>Adopted the teacher&rsquo;s advice and used 2% of his assets (through pledging) to pay for the Tesla purchase.</li>
<li>After adopting the 433 allocation, he felt excited when the market fell, in contrast to the panic of his colleagues.</li>
<li>Used a brokerage account (transfer from Yuantai Securities) that does not show the cost price, which helped reduce anxiety.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>Questions:
<ol>
<li>Has reached the retirement goal (50x annual expenses), but his current salary is equivalent to 6% of total assets. He hopes for a higher retirement replacement rate in the future (assets need to increase by another 2-3 times). Between 433 (30% cash + 2% withdrawal) and 442 (20% cash + no withdrawal), how to further think about the choice from the perspective of safety and applicability?</li>
<li>(Implicit question) Should he continue working for a sense of accomplishment, or retire early?</li>
</ol>
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Response:</li>
</ul>
<ol>
<li><strong>Regarding Purchasing the Car:</strong> Praised his use of &ldquo;non-own funds&rdquo; for consumption, pointing out that being able to borrow money is itself a manifestation of wealth, the key is controllable risk (sufficient cash).</li>
<li><strong>Regarding Retirement Choices:</strong> This is a classic question. Cited another case to illustrate that early retirement may bring huge benefits due to tax planning (such as Roth conversions). Suggested that Rui reflect: if work had no salary or recognition, would he still want to go? The value of work may change with stage, and there may be new pursuits in the future. Looking back from age 90, would he regret working several more decades? With financial freedom, the work mentality can be more relaxed.</li>
<li><strong>Regarding 433 vs 442 Safety:</strong> Assuming the market goes to zero, which is safer? The answer is the one with a higher cash ratio (433 has 30% cash, 442 has only 20%).</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Kai Xin 
    <div id="kai-xin" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#kai-xin" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question: Regarding whether the interest on the U.S. Pledged Asset Line (PAL, pledge loan) can be tax-deductible, and how to operate? Feels that the rules are complex and there are many restrictions.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Response: The money borrowed from PAL is mainly used for consumption, not reinvestment. The issue of interest tax deduction is complicated and may require adjusting the type of capital gains (e.g., converting long-term to short-term), relying on accountant operations. James himself does not pay attention to this operation because his strategy is to hold a lot of cash, making interest income far exceed PAL interest expenses, and PAL interest is close to zero. The more fundamental strategy is to achieve &ldquo;zero income, zero capital gains,&rdquo; so there is no need to consider tax deduction.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Derek 
    <div id="derek" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#derek" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Thanks to James and the community (Chen Feng, Sister K, etc.). Recently joined, the teacher&rsquo;s reply and teaching made him have the courage to operate according to the plan when the market fell, and deeply realized the importance of risk control. Listening to the teacher&rsquo;s videos can bring a sense of stability.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Comment: This is precisely the reason why he insists on teaching, knowing that it is difficult to succeed in investing alone, and guidance and companionship are needed.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Nai Xi 
    <div id="nai-xi" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#nai-xi" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: As the founding moderator of the Taiwan 00662 community, thanks to James&rsquo;s inspiration three years ago for changing his life. Thanks to all 19 administrators of the community (mentioning the rotation system, member contributions such as Chen Feng bringing it to a new height, Chris developing tools, etc.) for their hard work. Reiterated that he was inspired by the teacher&rsquo;s &ldquo;eliminate poverty&rdquo; mission and hopes to help more people through the community.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Comment: Recalled the meeting with Nai Xi and the community backbone (eighteen arhats), praised their quality and Nai Xi&rsquo;s persistence and humility. Affirmed the value and operation of the 00662 community and regretted that it was limited by the LINE platform and could not cover the world.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Ming Yu 
    <div id="ming-yu" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ming-yu" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: No questions or sharing.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Yao 
    <div id="yao" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#yao" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Mentioned recent rumors about Trump&rsquo;s friends profiting from trade war news, and extended thoughts about the relationship between the morality of politicians and social progress. Lamented that moral constraints are limited, but human technology is still developing.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Comment: Agreed that the world is full of unknowns (quoting Buffett), and the market always has surprises (epidemic circuit breakers, drastic trade war fluctuations). Need to remain humble and prepare for extreme risks (such as market closure/continuous decline for 10-15 years). Re-distinguished between safe borrowing (fixed repayment) and dangerous borrowing (linked to the market).</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Julia 
    <div id="julia" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#julia" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Revealed an American tax trap: the Wash Sale Rule may apply to all accounts (including 401k/IRA and other retirement accounts). If you sell a loss-making asset (such as QQQ) in a taxable account for Tax Loss Harvesting (TLH) and automatically buy a similar asset (such as an SP500 index fund) in a retirement account at the same time, the loss in the taxable account may be permanently disallowed (because retirement accounts are taxed at ordinary income rates when withdrawn, with no capital gains concept). This is especially important for high-tech employees, as they often hold a large number of RSUs and perform TLH.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Comment: Tax issues are extremely important. Pointed out that TLH itself also has risks, such as the market rebounding after selling, making it impossible to buy back the original asset (QQQ) at an ideal price, or generating new capital gains when buying back. If James himself has no need (such as no capital gains without selling stocks), he tends to let the loss carry forward and deduct $3,000 of ordinary income each year, rather than use it to offset capital gains. However, for Julia, who needs to offset a large amount of RSU capital gains, TLH is a reasonable strategy and needs to be operated carefully. Discussed the problem of high tax rates in California. Re-emphasized the ultimate goal of pursuing a zero-tax state, and the value of tax planning far exceeds the salary itself.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">DDF 
    <div id="ddf" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ddf" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question: Asked about the risk of the Pacific War two years ago, at that time the teacher suggested reducing 50% of QQQ. Now that he has adopted the strategy of holding a large amount of cash (such as 433/424), can he withstand this type of risk, insist on holding it and rebalancing at the end of the year, without selling in the middle?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Response: The evolution of the strategy is because the introduction of leveraged instruments allows holding a large amount of cash more effectively. The core risk management issue is not specific events (wars, disasters, etc.), but <strong>whether it is possible to survive in extreme market conditions (such as closure/deep decline for 10-15 years)</strong>. If cash reserves are sufficient to support such a long time, there is no need to make predictive operations for specific events. Comparing risks: for young people, the risk of carrying a mortgage and facing unemployment + market decline may be more realistic and fatal than the risk of war. Buying a house should be as easy and stress-free as buying slippers to be considered affordable.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Jason 
    <div id="jason" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#jason" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Summarized two major investment risks:
<ol>
<li><strong>Choosing the wrong asset:</strong> The market is full of various temptations, choosing a high-quality asset for the long term (such as QQQ) is the foundation. Thanks to the teacher for continuing to emphasize this.</li>
<li><strong>Missing the upside:</strong> Statistics show that missing the 10 days with the biggest market gains (in the past 20 years) will cut total returns in half. These big rally days often occur during periods of extreme panic (such as 2008, 2020). This confirms the importance of the &ldquo;never sell&rdquo; strategy to avoid timing the market.</li>
</ol>
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Comment: Highly Agreed. Defined <strong>the real, permanent loss</strong> as <strong>the returns that should have been earned but were not</strong> (such as missing a 12% rally). Book losses caused by market declines are temporary and will recover. Compared buying QQQ at a high point (540) with buying at a low point (440), the difference in annualized returns after holding for 40 years is extremely small (11.98% vs 12.5%), indicating that the timing of the purchase is not important, but long-term holding is key. Use a long-term perspective (40 years later) to review current decisions.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Jing 
    <div id="jing" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#jing" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question: Approaching retirement, but savings have not reached the 30-50x target. There is a stable high income in the next 5 years, and Pension/Social Security will cover most expenses after retirement. Does not use pledging due to concerns about risk. Can I not retain 20% cash and take a 100% stock holding strategy, relying on future income, emergency fund, and future pledgeable options to accelerate asset growth?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Response: <strong>No.</strong> Risk tolerance decreases as retirement approaches, the time window is short, and you should be more conservative. Since the Pension already covers most of the expenses, the urgency for asset growth should be reduced. <strong>The most aggressive allocation for retirement or near retirement, without using pledges and without holding leveraged funds, is 80% QQQ + 20% cash.</strong> Pension should be regarded as a stable source of income, and when calculating the total amount of retirement funds required, the <strong>Pension portion should be deducted</strong> from annual expenses first, and then the remaining net expenditure needs should be multiplied by a multiple (such as 30 or 50 times). If you hold leveraged funds, you must sell them and deal with tax issues before retirement.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Frank (from the comments section) 
    <div id="frank-from-the-comments-section" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#frank-from-the-comments-section" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question: Should global diversification be carried out?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Response: Not recommended. The U.S. market is optimal in terms of innovation, transparency, and long-term risk-reward ratio. Other markets have higher risks and relatively low return potential. Investing in U.S. index funds is sufficient.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">IV. Wonderful Views 
    <div id="iv-wonderful-views" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv-wonderful-views" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>The first step in investing is not to say, ah, I come in and start, what should the teacher buy, how much leveraged funds should I buy&hellip; No&hellip; The first thing to invest in is how much cash you need, how much cash you need to keep, this is more important than anything.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>Background: Emphasizes the primacy of cash reserves in investment planning.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Our strategy has nothing to do with market volatility&hellip; What are investment plans or investments supposed to do? It is to be based on your own risk tolerance&hellip; How much cash is appropriate to keep, this is the first step in investing.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>Background: Explains the core concept of his investment strategy, which is not affected by short-term market sentiment.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Beta is naturally formed in the end, not set at the beginning&hellip; So you have to ask the first few questions, how much cash do you keep to feel comfortable&hellip; An accident may come in the next second.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>Background: Explains the role of Beta in asset allocation, which is a result, not a goal, emphasizing safety first.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Young people should not take risks, because they lack experience, and rich people do not take risks much&hellip; Coming back to the point, taking risks is not very worthwhile, taking risks beyond what you can afford is just very stupid.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>Background: Refutes traditional concepts, pointing out that excessive risk-taking is not advisable, regardless of whether you are young or wealthy.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Don&rsquo;t turn your tactics into a strategy&hellip; It seems that the emergency fund should have been so much, but you, ah, it&rsquo;s dropped so much, quickly buy it all in. That turns tactics into a strategy, you can&rsquo;t do that.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>Background: When commenting on student sharing, distinguishes the boundaries between strategic determination and tactical flexibility.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>What you should look at is not your single stock (referring to leveraged ETFs)&hellip; Drops a lot, you should look at the range of fluctuations in your entire asset&hellip; Don&rsquo;t pay too much attention to the part that is dropping the most.
&ndash; CAD (Student)</p></blockquote>
<p>Background: Reminds that when holding leveraged ETFs, you should pay attention to the volatility of the overall investment portfolio rather than a single product, to stabilize your mentality.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>What is the real risk of the market? The real risk of the market is your investment return, the real risk is the returns that you should have earned but didn&rsquo;t, that you will never earn&hellip; A drop in losses is not a loss.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>Background: Redefines investment risk, emphasizing that opportunity cost (missing the upside) is the real permanent loss.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The risk of buying a house is higher than the risk of war&hellip; If you treat buying a house like buying slippers, then you can buy a house.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>Background: Responding to questions about geopolitical risks, compared and pointed out that for ordinary people, financial leverage (such as mortgages) may bring more direct and serious risks.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>If you don&rsquo;t manage your finances and taxes well, you may pay 85% of your assets in taxes in this life, and you actually only get 15%&hellip; Saving taxes can save tens of billions.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>Background: When discussing tax planning, emphasizes its huge impact on long-term wealth accumulation.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Because being poor is also right to do speculation&hellip; So it&rsquo;s also right that most people who speculate are poor&hellip; Many people who speculate don&rsquo;t even know it, they don&rsquo;t know what they don&rsquo;t know, which is very strange.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>Background: When discussing speculative psychology with his daughter, reflected on the relationship between poverty and greed, and that speculators often lack self-awareness.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">V. Summary 
    <div id="v-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#v-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This lecture once again consolidates James&rsquo;s core investment philosophy: <strong>taking sufficient cash reserves as a prerequisite for ultra-long-term (15+ years) holding of the Nasdaq 100 index fund.</strong> It emphasizes the priority of risk management, especially determining the cash ratio based on individual circumstances and building asset allocation based on this, rather than pursuing a specific Beta value or being driven by market sentiment. The differences in risk perception at different life stages and wealth levels were discussed, and the use of high-risk leverage (such as margin trading) for investment was strongly opposed. In addition, practical advice and warnings were shared on tax planning, retirement preparation, financial service selection, and consumption mentality. The Q&amp;A session delved into the specific problems encountered by students in practice, further clarifying strategy details and risk considerations, such as retirement fund calculation, the view on global diversification, and psychological management techniques (focus on overall portfolio rather than local volatility). Overall, this content revolves around the two words <strong>&ldquo;determination&rdquo;</strong> and <strong>&ldquo;safety,&rdquo;</strong> that is, maintaining strategic determination and financial security in a volatile market, and adhering to the correct principles.</p>

  



<div
  
    class="flex px-4 py-3 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900"
  >

  <span
    
      class="text-primary-400 ltr:pr-3 rtl:pl-3 flex items-center"
    >

    

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M506.3 417l-213.3-364c-16.33-28-57.54-28-73.98 0l-213.2 364C-10.59 444.9 9.849 480 42.74 480h426.6C502.1 480 522.6 445 506.3 417zM232 168c0-13.25 10.75-24 24-24S280 154.8 280 168v128c0 13.25-10.75 24-23.1 24S232 309.3 232 296V168zM256 416c-17.36 0-31.44-14.08-31.44-31.44c0-17.36 14.07-31.44 31.44-31.44s31.44 14.08 31.44 31.44C287.4 401.9 273.4 416 256 416z"/></svg>

  </span>


  </span>

  <span
    
      class="dark:text-neutral-300"
    ><strong>Disclaimer:</strong> This article is only a personal study note and does not constitute any investment advice.</span>
</div>

]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>00495 Market Highs and Lows Don't Exist: The Only Truth in Long-Term Investing; The Privilege of the Rich and the Secret of Asset Appreciation</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1734846063547/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1734846063547/</guid><description>In this session, James shares his year-end rebalancing strategy, investment philosophy, 433 asset allocation plan, and answers questions from students regarding QQQ, leveraged ETFs, ETNs, real estate, personal finance, and CLEC short video production.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<lite-youtube videoid="TCfozoZu0Hw" playlabel="TCfozoZu0Hw" params=""></lite-youtube>



<h2 class="relative group">I. Main Topic 
    <div id="i-main-topic" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-main-topic" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This session focuses on year-end investment strategies. James emphasizes the importance of rebalancing and delves into investment philosophy, asset allocation, handling market fluctuations, and other practical investment tips. The core message is: adopt a long-term investment approach, adhere to the &ldquo;buy whenever you have money, never sell&rdquo; strategy, and implement a suitable asset allocation and rebalancing plan based on individual circumstances.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">II. Briefing Content 
    <div id="ii-briefing-content" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii-briefing-content" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Year-End Rebalancing and Asset Allocation 
    <div id="year-end-rebalancing-and-asset-allocation" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#year-end-rebalancing-and-asset-allocation" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Importance of Rebalancing:</strong> James stresses the importance of rebalancing at the end or beginning of the year. He recommends passive rebalancing, which means rebalancing when the market is performing well, to avoid panic selling during market downturns. He points out that many investors are reluctant to rebalance during market rallies, hoping to earn more, but end up succumbing to losses during declines and selling at the bottom, resulting in greater losses.</li>
<li><strong>Pledging Stocks for Tax Payment:</strong> He advises individuals with pledged stocks to borrow money for tax payments instead of selling the stocks to avoid increasing capital gains tax and to better utilize their funds. He emphasizes that under the premise of sound asset allocation and risk management, the borrowed money can be used flexibly.</li>
<li><strong>Real Estate Investment:</strong>  James advises against buying real estate, believing it restricts personal freedom. He uses the example of a friend in the Bay Area selling their property to support this viewpoint, pointing out the high holding costs of real estate, including property taxes, maintenance fees, and insurance, which can put significant financial pressure on individuals.</li>
<li><strong>Children&rsquo;s Education and Wealth Perspective:</strong> He suggests parents support their children&rsquo;s choices, believing that happiness is more important than wealth. Children shouldn&rsquo;t live for the sake of glorifying their family but should pursue happiness, serve others, and do what they love.</li>
<li><strong>433 Asset Allocation Plan:</strong> James recommends the 433 asset allocation plan (40% QQQ, 30% TQQQ, 30% Cash) for the general public, adjustable based on individual circumstances. For retirees who are not pledging stocks, he suggests an 80/20 allocation (80% index funds, 20% cash). For investors unfamiliar with or averse to leveraged ETFs, he recommends 100% investment in QQQ or 00662.</li>
<li><strong>Taiwan&rsquo;s Investment Environment Advantage:</strong> James highly praises Taiwan&rsquo;s investment environment, believing it possesses cutting-edge financial tools, tax-free policies, and low interest rates, making it an ideal place for investment. He encourages Taiwanese investors to leverage this advantage.</li>
<li><strong>Mid-Life Investment Strategy:</strong> He advises middle-aged individuals, even with modest incomes, to persist in monthly investments, accumulating wealth gradually for retirement. He illustrates the returns of monthly investments of 5,000 and 10,000 at retirement with specific examples.</li>
<li><strong>Advantages of Nasdaq 100 Index Funds:</strong> James explains the rationale for investing in QQQ, stating that its constituent companies have strong profitability, focus on technology and innovation, and align with long-term human development trends. He also points out that the constituent companies of the Nasdaq 100 index have stronger profitability compared to the S&amp;P 500.</li>
<li><strong>Investment Philosophy:</strong>  He advocates for the &ldquo;buy whenever you have money, never sell&rdquo; strategy, ignoring short-term fluctuations and believing in the long-term upward trajectory of the market. He emphasizes that the purpose of investment is wealth appreciation, not short-term gains, and criticizes the drawbacks of short-term trading.</li>
<li><strong>The Difference Between the Rich and the Poor:</strong> James points out that the rich possess assets and credit, which they can use to &ldquo;print money&rdquo; through leverage for rapid wealth growth.  The poor, lacking investment knowledge, keep their money in banks, missing out on wealth growth opportunities. He uses the example of Warren Buffett issuing bonds to illustrate how the rich utilize credit for investment.</li>
<li><strong>Three Contributions of Investors:</strong>  First, allocating capital to the most efficient companies, promoting technological advancement; second, helping the government invest idle foreign exchange reserves; third, helping the poor activate their funds, maximizing their social value.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Other Investment Advice and Opinions 
    <div id="other-investment-advice-and-opinions" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#other-investment-advice-and-opinions" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Don&rsquo;t blindly trust the investment advice of financial advisors and banks, as they have profit motives and may recommend products beneficial to themselves, not necessarily to investors.</li>
<li>Don&rsquo;t believe in investment recommendations from so-called &ldquo;group leaders&rdquo; or random individuals. Think independently, make your own decisions, and be responsible for your investments.</li>
<li>Focus on investing in broad-market passive funds in the US, such as the Nasdaq 100 Index Fund (QQQ) and the S&amp;P 500 Index Fund (SPY). He provides codes for investing in Nasdaq 100 index funds globally.</li>
<li>Avoid investing in unfamiliar assets like Bitcoin. Focus on core investment strategies to avoid distractions.</li>
<li>Don&rsquo;t overemphasize short-term market fluctuations and various news. Maintain an optimistic mindset and firmly believe in the long-term upward trend of the market.</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">III. Q&amp;A Session 
    <div id="iii-qa-session" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii-qa-session" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Zhang Yong 
    <div id="zhang-yong" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#zhang-yong" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Expresses gratitude to James, shares his 15-year experience in the insurance industry, reflects on some existing problems within the industry, such as promoting low-yield financial insurance, and expresses admiration for the simplicity and effectiveness of the CLEC investment philosophy and how it can change his and his family&rsquo;s financial future. He also shares his desire to help friends and family learn the CLEC investment philosophy but acknowledges the challenges in promotion.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s comments: Affirms Zhang Yong&rsquo;s sharing and thanks Dr. Lao Chai for the recommendation. Emphasizes the power of word-of-mouth marketing and encourages Zhang Yong to continue promoting the CLEC investment philosophy.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Mike 
    <div id="mike" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#mike" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Shares a discussion with friends in Taiwan about QQQ&rsquo;s component stock adjustments and rebalancing mechanism, mentioning the Matthew effect and the idea that the strong get stronger. He also expresses surprise at the relatively small total market capitalization of QQQ.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s comments: Suggests focusing on long-term performance rather than short-term fluctuations and explains that QQQ&rsquo;s smaller market cap is due to the relatively low number of people who understand and invest in it.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 1:  The impact of QQQ component adjustments and rebalancing mechanisms on investments, and whether one should invest in the smaller 90 companies.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s reply:  Advises focusing on long-term performance and volatility, not short-term component adjustments. QQQ&rsquo;s adjustment mechanism ensures the inclusion of the best companies, illustrated by the performance of Mega 7 and MAGS. Points out the &ldquo;stronger get stronger&rdquo; phenomenon among large companies and explains QQQ&rsquo;s rebalancing mechanism.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2: James&rsquo;s methods, tools, and experience in creating short videos, and the application of AI technology.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s reply: Details the short video production process, including writing scripts, using speech recognition software, text-to-video conversion, and subtitle generation. He shares his experience with AI tools, emphasizing the importance of personal creation and the limitations of AI in emotional expression. Mentions using tools like speech recognition software, PowerDirector, and some Chinese and Taiwanese video production software.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Hui 
    <div id="hui" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#hui" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question 1:  FNGS has performed better than QQQ. Can FNGS replace QQQ?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s reply: No, because FNGS has excessive volatility and higher risk, illustrated by the 2000 tech bubble.  Emphasizes that asset allocation should consider volatility and maximum drawdown, not just performance. In the long run, QQQ offers better stability.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2: XLG has lower volatility than QQQ and decent returns.  Is it suitable for allocation?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s reply: No, because XLG&rsquo;s long-term performance is inferior to QQQ. He provides a performance comparison of QQQ and XLG from 2006 to the present, showing QQQ&rsquo;s significantly higher returns. Emphasizes focusing on long-term performance and avoiding investments with poor long-term track records despite low short-term volatility. Investments with less than 30 years of market history are not worth discussing.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Ethan 
    <div id="ethan" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ethan" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Shares his two-year experience learning and promoting the CLEC investment philosophy in China, highlighting the positive impact and challenges. He suggests domestic investors consider opening accounts in Hong Kong to invest in QQQ and shares the advantages of investing in Hong Kong.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s comments: Affirms Ethan&rsquo;s sharing and promotional efforts, agrees with his suggestion of opening accounts in Hong Kong, and adds to the advantages, such as access to leveraged ETFs and money market funds, making the 433 asset allocation plan more comprehensive.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Ling 
    <div id="ling" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ling" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Shares her experience and understanding of the CLEC investment philosophy and how she applies it to life, such as educating her children.  She shares a childhood story of collecting shells for money and her desire for investment.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s comments: Acknowledges Ling&rsquo;s sharing and praises her proactive approach.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question: How to pledge stocks after retirement?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s reply: Explains the process of pledging stocks after retirement and emphasizes the importance of asset allocation.  Suggests the 433 asset allocation plan, adjusted according to the value of the pledged stocks. Explains how to calculate borrowing limits based on the value of pledged stocks and how to add collateral.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Martin 
    <div id="martin" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#martin" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Shares his investment experience and observations in Europe and expresses envy for the US investment environment. Mentions issues such as strict regulations and heavy tax burdens in Europe.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s comments: Agrees with Martin&rsquo;s viewpoint, analyzes the disadvantages of the European investment environment, such as high taxes and restrictions on the tech industry, and explains his focus on the US market. Points out that European socialist ideology and wealth expropriation are detrimental to capital accumulation and economic development.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Ying 
    <div id="ying" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ying" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Reflects on some mistakes in his investment journey, such as missing a year of market gains for a 5% fixed deposit interest rate, and shares his experience and insights on all-in investing in QQQ and TQQQ, and how he persuaded his wife to start investing.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s comments: Affirms Ying&rsquo;s sharing and reiterates the &ldquo;buy whenever you have money, never sell&rdquo; strategy and the all-in investment philosophy. Points out the importance of overcoming human weaknesses for investment success.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Pamela 
    <div id="pamela" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#pamela" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Shares the story of her neighbor being scammed by an accountant, reminding everyone to be cautious of investment risks and not to trust others blindly, even friends or professionals.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s comments: Agrees with Pamela&rsquo;s point, emphasizes the importance of improving one&rsquo;s financial literacy, and advises against over-reliance on financial advisors and accountants.  Points out that an accountant&rsquo;s responsibility is tax filing, not financial planning, so investors should not solely rely on their investment advice.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Nick 
    <div id="nick" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#nick" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Shares his investment experience in Canada, recommends HQU, the Canadian equivalent of QQQ, and discusses using IBKR&rsquo;s margin account. Highlights the challenges of investing in Canada and how to utilize IBKR for leverage.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s comments: Thanks Macro for sharing and suggests that IBKR&rsquo;s margin account might be an option for investors in countries without stock pledging.  Recommends that investors from other countries try and provide feedback on their experience with IBKR&rsquo;s margin account.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Julie 
    <div id="julie" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#julie" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question 1: Will pledging stocks affect mortgage refinancing?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s reply: No, stock pledging does not appear on credit reports and will not affect mortgage refinancing rates. He advises Julie to pledge her stocks as soon as possible and not wait for interest rates to decline, as future interest rate movements are unpredictable.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2: How to use TQQQ for investment and how to balance returns and risks? How to invest the money set aside for property taxes?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s reply: Suggests the 433 asset allocation plan, adjustable based on individual circumstances.  Emphasizes the importance of Beta management and recommends holding leveraged ETFs in retirement accounts. He advises against investing property tax money in TQQQ, recommending instead to keep it in cash or money market funds for unexpected needs.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Other Q&amp;A 
    <div id="other-qa" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#other-qa" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>James answers audience questions on topics such as 20-year investment returns, Warren Buffett&rsquo;s cash holdings, account selection for funds, short video production, the impact of FNG&rsquo;s bankruptcy on QQQ, simulating investments in the top ten stocks, stock pledging in Taiwan, 50/25/25 asset allocation, money market fund selection, leveraged ETF investment ratios, investment time horizons, and investment options in Canada.</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">IV. Key Takeaways 
    <div id="iv-key-takeaways" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv-key-takeaways" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>Buy whenever you have money, never sell.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>This is James&rsquo;s consistent investment philosophy and the core strategy of CLEC.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Taiwan is a country with well-equipped weapons and cheap bullets.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>James praises Taiwan&rsquo;s investment environment, believing its financial tools, tax benefits, and low interest rates are highly advantageous for investors.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The most important thing in life is happiness.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>James emphasizes that the meaning of life lies in happiness, not in working and making money for its own sake.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>AI creations lack warmth.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>James shares his experience using AI tools for short video production, highlighting the limitations of AI in conveying emotions.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>You can be a benefactor to others, but whether they benefit depends on their destiny and fate.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>James shares his understanding of wealth and life, believing that an individual&rsquo;s wealth accumulation is influenced by destiny, fate, and luck, in addition to hard work.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The market has no peak, only higher highs; the market has no bottom, only a perpetual absence of a top or bottom.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>James emphasizes the long-term upward trend of the market and advises against trying to predict market tops and bottoms.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">V. Summary 
    <div id="v-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#v-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This session covered year-end rebalancing strategies, investment philosophy, the 433 asset allocation plan, CLEC short video production methods, and addressed various questions from students. James emphasized the importance of long-term investing and encouraged participants to create a reasonable asset allocation and rebalancing plan based on their individual circumstances, ignore short-term market fluctuations, and adhere to the &ldquo;buy whenever you have money, never sell&rdquo; principle.  During the Q&amp;A, students shared their investment experiences and concerns, raising questions about investment environments in different countries and specific investment products.  James provided professional guidance and advice, helping students better understand and apply the CLEC investment philosophy.</p>

  



<div
  
    class="flex px-4 py-3 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900"
  >

  <span
    
      class="text-primary-400 ltr:pr-3 rtl:pl-3 flex items-center"
    >

    

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M506.3 417l-213.3-364c-16.33-28-57.54-28-73.98 0l-213.2 364C-10.59 444.9 9.849 480 42.74 480h426.6C502.1 480 522.6 445 506.3 417zM232 168c0-13.25 10.75-24 24-24S280 154.8 280 168v128c0 13.25-10.75 24-23.1 24S232 309.3 232 296V168zM256 416c-17.36 0-31.44-14.08-31.44-31.44c0-17.36 14.07-31.44 31.44-31.44s31.44 14.08 31.44 31.44C287.4 401.9 273.4 416 256 416z"/></svg>

  </span>


  </span>

  <span
    
      class="dark:text-neutral-300"
    ><strong>Disclaimer:</strong> This article is for personal learning notes only and does not constitute any investment advice.</span>
</div>

]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>00481 Asset Allocation Strategies to Avoid Market Pitfalls; How to Achieve Steady Wealth through Proper Investment Strategies</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1728285792652/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1728285792652/</guid><description>In this session, James emphasizes the crucial role of mental strength in investment success. He discusses asset allocation, the use and rebalancing of leveraged ETFs, provides supplementary explanations of 401(k) and IRA accounts, and touches upon choosing the right brokerage. The Q&amp;amp;A session addresses audience questions concerning investing with mortgage loans, market crash risks, the risks associated with single brokerage accounts, and how to cope with the psychological pressure stemming from market fluctuations. Furthermore, the discussion includes insights on investment target selection, the purpose of holding cash, and life planning.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<lite-youtube videoid="ZvTM4--CaKw" playlabel="ZvTM4--CaKw" params=""></lite-youtube>



<h2 class="relative group">I. Main Theme 
    <div id="i-main-theme" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-main-theme" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This session centers around the importance of psychological resilience in investing. James&rsquo;s core message is that mental strength is the key to investment success, while other skills and calculations are secondary. Investors need to maintain a highly optimistic mindset, viewing market fluctuations as opportunities rather than crises in the long run. Long-term investing, rational analysis, and maintaining a healthy mindset are more crucial than striving for precise calculations.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">II. Briefing Content 
    <div id="ii-briefing-content" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii-briefing-content" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<ul>
<li><strong>Correction on 401(k) and IRA:</strong> James corrects a statement from the previous session regarding 401(k) and IRA contribution limits, clarifying that the limits for each are independent, but that IRAs have income restrictions. He provides further explanations about the Backdoor Roth IRA conversion, advising listeners to manage pre-tax and after-tax funds carefully to avoid account confusion and complications during tax filing.</li>
<li><strong>Asset Allocation Strategy:</strong> He emphasizes the significance of asset allocation and suggests listeners refer to existing articles and Excel spreadsheets for simulations, discouraging impulsive decision-making. He offers various asset allocation plans catering to different risk tolerances and retirement stages, stressing the concept of &ldquo;fuzzy accuracy&rdquo;  that it is not necessary to pursue overly precise ratios, but ensuring sufficient cash reserves is crucial. Example: A listener proposes an allocation of 60% QQQ and 40% cash, which James believes carries a risk of bankruptcy and advises them to consult the provided asset allocation plans.</li>
<li><strong>Leveraged ETFs and Rebalancing:</strong> Using QQQ&rsquo;s beta value of 1.0 as a benchmark, he simplifies beta calculations for leveraged ETFs, for instance, QLD is considered 2.0. He recommends a gradual approach when adjusting beta during rebalancing, advising against drastic changes. For investors with earned income, the frequency and ratio of rebalancing can be more flexible. Example: He suggests that young investors can rotate investments among QQQ, QLD, and TQQQ every six months, then rebalance at the end of the year.</li>
<li><strong>Long-Term Investing and Market Volatility:</strong> James reiterates the importance of long-term investing, using the dot-com bubble of 2000 as an example to demonstrate that long-term investors ultimately profit, even after enduring prolonged market downturns. Market dips are opportunities, and investors should remain optimistic, buying whenever they have funds available. He refutes the notion that &ldquo;investments in 2000 took 15 years to break even,&rdquo; emphasizing that the market always recovers in the long run. Example: An investment of $5 million at the peak of the market in 2000, despite experiencing the burst of the internet bubble, would still have grown to $32.375 million by 2024.</li>
<li><strong>Brokerage Selection:</strong> He advises choosing brokerages with physical branch offices and understanding how stocks and cash are held in custody to ensure asset security. Example: He explains the risks of nominee accounts and recommends selecting brokerages that allow for direct ownership of stocks, encouraging listeners to inquire about the brokerage&rsquo;s custodian banks for stocks and cash.</li>
<li><strong>Purpose of Holding Cash:</strong> He underlines that cash holdings are meant for emergencies and to seize buying opportunities during market downturns, not for pursuing interest income. Example: He suggests maintaining a 20% cash position, a portion of which can be utilized for adding to leveraged ETFs during dips.</li>
<li><strong>Investment Target Selection:</strong> He recommends selecting suitable investment targets based on individual circumstances. For instance, retirees or individuals with limited funds may consider high-dividend ETFs, while younger individuals or those with ample funds should focus on growth-oriented ETFs like QQQ. Example: Addressing a listener holding SCH, James advises them to assess whether high-dividend ETFs are appropriate based on their asset level and annual expenses.</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">III. Q&amp;A Session 
    <div id="iii-qa-session" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii-qa-session" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p><strong>Danny:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Shares: He has been following James&rsquo;s investment strategy for three years and achieved a return of approximately 35%.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Chang&rsquo;an:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Question: Brokerage security and recommendations in Hong Kong.</li>
<li>James&rsquo;s Response: Choose brokerages with physical branch offices in the region, understand the custodian banks for stocks and cash, and avoid easily dissolved online brokerages.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Eric:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Shares: He began investing during the pandemic, experienced the hardships of short-term trading, and eventually recognized the importance of long-term investing and psychological control. He uses the example of Jesse Livermore to illustrate the risks of trading.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Jessie:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Shares: Both she and her husband are nearing 60 years old, and a portion of their investment funds comes from a mortgage loan. She expresses concerns about a potential market crash and the risk of USD devaluation.</li>
<li>Questions:</li>
</ul>
<ol>
<li>How to cope with a possible future market crash, especially with a mortgage due before retirement?</li>
<li>What about USD devaluation?</li>
<li>Are there risks associated with concentrating large sums of money in a single brokerage account?</li>
<li>Is it feasible to refinance the mortgage in five years or repay it early with funds from the investment account?</li>
</ol>
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Response:</li>
</ul>
<ol>
<li>The market is unlikely to experience losses within a 15-year timeframe. Ensure you can comfortably handle mortgage payments for the next 13 years; the most secure approach is to sell the house and repay the loan.</li>
<li>He declines to answer hypothetical questions.</li>
<li>Stocks are registered under the investor&rsquo;s name, hence the risk of brokerage failure is manageable.</li>
<li>Refinancing or early repayment is not recommended. Excessive focus on short-term interest gains is akin to &ldquo;penny wise, pound foolish,&rdquo; and ultimately increases risk.</li>
</ol>
<p><strong>Sam:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Shares: He went all-in on QQQ, but after some short-term trading, realized it wasn&rsquo;t suitable for him and experienced psychological pressure due to large position fluctuations.</li>
<li>Question: How to overcome the psychological pressure brought about by fluctuations in a large portfolio?</li>
<li>James&rsquo;s Response:</li>
</ul>
<ol>
<li>Focus on realized gains rather than unrealized gains.</li>
<li>Maintain 20% cash and 20% leveraged ETFs to stabilize your mindset.</li>
<li>Exercise caution with short-term trading, as it may not be sustainable in the long run.</li>
</ol>
<p><strong>Haoqing:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Shares: He uses examples of friends gambling and raising children to illustrate the importance of moderate expectations and nurturing interests. He compares and contrasts education philosophies and Nobel Prize achievements between China and the US, emphasizing the significance of financial freedom for the next generation.</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">IV. Highlights 
    <div id="iv-highlights" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv-highlights" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>Mental fortitude is the equipment for investing, it determines whether you will succeed.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>Investment skills and calculations are undoubtedly important, but psychological resilience is the ultimate factor that decides investment success. Even for simple index fund investing, a sound mental state is needed to navigate market volatility.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>A market downturn is not a disaster, it&rsquo;s an opportunity.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>From a long-term investment perspective, market downturns provide excellent opportunities to acquire high-quality assets.  Maintain a long-term outlook and don&rsquo;t be intimidated by short-term fluctuations.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>There should be a limit to human pessimism.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>Excessive pessimism and worry are detrimental to investments. One should rationally analyze risks and develop sensible coping strategies. Do not let extreme scenarios or low-probability events unduly influence investment decisions.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Parents sometimes have these expectations for their children, don&rsquo;t impose your unfulfilled aspirations on them.
&ndash; Haoqing</p></blockquote>
<p>Parents should respect their children&rsquo;s individuality and interests and refrain from forcing their own unaccomplished goals onto them. Allowing children to have a joyful childhood and the autonomy to choose their own paths in life is more important than chasing conventional success.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">V. Summary 
    <div id="v-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#v-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>In this session, James reiterates the importance of mental fortitude in investing and the effectiveness of long-term investment and asset allocation strategies. By addressing listeners&rsquo; practical concerns, such as retirement planning, market volatility, and capital security, he helps them better understand and apply these investment principles. James also provides advice on choosing appropriate investment targets and the purpose of holding cash, aiding listeners in constructing more comprehensive investment strategies. Haoqing&rsquo;s sharing sparked reflection on educational philosophies and life values, advocating for a focus on children&rsquo;s overall development and mental well-being.</p>

  



<div
  
    class="flex px-4 py-3 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900"
  >

  <span
    
      class="text-primary-400 ltr:pr-3 rtl:pl-3 flex items-center"
    >

    

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M506.3 417l-213.3-364c-16.33-28-57.54-28-73.98 0l-213.2 364C-10.59 444.9 9.849 480 42.74 480h426.6C502.1 480 522.6 445 506.3 417zM232 168c0-13.25 10.75-24 24-24S280 154.8 280 168v128c0 13.25-10.75 24-23.1 24S232 309.3 232 296V168zM256 416c-17.36 0-31.44-14.08-31.44-31.44c0-17.36 14.07-31.44 31.44-31.44s31.44 14.08 31.44 31.44C287.4 401.9 273.4 416 256 416z"/></svg>

  </span>


  </span>

  <span
    
      class="dark:text-neutral-300"
    ><strong>Disclaimer:</strong> This document is only for personal learning and note-taking purposes and does not constitute any investment advice.</span>
</div>

]]></content:encoded></item></channel></rss>