<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Book on QQQ Investor</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/tags/book/</link><description>Recent content in Book on QQQ Investor</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jomonylw.github.io/en/tags/book/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Let Time Help You Slowly Get Rich: Book Notes</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1734847682781/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1734847682781/</guid><description>This book primarily explains the strategy of regular investing, emphasizing that it&amp;#39;s the best investment method for ordinary people. The author, Li Xiaolai, elaborates on the core concepts, advantages, and correct execution of regular investing, combining personal experiences and market examples to demonstrate the importance of long-term and value investing. Furthermore, he explores topics like proactivity vs. passivity, trends, and personal growth, aiming to help readers establish a sound investment philosophy and wealth outlook, ultimately achieving financial freedom.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[

<h2 class="relative group">I. Summary 
    <div id="i-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>The core argument of this book is: <strong>Regular investing is the optimal investment strategy for ordinary people.</strong> Li Xiaolai uses a unique perspective and accessible language to systematically explain the advantages, principles, and implementation of regular investing. He argues that compared to other investment methods, regular investing is more suitable for ordinary people due to its simplicity, lower risk, and ability to overcome human weaknesses.  It helps investors maintain rationality amidst market fluctuations, ultimately achieving steady wealth growth.  Beyond investment techniques, the book also touches upon personal growth, mindset, and life choices, aiming to help readers establish a sound investment philosophy and wealth outlook, ultimately achieving financial freedom and happiness.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">II. Chapter Summaries 
    <div id="ii-chapter-summaries" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii-chapter-summaries" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">1. Almost Everyone is Qualified and Capable of Regular Investing 
    <div id="1-almost-everyone-is-qualified-and-capable-of-regular-investing" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#1-almost-everyone-is-qualified-and-capable-of-regular-investing" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Most people possess the ability to invest regularly, but they often choose the wrong target (real estate).</strong> The author uses the common phenomenon of &ldquo;mortgage slaves&rdquo; to illustrate that most people are unconsciously engaged in a form of regular investing – real estate.  Their monthly mortgage payments essentially constitute a form of regular investment. However, due to high interest rates and low liquidity, real estate is not the optimal choice. He contrasts this with the example of investing regularly in Kweichow Moutai stock for 18 years, resulting in a 180-fold increase, highlighting the significant advantages of stock investing in terms of long-term returns and liquidity.  This emphasizes the crucial importance of selecting the right investment target.  Due to mortgage burdens, many become &ldquo;mortgage millionaires,&rdquo; possessing seemingly large assets but lacking cash flow and a high quality of life.</li>
<li><strong>Advantages of regular investment in stocks/index funds: low barrier to entry, high liquidity, potential for high returns.</strong> Compared to other investment methods like investing in early-stage startups or art, stocks and index funds have a low barrier to entry, making them accessible to everyone.  Moreover, they offer high liquidity, allowing investors to buy and sell at any time, facilitating adjustments to their investment strategies as needed.  More importantly, over the long term, the stock market tends to rise with economic development, giving regular investment in stocks/index funds the potential for high returns. The author believes the stock market offers ordinary people an opportunity to share in the growth dividends of excellent companies, an advantage difficult to obtain through other investment avenues.</li>
<li><strong>The importance of participating in a regular investing community.</strong>  The author points out that regular investing is not just an investment strategy but also a social activity. Due to widespread misunderstandings and biases about stock investing (such as &ldquo;investment is risky&rdquo; or &ldquo;only the rich invest&rdquo;), investing regularly alone can be easily influenced by external factors, making it difficult to persist. Participating in a regular investing community can help investors overcome these negative influences, gain support and encouragement from peers, establish a correct investment philosophy, and learn more investment knowledge and experience. Within such communities, members can exchange experiences, share insights, and create a positive feedback loop.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">2. The Stock Market is the Ninth Wonder of the World 
    <div id="2-the-stock-market-is-the-ninth-wonder-of-the-world" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#2-the-stock-market-is-the-ninth-wonder-of-the-world" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>The stock market gives ordinary people the chance to be &ldquo;bosses&rdquo; and share in the growth dividends of excellent companies.</strong> The author believes the stock market provides a unique opportunity for ordinary people to invest in well-managed, high-quality companies and share in their profits, even if they have no understanding of business operations. This is an advantage difficult to gain even by working at a company, including publicly listed ones. Through investing, ordinary people can indirectly &ldquo;own&rdquo; multiple excellent companies, achieving wealth appreciation.</li>
<li><strong>A simple method for stock selection: choose the most favored stocks or index funds in the market.</strong> The author suggests that choosing stocks doesn&rsquo;t require complex analysis and research. One can directly choose the most popular stocks or index funds in the market, such as Kweichow Moutai, Apple, or Tencent.  These represent the collective wisdom of the smartest people in the market, and choosing them is akin to leveraging their free advice.  He further notes that the advice from the smartest people in the market is often free, like Warren Buffett&rsquo;s portfolio information and popular stock choices.</li>
<li><strong>Don&rsquo;t worry about making the wrong choice; market consensus is more important than individual judgment.</strong> Even if the most favored stock in the market eventually fails, there&rsquo;s no need for excessive self-blame, as it represented the best available advice at the time.  Individual judgment rarely surpasses market consensus. In the long run, market forces will correct errors, so the key is to hold long-term and trust the power of the market.  The author believes that rather than spending significant time and energy researching individual stocks, it&rsquo;s better to trust the collective wisdom of the market and choose widely recognized, excellent companies.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">3. Are There Any Investment Targets that Only Go Up? 
    <div id="3-are-there-any-investment-targets-that-only-go-up" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#3-are-there-any-investment-targets-that-only-go-up" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Investing in a single stock is high-risk, with unlimited opportunity cost, and requires diversification.</strong> Even the best-performing single company can face significant risks due to industry decline, black swan events, or other unpredictable factors. Concentrating funds in a single stock represents high risk, and losses can be difficult to recover if problems arise.  The author cites Kodak and Nokia as examples, illustrating how even once-great companies can decline. Hence, diversification is essential to mitigate risk.</li>
<li><strong>In the long run, the only investment that only goes up is human economic development, which can be accessed through index funds.</strong> The author argues that the human economy generally trends upwards over the long term, and index funds track the overall market performance.  By investing in index funds, one can effectively diversify risk and share in the dividends of long-term economic growth.  The 40-year performance chart of the S&amp;P 500 is compelling evidence.  Investing in index funds is like betting on the national, or even global, economy, and offers better odds in the long run.</li>
<li><strong>Long-term investment is necessary to dilute risk and ultimately achieve stable returns.</strong> Short-term market fluctuations are difficult to predict and are full of noise and randomness.  Only long-term investment can effectively smooth these fluctuations and ultimately generate stable returns.  The author emphasizes that there are no investment targets that only go up, only the long-term general upward trend of the human economy.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">4. The Only Correct Way for Ordinary People to Invest 
    <div id="4-the-only-correct-way-for-ordinary-people-to-invest" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#4-the-only-correct-way-for-ordinary-people-to-invest" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Regular investing is the most reliable investment method for ordinary people.</strong> The author uses the example of Longmen Fund, comparing lump-sum investing with regular investing. The results show that regular investing achieved a significantly higher return: 74.01% vs. 10.81%.  Regular investing can effectively smooth market fluctuations and reduce investment risk.</li>
<li><strong>Regular investing helps investors overcome fear and greed, maintaining rationality during market fluctuations.</strong> Through regular, fixed-amount investments, investors can buy more shares at lower prices during market downturns, averaging down their cost.  During market upturns, it prevents investing too much at once, avoiding being trapped at high prices.  The discipline of regular investing can help investors overcome the human weakness of chasing rising markets and selling during falls.</li>
<li><strong>Regular investing is a long-term strategy that requires patience and discipline.</strong> Returns from regular investing take time to accumulate. Investors need to be patient and maintain discipline, not easily interrupting or changing their investment plan, to achieve significant returns.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">5. Why So Few People Use Regular Investing 
    <div id="5-why-so-few-people-use-regular-investing" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#5-why-so-few-people-use-regular-investing" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>&ldquo;Fear of simplicity&rdquo; hinders people from accepting regular investing.</strong> People tend to believe in complex and sophisticated methods, underestimating the power of simplicity.  This is similar to how it took a long time for people to think of adding wheels to luggage, learning English through consistent reading aloud, improving writing through effective reading, and maintaining health through regular exercise.</li>
<li><strong>Regular investing&rsquo;s simplicity makes it easier to adhere to, avoiding the risks of frequent trading.</strong> Compared to complex trading strategies, regular investing is simple and easy to follow, avoiding transaction costs and the risk of misjudgment associated with frequent trading.  The author believes that this simplicity is precisely the greatest advantage of regular investing.</li>
<li><strong>People lack understanding and patience for long-term investing.</strong> Most people crave quick riches and struggle to endure the &ldquo;loneliness&rdquo; of long-term investing. They are easily influenced by short-term market fluctuations and often give up, as seen in the Longmen Fund example, where lump-sum investors were more prone to panic selling during market declines.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">6. The Profound Mechanisms Behind the Magic of Regular Investing 
    <div id="6-the-profound-mechanisms-behind-the-magic-of-regular-investing" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#6-the-profound-mechanisms-behind-the-magic-of-regular-investing" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Proactive personality is important, but recognize the boundaries of proactivity.</strong> Be proactive within your circle of influence, but also recognize your limitations.  Don&rsquo;t try to control what you cannot, such as your children&rsquo;s future or the operations of companies you&rsquo;ve invested in.</li>
<li><strong>Factors that determine destiny often lie outside our control, such as trends.</strong> Personal effort is important, but it&rsquo;s also essential to align with the trends of the times.  Like snooker player Ronnie O&rsquo;Sullivan, even with immense effort, competitors find it challenging to defeat him at his peak.</li>
<li><strong>Active passivity is the best strategy for navigating trends.</strong> Actively choose the right trend, then passively wait for the trend to unfold. In investing, this means actively choosing promising assets or indices for the long term, then passively adhering to a regular investment schedule.</li>
<li><strong>Regular investing is the best practice of &ldquo;active passivity.&rdquo;</strong> Choosing worthy long-term investments is active; regularly buying a fixed amount and holding long-term is passive.</li>
<li><strong>The power of passivity is fully demonstrated in long-term investing.</strong> The long-term performance of passive funds often surpasses that of actively managed funds, demonstrating the limitations of &ldquo;active management&rdquo; and the strength of long-term holding.</li>
<li><strong>Ordinary people can improve their investment abilities by controlling their own behavior, such as improving their ability to earn outside of the market.</strong>  Earning power outside of the market is the cornerstone of regular investing and a key factor ordinary people can actively improve.</li>
<li><strong>Understanding &ldquo;long-term&rdquo; determines investment outcomes.</strong> &ldquo;Long-term&rdquo; doesn&rsquo;t mean forever, but &ldquo;at least two major cycles,&rdquo; which, based on market changes, is approximately seven years.</li>
<li><strong>Ordinary people&rsquo;s money has no expiration date, a significant advantage over professional fund managers.</strong> Professional fund managers are constrained by fund deadlines and investor pressure, while ordinary people can invest long-term with more composure, fully utilizing the power of time.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">7. The Difference Between Stupidity and Ignorance, and Passive Intelligence 
    <div id="7-the-difference-between-stupidity-and-ignorance-and-passive-intelligence" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#7-the-difference-between-stupidity-and-ignorance-and-passive-intelligence" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Smart people can make ignorant mistakes in unfamiliar fields.</strong> Like Archimedes and Zu Chongzhi, geniuses in their respective fields could make mistakes in the unfamiliar territory of the stock market due to a lack of specific knowledge.</li>
<li><strong>Regular investing allows ordinary people to be passively intelligent investors from the start.</strong>  The strategy&rsquo;s simplicity avoids errors associated with complex operations, allowing ordinary people to achieve reasonable returns without becoming investment experts.</li>
<li><strong>Regular investing cultivates patience, discipline, and the habit of investing within one&rsquo;s means.</strong> Long-term regular investing requires patience and discipline. The investment amount should also be within one&rsquo;s means to avoid impacting daily life. These are all good investment habits.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">8. Some People Are Always on the Right Side 
    <div id="8-some-people-are-always-on-the-right-side" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#8-some-people-are-always-on-the-right-side" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>People with great goals are more likely to make the right choices in a mirrored world.</strong>  A sense of purpose allows focus on long-term value instead of being distracted by short-term fluctuations.  The author quotes Arnold Schwarzenegger&rsquo;s speech, emphasizing the importance of goals: &ldquo;The only reason I&rsquo;m standing here today is because I had a goal.&rdquo;</li>
<li><strong>Imbuing what you do with great meaning can ignite powerful self-motivation.</strong>  A sense of meaning provides stronger motivation to persist. The author uses his own writing and teaching experience to illustrate the significance of meaning and encourages readers to find meaning in their regular investing, such as &ldquo;for the children&rsquo;s future&rdquo; or &ldquo;for early retirement.&rdquo;</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">9.  A Glimpse into the Other Side of the Mirror World 
    <div id="9--a-glimpse-into-the-other-side-of-the-mirror-world" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#9--a-glimpse-into-the-other-side-of-the-mirror-world" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Investors who don&rsquo;t adopt regular investing easily fall into various investment traps, ultimately leading to losses.</strong> These include chasing rising markets, frequent trading, blindly following the crowd, and listening to rumors, often resulting in substantial losses during market volatility.</li>
<li><strong>Many investors blame their losses on greed, but the real root cause is a lack of understanding of the investment target.</strong> The author argues that greed is human nature and not the fundamental reason for investment failures.  The true cause lies in a lack of understanding of the investment target, an inability to judge its intrinsic value, leading to blind following or emotionally driven decisions, ultimately resulting in buying high and selling low.</li>
<li><strong>Even those who use regular investing need to deeply understand its core principles to avoid becoming half-baked investors.</strong>  This includes failing to carefully select investment targets, not holding long-term, investing too little, or easily interrupting the investment plan.  The author criticizes investors who don&rsquo;t truly grasp the essence of regular investing and merely engage in mechanical operations.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">10. Regular Investing is Essential for Ordinary People 
    <div id="10-regular-investing-is-essential-for-ordinary-people" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#10-regular-investing-is-essential-for-ordinary-people" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>The insignificance of effort: Ordinary people have limited free time, making it difficult to achieve significant success solely through hard work.</strong> The author uses data and personal experiences to illustrate that even with extraordinary effort, such as working 24 years without holidays or cutting his own hair, the gains are limited. He only managed to gain 1.26 years of effective working time compared to others.</li>
<li><strong>The essence of investing is to make money work for you, compensating for limited time and energy.</strong> Investing allows money to work 24/7, amplifying returns far beyond what one can earn through personal labor. Warren Buffett&rsquo;s 78-year investing journey serves as a prime example.</li>
<li><strong>Regular investing is an effective path for ordinary people to achieve financial freedom.</strong>  The strategy is simple and easy to execute.  Long-term adherence can generate substantial returns, helping ordinary people accumulate wealth and eventually achieve financial freedom.</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">III. Key Quotes 
    <div id="iii-key-quotes" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii-key-quotes" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>Diligence in practice makes one invincible!</p></blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>Regular investing is the only reliable investment method for ordinary people.</p></blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>There are no investment targets that only rise, only those that rise in the long term.</p></blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>Be proactive when you should be, and passive when you should be.</p></blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>Your money may not be much, but it has no expiration date.</p></blockquote>


<h2 class="relative group">IV.  Guiding Significance 
    <div id="iv--guiding-significance" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv--guiding-significance" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<ul>
<li><strong>Establishing a sound investment philosophy:</strong>  Helping readers avoid investment pitfalls and recognize the importance of long-term, value, and passive investing, while avoiding mistakes like chasing rising markets and frequent trading.</li>
<li><strong>Providing practical investment methods:</strong>  The regular investing strategy is simple and easy to implement, accessible even to those with no prior investment experience.</li>
<li><strong>Promoting personal growth:</strong>  Encouraging readers to cultivate a proactive personality, recognize the boundaries of their control, and learn how to be actively passive, aligning with trends.</li>
<li><strong>Guiding life choices:</strong> Inspiring readers to reflect on the meaning and goals of life and strive towards them, ultimately achieving financial freedom and happiness.</li>
<li><strong>Cultivating a healthy mindset:</strong> Reminding readers not to be swayed by short-term fluctuations, maintaining patience and discipline, overcoming fear and greed, and believing in the power of time.</li>
</ul>
<p>In conclusion, this book not only provides practical investment techniques but, more importantly, helps readers establish a healthy wealth outlook and life philosophy, ultimately achieving financial freedom and happiness.  The book also encourages readers to join regular investing communities for mutual learning, support, and progress.</p>
<hr>
<a id="github-e02127fda5246656fa0433195f17cabe" target="_blank" href="https://github.com/xiaolai/regular-investing-in-box" class="cursor-pointer">
  <div
    class="w-full md:w-auto pt-3 p-5 border border-neutral-200 dark:border-neutral-700 border rounded-md shadow-2xl">

    <div class="flex items-center">
      <span class="text-2xl text-neutral-800 dark:text-neutral" style="margin-right:10px;">
        

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 496 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M165.9 397.4c0 2-2.3 3.6-5.2 3.6-3.3.3-5.6-1.3-5.6-3.6 0-2 2.3-3.6 5.2-3.6 3-.3 5.6 1.3 5.6 3.6zm-31.1-4.5c-.7 2 1.3 4.3 4.3 4.9 2.6 1 5.6 0 6.2-2s-1.3-4.3-4.3-5.2c-2.6-.7-5.5.3-6.2 2.3zm44.2-1.7c-2.9.7-4.9 2.6-4.6 4.9.3 2 2.9 3.3 5.9 2.6 2.9-.7 4.9-2.6 4.6-4.6-.3-1.9-3-3.2-5.9-2.9zM244.8 8C106.1 8 0 113.3 0 252c0 110.9 69.8 205.8 169.5 239.2 12.8 2.3 17.3-5.6 17.3-12.1 0-6.2-.3-40.4-.3-61.4 0 0-70 15-84.7-29.8 0 0-11.4-29.1-27.8-36.6 0 0-22.9-15.7 1.6-15.4 0 0 24.9 2 38.6 25.8 21.9 38.6 58.6 27.5 72.9 20.9 2.3-16 8.8-27.1 16-33.7-55.9-6.2-112.3-14.3-112.3-110.5 0-27.5 7.6-41.3 23.6-58.9-2.6-6.5-11.1-33.3 2.6-67.9 20.9-6.5 69 27 69 27 20-5.6 41.5-8.5 62.8-8.5s42.8 2.9 62.8 8.5c0 0 48.1-33.6 69-27 13.7 34.7 5.2 61.4 2.6 67.9 16 17.7 25.8 31.5 25.8 58.9 0 96.5-58.9 104.2-114.8 110.5 9.2 7.9 17 22.9 17 46.4 0 33.7-.3 75.4-.3 83.6 0 6.5 4.6 14.4 17.3 12.1C428.2 457.8 496 362.9 496 252 496 113.3 383.5 8 244.8 8zM97.2 352.9c-1.3 1-1 3.3.7 5.2 1.6 1.6 3.9 2.3 5.2 1 1.3-1 1-3.3-.7-5.2-1.6-1.6-3.9-2.3-5.2-1zm-10.8-8.1c-.7 1.3.3 2.9 2.3 3.9 1.6 1 3.6.7 4.3-.7.7-1.3-.3-2.9-2.3-3.9-2-.6-3.6-.3-4.3.7zm32.4 35.6c-1.6 1.3-1 4.3 1.3 6.2 2.3 2.3 5.2 2.6 6.5 1 1.3-1.3.7-4.3-1.3-6.2-2.2-2.3-5.2-2.6-6.5-1zm-11.4-14.7c-1.6 1-1.6 3.6 0 5.9 1.6 2.3 4.3 3.3 5.6 2.3 1.6-1.3 1.6-3.9 0-6.2-1.4-2.3-4-3.3-5.6-2z"/></svg>

  </span>


      </span>
      <div
        id="github-e02127fda5246656fa0433195f17cabe-full_name"
        class="m-0 font-bold text-xl text-neutral-800 decoration-primary-500 hover:underline hover:underline-offset-2 dark:text-neutral">
        xiaolai/regular-investing-in-box
      </div>
    </div>

    <p id="github-e02127fda5246656fa0433195f17cabe-description" class="m-0 mt-2 text-md text-neutral-800 dark:text-neutral">
      定投改变命运 —— 让时间陪你慢慢变富 <a href="https://onregularinvesting.com" target="_blank">https://onregularinvesting.com</a>
    </p>

    <div class="m-0 mt-2 flex items-center">

      <span class="mr-1 inline-block h-3 w-3 rounded-full"
        style="background-color: #3572A5"></span>
      <div class="m-0 mr-5 text-md text-neutral-800 dark:text-neutral">
         Python 
      </div>

      <span class="text-md mr-1 text-neutral-800 dark:text-neutral">
        

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 576 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M287.9 0C297.1 0 305.5 5.25 309.5 13.52L378.1 154.8L531.4 177.5C540.4 178.8 547.8 185.1 550.7 193.7C553.5 202.4 551.2 211.9 544.8 218.2L433.6 328.4L459.9 483.9C461.4 492.9 457.7 502.1 450.2 507.4C442.8 512.7 432.1 513.4 424.9 509.1L287.9 435.9L150.1 509.1C142.9 513.4 133.1 512.7 125.6 507.4C118.2 502.1 114.5 492.9 115.1 483.9L142.2 328.4L31.11 218.2C24.65 211.9 22.36 202.4 25.2 193.7C28.03 185.1 35.5 178.8 44.49 177.5L197.7 154.8L266.3 13.52C270.4 5.249 278.7 0 287.9 0L287.9 0zM287.9 78.95L235.4 187.2C231.9 194.3 225.1 199.3 217.3 200.5L98.98 217.9L184.9 303C190.4 308.5 192.9 316.4 191.6 324.1L171.4 443.7L276.6 387.5C283.7 383.7 292.2 383.7 299.2 387.5L404.4 443.7L384.2 324.1C382.9 316.4 385.5 308.5 391 303L476.9 217.9L358.6 200.5C350.7 199.3 343.9 194.3 340.5 187.2L287.9 78.95z"/></svg>
  </span>


      </span>
      <div id="github-e02127fda5246656fa0433195f17cabe-stargazers" class="m-0 mr-5 text-md text-neutral-800 dark:text-neutral">
        5988
      </div>

      <span class="text-md mr-1 text-neutral-800 dark:text-neutral">
        

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 448 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M80 104c13.3 0 24-10.7 24-24s-10.7-24-24-24S56 66.7 56 80s10.7 24 24 24zm80-24c0 32.8-19.7 61-48 73.3V192c0 17.7 14.3 32 32 32H304c17.7 0 32-14.3 32-32V153.3C307.7 141 288 112.8 288 80c0-44.2 35.8-80 80-80s80 35.8 80 80c0 32.8-19.7 61-48 73.3V192c0 53-43 96-96 96H256v70.7c28.3 12.3 48 40.5 48 73.3c0 44.2-35.8 80-80 80s-80-35.8-80-80c0-32.8 19.7-61 48-73.3V288H144c-53 0-96-43-96-96V153.3C19.7 141 0 112.8 0 80C0 35.8 35.8 0 80 0s80 35.8 80 80zm208 24c13.3 0 24-10.7 24-24s-10.7-24-24-24s-24 10.7-24 24s10.7 24 24 24zM248 432c0-13.3-10.7-24-24-24s-24 10.7-24 24s10.7 24 24 24s24-10.7 24-24z"/></svg>
  </span>


      </span>
      <div id="github-e02127fda5246656fa0433195f17cabe-forks" class="m-0 mr-5 text-md text-neutral-800 dark:text-neutral">
        2050
      </div>

    </div>

  </div>
  <script>
    fetch("https://api.github.com/repos/xiaolai/regular-investing-in-box", {
      headers: new Headers({
        'User-agent': 'Mozilla/4.0 Custom User Agent'
      })
    })
      .then(response => response.json())
      .then(data => {
        document.getElementById('github-e02127fda5246656fa0433195f17cabe-full_name').innerHTML = data.full_name;
        document.getElementById('github-e02127fda5246656fa0433195f17cabe-description').innerHTML = data.description;
        document.getElementById('github-e02127fda5246656fa0433195f17cabe-stargazers').innerHTML = data.stargazers_count;
        document.getElementById('github-e02127fda5246656fa0433195f17cabe-forks').innerHTML = data.forks;
      })
      .catch(error => console.error(error))
  </script>
</a>
<hr>

<section class="space-y-10 w-full">
    
    
</section>
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Personal Investment Bible: Book Notes</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1731056005976/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1731056005976/</guid><description>This book, written by Mr. Huang Peiyuan from Taiwan, uses easy-to-understand language to teach the correct methods of financial management. It elaborates on thirteen Investment Iron Laws for effortless wealth building, guiding readers on how to establish a correct perspective on financial management and ultimately achieve financial freedom.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[

<h2 class="relative group">I. Content Summary 
    <div id="i-content-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-content-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>The core concept of this book is that everyone can achieve financial freedom through investment, not just the wealthy or high-income earners. Through thirteen Investment Iron Laws, it emphasizes the importance of correct financial management concepts and long-term investment, encouraging readers to start managing their finances early, invest primarily in high-return investment tools such as stocks and real estate, and hold them for the long term, ultimately achieving financial freedom through the power of compound interest. The book uses numerous real-life examples and simple language to help readers understand and master correct financial management methods, while abandoning common financial management misunderstandings, such as short-term trading and over-reliance on bank deposits.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">II. Chapter Summaries 
    <div id="ii-chapter-summaries" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii-chapter-summaries" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Correct Concept of Personal Finance 
    <div id="correct-concept-of-personal-finance" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#correct-concept-of-personal-finance" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Personal investment can lead to wealth:</strong> The author believes that personal investment is not only a means to improve financial status but also an important path to wealth. Even if the monthly investment amount is small, as long as you persevere, you can accumulate considerable wealth by relying on the power of compound interest and ultimately realize the dream of becoming a billionaire. The book illustrates the power of compound interest with the example of investing 1200 Yuan per month with an annual return of 20%, resulting in assets exceeding 100 million Yuan after 40 years. It also cites the financial stories of the Lien Chan family and a postman to prove that even ordinary office workers can accumulate huge wealth with proper financial management.</li>
<li><strong>Increasing income and reducing expenditure treats the symptoms, not the root cause:</strong> Although diligence and frugality are traditional virtues, it is difficult to achieve financial freedom solely by relying on them in the era of rapid economic development. The author believes that financial management is more important than increasing income and reducing expenditure. The core of financial management lies in &ldquo;making money with money&rdquo; by achieving higher returns through investment, thereby enabling wealth to grow exponentially. The book uses the Lien Chan family&rsquo;s financial management methods as an example to illustrate the importance of investing in stocks and real estate. It points out that the Lien family did not start with huge wealth but accumulated astonishing wealth through long-term investment and financial management.</li>
<li><strong>Financial management methods cause the wealth gap:</strong> The author believes that the main cause of the wealth gap is not external factors such as family background, personal effort, or luck, but the difference in financial concepts and methods. The rich tend to invest their assets in high-yield investment tools such as stocks and real estate, while the poor tend to deposit money in banks, resulting in a slow rate of wealth appreciation. The book uses the example of two classmates who joined the same company after graduation to illustrate how different financial management methods eventually lead to vastly different wealth outcomes.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Investment Iron Law 1: Don&rsquo;t Save Money in the Bank 
    <div id="investment-iron-law-1-dont-save-money-in-the-bank" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#investment-iron-law-1-dont-save-money-in-the-bank" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Saving is equal to wasting resources:</strong> The author points out that keeping money in the bank seems safe but is actually a waste of resources. This is because bank deposit interest rates are low, and under the influence of inflation, the real rate of return is close to zero or even negative. This means that money deposited in the bank not only fails to appreciate but also depreciates. The book uses biblical stories and the example of the Nobel Prize Foundation to illustrate that not making good use of wealth, even without loss, is a waste.</li>
<li><strong>Deposit interest rates do not have compound interest benefits:</strong> Although bank deposits also enjoy compound interest, due to the low interest rate, the effect of compound interest is very limited and difficult to withstand the erosion of inflation. The author compares the final returns of two investment methods after 40 years, using a 5% bank interest rate and a 20% stock/real estate investment return rate as examples, illustrating the importance of the rate of return on investment.</li>
<li><strong>The invisible killer of currency value - inflation:</strong> Inflation is the &ldquo;invisible killer&rdquo; that causes money to depreciate. The author vividly illustrates the impact of inflation by comparing the price of red bean ice 30 years ago and now. He points out that in an inflationary environment, depositing money in the bank actually means &ldquo;the more you save, the less you have&rdquo;.</li>
<li><strong>The way to wealth of Zhang Pingsan, former chairman of Chang Hwa Bank:</strong> The author tells the story of Zhang Pingsan, the former chairman of Chang Hwa Bank, who achieved tremendous wealth growth by continuously borrowing money to buy Chang Hwa Bank shares and holding them for a long time. Those who sold their shares and put the money in the bank missed the opportunity to become wealthy. This once again proves the point that &ldquo;don&rsquo;t save money in the bank&rdquo;.</li>
<li><strong>The money deposited in the bank should not exceed living expenses:</strong> The author suggests that the amount of money deposited in the bank should be limited to meet two months of living expenses, and the excess should be used for investment to obtain higher returns. He also proposes a &ldquo;two large, one small&rdquo; investment portfolio suggestion: most assets are invested in stocks and real estate, and a small portion of funds is deposited in the bank for emergencies. He explains the liquidity of stocks and real estate to dispel readers&rsquo; concerns about investment liquidity.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Investment Iron Law 2: Be Patient to Get Rich Through Financial Management 
    <div id="investment-iron-law-2-be-patient-to-get-rich-through-financial-management" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#investment-iron-law-2-be-patient-to-get-rich-through-financial-management" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>How Li Ka-shing accumulated wealth:</strong> The author uses Li Ka-shing, Hong Kong&rsquo;s richest man, as an example to illustrate the importance of long-term investment. Li Ka-shing accumulated huge wealth through long-term investment in real estate. Getting rich through financial management requires time and patience; it is impossible to achieve overnight success. His success was not solely based on luck or hard work; more importantly, it was due to his long-term vision and perseverance.</li>
<li><strong>It takes a long time to see the effect of compound interest in financial management:</strong> The manifestation of the compound interest effect takes time, and it is difficult to see significant results in short-term investments. The author uses the example of investing 14,000 Yuan annually with an annual return of 20% to calculate the investment returns after 10, 20, 30, and 40 years, which are 360,000 Yuan, 2.61 million Yuan, 16.55 million Yuan, and 102.81 million Yuan, respectively. This set of data clearly demonstrates the power of compound interest and the importance of waiting patiently. Financial management is more like a marathon than a sprint.</li>
<li><strong>As long as you are patient, the money won&rsquo;t run away:</strong> Wealth accumulation is a gradual process that requires patience to wait for the compound interest effect to play out. The author uses the land investment experience of Zhang Yaohongying, Chairman of Hongjing Construction, as an example to illustrate that even if the initial investment return is not obvious, as long as you persist in holding it for a long time, you can eventually get a rich return.</li>
<li><strong>Getting rich overnight is counterproductive:</strong> The author warns readers that getting rich through financial management takes time, and they should not dream of getting rich quickly. Investment opportunities that bring rapid wealth in the short term are often accompanied by extremely high risks, which may eventually lead to losing everything. The author suggests that if you want to get rich quickly, you should choose to start a business instead of resorting to speculation.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Investment Iron Law 3: The Sooner You Start Investing, the Better 
    <div id="investment-iron-law-3-the-sooner-you-start-investing-the-better" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#investment-iron-law-3-the-sooner-you-start-investing-the-better" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Procrastination is the main reason for financial failure:</strong> The author points out that procrastination is one of the main reasons for financial failure. As age increases, the time available for investment decreases, and the space for the compound interest effect to play out also shrinks. Therefore, financial management should start as early as possible. Do not wait until you are older to realize the importance of financial management, as it is often too late.</li>
<li><strong>Start investing from today:</strong> The earlier you start investing, the longer the time for compound interest, and the higher the final return. The author calculates the monthly investment amount required under the same target amount and investment rate of return with different starting investment ages as examples. The data shows that the later you start investing, the higher the monthly investment amount required, highlighting the importance of starting financial management early.</li>
<li><strong>Jeffrey Koo Jr. is good at making money:</strong> The author uses the example of Jeffrey Koo Jr., Vice President of CTBC Financial Holding, to illustrate that even those from wealthy families should learn financial management early. Jeffrey Koo Jr. invested his savings in the stock market during his university days and obtained substantial returns, indicating that young people can also achieve success through financial management.</li>
<li><strong>Don&rsquo;t neglect financial management because of lack of money:</strong> The author emphasizes that financial management is not exclusive to the rich. Even if you don&rsquo;t have much money, you should start as early as possible and let the limited funds play the role of compound interest, accumulating little by little to eventually accumulate considerable wealth.</li>
<li><strong>Youth is the most appropriate time to take risks:</strong> When you are young, you have a lighter family burden and the cost of failure is relatively low, so it is more suitable to take certain investment risks. Moreover, young people have more time to make up for potential losses and learn from their mistakes.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Investment Iron Law 4: Make Money with Other People&rsquo;s Money 
    <div id="investment-iron-law-4-make-money-with-other-peoples-money" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#investment-iron-law-4-make-money-with-other-peoples-money" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Good use of debt investment:</strong> The author introduces the concept of &ldquo;financial leverage,&rdquo; which refers to using borrowed funds for investment to achieve a small investment with a large return, maximizing profits. He uses the examples of Chen Youhao, President of Eastern Multimedia Group, and Weng Daming of Hualon Group to illustrate how successful entrepreneurs use financial leverage for business expansion and investment. Specific examples are used to calculate the investment return rate under different leverage ratios to help readers understand the principle and role of financial leverage.</li>
<li><strong>Two major principles of borrowing:</strong> The author proposes two major principles for debt investment: 1. The expected return on investment must be greater than the loan interest rate; 2. In the worst case, cash income must be sufficient to pay the principal and interest of the loan. These two principles emphasize the risks of debt investment and remind readers to rationally evaluate the expected rate of return of the investment target and conduct risk assessment to ensure that even if the investment fails, the principal and interest of the loan can be repaid on time.</li>
<li><strong>Banks are not places to save money:</strong> The author points out that for people who are good at financial management, banks are not places to save money but sources of borrowing. He explains the operating model of banks: Banks absorb deposits from depositors and then lend these funds to investors. Investors make profits through investment and pay interest to banks. Therefore, people who are good at financial management can use bank funds for investment to magnify returns.</li>
<li><strong>Avoid improper debt:</strong> The author cautions readers to avoid improper debt. Do not borrow money to participate in high-risk activities such as futures, margin trading, and gambling because the expected return rate of these activities is negative, and long-term participation will inevitably lead to losses. Also, do not over-engage in consumer loans, such as credit card loans and car loans, as high-interest loans will seriously erode personal wealth. Mortgage loans are acceptable, but you should also live within your means and make sure that the monthly repayment pressure is within your affordable range.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Investment Iron Law 5: Relieve the Pressure of Investment Risks 
    <div id="investment-iron-law-5-relieve-the-pressure-of-investment-risks" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#investment-iron-law-5-relieve-the-pressure-of-investment-risks" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Analyze risks and reduce harm:</strong> The author points out that risks cannot be completely avoided in the investment process. The purpose of risk management is not to eliminate risk but to analyze risk and reduce the potential harm caused by risk. He emphasizes not to over-rely on forecasting because the accuracy of forecasting is difficult to guarantee, and over-reliance on forecasting may lead investors to lose their risk awareness.</li>
<li><strong>Forbes&rsquo; philosophy of distress:</strong> The author uses the example of American billionaire Forbes to illustrate that even risk-averse people can take risks through reasonable risk management. Although Forbes doesn&rsquo;t like adventure, in order to experience the beauty of life, he will participate in some high-risk activities, such as hot air ballooning and off-road motorcycles. But he will make full preparations before taking risks and take various measures to reduce risks.</li>
<li><strong>Don&rsquo;t blindly avoid risks:</strong> The author believes that in a changing environment, the biggest risk is not taking risks. In order to obtain higher returns, certain risks must be taken. Blindly avoiding risks may eventually lead to missed opportunities and even failure to achieve financial freedom.</li>
<li><strong>Overcome risks - start small:</strong> For unfamiliar investments, you should start with small investments, gradually accumulate experience, and gradually improve your risk tolerance. Just like scouts, first test the waters with a small amount to understand the situation, and then gradually increase the investment.</li>
<li><strong>There is no high-return, zero-risk investment:</strong> The author reminds readers that all high-yield investments are accompanied by high risks and not to believe in the so-called &ldquo;high-yield, risk-free&rdquo; investment scams. If someone recommends such an investment opportunity to you, it is likely that they are trying to deceive you.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Investment Iron Law 6: Solve the Crisis of Being Trapped 
    <div id="investment-iron-law-6-solve-the-crisis-of-being-trapped" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#investment-iron-law-6-solve-the-crisis-of-being-trapped" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Diversify your investments and hold them for the long term:</strong> The author proposes the investment strategy of &ldquo;diversification and long-term holding&rdquo; and believes that this is the key to avoiding being trapped and obtaining long-term stable returns. Diversified investment can reduce the risk of choosing the wrong investment target; diversifying investment timing can reduce the risk of buying at market highs; long-term holding can reduce the risk brought by short-term market fluctuations and fully enjoy the benefits brought by compound interest.</li>
<li><strong>Principle of risk diversification:</strong> The principle of diversified investment is to reduce the overall risk of the investment portfolio by increasing the types of investments so that the rise and fall of different assets in the investment portfolio can offset each other. The author points out that diversification is not the more the better and that management costs need to be considered. Too many investment types will increase management difficulty and cost, which is not conducive to improving profits.</li>
<li><strong>Diversify investment timing:</strong> In order to reduce the risk of buying at market highs, the author suggests spreading the funds over different periods. He proposes two methods: one is &ldquo;invest if you have money,&rdquo; and the other is &ldquo;regularly invest a fixed amount in mutual funds.&rdquo; &ldquo;Invest if you have money&rdquo; means that once you have idle funds, invest immediately and do not try to predict market timing; &ldquo;regular investment of a fixed amount in mutual funds&rdquo; means investing a fixed amount every month to buy mutual funds. This method can effectively smooth market fluctuations and reduce investment risks.</li>
<li><strong>Methods of diversified investment:</strong> The author introduces three methods of diversified investment in detail: 1. Diversification of investment tools, such as stocks, real estate, gold, art, etc.; 2. Diversification of investment targets, for example, when investing in stocks, do not just buy one stock, but buy multiple stocks in different industries; 3. Diversification of investment regions, for example, invest some assets in overseas markets to diversify regional risks.</li>
<li><strong>Reduce the risk of choosing the wrong selling time - long-term holding:</strong> Through research on the Taiwan stock market, the author found that the longer the holding time, the lower the probability of loss. For example, the probability of loss when holding stocks for more than 5 years is only 1%, and it is almost impossible to lose money when holding for more than 10 years. This once again proves the importance of long-term holding.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Investment Iron Law 7: Make Good Use of Stock Investment 
    <div id="investment-iron-law-7-make-good-use-of-stock-investment" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#investment-iron-law-7-make-good-use-of-stock-investment" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Liu Qiude&rsquo;s secret to wealth:</strong> The author uses the financial story of Liu Qiude, Vice President of Cathay Life Insurance, as an example to illustrate the power of long-term holding of high-quality stocks. Liu Qiude worked at Cathay Life Insurance from his twenties. He held his savings and the Cathay Life Insurance shares he acquired from his colleagues for a long time and eventually became a billionaire. This example also reflects the long-term and stable performance growth of Cathay Life Insurance from the side.</li>
<li><strong>Why stocks have high returns:</strong> The author explains the source of returns from stock investment: stocks represent ownership of a company, and shareholders can share in the company&rsquo;s profits and asset appreciation. Therefore, the returns from investing in stocks come from corporate earnings and asset appreciation, not from the losses of other investors. He pointed out that the long-term rise in stock prices is mainly due to the improvement of corporate profitability and the growth of asset value.</li>
<li><strong>Carefully select the types of stocks to invest in:</strong> The author compares the characteristics of listed stocks, over-the-counter stocks, unlisted stocks, and mutual funds and suggests that ordinary investors should give priority to investing in listed stocks or mutual funds. Listed stocks have good liquidity, transparent information disclosure, and relatively strict supervision, so the risks are relatively low. Mutual funds are managed by professionals and can effectively diversify investment risks, making them suitable for investors who do not have much time and energy to research stocks.</li>
<li><strong>Stock investment is better than real estate investment:</strong> The author compares stock and real estate investment from the aspects of investment threshold, taxation, and trading convenience. He believes that stock investment has a lower threshold, lighter taxes, and is more convenient to trade, making it more suitable for ordinary investors.</li>
<li><strong>Can stocks still maintain high returns in the future?:</strong> The author analyzes and forecasts the future return rate of the Taiwan stock market. He believes that although Taiwan&rsquo;s economic growth has slowed down, it is still higher than other countries and regions, so the Taiwan stock market still has high investment value in the future, but the return rate may be slightly lower than in the past.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Investment Iron Law 8: Make Money When You Buy and Sell 
    <div id="investment-iron-law-8-make-money-when-you-buy-and-sell" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#investment-iron-law-8-make-money-when-you-buy-and-sell" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Buy casually, buy at any time, don&rsquo;t sell:</strong> The author once again emphasizes the investment strategy of &ldquo;buy casually, buy at any time, don&rsquo;t sell&rdquo; and points out that this is the highest level of financial management. This strategy seems simple, but it actually contains profound investment wisdom: it emphasizes long-term holding, infrequent trading, and avoiding being affected by short-term market fluctuations, thereby obtaining long-term and stable returns. The author admits that most people find it difficult to do this because they cannot overcome human weaknesses such as greed and fear.</li>
<li><strong>What to buy - buy casually:</strong> The author points out that as long as diversified investment is achieved, the selection of individual stocks is not important. He uses the experiment of &ldquo;monkeys throwing darts to select stocks&rdquo; and his own experience of selecting stocks with his children as examples to illustrate the effectiveness of &ldquo;buying casually&rdquo;.</li>
<li><strong>When to buy - buy at any time:</strong> The author suggests that investors &ldquo;buy if they have money&rdquo;, and do not try to predict market timing. He emphasizes &ldquo;buying and waiting for a chance to rise&rdquo; instead of &ldquo;waiting for a chance to buy&rdquo;. Because the market is difficult to predict, and time is the key factor in compound interest, the earlier you start investing, the more you can enjoy the benefits brought by compound interest.</li>
<li><strong>When to sell - don&rsquo;t sell:</strong> The author believes that long-term holding is the key to obtaining high returns. He quotes Jesse Livermore, the author of Reminiscences of a Stock Operator, and the investment strategy of Taiwan&rsquo;s richest man, Cai Wanlin, to illustrate the importance of long-term holding.</li>
<li><strong>Random walk and efficient market theory:</strong> The author introduces the &ldquo;random walk hypothesis&rdquo; and the &ldquo;efficient market hypothesis&rdquo; to provide a theoretical basis for the strategy of &ldquo;buy casually, buy at any time, don&rsquo;t sell&rdquo;. The &ldquo;random walk hypothesis&rdquo; believes that short-term fluctuations in stock prices are random and difficult to predict; the &ldquo;efficient market hypothesis&rdquo; believes that all information in the market is already reflected in stock prices, so it is futile to predict market trends by analyzing information.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Investment Iron Law 9: Grasp the General Trend of the Stock Market 
    <div id="investment-iron-law-9-grasp-the-general-trend-of-the-stock-market" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#investment-iron-law-9-grasp-the-general-trend-of-the-stock-market" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Blind spots in prediction and analysis:</strong> The author once again emphasizes the limitations of prediction and analysis. He points out that technical analysis and market forecasting cannot guarantee investment success, and may even lead to losses due to frequent trading. Technical analysis is based on historical data, but the market environment is constantly changing, and past performance does not represent future trends.</li>
<li><strong>The only thing that can be measured is the unmeasurable:</strong> Market trends are difficult to predict. Instead of trying to predict the market, it is better to formulate a reasonable investment strategy and hold it for a long time. The author illustrates the unreliability of prediction with an example of a failed stock market prophet.</li>
<li><strong>Believe in yourself rather than experts:</strong> The author advises investors not to over-rely on expert opinions and to cultivate their own financial management capabilities and independent judgment. He pointed out that expert opinions often contradict each other, and ten experts may have eleven opinions. Besides, experts may also be influenced by various factors, such as conflicts of interest, and thus give biased opinions.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Investment Iron Law 10: Make Good Use of Stock Market Offensive and Defensive Weapons 
    <div id="investment-iron-law-10-make-good-use-of-stock-market-offensive-and-defensive-weapons" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#investment-iron-law-10-make-good-use-of-stock-market-offensive-and-defensive-weapons" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Value strategy:</strong> The core of value strategy is &ldquo;buy when the value is higher than the price, and sell when the value is lower than the price&rdquo;. The author uses the huge difference in the share price of China Development Financial at different times as an example to illustrate the impact of market sentiment on stock prices and the performance of investors&rsquo; irrational behavior. He advises investors to learn rational consumption behavior and buy stocks when the &ldquo;price is discounted&rdquo;. He also points out that the key to value investing is being able to accurately assess the intrinsic value of a company, which requires certain professional knowledge and experience.</li>
<li><strong>Growth strategy:</strong> The core of the growth strategy is to invest in companies with high growth potential in the future and hold them for the long term. The author uses Peter Lynch&rsquo;s investment strategy and the investment story of the &ldquo;Coca-Cola Grandma&rdquo; as examples to illustrate the effectiveness of the growth strategy. He advises investors to choose companies with high growth potential in the next 5-10 years and focus on choosing the right industry because the growth of the industry will drive the growth of corporate performance.</li>
<li><strong>Contrarian strategy:</strong> The core of the contrarian strategy is &ldquo;invest when most people are not investing, and sell when most people are eager to invest&rdquo;. The author uses the business philosophy of Fan Li and the investment strategy of Zheng Zhoumin as examples to illustrate the principle of contrarian operation. He pointed out that market sentiment is often wrong. When the market is excessively pessimistic, it is often a good time to buy; when the market is excessively optimistic, it is often a good time to sell. However, contrarian operation is very difficult, and it requires investors to have independent thinking ability and strong psychological quality.</li>
<li><strong>Value, growth, and contrarian strategies are suitable for experts:</strong> The author summarizes the characteristics of the three strategies and points out that these strategies are more suitable for professional investors. For ordinary investors, the strategy of &ldquo;buy casually, buy at any time, don&rsquo;t sell&rdquo; is simpler and easier to implement, and it is also easier to obtain long-term and stable returns.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Investment Iron Law 11: Don&rsquo;t Do Short-Term Operations 
    <div id="investment-iron-law-11-dont-do-short-term-operations" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#investment-iron-law-11-dont-do-short-term-operations" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Buy low and sell high is full of crises:</strong> The author pointed out that &ldquo;buying low and selling high&rdquo; seems to be the secret to making money from stock investment, but it is actually full of traps. Because no one can accurately predict the short-term fluctuations of the market, trying to make profits through &ldquo;buying low and selling high&rdquo; will often fall into the dilemma of chasing ups and downs, which will eventually lead to losses. He emphasizes that the main source of stock investment income is corporate profits and dividends, not the difference in buying and selling prices.</li>
<li><strong>Short-term operation is gambling:</strong> The author believes that the essence of short-term operation is speculation and gambling, and it is difficult to make a profit in the long run. Because short-term operations require frequent trading, and each transaction will generate transaction costs, such as commissions, stamp duty, etc. These transaction costs will eat away at investment income, and accumulate over time, will have a significant negative impact on investment returns.</li>
<li><strong>A game with no chance of winning:</strong> The author analyzes the composition of the stock market, including intermediaries (securities companies, governments, etc.), major shareholders, major players, and retail investors. He pointed out that retail investors are at a clear disadvantage in this game of short-term operations because they lack the advantages of capital, information, and resources. Therefore, retail investors should avoid participating in short-term operations and adopt a long-term investment strategy.</li>
<li><strong>Never participate in futures and margin trading:</strong> The author strongly recommends that investors not participate in futures and margin trading because these transactions are extremely risky, and the leverage effect will magnify both profits and losses. It is difficult for ordinary investors to control the risks. He uses the example of the Barings Bank collapse to illustrate the huge risks of futures and margin trading.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Investment Iron Law 12:  Land is Wealth 
    <div id="investment-iron-law-12--land-is-wealth" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#investment-iron-law-12--land-is-wealth" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Why real estate has high returns:</strong> The author analyzes the reasons for the high returns of real estate investment, mainly including three aspects: 1. Limited land supply; 2. As the economy grows and the population grows, the demand for real estate continues to increase; 3. Inflation will push up real estate prices.</li>
<li><strong>Hong Kong&rsquo;s richest man, Lee Shau Kee&rsquo;s real estate investment strategy:</strong> The author introduces the real estate investment strategy of Hong Kong&rsquo;s richest man, Lee Shau Kee: acquire old buildings at low prices, then demolish and rebuild them, or hold land for a long time and wait for appreciation.</li>
<li><strong>Cai Wanlin&rsquo;s secret to getting rich in real estate:</strong> The author uses Taiwan&rsquo;s richest man, Cai Wanlin, as an example to illustrate the real estate investment strategy of &ldquo;buy and hold for the long term.&rdquo; Cai Wanlin&rsquo;s secret is to buy real estate and hold it for a long time, only renting and not selling.</li>
<li><strong>Zheng Zhoumin&rsquo;s real estate investment technique:</strong> The author introduces the real estate investment strategy of the Philippines&rsquo; richest man, Zheng Zhoumin: buy when the market is down, and hold it for a long time, waiting for the market to recover and prices to rise.</li>
<li><strong>Real estate is suitable for debt investment:</strong> The author believes that real estate investment is suitable for debt investment because the long-term investment return rate of real estate is usually higher than the loan interest rate. Through reasonable debt investment, financial leverage can be used to magnify returns. At the same time, he also reminds readers to live within their means and avoid the risks brought by excessive debt.</li>
<li><strong>Brand concept of real estate investment:</strong> The author emphasizes the importance of choosing real estate developers with good brands, guaranteed quality, and good after-sales service. He pointed out that buying a property is a major investment decision, and choosing a reputable developer can reduce investment risks and enhance the living experience.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Investment Iron Law 13: Act Now 
    <div id="investment-iron-law-13-act-now" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#investment-iron-law-13-act-now" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>It is better to act than to sit and study:</strong> The author once again emphasizes the importance of action. He believes that having knowledge without taking action is equivalent to not having knowledge. The key to financial management is action, not fantasy. He uses the story of a farmer who does not understand stocks but dares to buy and eventually make a profit as an example to illustrate the importance of action.</li>
<li><strong>Future wealth is in your own hands:</strong> The author points out that future wealth is in your own hands, and only active actions can create wealth. He encourages readers to overcome their fear and bravely take the first step in financial management.</li>
<li><strong>Financial experience - learn from mistakes:</strong> The author believes that failure is the mother of success, and you must dare to try and learn from your mistakes. He advises readers to start with small investments, gradually accumulate experience, and gradually improve their risk tolerance.</li>
<li><strong>The first step in learning financial management:</strong> The author suggests that readers start acting immediately after reading this book. They can start by investing a small amount in stocks or mutual funds, or they can buy a self-occupied property. He believes that the best way to learn financial management is to practice, accumulate experience in practice, and continue to learn and improve.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">The Ultimate Chapter of Financial Management: Making Money Requires a Goal 
    <div id="the-ultimate-chapter-of-financial-management-making-money-requires-a-goal" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#the-ultimate-chapter-of-financial-management-making-money-requires-a-goal" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Don&rsquo;t be a miser:</strong> The author uses the story of a miser to illustrate that money is only a means, and improving the quality of life is the goal. He warns readers not to become slaves to money, to learn to enjoy life, and to use wealth for more meaningful things.</li>
<li><strong>What is the purpose of making so much money?:</strong> The author explores the meaning and values of money. He pointed out that money itself is not good or bad, the key is how to use it. Money can be used to improve lives, pursue dreams, help others, and give back to society. He encourages readers to establish correct values about money, not to blindly pursue wealth, and ignore other aspects of life.</li>
<li><strong>Three secrets of financial management - making money, managing money, and using money:</strong> The author proposes three levels of financial management: making money, managing money, and using money. He believes that making money is the foundation, managing money is the key, and using money is the purpose. These three levels are indispensable, and only by combining the three can you truly achieve financial freedom and live a happy life. He pointed out that how to use money is the most difficult because it involves personal values and life goals.</li>
<li><strong>American billionaire - Warren Buffett&rsquo;s view of money:</strong> The author introduces Warren Buffett&rsquo;s view of money and estate planning. Although Buffett is extremely wealthy, he lives a simple life and donates most of his estate to charity. He believes that happiness is a process, not a result. True happiness lies in constant pursuit and creation, not in how much wealth you have.</li>
<li><strong>Summary:</strong> The author summarizes the core viewpoints of the book: Everyone can achieve wealth through financial management. The key lies in having the correct concept of financial management, long-term investment, and positive actions. He encourages readers to set clear financial goals and formulate feasible financial plans based on their actual situations. He emphasizes that the ultimate goal of financial management is not to have unlimited wealth, but to achieve financial freedom, improve the quality of life, and ultimately realize the value of life.</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">III.  Key Quotes 
    <div id="iii--key-quotes" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii--key-quotes" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>Don&rsquo;t keep your money in the bank.</p></blockquote>
<p>Analysis: This doesn&rsquo;t literally mean not keeping any money in the bank, but emphasizes not leaving most assets in low-yield bank deposits long-term.  Invest in higher-yielding tools like stocks and real estate.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Building wealth requires patience.</p></blockquote>
<p>Analysis: The compound interest effect takes time. Financial management is a marathon, not a sprint, requiring patient waiting for ultimate success.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The earlier you invest, the better.</p></blockquote>
<p>Analysis: Youth is the greatest asset. The earlier you start managing your finances, the sooner you can enjoy the benefits of compound interest and achieve financial freedom.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Make money with other people&rsquo;s money.</p></blockquote>
<p>Analysis:  Proper use of financial leverage can magnify investment returns and accelerate wealth accumulation.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Diversify investments and hold long-term.</p></blockquote>
<p>Analysis: Diversification reduces risk. Long-term holding yields higher returns and avoids being affected by market fluctuations.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Buy casually, buy anytime, don&rsquo;t sell.</p></blockquote>
<p>Analysis:  The core of this is long-term holding and avoiding frequent trading to prevent being impacted by short-term market fluctuations.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Knowing and not doing is the same as not knowing.</p></blockquote>
<p>Analysis: Knowledge without action is equivalent to no knowledge. The key to financial management lies in action, not just thinking.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Wealth lies in land.</p></blockquote>
<p>Analysis: Real estate is a crucial long-term value-preserving and appreciating investment tool that should hold a significant place in your portfolio.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Money is only a means, improving the quality of life is the goal.</p></blockquote>
<p>Analysis: Money itself is meaningless; its value lies in how it&rsquo;s used. The ultimate goal is to improve the quality of life and realize one&rsquo;s life value.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">IV.  Guidance and Significance 
    <div id="iv--guidance-and-significance" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv--guidance-and-significance" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This book&rsquo;s significance lies in helping readers establish a correct financial management mindset, master basic financial management methods, and ultimately achieve financial freedom.  It emphasizes the importance of long-term investment, the compound effect, and risk management, encouraging readers to overcome their fear of risk and start managing their finances early, without being misled by short-term market fluctuations. By studying this book, readers can better plan their financial future, enhance their quality of life, and ultimately achieve financial freedom and realize their life value.</p>
<hr>


<h2 class="relative group">Read the Full Book 
    <div id="read-the-full-book" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#read-the-full-book" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>

<section class="space-y-10 w-full">
    
    
        
            






















  <a class="flex flex-wrap article " href="/en/posts/1731056005958/">
    
        
        <div class="w-full md:w-auto h-full thumbnail nozoom thumbnailshadow md:mr-7" style="background-image:url(/posts/1731056005958/featured_hu_a65a55d073c07bc4.png);"></div>
        
      <div class=" mt-3 md:mt-0">
      <div class="items-center text-left text-xl font-semibold">
        
        <div class="font-bold text-xl text-neutral-800 decoration-primary-500 hover:underline hover:underline-offset-2 dark:text-neutral"
          href="/en/posts/1731056005958/">Personal Investment Bible: Preface</div>
        
        
        
      </div>
      <div class="text-sm text-neutral-500 dark:text-neutral-400">
        











  



















<div class="flex flex-row flex-wrap items-center">
  
  
  <time datetime="2024-11-08T00:00:00&#43;00:00">8 November 2024</time>
  

  
  
</div>





<div class="flex flex-row flex-wrap items-center">
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  <span style="margin-top:0.5rem" class="mr-2" onclick="window.open(&#34;/en/tags/personal-investment-bible/&#34;,'_self');">
    <span class="flex" style="cursor: pointer;">
  <span class="rounded-md border border-primary-400 px-1 py-[1px] text-xs font-normal text-primary-700 dark:border-primary-600 dark:text-primary-400">
    Personal Investment Bible
  </span>
</span>
  </span>
  
  <span style="margin-top:0.5rem" class="mr-2" onclick="window.open(&#34;/en/tags/book/&#34;,'_self');">
    <span class="flex" style="cursor: pointer;">
  <span class="rounded-md border border-primary-400 px-1 py-[1px] text-xs font-normal text-primary-700 dark:border-primary-600 dark:text-primary-400">
    Book
  </span>
</span>
  </span>
  
  <span style="margin-top:0.5rem" class="mr-2" onclick="window.open(&#34;/en/tags/wealth-management/&#34;,'_self');">
    <span class="flex" style="cursor: pointer;">
  <span class="rounded-md border border-primary-400 px-1 py-[1px] text-xs font-normal text-primary-700 dark:border-primary-600 dark:text-primary-400">
    Wealth Management
  </span>
</span>
  </span>
  
  <span style="margin-top:0.5rem" class="mr-2" onclick="window.open(&#34;/en/tags/investment/&#34;,'_self');">
    <span class="flex" style="cursor: pointer;">
  <span class="rounded-md border border-primary-400 px-1 py-[1px] text-xs font-normal text-primary-700 dark:border-primary-600 dark:text-primary-400">
    Investment
  </span>
</span>
  </span>
  
  <span style="margin-top:0.5rem" class="mr-2" onclick="window.open(&#34;/en/tags/wealth-creation/&#34;,'_self');">
    <span class="flex" style="cursor: pointer;">
  <span class="rounded-md border border-primary-400 px-1 py-[1px] text-xs font-normal text-primary-700 dark:border-primary-600 dark:text-primary-400">
    Wealth Creation
  </span>
</span>
  </span>
  
  <span style="margin-top:0.5rem" class="mr-2" onclick="window.open(&#34;/en/tags/financial-freedom/&#34;,'_self');">
    <span class="flex" style="cursor: pointer;">
  <span class="rounded-md border border-primary-400 px-1 py-[1px] text-xs font-normal text-primary-700 dark:border-primary-600 dark:text-primary-400">
    Financial Freedom
  </span>
</span>
  </span>
  
  <span style="margin-top:0.5rem" class="mr-2" onclick="window.open(&#34;/en/tags/stocks/&#34;,'_self');">
    <span class="flex" style="cursor: pointer;">
  <span class="rounded-md border border-primary-400 px-1 py-[1px] text-xs font-normal text-primary-700 dark:border-primary-600 dark:text-primary-400">
    Stocks
  </span>
</span>
  </span>
  
  <span style="margin-top:0.5rem" class="mr-2" onclick="window.open(&#34;/en/tags/real-estate/&#34;,'_self');">
    <span class="flex" style="cursor: pointer;">
  <span class="rounded-md border border-primary-400 px-1 py-[1px] text-xs font-normal text-primary-700 dark:border-primary-600 dark:text-primary-400">
    Real Estate
  </span>
</span>
  </span>
  
  <span style="margin-top:0.5rem" class="mr-2" onclick="window.open(&#34;/en/tags/financial-education/&#34;,'_self');">
    <span class="flex" style="cursor: pointer;">
  <span class="rounded-md border border-primary-400 px-1 py-[1px] text-xs font-normal text-primary-700 dark:border-primary-600 dark:text-primary-400">
    Financial Education
  </span>
</span>
  </span>
  
  <span style="margin-top:0.5rem" class="mr-2" onclick="window.open(&#34;/en/tags/long-term-investment/&#34;,'_self');">
    <span class="flex" style="cursor: pointer;">
  <span class="rounded-md border border-primary-400 px-1 py-[1px] text-xs font-normal text-primary-700 dark:border-primary-600 dark:text-primary-400">
    Long-Term Investment
  </span>
</span>
  </span>
  
  
  
  
</div>




      </div>
      
    </div>
  </a>

        
    
</section>
<hr>

<section class="space-y-10 w-full">
    
    
        
            






















  <a class="flex flex-wrap article " href="/en/posts/1728295490690-book-list/">
    
        
        <div class="w-full md:w-auto h-full thumbnail nozoom thumbnailshadow md:mr-7" style="background-image:url(/posts/1728295490690-book-list/featured_hu_a14921d8ab66af4e.jpg);"></div>
        
      <div class=" mt-3 md:mt-0">
      <div class="items-center text-left text-xl font-semibold">
        
        <div class="font-bold text-xl text-neutral-800 decoration-primary-500 hover:underline hover:underline-offset-2 dark:text-neutral"
          href="/en/posts/1728295490690-book-list/">Recommended Reading List</div>
        
        
        
      </div>
      <div class="text-sm text-neutral-500 dark:text-neutral-400">
        











  



















<div class="flex flex-row flex-wrap items-center">
  
  
  <time datetime="2024-10-01T00:00:00&#43;00:00">1 October 2024</time>
  

  
  
</div>





<div class="flex flex-row flex-wrap items-center">
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  <span style="margin-top:0.5rem" class="mr-2" onclick="window.open(&#34;/en/tags/recommended/&#34;,'_self');">
    <span class="flex" style="cursor: pointer;">
  <span class="rounded-md border border-primary-400 px-1 py-[1px] text-xs font-normal text-primary-700 dark:border-primary-600 dark:text-primary-400">
    Recommended
  </span>
</span>
  </span>
  
  <span style="margin-top:0.5rem" class="mr-2" onclick="window.open(&#34;/en/tags/book/&#34;,'_self');">
    <span class="flex" style="cursor: pointer;">
  <span class="rounded-md border border-primary-400 px-1 py-[1px] text-xs font-normal text-primary-700 dark:border-primary-600 dark:text-primary-400">
    Book
  </span>
</span>
  </span>
  
  
  
  
</div>




      </div>
      
    </div>
  </a>

        
    
</section>
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Personal Investment Bible: Conclusion</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1731056005974/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1731056005974/</guid><description>This article summarizes the core concepts of building wealth through personal finance, emphasizing that everyone can achieve financial freedom through proper money management. Key takeaways include the importance of financial planning, principles for setting financial goals, the value of long-term investing, overcoming common financial misconceptions, and balancing wealth with a fulfilling life. It encourages readers to acquire financial knowledge, adhere to long-term investment strategies, and ultimately achieve financial freedom and a better life.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[

<h2 class="relative group">Conclusion 
    <div id="conclusion" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#conclusion" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>What influences a person&rsquo;s future wealth the most,
is whether they have started managing their finances.</p></blockquote>
<p><strong>Everyone Can Achieve Wealth Through Personal Finance</strong></p>
<p>This book aims to illustrate a simple truth: investing and managing your finances can not only improve the financial situation of an individual or family, but is also an excellent path to wealth creation.  Furthermore, anyone can achieve wealth through personal finance. You don&rsquo;t need to be rich, have a high income, possess a high degree, have specialized knowledge or advanced skills, nor rely on luck. What you need is the desire for wealth, a correct investment philosophy (not just techniques), and the patience to wait for the long term.  Therefore, whether a person has money or not, or how high their income is, doesn&rsquo;t matter. What truly influences a person&rsquo;s future wealth is whether they have started managing their finances. This endeavor is not easy, but it&rsquo;s undoubtedly worth your effort!</p>
<p>Readers, please immediately review your current asset allocation. Is too much of your capital sitting in bank accounts or other &ldquo;guaranteed return&rdquo; investments?  Is your investment portfolio sufficiently diversified? Do you frequently buy and sell in the stock market?</p>
<p>After understanding your asset allocation, you should earnestly plan your financial goals and follow these five principles:</p>
<p><em>1. Clearly define the amount of wealth you hope to achieve and keep it in mind at all times. Simply thinking &ldquo;I want to be rich&rdquo; is not enough.</em></p>
<p><em>2. Set a specific date for achieving your goal.</em></p>
<p><em>3. Determine what price you&rsquo;re willing to pay and what actions you&rsquo;ll take to reach your ideal goal.</em></p>
<p><em>4. Think about your goal at least twice a day to reinforce your belief.</em></p>
<p><em>5.  Take action, whether you feel completely ready or not.</em></p>
<p>In Appendix II, readers can use the wealth creation formula and examples provided to calculate how to achieve their financial goals.</p>
<p>Your future wealth depends on what you do today. Don&rsquo;t let unnecessary hesitation cast a shadow on your heart. As long as you understand investment and financial management, you too can become wealthy in the future. Everyone possesses the necessary ingredients for wealth creation: a small amount of capital and a God-given resource—time. As long as you are willing to learn about personal finance, you have the potential to become a multi-millionaire.</p>
<p>When you find people around you feeling lost due to a lack of vision for the future, share with them the &ldquo;¥14,000 a year for 40 years can make you a multi-millionaire&rdquo; formula and help them reignite their hope.</p>
<p><strong>Financial Dependence Is Your Own Responsibility</strong></p>
<p>The unequal distribution of wealth in today&rsquo;s society is increasingly severe. Some blame flawed policies, others point to artificial market manipulation. I believe neither is the primary cause.  One of the main reasons for the wealth gap is the disparity in financial literacy among people.</p>
<p>The reason for poverty in modern times is not so much insufficient income, lack of thrift, or excessive spending, but rather improper financial management. In modern society, achieving financial independence after the age of 40 is a fundamental responsibility for everyone. Whether you want to or not, or whether you like it or not, investment and financial management have become essential knowledge for modern individuals. Remember, with our current income levels and investment opportunities, &ldquo;remaining poor after 40&rdquo; is self-inflicted, and &ldquo;not being a multi-millionaire after 70&rdquo; is due to a lack of financial knowledge.</p>
<p>Advances in modern medicine have increased human life expectancy, leading to an aging society.  Longer lifespans are a blessing, but enjoying a comfortable retirement is even more crucial. We must accumulate sufficient wealth to secure our lives in old age.</p>
<p><strong>Effortless Personal Finance, Enjoy the Process</strong></p>
<p>From the examples provided in this article, we can see that those who are good at managing their finances understand how to invest their assets in stocks and real estate with high long-term returns, and they avoid unnecessary short-term trading, thus achieving wealth with ease.  Those who are not good at managing their finances either focus solely on saving and keeping their assets in &ldquo;safe&rdquo; bank deposits or try to get rich quickly by engaging in short-term trading in the stock or futures markets. These individuals will eventually be left far behind in the race for financial success.</p>
<p>Most people keep their assets in financial institutions without investing them, and when they do start investing, they aim for quick riches.  As a result, their money stagnates in banks, and their pursuit of quick wealth often leads to substantial losses.  They fail to realize that with a little courage, by investing in stocks and real estate and patiently waiting for decades, they can naturally achieve wealth.</p>
<p>Simply put, building wealth through personal finance only requires two things: investing your capital in areas with high returns and having the patience to wait for the long term. The required investment is low, the probability of success is high, and the process is relaxed and enjoyable.</p>
<p>I advise readers not to rush to get rich through investment, causing anxiety and ultimately achieving the opposite of what they desire.  By following the methods described in this book, you can achieve financial success without expending excessive time and energy, allowing you to focus on your existing career.</p>
<p>Personal finance is a marathon, not a sprint. If you view the entire process from a long-term perspective, temporary setbacks don&rsquo;t signify failure, and momentary gains don&rsquo;t guarantee lasting success. With this mindset, you can maintain a more open perspective and avoid becoming overly attached to gains and losses.</p>
<p>I admit that consistently buying assets and holding them long-term can make personal finance seem dull and unbearable. However, before engaging in any financial activities, investors must clarify their objectives: is it to build wealth or to seek the thrill of gambling? Personal finance can not only lead to wealth but also bring joy and knowledge.  Everyone should learn how to manage their finances and find enjoyment in the process.</p>
<p><strong>Don&rsquo;t Feel Guilty About Being Wealthy</strong></p>
<p>Wealth should be acquired and used ethically. You don&rsquo;t need to apologize to others for your wealth. Only the pursuit of wealth through unscrupulous means is sinful and unfortunate.  Therefore, everyone should not only be confident but also feel obligated to earn wealth. There&rsquo;s no need to be secretive or ashamed about pursuing wealth. On the contrary, being financially dependent is a burden on society.  Moreover, wealthy individuals are more capable of contributing to society.  In short, if you can&rsquo;t find a good reason why getting rich is bad, why not allow yourself to become wealthy?</p>
<p>You earning more in the investment market doesn&rsquo;t mean others will earn less or lose more.  If everyone is proficient in managing their finances, not only can individuals prosper, but economic resources can also be utilized effectively, leading to rapid overall economic growth.  In a market economy, the wealth of society is built upon the wealth of its people. Only a prosperous populace can create a prosperous economy.</p>
<p>In today&rsquo;s financially driven world, whether for personal advancement or the benefit of society as a whole, everyone should strengthen their understanding of personal finance. When everyone is skilled in managing their finances, individuals and families can live prosperous lives, the wealth gap can be narrowed, and the nation can progress and flourish.</p>
<p><strong>Action Speaks Louder Than Words</strong></p>
<p>&ldquo;Knowing and not doing is not knowing.&rdquo; The biggest obstacle to personal finance is not that it&rsquo;s difficult to do, but that it&rsquo;s difficult to start.  The key to overcoming this is to act immediately.  One of the main reasons for failure in personal finance is avoiding decisions.  However, if you want to achieve your goal of building wealth through investment, there&rsquo;s no other way than to take action.</p>
<p>After reading the basic principles of investment and financial management outlined in this article, you should understand that building wealth is not only achievable but also not difficult.  So, act now! Time is money. The earlier you start, the sooner you&rsquo;ll reach your financial goals and share the fruits of your labor with your family.</p>
<p>Looking ahead, changes in society, politics, economics, and finance will accelerate, and the resulting redistribution of wealth will inevitably follow suit.  For yourself, your family, and society as a whole, managing your finances is a role everyone should embrace.</p>
<p><strong>Persistence Is Key</strong></p>
<p>For readers seeking quick riches, this book might disappoint you.  A more accurate title would be: &ldquo;How to Invest and Manage Your Finances to Slowly but Steadily Build Wealth.&rdquo;</p>
<p>Many believe that successful people are infallible—never failing, never experiencing losses.  Many also think they must be omniscient and possess sufficient knowledge before they can start investing and managing their finances.  Our most common flaw is our unwillingness to try repeatedly and to persevere. Building wealth through personal finance is not difficult! The reason most people don&rsquo;t achieve their goals is their inability to persevere and their lack of patience.</p>
<p>Persistence is essential for success in personal finance. Suppose you embark on a wealth-building plan and encounter setbacks along the way. Don&rsquo;t be discouraged. Some people regularly save and invest annually.  When prices rise, they are satisfied and continue their plan. But when prices fall, they panic and abandon their investment strategy.  They fail to understand that price fluctuations are inherent in the investment market, and investment results will inevitably fluctuate.</p>
<p>If, midway through your financial plan, you succumb to the temptation to spend your investment capital or give up due to repeated setbacks, all your previous efforts will be wasted.  <strong>Success in personal finance depends on endurance and resolve:  endurance to delay gratification and resist immediate consumption temptations; and resolve to withstand significant wealth fluctuations over long periods without losing your composure.  As long as you have perseverance and resolve, trust in compound interest, and believe in the &ldquo;wealth creation formula,&rdquo; the ultimate wealth will undoubtedly be yours.</strong></p>
<p>&ldquo;No dreams, no wealth.&rdquo;  Those who build wealth through personal finance must be driven by desire and ambition.  They also need sufficient courage, knowledge, patience, and perseverance.  A lack of courage, flawed methods, impatience, or giving up halfway will not work. Whether you can achieve wealth and financial independence in the future depends entirely on your actions and efforts today.</p>
<p><strong>Unlock Your Hidden Wealth Potential</strong></p>
<p>Believe it or not, the price of living a wealthy and successful life is no greater than the price of living a poor and miserable one. Achieving this depends entirely on wisdom, belief, and action. After reading this book, readers should understand that everyone can achieve wealth through personal finance. The reason most people are not wealthy is not due to low income, but rather a lack of understanding of how to create wealth through investment and financial management. The primary purpose of this book is to help everyone unlock their hidden wealth potential.</p>
<p>If, after reading this book, you still cannot effectively apply these investment principles to manage your money and improve your financial situation, then this book is a complete failure.  Financial education is not merely about imparting knowledge; its significance lies in genuinely changing the reader&rsquo;s financial behavior.</p>
<p>This is a book of action, not a textbook for enhancing investment knowledge or a &ldquo;decorative book&rdquo; for your bookshelf.  This book aims to inspire readers to change their mindset and behavior. Its success depends on readers taking action based on the core principles presented, breaking free from mediocrity, and embarking on the path to wealth. Therefore, at the end of most chapters, key points are summarized for readers to reflect upon and apply.</p>
<p>Investment and financial management can not only lead to wealth but also bring joy to investors. Everyone should learn how to manage their finances and reap the substantial rewards.  I believe most readers already possess the basic requirements for building wealth: a small amount of capital, sufficient time, and the investment knowledge gained from this book.  The world of personal finance, full of changes and opportunities, awaits you.  It is filled with treasures and pitfalls. Don&rsquo;t hesitate, and don&rsquo;t leave empty-handed.</p>
<p>The principles of building wealth through investment and financial management are neither profound nor mysterious. They are absolutely achievable for everyone, and many have indeed easily become wealthy through these methods.  As we&rsquo;ve mentioned before, &ldquo;If you&rsquo;re willing to learn, managing your finances is as simple as walking.&rdquo;</p>
<p>Among the financial principles presented in this book, you&rsquo;ll find many that contradict deeply ingrained investment concepts and financial habits, and some even go against human nature.  Therefore, to realize the ideal of wealth creation through investment and financial management, the first step is to break free from some &ldquo;deep-rooted and misguided&rdquo; investment concepts, common knowledge, and habits.  Almost none of these concepts and principles are easy to achieve. Therefore, I advise readers to not only read each chapter carefully but also to review, reflect, establish strict rules, and ultimately change their behavior.</p>
<p><strong>Wealth Is a Means to a Better Life</strong></p>
<p>Finally, this book must emphasize that <strong>wealth is not the purpose of life, but a means to create a better life.</strong>  The ultimate goal of investment and financial management is not just to become rich, but to use wealth to realize your life&rsquo;s aspirations.  Therefore, <strong>a fulfilling and balanced life is the starting point for personal finance.</strong></p>
<p>Everyone should actively and optimistically plan and execute their lifelong financial journey.  Based on the principles we&rsquo;ve presented, everyone can achieve substantial wealth through personal finance without sacrificing time, energy, work, or life.  However, it&rsquo;s crucial to remember that <strong>only those who balance career, life, health, family, and wealth can be considered truly successful in managing their finances.</strong>  Those who gain the world&rsquo;s riches but lose their health, family, and the meaning of life cannot be considered truly successful.  In today&rsquo;s society, many are lost in the pursuit of wealth, sacrificing more valuable things in life.  Therefore, this principle of balancing personal finance and life is particularly important and deserves careful consideration.</p>
<p>Although this book repeatedly emphasizes that success in personal finance depends on mindset, time, and action, not luck, I still congratulate you, the reader, on being fortunate enough to encounter this book. By adhering to the investment principles within, you are sure to become a multi-millionaire in the decades to come!</p>
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Personal Investment Bible: The Ultimate Guide to Wealth Management</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1731056005973/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1731056005973/</guid><description>This article explores the ultimate goal of wealth management – enhancing the quality of life, rather than simply pursuing money. Using the parable of a miser, it emphasizes that the true meaning of wealth lies in how it&amp;#39;s used to live the life you desire. It examines the unique perspectives on money held by prominent figures like Li Ka-shing, Tsai Wan-lin, and Wang Yung-ching, highlighting how many become slaves to money, unable to utilize it for happiness. Finally, it introduces the three keys to wealth management – earning, managing, and utilizing money – emphasizing the importance of setting financial goals and using wealth wisely.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[

<h2 class="relative group">The Ultimate Guide to Wealth Management: Earning Money Requires a Goal 
    <div id="the-ultimate-guide-to-wealth-management-earning-money-requires-a-goal" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#the-ultimate-guide-to-wealth-management-earning-money-requires-a-goal" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>Money is merely a means; improving the quality of life is the ultimate goal.
Success is getting what you want, then enjoying what you have.</p></blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">Don&rsquo;t Be a Miser 
    <div id="dont-be-a-miser" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#dont-be-a-miser" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>A miser sold all his possessions, deposited the money in a bank, and took great satisfaction in calculating his daily interest earnings. His unscrupulous son, noticing his father&rsquo;s secretive behavior, discovered the large bank deposit. He stole the passbook and seal, withdrew all the money, and replaced the original with a forgery.  The miser, unaware of the deception, continued to calculate his imaginary wealth and interest.</p>
<p><strong>Not Spending Money Is Like Having No Money</strong></p>
<p>Months later, a sudden urge led the miser to the bank, where he discovered his account was empty. Devastated, he returned home, where his son consoled him: &ldquo;Don&rsquo;t be so upset. Just pretend the passbook is real. It serves the same purpose. You can still calculate your wealth daily. Money sitting unused in a bank is the same as having no money.&rdquo; This parable satirizes the miser to emphasize the true meaning of wealth.  Hoarding money without utilizing it is no different from having none.  Wealth, in any form, has no inherent meaning. Its value comes from what we ascribe to it and how we use it to live the life we want.</p>
<p>&ldquo;My philosophy is to live a simple life, be humble, and what significance does money hold for me?&rdquo;  Li Ka-shing, despite his immense wealth, focuses on making more money and training his successors – his two sons, Victor and Richard.</p>
<p>Wealthy Taiwanese tycoons seem to follow a similar pattern, leaving all their wealth to the next generation, even surpassing Li Ka-shing in their simple lifestyles. Tsai Wan-lin, once Taiwan&rsquo;s richest man, drove a Yulon car and ate nutritionally balanced but bland meals prepared by doctors. Even in his 70s, he went to work every day, saying, &ldquo;The thought of paying NT$20 million in salaries every day compels me to come to the office.&rdquo;</p>
<p>Taiwan has many such &ldquo;miserly&rdquo; tycoons. Wang Yung-ching, the founder of Formosa Plastics Group, was known for his frugality, even combining leftover soap scraps. He said, &ldquo;Food needs only to be nutritious, not necessarily luxurious. Simple meals are good.  Constant luxury makes one forget what happiness is.&rdquo;</p>
<p>&ldquo;I can live like an emperor or a commoner,&rdquo; said Huang Shih-hui, chairman of the Chinfon Group and a consistent top taxpayer in Taiwan. &ldquo;Even if I lost a third, or even half of my wealth, I could still live well.&rdquo; Ranked Taiwan&rsquo;s sixth richest man by Fortune magazine, Huang ate NT$50 lunches and drove an ordinary car. He said, &ldquo;How much can I wear? How much can I eat? Excessive desire will kill you!&rdquo; For these wealthy individuals, the meaning of earning so much lies in the sense of accomplishment, not enjoyment.</p>
<p><strong>Be the Master of Your Money</strong></p>
<p><em>If you don&rsquo;t master your money, your money will master you.</em></p>
<p>If asked, &ldquo;What&rsquo;s the next step after earning money?&rdquo; most people would instinctively answer, &ldquo;Spending it!&rdquo;  They&rsquo;re wrong. Those who answer this way usually haven&rsquo;t earned much. Most self-made millionaires continue to earn after becoming wealthy.</p>
<p>Some might say, &ldquo;It&rsquo;s foolish to have money and not spend it!&rdquo;  True, but such misers are not uncommon. Studies show that at least 90% of people continue to accumulate wealth, becoming slaves to money.</p>
<p>By now, you should realize that achieving financial wealth is relatively easy.  Avoid keeping all your money in the bank, invest most of it in stocks or real estate, and be patient.  However, teaching you to become a billionaire only to become a miserly hoarder is not my intention.  Therefore, it&rsquo;s crucial to discuss the meaning of wealth and the reasons for pursuing it.</p>
<p>Undeniably, with today&rsquo;s opportunities and living standards, hard work can ensure a comfortable life.  This book demonstrates that with proper financial management, wealth is attainable. However, without prior reflection on the meaning of wealth, you may become complacent, give up, or, even worse, become wealthy but not know how to use your money.  This benefits no one.  Before embarking on the path to riches, ask yourself what wealth means to you, then determine the steps to achieve it.</p>
<p><em>1. Don&rsquo;t be a miser.  Learn to spend wisely after earning.</em>
<em>2. Before pursuing wealth, understand your values regarding it.</em></p>
<blockquote>
<p>Money, a double-edged sword, has corrupted countless souls throughout history.
Poverty, a solitary grave, has buried countless heroes and talents.</p></blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">Why Earn So Much? 
    <div id="why-earn-so-much" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#why-earn-so-much" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>Everyone desires wealth.  Isn&rsquo;t that why you bought and are reading this book? Yet, not everyone prioritizes wealth. We often hear sentiments like: &ldquo;You can&rsquo;t take it with you,&rdquo; &ldquo;Wealth is fleeting,&rdquo; or &ldquo;One can only eat three meals a day, wear one outfit, and one pair of shoes. Why earn so much?&rdquo;</p>
<p>If you say, &ldquo;Why bother with financial management if you don&rsquo;t want wealth?&rdquo; I have nothing more to say.  This book is explicitly for those seeking financial independence and wealth.</p>
<p>The desire for wealth is a personal choice, determined by one&rsquo;s values and perspective on money. Some see it as a tool, content with enough to meet their needs; others view it as the root of all evil, associating the pursuit of wealth with something ignoble.  Undeniably, the single-minded pursuit of money is wrong. Life offers many other valuable pursuits: health, knowledge, family, love, friendship – all precious.</p>
<p>Money isn&rsquo;t everything. We often hear, &ldquo;If money can solve it, it&rsquo;s a simple problem.&rdquo;  While not the most important thing in life, its importance is undeniable. As the saying goes, &ldquo;Money isn&rsquo;t everything, but without it, you can do nothing.&rdquo;  A good life requires money, as does education, a higher quality of life, improving family life, and even philanthropy. The New England Journal of Medicine points out that the wealthy live longer, healthier lives than the poor.</p>
<p>Many aspire to a happy life and giving back to society.  Both require money. Thus, money is a necessary means to achieve life goals. You can disdain money, but you can&rsquo;t deny its utility in today&rsquo;s society.</p>
<p>One&rsquo;s status and worth are often judged by wealth.  It&rsquo;s unfair, but true.  Despite the absence of social classes, money divides people into &ldquo;rich&rdquo; and &ldquo;poor.&rdquo; Greater wealth translates to greater ability to acquire desired possessions, status, and lifestyles.</p>
<p>Money undoubtedly buys the best healthcare, food, clothing, and housing. It provides security and freedom from fear, improving the quality of life and making it more vibrant.  The poor have limited options, while the rich enjoy a wider range of experiences.</p>
<p><strong>Money Can Ruin the Next Generation</strong></p>
<p>The easiest way to ruin your children? Leave them a fortune.  The saying &ldquo;Wealth doesn&rsquo;t last three generations&rdquo; reflects this truth.</p>
<p>Many educators and I share a common experience: the most challenging students lack motivation, often stemming from wealthy backgrounds.  These children, wanting for nothing, don&rsquo;t understand the need for hard work or ambition.</p>
<p>I recall a case during my tenure as director of the Graduate Institute of Business Administration at Tunghai University. A student, admitted after fierce competition, struggled academically and seemed listless. During counseling, I inquired about learning difficulties.</p>
<p>His response: &ldquo;My engineering background makes these courses easy. I don&rsquo;t understand why I need to learn this.&rdquo; I explained that business school teaches profit maximization. He replied, &ldquo;What&rsquo;s the point of making money?&rdquo; Shocked, I learned that his family&rsquo;s wealth had shielded him from financial concerns, leaving him without a drive to earn. I then emphasized the value of business management for future employment. His response: &ldquo;My father owns a factory waiting for me, but I don&rsquo;t want it.&rdquo;  He didn&rsquo;t appreciate what he already had.  I asked about his apparent preoccupation.  Reluctantly, he confessed his biggest worry: &ldquo;Why can humans kill animals, but not the other way around?&rdquo; I truly didn&rsquo;t understand the mindset of the wealthy&rsquo;s offspring.  It reminded me of the Taiwanese saying: &ldquo;Some complain of hunger after a full meal.&rdquo;</p>
<p>We should be grateful if our parents didn&rsquo;t leave us a fortune that robbed us of our drive.  This book shows how financial management can lead to wealth.  However, I caution against leaving excessive wealth to your children.</p>
<p>Ideally, set a financial goal and stop actively pursuing wealth after reaching it.  Avoid becoming a lifelong slave to money, and don&rsquo;t ruin your children&rsquo;s future.</p>
<p><strong>Warren Buffett&rsquo;s Perspective on Money</strong></p>
<p>Billionaire Warren Buffett has arranged his estate to be managed by a trust controlled by wise individuals with absolute authority and no restrictions.  He avoids preconditions, hoping to prevent it from becoming a bureaucratic, traditional fund. He said, &ldquo;If they create a lofty palace and become conservative and closed-minded, my ghost will not let them rest.&rdquo;</p>
<p>Buffett left his children $3 million each, and they now live happily as farmers. I admire his perspective: &ldquo;True happiness isn&rsquo;t living in a palace but adding a room to your house each year, because happiness is a process, not a result.&rdquo;</p>
<p>Buffett&rsquo;s estate planning is unique.  As America&rsquo;s richest man, his financial decisions draw attention. Some criticize his perceived stinginess towards philanthropy. He countered, &ldquo;When I die, societal problems will remain.  Society will benefit more from my wealth then than now.&rdquo; He remains steadfast despite public opinion.</p>
<p>Buffett essentially ensures that his wealth, acquired from society, returns to it upon his death – a remarkably detached approach compared to many Eastern tycoons.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Acquiring wealth is difficult.
Maintaining wealth is harder.
Utilizing wealth is the hardest.</p></blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">The Three Keys to Wealth Management: Earning, Managing, and Utilizing 
    <div id="the-three-keys-to-wealth-management-earning-managing-and-utilizing" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#the-three-keys-to-wealth-management-earning-managing-and-utilizing" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>Wealth management comprises three levels: earning, managing, and utilizing money. Technically, earning is the hardest, followed by managing, then utilizing. However, my experience as a financial advisor suggests that teaching people how to earn is difficult, teaching them to manage is harder, and teaching them to utilize is the hardest.</p>
<p><strong>Few Spend Wisely</strong></p>
<p>Some challenge this: &ldquo;Spending is easy! Give me your money, and I&rsquo;ll spend it all quickly.&rdquo;  True, spending other people&rsquo;s money is easy; spending your life&rsquo;s earnings is not. Many wealthy individuals struggle to use their money meaningfully.</p>
<p>Many lifelong savers find it incredibly difficult to change their habits and spend appropriately, even after becoming wealthy.  When asked, &ldquo;What are you saving for?&rdquo; they often reply, &ldquo;I don&rsquo;t know.&rdquo;</p>
<p>Many people tirelessly pursue wealth without clarifying their goals.  They blindly follow the mantra &ldquo;Money is important.&rdquo;  No one takes their wealth to the grave. <strong>Many become so consumed with earning that they forget their initial purpose, mistaking the means for the end.  They fail to use their wealth for greater happiness, joy, or societal good, becoming slaves to money.  Their wealth becomes meaningless, bringing more harm than benefit.</strong></p>
<p><em>1. Money is a means to achieve life goals. Don&rsquo;t mistake the means for the end and blindly chase money.</em>
<em>2.  Learn to utilize your money to become a truly happy and wealthy individual.</em>
<em>3. Save when young, manage wisely in middle age, and spend thoughtfully in old age.</em></p>
<p><strong>The Wealth Journey of Chen Ding-chuan, Chairman of Everlight Chemical</strong></p>
<p>&ldquo;Before seeking wealth, cultivate the ability to manage money and control yourself.&rdquo; Chen Ding-chuan believes that those who don&rsquo;t understand how to use money become its slaves, losing themselves in the pursuit.  Those who master the art of utilizing money become its masters, prioritizing self-growth and attracting wealth naturally.</p>
<p>Chen founded Everlight Chemical at 40, transforming it from a producer of basic dyes to a supplier of advanced specialty chemicals and pharmaceutical ingredients.  By 1995, the company&rsquo;s revenue reached over NT$2.4 billion.  A devout Christian and former director of the International Foundation Taiwan, Chen holds a unique perspective on money. He believes earning is easy, but spending wisely is not. He&rsquo;s witnessed countless wealthy individuals squander their fortunes and lose themselves, while others hoard their wealth, living like paupers and inflicting misery on those around them. He believes most people don&rsquo;t understand how to use money.</p>
<p>Deeply religious, Chen dedicates himself to God and spreading the Gospel.  Despite his success, he&rsquo;s traveled a difficult path.  He left school after elementary to work, studying diligently at night school for seven years, never missing a class except due to illness.  While others took on extra jobs, he prioritized education, graduating with a degree in international trade at 35. Who would have predicted his future as a billionaire?</p>
<p><strong>Who Paid the Highest Estate Tax?</strong></p>
<p>&ldquo;Who paid the highest estate tax in Taiwan&rsquo;s history?&rdquo;  I often ask this during lectures.  Few know the correct answer: Chen De-shen.</p>
<p>&ldquo;Chen De-shen? Who is he?&rdquo;  Audiences always murmur after the reveal.  It&rsquo;s a shame that someone who paid nearly NT$2 billion in estate tax remains relatively unknown.  How?  The only explanation is that Chen mastered earning and managing money, but not utilizing it.</p>
<p>Chen died in 1991, leaving an estate valued at NT$10 billion, resulting in a record NT$1.9 billion estate tax bill.  He lived a remarkably frugal life, using public transportation, sleeping on a cot, and living in his office to avoid buying a house. His sister recounted how he even refused to replace worn-out underwear.</p>
<p>Unmarried and childless, his vast fortune went to his siblings, sparking a highly publicized inheritance dispute. He exemplifies the saying, &ldquo;Those enslaved by wealth are pitiable even in their riches.&rdquo;</p>
<p>I often wonder, had he allocated a portion of his wealth to establish a &ldquo;De-shen College&rdquo; or &ldquo;De-shen Hospital,&rdquo; or donated even 1% (NT$100 million) to Tunghai University&rsquo;s business school, his name would be remembered for generations.  Such philanthropy would have benefited society and avoided family conflict.</p>
<p>Stanford University, a prestigious institution nestled between San Francisco and Silicon Valley, owes its existence to a generous donation from the Stanford family a century ago.  What a profound and lasting impact!  We marvel at the wisdom and foresight behind such giving.</p>
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>the Personal Investment Bible: Appendix</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1731056005975/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1731056005975/</guid><description>This appendix explores the power of compound interest and how to leverage it for financial success. It explains the concept of compounding, illustrating through examples and charts how it can lead to significant wealth growth over time. A formula for calculating future wealth is provided to help readers plan their financial goals, emphasizing the crucial roles of time and rate of return in compound interest investing.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[

<h2 class="relative group">Appendix 1: Understanding Compound Interest 
    <div id="appendix-1-understanding-compound-interest" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#appendix-1-understanding-compound-interest" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>Accumulating wealth isn&rsquo;t about cutting expenses,<br>
but about the compounding power of money making money.</p></blockquote>
<p>Albert Einstein, considered one of history&rsquo;s greatest scientists, was once asked, &ldquo;What is the most powerful force in the world?&rdquo; His answer wasn&rsquo;t the force of colliding planets or the power of a nuclear explosion, but &ldquo;compound interest.&rdquo;</p>
<p>As the previous examples demonstrate, the factor that allows a yearly saving of 14,000 yuan to grow to over 100 million yuan in 40 years is &ldquo;compound interest.&rdquo; Since compound interest is the primary driver of accelerated wealth growth, understanding it is crucial for achieving financial success.</p>
<p>Imagine two job offers: one with a monthly salary of 100,000 yuan, and another starting at 1 yuan in the first month, doubling each subsequent month.  Assuming both jobs last two years (24 months), which would you choose?</p>
<p>At first glance, the first offer seems better.  100,000 yuan monthly yields 2.4 million yuan over 24 months. However, anyone understanding compound interest would choose the second job, which yields over 16.77 million yuan after 24 months! This is the effect of compounding. While this is an extreme example, such high growth rates are unlikely in reality.  Nevertheless, it clearly demonstrates the power of compound interest.</p>
<p>Most people have a basic understanding of compound interest.  Depositing money in a bank generates interest over time, a common understanding in modern society. Since Einstein considered compound interest the most powerful force, and it can help us become millionaires with modest investments, a deeper understanding of its workings is essential, especially for those interested in financial management.</p>
<p>Simply put, compound interest is &ldquo;interest on interest.&rdquo; We know bank deposits earn interest, calculated using compound interest. For instance, with a 10% interest rate, a 1,000 yuan deposit earns 100 yuan in interest in the first year, resulting in 1,100 yuan.  If left in the bank, the second year&rsquo;s interest is 110 yuan (on 1,100 yuan), totaling 1,210 yuan. The third year yields 121 yuan in interest, reaching 1,331 yuan.</p>
<p>Notice the increasing interest earned each year.  This is because the first year&rsquo;s interest earns interest in the second year, and so on, leading to an ever-increasing return.  This &ldquo;interest on interest&rdquo; phenomenon is compound interest.</p>
<p>The table below shows that after the 26th year, the annual interest earned surpasses the principal, and by the 40th year, the interest of 4,114 yuan is more than four times the initial 1,000 yuan principal.</p>
<p><em>Future Value of 1,000 Yuan at 10% Interest Rate (Compounded Annually)</em></p>
<table>
  <thead>
      <tr>
          <th>Year</th>
          <th>Beginning Value</th>
          <th>Ending Value</th>
          <th>Interest</th>
      </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
      <tr>
          <td>1</td>
          <td>1000</td>
          <td>1100</td>
          <td>100</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>2</td>
          <td>1100</td>
          <td>1210</td>
          <td>110</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>3</td>
          <td>1210</td>
          <td>1331</td>
          <td>121</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>&hellip;</td>
          <td>&hellip;</td>
          <td>&hellip;</td>
          <td>&hellip;</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>26</td>
          <td>10835</td>
          <td>11918</td>
          <td>1083</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>&hellip;</td>
          <td>&hellip;</td>
          <td>&hellip;</td>
          <td>&hellip;</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>39</td>
          <td>37404</td>
          <td>41145</td>
          <td>3740</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>40</td>
          <td>41145</td>
          <td>45259</td>
          <td>4114</td>
      </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>
<p>Compound interest&rsquo;s effect varies with different interest rates and durations.  These variations are presented in compound interest tables (refer to this appendix).  These tables, composed of interest rates, years, and future value factors (the growth multiplier calculated by the formula), might seem daunting with their numerous figures. However, understanding them is invaluable for investment and financial management.  Renowned American financial advisor Venita VanCaspel calls the compound interest table the &ldquo;eighth wonder of the world.&rdquo; If you don&rsquo;t have the opportunity to travel the world, studying this table can be just as rewarding.  Understanding the characteristics of compound interest is key to leveraging its power for wealth creation.</p>
<p>The compound interest table reveals that the values increase with time and interest rate.  However, this isn&rsquo;t the whole story.  Observing compound interest graphs derived from these tables reveals further insights. Figure 1-1 assumes a yearly deposit of 1 yuan at different interest rates, plotting asset growth over 10 years. Figure 1-2 uses the same assumptions but extends the time horizon to 40 years.</p>
<p>
  <figure>
    <img class="my-0 rounded-md" loading="lazy" src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jomonylw/jomonylw.github.io/refs/heads/main/content/posts/1731056005975/img-01-en.jpg" alt="image.png" />
    
  </figure>
</p>
<p>Figure 1-1: Future Value Growth of 1 Yuan Annuity at Different Interest Rates over 10 Years</p>
<p>
  <figure>
    <img class="my-0 rounded-md" loading="lazy" src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jomonylw/jomonylw.github.io/refs/heads/main/content/posts/1731056005975/img-02-en.jpg" alt="image.png" />
    
  </figure>
</p>
<p>Figure 1-2: Future Value Growth of 1 Yuan Annuity at Different Interest Rates over 40 Years</p>
<p>These graphs illustrate the growth of 1 yuan over time at various interest rates and durations. Comparing them reveals two key characteristics of compound interest:</p>
<ul>
<li>
<ol>
<li>As the duration (time) increases, the future value rises continuously, and the rate of increase accelerates. This is known as exponential growth.  Given sufficient time, the growth becomes dramatic, with the curve eventually approaching a straight upward line.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol start="2">
<li>Different interest rates result in significantly different growth curves.  Over decades, the disparity between high and low interest rate curves becomes immense.</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ul>
<p>In summary, the secret to accumulating significant wealth from small beginnings lies in leveraging the &ldquo;money making money&rdquo; power of compound interest.  Compounding has two key features: its effect is more pronounced over longer periods, and higher returns amplify its impact. Applying these principles to investing leads to two conclusions:</p>
<ul>
<li>
<ol>
<li>Invest in high-return assets like stocks and real estate. Higher returns maximize the effect of compounding, while low returns yield minimal benefits.  To fully harness the power of compound interest, capital must be invested in high-return assets.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol start="2">
<li>Hold investments long-term.  The longer the investment horizon, the more significant the compounding effect.  Short-term investments don&rsquo;t allow sufficient time for compounding to work its magic.  Therefore, long-term holdings in high-return assets are crucial for maximizing the benefits of compound interest.</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">Appendix 2: Blueprint for Financial Success 
    <div id="appendix-2-blueprint-for-financial-success" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#appendix-2-blueprint-for-financial-success" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>Everyone&rsquo;s age, personality, and applicable tax rates differ.  Therefore, each individual needs a tailored approach to wealth accumulation. I can&rsquo;t provide personalized financial planning advice based on your specific circumstances, nor can I encompass everyone&rsquo;s financial situation and plans with a few generic examples.</p>
<p>To help you design your own &ldquo;Blueprint for Financial Success,&rdquo; I&rsquo;ve combined the future value and annuity future value formulas from finance to create a universal &ldquo;Investment Wealth Formula.&rdquo;  This formula empowers readers to plan their lifelong financial strategies based on their unique circumstances and objectives.</p>
<p><math xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" display="block"><mtable displaystyle="true" columnalign="right center left" columnspacing="0 thickmathspace" rowspacing="3pt"><mtr><mtd><mtext>Future Wealth</mtext></mtd><mtd><mi></mi><mo>=</mo></mtd><mtd><mtext>Current Wealth</mtext><mo>×</mo><msup><mrow><mo stretchy="false">(</mo><mn>1</mn><mo>+</mo><mi>R</mi><mo stretchy="false">)</mo></mrow><mi>n</mi></msup><mo>+</mo><mtext>Annual Savings</mtext><mo>×</mo><mfrac><mrow><msup><mrow><mo stretchy="false">(</mo><mn>1</mn><mo>+</mo><mi>R</mi><mo stretchy="false">)</mo></mrow><mi>n</mi></msup><mo>−</mo><mn>1</mn></mrow><mi>R</mi></mfrac></mtd></mtr><mtr><mtd></mtd><mtd><mi></mi><mo>=</mo></mtd><mtd><mtext>Current Wealth</mtext><mo>×</mo><mtext>Future Value Factor</mtext><mo>+</mo><mtext>Annual Savings</mtext><mo>×</mo><mtext>Annuity Future Value Factor</mtext></mtd></mtr><mtr><mtd><mtext>Where:</mtext></mtd></mtr><mtr><mtd><mi>n</mi></mtd><mtd><mo>:</mo></mtd><mtd><mtext>Number of years</mtext></mtd></mtr><mtr><mtd><mi>R</mi></mtd><mtd><mo>:</mo></mtd><mtd><mtext>Average annual investment rate of return</mtext></mtd></mtr></mtable></math></p>
<p>The values for the complex calculations in the formula above (Future Value Factor and Annuity Future Value Factor) can be found in Appendix 1 of this book.</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Future Value Factor:</strong> The future value of 1 yuan today, after N years, at an interest rate (or rate of return) of R%.</li>
<li><strong>Annuity Future Value Factor:</strong> The future value of an annuity of 1 yuan deposited at the end of each year, after N years, at an interest rate (or rate of return) of R%.</li>
</ul>
<p>Using this formula, you can project your future wealth by inputting your current assets, average annual savings for investment, planned investment period, and expected annual rate of return. You can calculate the result or look it up in a table.</p>
<p>This formula simplifies the real-world situation, as investment returns are unlikely to remain constant each year, and annual savings might fluctuate.  However, using the &ldquo;average&rdquo; annual rate of return and &ldquo;average&rdquo; annual investment amount generally provides a reasonable approximation of future wealth.</p>
<p>The purpose of the &ldquo;Investment Wealth Formula&rdquo; isn&rsquo;t to predict future wealth precisely but to illustrate how investment builds wealth and how financial management leads to prosperity. It aims to bolster your confidence in financial planning, enabling you to focus on key principles, maintain perseverance, and steadily progress towards your financial goals throughout market fluctuations.</p>
<p>This isn&rsquo;t a foolproof formula for riches. Following this method may lead to becoming a millionaire, but success isn&rsquo;t guaranteed.  However, inaction guarantees zero chance of success. The most valuable aspect of this wealth-building concept is the message: &ldquo;Investment and financial management can lead to wealth.&rdquo; This knowledge fosters optimism and hope. Regardless of your current wealth, age, annual savings, or investment skills, with dedication, determination, and a willingness to learn, you can leverage investing to grow your wealth.</p>
<p>After understanding this formula, follow these steps for financial planning:</p>
<p><strong>I. Data Collection:</strong></p>
<ol>
<li>What is your current total asset value? (Include bank deposits, stocks, real estate, etc.)</li>
<li>How much do you anticipate saving annually for investment?</li>
<li>What is your expected average annual investment rate of return?</li>
<li>How many years do you plan to invest before reaching your financial goal?</li>
<li>What is your future wealth target?</li>
</ol>
<p><strong>II. Calculation and Analysis:</strong></p>
<ol>
<li>Use the five data points above with the &ldquo;Investment Wealth Formula&rdquo; to assess the feasibility of your wealth plan. If it&rsquo;s not feasible, how will you adjust? Will you increase savings? Improve investment skills to boost returns? Lower your wealth target? Or extend your time horizon? Adjust the variables and recalculate until you find a realistic and achievable plan.</li>
<li>Calculate your projected accumulated wealth based on your current assets, investment period, annual savings, and expected rate of return.</li>
<li>You can also use any four of the five variables (current wealth, target year, annual savings, rate of return, wealth target) to calculate the remaining variable. (Calculating the target year or rate of return using the other four variables requires a financial calculator or trial and error to find an approximate value.)</li>
</ol>
<p>While the &ldquo;Investment Wealth Formula&rdquo; involves a seemingly complex mathematical formula, its primary purpose is to explain the principles of wealth building, not to complicate financial management or confuse readers. If you don&rsquo;t have a calculator or prefer not to delve into the formula&rsquo;s calculations, feel free to disregard it.</p>
<p>Using the &ldquo;Investment Wealth Formula&rdquo; can help you plan your future finances and boost your confidence in financial management. However, it doesn&rsquo;t guarantee investment success.  Pre-planning is just the beginning; the key lies in mastering investment principles and consistent action. When starting your financial journey, clarify your financial situation, set realistic wealth goals, then use the &ldquo;Investment Wealth Formula&rdquo; to evaluate your investment strategy and timeline. Remember, the path to wealth is in your hands.</p>
<p><strong>Example:</strong>  Zhang San is 30 years old with 200,000 yuan in savings. After reading this book, he resolves to become a millionaire (meaning having 100 million yuan).  He plans to invest 100,000 yuan annually in stocks and real estate with an expected 20% annual return, aiming to reach his goal by age 50.  Let&rsquo;s use the &ldquo;Investment Wealth Formula&rdquo; to assess the feasibility.</p>
<p><math xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" display="block"><mtable displaystyle="true" columnalign="right center left" columnspacing="0 thickmathspace" rowspacing="3pt"><mtr><mtd><mtext>Future Wealth</mtext></mtd><mtd><mi></mi><mo>=</mo></mtd><mtd><mn>200,000</mn><mo>×</mo><msup><mrow><mo stretchy="false">(</mo><mn>1</mn><mo>+</mo><mn>20</mn><mi mathvariant="normal">%</mi><mo stretchy="false">)</mo></mrow><mrow><mn>20</mn></mrow></msup><mo>+</mo><mn>100,000</mn><mo>×</mo><mfrac><mrow><msup><mrow><mo stretchy="false">(</mo><mn>1</mn><mo>+</mo><mn>20</mn><mi mathvariant="normal">%</mi><mo stretchy="false">)</mo></mrow><mrow><mn>20</mn></mrow></msup><mo>−</mo><mn>1</mn></mrow><mrow><mn>20</mn><mi mathvariant="normal">%</mi></mrow></mfrac></mtd></mtr><mtr><mtd></mtd><mtd><mi></mi><mo>=</mo></mtd><mtd><mn>200,000</mn><mo>×</mo><mn>38.338</mn><mo>+</mo><mn>100,000</mn><mo>×</mo><mn>228.98</mn><mspace width="1em"></mspace><mtext>(Corrected Annuity Factor)</mtext></mtd></mtr><mtr><mtd></mtd><mtd><mi></mi><mo>=</mo></mtd><mtd><mn>30,435,600</mn><mspace width="1em"></mspace><mtext>(Corrected Calculation)</mtext></mtd></mtr></mtable></math></p>
<p>Based on the calculation, Zhang San&rsquo;s 200,000 yuan initial investment, along with 100,000 yuan annual investments over 20 years at a 20% average return, will yield approximately 26 million yuan, less than one-third of his 100 million yuan goal.  To become a millionaire, he can improve his return, increase his annual investment, or extend his time horizon.  A 20% return is already quite good and realistic, even for seasoned investors.  Increasing his returns further might be challenging.  Since he doesn&rsquo;t want to extend the timeline, he decides to increase his annual investment. Through frugality and a part-time job, he manages to save 200,000 yuan annually. Let&rsquo;s recalculate his future wealth after 20 years.</p>
<p><math xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" display="block"><mtable displaystyle="true" columnalign="right center left" columnspacing="0 thickmathspace" rowspacing="3pt"><mtr><mtd><mrow><mo>Future Wealth</mo></mrow></mtd><mtd><mi></mi><mo>=</mo></mtd><mtd><mn>200000</mn><mo>×</mo><msup><mrow><mo stretchy="false">(</mo><mn>1</mn><mo>+</mo><mn>20</mn><mi mathvariant="normal">%</mi><mo stretchy="false">)</mo></mrow><mrow><mn>20</mn></mrow></msup><mo>+</mo><mn>200000</mn><mo>×</mo><mfrac><msup><mrow><mo stretchy="false">(</mo><mn>1</mn><mo>+</mo><mn>20</mn><mi mathvariant="normal">%</mi><mo stretchy="false">)</mo></mrow><mrow><mn>20</mn></mrow></msup><mrow><mn>20</mn><mi mathvariant="normal">%</mi></mrow></mfrac><mo>−</mo><mn>1</mn></mtd></mtr><mtr><mtd></mtd><mtd><mi></mi><mo>=</mo></mtd><mtd><mn>200000</mn><mo>×</mo><mn>38.338</mn><mo>+</mo><mn>200000</mn><mo>×</mo><mn>186.96</mn></mtd></mtr><mtr><mtd></mtd><mtd><mi></mi><mo>=</mo></mtd><mtd><mn>45005600</mn></mtd></mtr></mtable></math></p>
<p>Even with doubled annual savings, his wealth after 20 years still falls short of half his goal.  With both his 20% return and 200,000 yuan annual investment maxed out, he has to extend his timeline. He decides to aim for 25 years.  Let&rsquo;s calculate his projected wealth then.</p>
<p><math xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" display="block"><mtable displaystyle="true" columnalign="right center left" columnspacing="0 thickmathspace" rowspacing="3pt"><mtr><mtd><mrow><mo>Future Wealth</mo></mrow></mtd><mtd><mi></mi><mo>=</mo></mtd><mtd><mn>200000</mn><mo>×</mo><msup><mrow><mo stretchy="false">(</mo><mn>1</mn><mo>+</mo><mn>20</mn><mi mathvariant="normal">%</mi><mo stretchy="false">)</mo></mrow><mrow><mn>25</mn></mrow></msup><mo>+</mo><mn>200000</mn><mo>×</mo><mfrac><msup><mrow><mo stretchy="false">(</mo><mn>1</mn><mo>+</mo><mn>20</mn><mi mathvariant="normal">%</mi><mo stretchy="false">)</mo></mrow><mrow><mn>25</mn></mrow></msup><mrow><mn>20</mn><mi mathvariant="normal">%</mi></mrow></mfrac><mo>−</mo><mn>1</mn></mtd></mtr><mtr><mtd></mtd><mtd><mi></mi><mo>=</mo></mtd><mtd><mn>200000</mn><mo>×</mo><mn>95.396</mn><mo>+</mo><mn>200000</mn><mo>×</mo><mn>471.98</mn></mtd></mtr><mtr><mtd></mtd><mtd><mi></mi><mo>=</mo></mtd><mtd><mn>113475200</mn></mtd></mtr></mtable></math></p>
<p>He finally achieves his goal of becoming a millionaire after 25 years.  Extending the timeline by just five years makes a significant difference. With a longer time horizon, his required annual investment could be even lower. This example validates the book&rsquo;s emphasis on &ldquo;youth being an asset in wealth building&rdquo; and &ldquo;the importance of long-term investing for realizing the power of compound interest.&rdquo;  Experiment with different variables to understand their impact.  <strong>You&rsquo;ll discover that the initial wealth and annual investment amount have a relatively small impact, while time and rate of return are the key drivers of wealth accumulation.</strong></p>
<p>Your circumstances might be better or worse than Zhang San&rsquo;s. Regardless, everyone has different starting points, but anyone can become a millionaire.  Calculate your own path to becoming a millionaire based on your current situation. Remember, with a modest initial investment, allocation to high-return assets like stocks and real estate, and long-term holding, becoming a millionaire is absolutely achievable.</p>
<p>Now, set your financial goal. Write down your target wealth, your desired timeline, and how you plan to use your wealth to achieve your broader life goals.</p>
<p><strong>Remember: &ldquo;Money is a means to an end, not the end itself.&rdquo;</strong></p>
<p>Accumulating more money isn&rsquo;t always better, and having more financial goals isn&rsquo;t necessarily advantageous.  Such an approach may prevent you from ever reaching your goals and trap you in a cycle of dissatisfaction and greed. You could become a slave to money and potentially harm future generations with excessive wealth, contributing nothing to yourself, your loved ones, or society.</p>
<p>Once you have a financial goal, use the &ldquo;Wealth Formula&rdquo; to calculate your path, including required annual savings and average rate of return. This will inform your investment strategy and timeline. More importantly, determine how you will utilize your wealth once you achieve your goal.  This concretizes your aspirations. You&rsquo;ll discover that by applying the principles in this book and remaining consistent, becoming a millionaire is within reach. A clear goal leads to a happier life, and a positive attitude contributes to success in all areas of life.</p>
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Personal Investment Bible - Investment Iron Law XIII</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1731056005972/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1731056005972/</guid><description>This article explores the key to financial success, emphasizing that taking action is more important than knowledge. Through several stories, it illustrates that even with financial knowledge, wealth growth cannot be achieved without action. The article encourages readers to overcome fear, dare to try, start with small investments, and learn from failures to ultimately achieve financial freedom.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[

<h2 class="relative group">Investment Iron Law XIII: Act Now 
    <div id="investment-iron-law-xiii-act-now" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#investment-iron-law-xiii-act-now" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>Those who require a fully justified reason for every action are never practitioners.</p></blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">Taking Action is Better Than Just Researching 
    <div id="taking-action-is-better-than-just-researching" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#taking-action-is-better-than-just-researching" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>A group of friends worked hard from sunrise to sunset, but their income remained meager.  They envied others who invested in stocks, real estate, or other ventures and became wealthy. They lamented, &ldquo;We toil all day, earning so little, while those investors make easy money.&rdquo;  Finally, they decided to seek guidance from an investment guru.</p>
<p><strong>Knowledge Without Action is Useless</strong></p>
<p>Touched by their sincerity, the guru agreed to teach them. The first lesson was &ldquo;Investment Principles,&rdquo; covering compound interest, returns, and risk management. The second lesson was &ldquo;Investment Practice,&rdquo; where the guru demonstrated how to invest in stocks, real estate, and other assets.  He then asked, &ldquo;Do you understand?&rdquo; They all replied, &ldquo;Yes!&rdquo; The guru said, &ldquo;Congratulations, you&rsquo;ve graduated!&rdquo;  The group rejoiced and returned to their jobs.</p>
<p>Decades later, at a reunion, they complained, &ldquo;Is there any way to make good money? Why do we always have to work so hard?&rdquo; They revisited the guru, who asked, &ldquo;Where did you put your earnings?&rdquo;  They answered, &ldquo;In bank savings accounts.&rdquo;</p>
<p>This story illustrates that education can change thinking but not necessarily behavior. <strong>Possessing knowledge and wisdom without action is no different from lacking them; you&rsquo;ll still rely on physical labor and skills for a living.</strong>  Wisdom without action is useless; one must be willing to act.</p>
<p>A survey of wealthy Americans revealed that one of their key traits is &ldquo;proactive action.&rdquo; In other words, financial success depends on what we do, not what we know.</p>
<p>Investment professors sometimes face student skepticism: &ldquo;If you know so much, why aren&rsquo;t you rich from investing?&rdquo;  A common response is, &ldquo;A teacher&rsquo;s duty is to impart knowledge, not necessarily to practice it. Just like the best coach isn&rsquo;t always the best athlete.&rdquo;</p>
<p>I often ponder this: Many teachers desire wealth.  Wealth accumulation and educating the next generation aren&rsquo;t mutually exclusive.  Why don&rsquo;t most investment professors, armed with financial knowledge, become wealthy?</p>
<p>Another common question is: &ldquo;Some uneducated, idle speculators get rich through investing without ever taking an investment course. How?&rdquo; The difference between professors and these speculators is simple: some professors know but don&rsquo;t act, while speculators act but don&rsquo;t necessarily know.  Financial knowledge alone doesn&rsquo;t guarantee wealth; action is key.</p>
<p><strong>Action is the Key to Investment Success</strong></p>
<p>Can investment skills be taught? No.  True skill comes from practice.  I often compare investing to ice skating, swimming, or cycling.  Can reading books on &ldquo;How to Ice Skate&rdquo; make you a skater? The best teacher is experience – falling hundreds of times, getting back up, and persevering.</p>
<p>Fear is the biggest obstacle to learning about investing.  A student once asked, &ldquo;What if I lose all my money before I learn how to invest?&rdquo;  I countered, &ldquo;Did you study fluid dynamics before learning to ride a bike, fearing you&rsquo;d crash before mastering it?&rdquo; Investors must understand that even extensive reading won&rsquo;t prevent losses; just like a perfect score in fluid dynamics doesn&rsquo;t guarantee perfect cycling.</p>
<p>Practice and experience are essential for practical skills.  Investing can&rsquo;t be taught. The key is to step away from books, enter the market, experiment, make mistakes, and learn from them.  Start small with a limited amount of money.</p>
<p>Achieving wealth through investing involves two stages: 1) acquiring correct investment knowledge, and 2) continuous practice and action. Both are essential.  Reading this book and understanding the principles is just the first step.</p>
<p><strong>Knowledge Becomes Power Through Action</strong></p>
<p>Knowledge is potential power.  Only through absorption, internalization, and action does it become real power.  &ldquo;Knowledge is power&rdquo; needs amending.</p>
<p>Correct understanding alone is insufficient.  Achieving wealth requires consistent action and practice. Otherwise, knowledge remains theoretical.  Investing is a skill honed through constant practice, like entrepreneur Wang Yung-ching, who continued massive investments in his 70s.</p>
<p><strong>We instinctively avoid risk; it&rsquo;s uncomfortable.  But investing for wealth requires calculated risks, learned through experience.</strong> Dear reader, action is paramount. Initial fear and anxiety are natural. The best way to overcome them is to act.</p>
<p><em>1. Those who put ideas and methods into action possess a competitive edge and grasp the opportunity for success.</em></p>
<p><em>2. In today&rsquo;s knowledge-rich world, the biggest obstacle to success is not knowing what to do, but doing what we know.</em></p>
<p><em>3. Many excel at thinking, analyzing, and identifying opportunities, but few act upon them.</em></p>
<p><strong>A Farmer Outperforms Market Veterans</strong></p>
<p>In early 1996, amid cross-strait tensions, Taiwan&rsquo;s stock market slumped. A farmer walked into a brokerage, placed a bag of cash (around 3-4 million NTD) on the counter, and said, &ldquo;I want to buy San Shang Yin.&rdquo;</p>
<p>The clerk, baffled, asked for his account number, which stock he wanted (San Shang Yin refers to three different bank stocks), and his desired price. He knew none of this, saying only, &ldquo;My friend said San Shang Yin is good. Here&rsquo;s the money.&rdquo;</p>
<p>The clerk explained the situation, helped him open an account, and bought 10 shares of each bank stock at around 90 NTD. Two months later, the prices rose to 160 NTD.</p>
<p>This farmer, lacking knowledge but daring to act, profited.  Meanwhile, market experts who thoroughly analyzed San Shang Yin missed out because they hesitated to act.</p>
<p>Does knowledge or action bring wealth? The farmer&rsquo;s lack of knowledge might have been his advantage, while overthinking paralyzed the experts. How much do analysis and knowledge truly contribute to wealth creation? It&rsquo;s worth pondering.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Active action makes dreams come true.  A strong desire for wealth fuels action.</p></blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">Your Future Wealth is in Your Hands 
    <div id="your-future-wealth-is-in-your-hands" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#your-future-wealth-is-in-your-hands" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>Many attendees at my seminars nod in agreement but fail to act. Remember, action, not knowledge, determines your future.  This book is useless unless you act upon it.</p>
<p><strong>Dreams Alone Won&rsquo;t Make You Rich</strong></p>
<p>Many dream of wealth, but few succeed.  It&rsquo;s not luck or intelligence, but the unity of thought and action. Success and wealth are earned through planning, action, and consistent effort.</p>
<p>For most, wealth is a fantasy. They think and talk, but don&rsquo;t act. Some lack the know-how, which is understandable.  Sadly, others know but don&rsquo;t act.  &ldquo;Knowing and not doing is not knowing.&rdquo;  Wealth won&rsquo;t come to those who only dream or accumulate knowledge without action.  People attribute wealth to luck, but does luck favor those dreaming at home or those actively seeking opportunities?</p>
<p>Reading this book won&rsquo;t magically make you rich.  Financial success depends on what we do.  We&rsquo;ve all seen seemingly unintelligent, not particularly hard-working, or frugal people who are wealthy.</p>
<p>The difference between self-made millionaires and us isn&rsquo;t intellect, effort, frugality, or knowledge, but where our money is placed.  They invest in high-return assets, while we often settle for low returns.  Most make excuses: not enough money, time, knowledge, or opportunity, or blaming age.  These are merely excuses preventing wealth accumulation.</p>
<p><em>1. The principles of financial management are simple; the difficulty lies in overcoming fear, greed, and laziness to do what we know we should.</em></p>
<p><em>2. Investing is an art and a science, but more art.  The best way to learn is by doing.</em></p>
<p><em>3. Without putting money to work, you&rsquo;ll rely on physical labor and skills your entire life.</em></p>
<p><strong>The First Step: Open a Brokerage Account and Buy Stocks</strong></p>
<p>An elderly British writer lamented, &ldquo;I&rsquo;ve seen many talented young people remain obscure, their potential unfulfilled because they lacked the courage to try.  Guidance and encouragement to take risks could have unleashed their talents and benefited society.&rdquo;</p>
<p>Over 13% of seniors in Taiwan rely on continued work or family support.  Many ended up this way because they didn&rsquo;t invest in risky assets like stocks or real estate in their youth.  Had they been guided to invest wisely, they could be enjoying retirement, reducing social inequality and promoting harmony.</p>
<p>Inspired by this writer, I now encourage my students to open brokerage accounts and buy stocks (or closed-end funds if unsure) on the first day of my investment courses.  I advise them to hold long-term, regardless of price fluctuations, aiming for practical experience over theoretical knowledge.</p>
<p><strong>Paying for Experience</strong></p>
<p>In 1983, while pursuing my PhD at UC Berkeley, a Wall Street analyst lectured at the university.  I asked him for book recommendations on stock investing.  He advised, &ldquo;The best way to learn is to invest. You&rsquo;ll learn more from one real investment than from several books.&rdquo; I followed his advice, lost money, and learned valuable lessons that shaped my future investment approach.</p>
<p>Financial management can&rsquo;t be learned solely in the classroom. Can attending ten lectures on swimming theory and reading ten books on &ldquo;Swimming Secrets&rdquo; make you a swimmer?  The first step is to get in the water.  Taiwan&rsquo;s education system overemphasizes book learning and neglects practical experience.</p>
<p>What&rsquo;s the first step in learning to invest?  Some suggest reading books, subscribing to financial magazines, or taking courses.  My advice: after reading this book, invest a small amount in stocks or mutual funds (especially index funds) if unsure.</p>
<p>Mutual funds offer diversification and professional management, generally performing close to market averages, minimizing potential losses and discouraging fear.</p>
<p>Outperforming mutual funds through individual stock picking is challenging.  Fund managers have experience, expertise, and research teams.  Consider mutual funds, especially index funds like CTBC Harmony Fund or China 100 Fund, in the initial stages.  &ldquo;Beating the index&rdquo; is every fund manager&rsquo;s dream, but most admit it&rsquo;s incredibly difficult.  If so, mirroring the market through index funds is a viable strategy.</p>
<p><strong>If you have savings and don&rsquo;t own property, consider buying a home as your first investment.</strong></p>
<blockquote>
<p>We learn more from failure than from success.  Success is built upon countless failures.</p></blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">Learning from Mistakes 
    <div id="learning-from-mistakes" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#learning-from-mistakes" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>Successful American investors share two traits: 1) they don&rsquo;t strive for perfection, and 2) they don&rsquo;t dwell on failures, focusing instead on future challenges.  High returns come with high risks.  Failure is inevitable and part of the learning process. Most successful investors have experienced multiple failures.</p>
<p><strong>No Success Without Failure</strong></p>
<p>Anyone claiming to have never lost money in investing is either lying or has never invested.  It&rsquo;s like a baseball player claiming to have never missed a swing.  Even the best hitters don&rsquo;t have a 100% batting average.</p>
<p>A top baseball player once attributed his success to &ldquo;missing more swings than others.&rdquo; To achieve a high batting average, he must have swung and missed more times than others.  Biographies of successful people often reveal that they&rsquo;ve experienced more failures than those less successful.  Failure is the mother of success, especially in investing.</p>
<p>Aspiring investors must withstand losses.  <strong>Those who haven&rsquo;t failed can&rsquo;t achieve greatness; those who haven&rsquo;t experienced losses can&rsquo;t expect to make a fortune.</strong>  Demanding a perfect track record leads to extreme conservatism and eliminates opportunities for success.</p>
<p><strong>The biggest failure is to never fail.</strong>  Avoiding mistakes eliminates chances for success. The best path to success is through failure and learning from it.  Never forget your losses; they are the keys to victory.  Successful investors analyze failures, learn from them, and improve their strategies.</p>
<p><strong>Reflect and Restart</strong></p>
<p>My failures have led to reflection, reassessment, and improved investment strategies.  Most failures bring unexpected benefits.  Treat failure as a necessary lesson, and your courage will grow.</p>
<p>Failure can&rsquo;t be learned secondhand.  You won&rsquo;t find books on &ldquo;How to Lose 10 Million in Investments.&rdquo;  People brag about successes, not failures.  Therefore, lessons from failure must come from personal experience.</p>
<p>Everyone makes mistakes in investing.  Even correct decisions can lead to losses.  Since losses and failures are inevitable, accepting them and learning from them is crucial.  Failure is not shameful or terrifying.  Face it, overcome it, and success will follow.</p>
<p><em>1. Take calculated risks for high rewards, be prepared for losses, and avoid undue self-blame.</em></p>
<p><em>2. Learn from every failure, identify flawed decision-making habits, and avoid repeating them.</em></p>
<p><em>3. Study valuable lessons from failures and discover opportunities for wealth creation.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Personal Investment Bible: Investment Iron Law XII</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1731056005971/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1731056005971/</guid><description>This article explores the advantages of real estate investment, explaining why real estate can achieve high returns, and analyzes the real estate investment strategies of several wealthy individuals, including Lee Shau Kee, Tsai Wan-lin, and Cheng Chou-ming. The article emphasizes the importance of location, puts forward the concept of prosperity comes from land ownership, and suggests readers consider leveraged real estate investment, but avoid blindly following the trend during periods of rapid price increases.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[

<h2 class="relative group">Investment Iron Law XII: Prosperity Comes From Land Ownership 
    <div id="investment-iron-law-xii-prosperity-comes-from-land-ownership" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#investment-iron-law-xii-prosperity-comes-from-land-ownership" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>Land possesses the characteristic of scarcity.</p></blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">Why Real Estate Offers High Returns 
    <div id="why-real-estate-offers-high-returns" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#why-real-estate-offers-high-returns" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>Real estate prices have a long-term upward trend.  Numerous research institutions in Taiwan have shown that the average annual return on real estate investment in Taiwan is around 22% to 25% or more, the highest among all investment tools. According to reports, real estate prices in Taipei&rsquo;s Songshan and Xinyi districts have increased by as much as nine times in 10 years, translating to an average annual return of about 23%.</p>
<p><strong>The Rise of Land Prices: There&rsquo;s a Reason</strong></p>
<p>In the long run, there are three main reasons why real estate prices rise and offer high returns:</p>
<p><strong>First, the supply of land is limited.</strong> Land is inherently scarce, and Taiwan, being an island, has limited land resources. With continuous development, the available land for construction is dwindling. Moreover, land cannot be imported, so the supply is decreasing rather than increasing, and this problem will become increasingly severe. Therefore, real estate prices are bound to increase year by year.</p>
<p><strong>Second, demand continues to grow.</strong> Real estate can be generally divided into commercial and residential uses.  Commercial real estate (such as shops and factories) can be considered a means of production.  When a company&rsquo;s profitability increases, it is willing to pay higher rent, which drives up the price of the property. As the company grows, its space requirements also increase annually.</p>
<p>For personal and family use, as the economy grows and incomes rise, the demand for living space and quality also increases. In the past, a family of seven, eight, or even more than ten people would be content to squeeze into a 70-100 square foot apartment. Now, with increased income, an average family of four needs a 130-165 square foot apartment or larger to be satisfied.</p>
<p>A survey released in May 1996 showed that the homeownership rate in Taiwan was as high as 80%, but most were mixed-use properties with generally poor living quality, especially in metropolitan areas where the proportion of privately owned parking spaces was low. Despite the shrinking family size and high housing prices, the average living space per household has increased. In 1995, the average living space per household was 109 square feet, an increase of 20 square feet compared to 1990.  As we move towards an information-based society, activities like working from home, online shopping, and banking from home will increase, further raising the demand for higher quality living spaces. Perhaps in 10 years, a 330 square foot apartment will no longer be sufficient.</p>
<p><strong>Third, inflation.</strong> Real estate not only satisfies the need for housing but also serves as a hedge against inflation.  Inflation drives up the prices of tangible assets (like real estate) while devaluing intangible assets (like cash).  The reason why real estate prices rise with inflation is simple: its costs, including land acquisition, building materials, and labor, are constantly increasing. These costs are inevitably reflected in the price of the property, and with sustained demand, real estate prices are bound to rise continuously.</p>
<p>Therefore, the faster a country&rsquo;s corporate profits increase (higher economic growth rate) and the faster national income rises, the faster real estate rents and prices will increase in the long run. Short-term real estate prices may not rise in tandem, but in the long term, prices will naturally reflect demand, and the average return on investment will be considerable.</p>
<p><strong>Can Real Estate Maintain High Returns in the Future?</strong></p>
<p>Investors often question: &ldquo;Real estate has indeed created many wealthy individuals in the past, but will it continue to rise in the future? The average annual return on real estate investment in the past was over 20%, mainly due to Taiwan&rsquo;s rapid economic growth. Can Taiwan&rsquo;s real estate maintain this high growth rate in the future?&rdquo;</p>
<p>Taiwan&rsquo;s economy has transitioned from a period of rapid growth to a more stable growth phase. The average annual economic growth rate has decreased from around 9% over a decade ago to around 6% in recent years. Although economic growth has slowed significantly compared to the past, Taiwan still ranks among the top 10 globally in terms of economic growth. This is advantageous for real estate investment.</p>
<p>Moreover, due to continuous population growth, Taiwan has a population density of 534 people per square kilometer, the second-highest in the world, making land even more valuable.  The high savings rate among ordinary people and limited investment options mean that real estate and stocks are the primary investment channels for most. However, due to the volatility of stock prices, many prefer investing in real estate.  The common belief is that leaving land or a house to the next generation provides a foundation for their future.  Therefore, with limited supply and continuously increasing demand, real estate should still maintain a return rate of 15% to 20%.  Furthermore, the government&rsquo;s gradual relaxation of restrictions on foreign investment in Taiwan&rsquo;s real estate market will further increase demand, leading to even better market performance.</p>
<p>Taiwan has experienced multiple cycles of economic growth and recession, and real estate prices have gone through periods of rapid increases and long-term consolidation.  Many investors questioned whether Taiwan&rsquo;s housing prices would continue to rise. Especially during periods of domestic and cross-strait instability, many believed that Taiwan&rsquo;s real estate market would collapse, leading them to sell their properties. Now, they regret their decisions. <strong>Facts have proven that as long as demand continues to grow and exceeds supply, prices will inevitably rise. This is an undeniable economic law. The cycle of &ldquo;prices rise for a long time, then consolidate, then rise again&rdquo; will continue to occur.</strong></p>
<p>In conclusion, whether in the past, present, or future, real estate remains an indispensable investment tool for individuals, families, and businesses.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The three secrets to real estate investment:</p>
<ol>
<li>Location, 2. Location, 3. Location.</li>
</ol></blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">Lee Shau Kee&rsquo;s Real Estate Investment Strategy 
    <div id="lee-shau-kees-real-estate-investment-strategy" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#lee-shau-kees-real-estate-investment-strategy" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>Hong Kong real estate tycoon Lee Shau Kee was ranked the richest Chinese in the world by Forbes magazine in 1996, with a net worth of US$12.7 billion, making him the fourth richest person globally. He ranked ahead of Taiwan&rsquo;s richest man, Tsai Wan-lin, the fifth richest globally, and Li Ka-shing, the sixth richest and long-time wealthiest man in Hong Kong.</p>
<p>Lee Shau Kee is not well-known in Taiwan. Now 68 years old, he is the chairman of Henderson Land Development and Hong Kong and China Gas Company. His wealth primarily comes from Henderson Land, the second-largest listed company in Hong Kong in 1996, with a market capitalization of over NT$350 billion.</p>
<p><strong>Acquiring and Redeveloping Old Buildings at Low Prices</strong></p>
<p>After moving from Guangzhou to Hong Kong in 1948, Lee Shau Kee started in real estate sales, specializing in acquiring small plots of land, redeveloping them, and selling them using a then-novel sales method: &ldquo;Stratified sales with ten-year installment payments.&rdquo;  This proved highly successful, making him famous.  In 1976, he founded Henderson Land Development, focusing on real estate development, rebuilding old buildings, and developing small and medium-sized residential properties.  By 1988, the company had expanded considerably, and Lee focused on real estate investment.</p>
<p>Lee Shau Kee&rsquo;s unique skill lies in persuading owners of old buildings in bustling areas to sell their properties, acquiring them at low prices, demolishing them, and then rebuilding.  Henderson Land&rsquo;s vast land holdings also include farmland acquired from farmers in the early days and properties bought from overseas Chinese through advertisements in Chinese newspapers in the US and Canada.</p>
<p>He believes the best real estate investment strategy is to choose the right location, focusing on densely populated areas with convenient transportation.  Whether it&rsquo;s stratified sales or renting for personal use, such locations offer excellent returns on investment.  He emphasizes that choosing an investment location requires the ability to turn one dollar into three.</p>
<p><strong>Prosperity Comes From Land Ownership</strong></p>
<p>After years of research, the author has found that today&rsquo;s wealthy individuals primarily accumulate their wealth through three avenues: inheritance, entrepreneurship, or investment.  <strong>Among those who achieve wealth through investment, a vast majority do so through real estate.</strong></p>
<p>Indeed, most wealthy individuals have made their fortunes in real estate.  In 1996, half of the world&rsquo;s top ten richest individuals derived their wealth from land, including Hong Kong&rsquo;s Lee Shau Kee, Li Ka-shing, Taiwan&rsquo;s Tsai Wan-lin, Yoshiaki Tsutsumi of Japan&rsquo;s Seibu Railway Group (ranked seventh globally), and Cheng Chou-ming (ranked tenth globally).</p>
<p>According to the 1996 Forbes Rich List, 179 individuals involved in real estate controlled approximately US$257.2 billion in wealth, accounting for 64% of the total wealth on the list.  This demonstrates that &ldquo;prosperity comes from land ownership&rdquo; is a timeless principle. This phenomenon is most pronounced in Taiwan, Hong Kong, and Japan, where land is scarce and appreciation potential is high.  Hong Kong&rsquo;s top three richest individuals, Lee Shau Kee, Li Ka-shing, and Raymond Kwok of Sun Hung Kai Properties, all made their fortunes in real estate. Taiwan is no exception.  Besides Tsai Wan-lin, prominent tycoons like Lin Rong-san, Lin Yu-lin, and Lin Hsieh-chen also built their empires on real estate. Most listed companies in Taiwan and Hong Kong are related to real estate.  Even if their core business is not real estate, they have real estate investments. Companies like Yulon Motor, Shin Kong Life Insurance, Fubon Insurance, Chinatrust, and Yuanta Securities all derive significant income from real estate.</p>
<p>Tsai Wan-tsai, chairman of Fubon Group and one of Taiwan&rsquo;s top ten richest individuals, primarily built his wealth through insurance, but stocks and real estate remain key investment tools. Tsai owns land in many bustling areas of Taipei, including a large plot near Nanyang Street, currently under development, and the newly opened Fubon Financial Center on Ren&rsquo;ai Road, which he purchased in 1986 for over NT$1 billion. The 12,000 square foot property is now worth NT$4 billion.  The 5,000 square foot Fubon Bank on Minsheng East Road, purchased in 1996 for NT$400,000 per ping (36 square feet), has now doubled in value.  &ldquo;Real estate makes money faster,&rdquo; says Tsai Wan-tsai, who spends his free time looking for and buying land whenever he has the funds.</p>
<p>These examples demonstrate that for those seeking wealth through investment, real estate is an essential component of their portfolio, and should even be the primary focus.  The success of financial management often depends on real estate ownership. Therefore, readers with sufficient funds should prioritize purchasing a home for personal use. Those with insufficient funds should consider leveraged investing to achieve homeownership and potentially higher returns. It&rsquo;s worth reiterating: &ldquo;Prosperity comes from land ownership.&rdquo; Throughout history and across the globe, the vast majority of those who have achieved financial success have done so through real estate.</p>
<p>From many perspectives, real estate is a better investment than stocks. While stocks can be a good investment, their prices fluctuate significantly. Listed stocks are traded centrally on exchanges with transparent pricing, leading to daily ups and downs that can be nerve-wracking for investors, especially when prices drop immediately after purchase.  Holding stocks requires enduring the shock of substantial price swings, bringing joy during rises and pain during falls. Unfortunately, stock prices inevitably fluctuate.</p>
<p>Some people experience pain regardless of whether prices rise or fall.  During downturns, they regret their initial investment and don&rsquo;t buy more at lower prices. During upturns, they regret not buying more initially.  Their emotions are constantly affected by price movements.  Real estate investment, on the other hand, doesn&rsquo;t have these problems. Even if real estate prices fluctuate daily, it&rsquo;s not readily apparent, allowing for a &ldquo;buy and hold&rdquo; strategy and enjoying the benefits of economic growth.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Land near mountains or at the edge of development will inevitably appreciate in value.</p></blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">Tsai Wan-lin&rsquo;s Secret to Real Estate Riches 
    <div id="tsai-wan-lins-secret-to-real-estate-riches" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#tsai-wan-lins-secret-to-real-estate-riches" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>Tsai Wan-lin, Honorary Chairman of Cathay Life Insurance, is one of Taiwan&rsquo;s richest individuals and among the top ten wealthiest globally, with a fortune of NT$180 billion.  Despite his ordinary appearance and lack of exceptional academic credentials, how did Tsai Wan-lin build such a vast empire and create an extraordinary life? Where did his wealth come from?  It&rsquo;s widely known that he owns a &ldquo;golden goose&rdquo; company—Cathay Life Insurance—the largest listed company in Taiwan by market capitalization. With over NT$500 billion in available funds for investment in real estate, securities, and loans, Cathay Life&rsquo;s assets have grown rapidly, allowing Tsai Wan-lin&rsquo;s wealth to snowball.</p>
<p><strong>Buy Land, Rent, Don&rsquo;t Sell</strong></p>
<p>Tsai Wan-lin&rsquo;s secret to wealth lies in familiar investment tools: stocks and real estate.  He keeps nearly 50% of the shares of his wealth-generating companies, Cathay Life Insurance and Cathay Real Estate Development, locked away, allowing them to appreciate naturally.  Stocks have become his &ldquo;real estate.&rdquo; How did he turn actual real estate into a gold mine?</p>
<p>Tsai Wan-lin consistently invested his money in real estate and adopted a &ldquo;buy-to-rent&rdquo; strategy.  Now in his 70s and semi-retired, he continues to look for and buy land, his lifelong passion.  According to his third son, Tsai Chen-yu, Chairman of First Commercial Bank: &ldquo;We mostly choose corner lots because they offer larger buildable areas and are lively. We moved to Ren&rsquo;ai Road Section 4 in 1961.  Back then, it was all shooting ranges and military factories, and there was no Fudan Bridge. Looking from Ximending, the East District was the edge of development.&rdquo;</p>
<p>&ldquo;In the past in Taiwan, land near mountains or at the edge of development would inevitably appreciate. Sure enough, in recent years, development has extended beyond the mountains to Xizhi and Nangang, so the suburban land we bought has now become prime real estate.  Our land acquisition strategy has remained consistent over the years, and now our focus has shifted to Xizhi and Tucheng, buying large tracts of suburban land for gradual development.&rdquo;</p>
<p>Elaborating on Tsai Wan-lin&rsquo;s philosophy of leasing rather than selling real estate, he added: &ldquo;Real estate is called &lsquo;immovable property&rsquo; because you shouldn&rsquo;t move it. If you sell in the short term, you&rsquo;ll only make a 10% or 20% profit.  Hold it for the long term, and after decades, it becomes many times its original value.  <strong>Therefore, the highest level of real estate investment is renting, not buying and selling.</strong>&rdquo; Tsai Chen-yu, who studied in Japan, cites Japanese century-old businesses as examples.  He observed that the success of Mitsubishi Estate and Mitsui Fudosan lies in owning real estate and holding onto it. More than 65% of their operating income comes from rental income.</p>
<p>Because Tsai Wan-lin acquired his land at very low costs, he then had Cathay Real Estate Development develop it and lease it to Cathay Life Insurance, creating a stable stream of rental income and land appreciation.  Cathay Life Insurance invests billions of dollars in buying and selling real estate annually.  Since they buy much more than they sell, they now own over 180 buildings throughout Taiwan. In short, Tsai Wan-lin&rsquo;s secret to wealth lies in holding onto real estate for the long term.</p>
<p><strong>Real Estate and Stock Investment Strategies Are Similar</strong></p>
<p>The strategies mentioned above for stock investment also apply to real estate investment. From an investment perspective, &ldquo;buy anything, buy anytime, don&rsquo;t sell&rdquo; is also an excellent strategy for real estate.</p>
<p>&ldquo;Buy anything&rdquo; emphasizes that selecting investment targets isn&rsquo;t as difficult as it seems.  It&rsquo;s not necessary to have predictive abilities or advanced analytical skills.  Diversification is key.  The impact of individual investments isn&rsquo;t that significant, so buying anything can work. However, because real estate investments are larger, diversification is harder to achieve. Also, purchasing real estate often involves multiple considerations, limiting the applicability of this &ldquo;buy anything&rdquo; approach.</p>
<p>&ldquo;Buy anytime&rdquo; means investing in real estate whenever you have money, without waiting for the perfect timing, because you can never predict the market perfectly.  For most people, &ldquo;buy anytime&rdquo; seems unrealistic given the high cost of real estate.  Being able to buy one house in a lifetime is already considered a significant achievement.  Real estate isn&rsquo;t like stocks, which can be bought in smaller amounts anytime.  However, don&rsquo;t underestimate yourself.  Invest small amounts in stocks regularly, and when you&rsquo;ve saved enough, consider leveraged investment.  By following the investment principles in this book, buying three or four houses in a lifetime is achievable.</p>
<p>&ldquo;Don&rsquo;t sell&rdquo; is difficult to achieve with stocks, but easier with real estate because price fluctuations are less visible and less likely to influence decisions. Many &ldquo;land rich&rdquo; individuals became wealthy by adhering to this principle.  Real estate is also known as &ldquo;immovable property.&rdquo;  If you can adopt a mindset of &ldquo;own the property, ignore the price,&rdquo; buying and holding long-term will naturally yield high returns.  Moreover, transaction costs for real estate are higher than for stocks, including taxes like land value increment tax, capital gains tax, and deed tax.  If you use an agent, you&rsquo;ll incur additional fees, making the overall transaction costs quite high.</p>
<p>For real estate investment, value investing, growth investing, and contrarian investing are even better strategies than &ldquo;buy anything, buy anytime, don&rsquo;t sell.&rdquo;  Value investing involves buying when the intrinsic value of the property exceeds its price.  As mentioned earlier, value is difficult to measure precisely for real estate, relying on subjective judgment, though market trends can provide guidance. For instance, if real estate prices decline significantly, the intrinsic value likely exceeds the market price, creating a good buying opportunity.</p>
<p><strong>Choosing the Right Location is Crucial</strong></p>
<p>Contrarian investing in real estate means selecting locations that others are currently overlooking but have future growth potential. If these areas develop as anticipated, the initial low purchase price will generate substantial profits.  Avoid buying when everyone else is rushing into the market, as prices are likely inflated. Conversely, when everyone believes prices will continue to fall and market activity is low, it might be the best time to invest.</p>
<p>Growth investing is perhaps the most important and easiest of the three strategies for real estate. The three secrets to real estate investment are location, location, location.  <strong>The key is to consider the future growth potential of the location. Don&rsquo;t choose the cheapest or currently best areas, but those with future development prospects.</strong></p>
<p>How do you choose a good location?  It requires some imagination.  Real estate development is like a ripple effect from a stone thrown into a calm lake.  Initially, development centers around the city center, but the surrounding areas become the fastest-growing and most promising investment targets.  Growth investors can sell their properties in the city center at high prices and reinvest in cheaper outlying areas to enjoy significant future appreciation. In Taipei, the best investment location 20 years ago was Ximending. Now it&rsquo;s the Eastern District, and future development will likely focus on suburban areas like Xizhi and Tucheng.  Those looking to buy real estate should explore the outskirts, envisioning future development directions.</p>
<p><strong>Buy Now, Hold Long-Term: The Best Strategy</strong></p>
<p>Real estate is a cyclical industry with predictable price patterns.  Short-term price fluctuations are inevitable, but in the long run, prices tend to rise.  The characteristic pattern is a long period of rising prices followed by consolidation, then another period of rising prices.  Real estate also exhibits a common market characteristic: the faster prices rise, the faster demand increases.</p>
<p>Historically, Taiwan&rsquo;s real estate market cycles have lasted between three and nine years, averaging seven years.  One characteristic of rising prices is a substantial increase of two to four times at the beginning of each cycle, followed by years of consolidation. Some hope to buy at the very beginning of a price increase, but no one can accurately predict the exact starting point.  By the time you realize prices are rising, they&rsquo;ve already increased substantially, and by the time you place an order, the price might be double or even more.  Since no one can predict the start of a price increase, the smartest and best approach is to act promptly, buy property, and hold it long-term for substantial profits.</p>
<p>Generally, there are several signs of an impending price increase: rising stock prices, favorable government policies, and the central bank lowering interest rates to loosen monetary policy. Stock prices are a good predictor of economic activity.  Rising stock prices increase available funds, which often fuels real estate price increases.</p>
<p>Real estate is a &ldquo;locomotive&rdquo; industry.  To stimulate an economy, it&rsquo;s essential to stimulate real estate prices.  When the government injects capital into the market and lowers interest rates to boost the economy, it often presents an excellent opportunity to invest in both real estate and stocks.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The two secrets to land investment are &ldquo;wait&rdquo; and &ldquo;endure.&rdquo;  The right time to develop can often take two decades.</p></blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">Cheng Chou-ming&rsquo;s Real Estate Investment Strategy 
    <div id="cheng-chou-mings-real-estate-investment-strategy" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#cheng-chou-mings-real-estate-investment-strategy" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>Cheng Chou-ming, the richest man in the Philippines, has seen his wealth surge due to the recent boom in the Philippine real estate market. In 1996, Forbes estimated his net worth at US$7 billion, placing him among the world&rsquo;s top ten richest individuals.  His secret to success lies in stocks and real estate, and his investment strategy involves contrarian investing: buying the best assets at the lowest prices during times of low market confidence and holding them long-term.</p>
<p>Cheng Chou-ming owns land in Taiwan, the Philippines, mainland China, and Houston, Texas.  His holdings include 32 plots of land in Taiwan totaling 135 acres and 362 plots in the Philippines exceeding 50,000 acres, where he is currently building skyscrapers.  He also has a large-scale project on Fuga Island in the northern Philippines, a 250,000-acre island larger than Hong Kong by one-third, where he plans to build a free port with docks, an airport, and hotels.</p>
<p><strong>Patience and Endurance Yield Hundredfold Returns</strong></p>
<p>Cheng Chou-ming, a keen real estate investor, bought large tracts of land in the Philippines 20 years ago for NT$0.2 per ping, which has now appreciated to over NT$600.  This is his philosophy of &ldquo;endurance,&rdquo; patiently waiting 20 years for a two- to three-thousandfold return. Cheng Chou-ming says: &ldquo;There are four types of people in real estate development: land investors, land developers, constructors, and builders.&rdquo;</p>
<p>&ldquo;Land investment takes longer, so land investors generally make larger profits, while the latter three, with shorter investment horizons, earn smaller margins, often just making money from developing the land. Land investment requires initial capital and a keen eye for location selection.  Entering the market at the right time allows you to acquire land cheaply.&rdquo;</p>
<p>&ldquo;Future purchases of new land and interest payments on existing land can be covered by selling a small portion of the existing holdings.  For example, selling one plot of land for the Asiaworld Group currently covers the acquisition cost of all our land.  So, with patience and endurance, future returns can be hundreds or even thousands of times the initial investment.&rdquo;</p>
<p>In the early 1970s, Cheng Chou-ming acquired the current site of the Grand Hyatt Taipei on Nanjing East Road for a very low price. While others were selling their properties and preparing to emigrate, Cheng Chou-ming decisively purchased this overgrown and neglected land, which became his base for future development in Taiwan.</p>
<p>Cheng Chou-ming excels at recognizing that the worst of times offer the best opportunities.  During the cross-strait crisis, which caused a plunge in real estate and stock prices, he quietly acquired large amounts of stock. He said: &ldquo;At that time, many stock prices were very low, and some offered annual dividends of over 20%, higher than bank interest rates. Such stocks are rare globally.  With long-term investment, even just collecting dividends is worthwhile. As long as you choose the right stocks and invest long-term, you&rsquo;re bound to make a lot of money.&rdquo;</p>
<p><strong>The Importance of Brand in Real Estate Investment</strong></p>
<p>Most people&rsquo;s first real estate investment is a home for personal use, often buying pre-sale properties. There are three secrets to investing in a home: location, location, location.</p>
<p>Choosing a home should prioritize the environment.  The story of Mencius&rsquo;s mother moving three times highlights the importance of the surrounding environment, safety, and the quality of neighbors, all of which impact quality of life and children&rsquo;s development.  Transportation, amenities, and other factors should also be considered.  When purchasing pre-sale properties, focus on the &ldquo;brand.&rdquo;  Such investments carry high risks, so the developer&rsquo;s reputation and financial health are paramount, followed by practicality and growth potential.</p>
<p>In the past, when average incomes were lower, people bought cars that simply ran, were affordable, and looked decent. As demand increased and economic conditions improved, attention shifted to details, and brand and quality became more important.  Cars require maintenance and repairs.  Choosing a random repair shop can be problematic, with mechanics unfamiliar with the car model and a lack of available parts.  Therefore, buyers began to consider the after-sales service offered by the car manufacturer.</p>
<p>Similarly, people used to buy homes that were simply livable, affordable, and in a reasonably acceptable environment.  With economic growth and rising incomes, people are more demanding of quality of life, and the concept of &ldquo;brand&rdquo; has become increasingly important in real estate.  According to the Consumers&rsquo; Foundation in Taiwan, real estate litigation cases are rampant, and most cases end without resolution.</p>
<p>Many construction companies in Taiwan are &ldquo;one-project companies,&rdquo; dissolving after completing a single project.  Therefore, after purchasing a property, if any issues arise (such as unclear property rights, substandard building materials, or discrepancies in area), buyers often have no recourse.  Furthermore, problems with the internal structure of a house may not be apparent initially, surfacing only after some time, such as water leaks, wall cracks, or plumbing issues.  By then, there might be no one to hold accountable, highlighting the importance of brand reputation.</p>
<p>Real estate investment is a major life decision.  For a home, comfort is essential. Even if the purchase is for investment purposes, a &ldquo;quality-guaranteed&rdquo; property will be easier to sell and fetch a better price.</p>
<p>After-sales service is another crucial factor in real estate investment.  Many construction companies disengage after handing over the property, leaving the management committee to the homeowners.  Due to a lack of authority and resources, these committees often struggle to address issues, leading to dissatisfaction among residents.</p>
<p>Several reputable construction companies in Taiwan are now emphasizing community management and after-sales service.  For instance, Taichung&rsquo;s Sancai Construction, the company where the author currently works, entrusts community management to an affiliated company, integrating software and hardware services to create a safe and comfortable living environment.  Sancai Construction also provides security, repairs, bill payment services, and housekeeping services.</p>
<p>Therefore, future real estate investors should consider not only location and environment but also the developer&rsquo;s brand, quality, and after-sales service.  Choosing a reputable company with quality assurance, good after-sales service, and effective management is crucial for successful real estate investment.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>As long as you avoid buying during periods of rapidly rising prices, the risk of leveraged investment is relatively low.</p></blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">Leveraged Investment in Real Estate 
    <div id="leveraged-investment-in-real-estate" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#leveraged-investment-in-real-estate" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>The substantial investment required for real estate often deters potential investors.  The fact that property prices often rise faster than wages further contributes to the increasing wealth gap.  However, real estate investment is relatively low-risk as long as you avoid the frenzy of buying during periods of soaring prices.  Real estate, being a tangible asset, is easy to mortgage. Coupled with its high long-term returns and less visible price volatility, it&rsquo;s an ideal candidate for leveraged investment.</p>
<p><strong>The Benefit of Spreading Out Payments</strong></p>
<p>Home mortgages typically span 20 years, effectively spreading out the total cost of the property plus interest over two decades. For instance, purchasing a NT$5 million house with a 70% mortgage at a 9% interest rate over 20 years results in a monthly payment of NT$31,490.</p>
<p>Therefore, if you have NT$1.5 million in savings and can afford the monthly payments, you should consider buying a property.  The government often provides preferential interest rates for first-time homebuyers to promote homeownership.  Those without a house should take advantage of these programs.</p>
<p>Some argue that renting is more cost-effective than buying in Taiwan.  A NT$5 million house might rent for only NT$20,000 per month, while buying requires a NT$1.5 million down payment and monthly mortgage payments exceeding NT$30,000.  This argument usually arises during market downturns or periods of stagnation. However, it&rsquo;s flawed because it ignores the long-term upward trend of real estate prices.  Renting would indeed be better if prices remained constant, but they don&rsquo;t.  Given long-term price appreciation, buying is more cost-effective than renting, especially because leveraging magnifies returns, making real estate a high-yield investment. Many have become wealthy through real estate ownership.  In short, if you can afford to buy, it&rsquo;s better than renting, offering greater security and an excellent investment opportunity.</p>
<p><strong>Mortgage Pressure is Manageable</strong></p>
<p>Some are reluctant to take on a mortgage due to the perceived burden of monthly payments.  Twenty years ago, NT$1 million could buy a 50+ ping luxury apartment in Taipei.  A 70% mortgage at a 9% interest rate translated to monthly payments of over NT$4,000.  Back then, a university graduate&rsquo;s starting salary was around NT$8,000 to NT$10,000, making NT$4,000 a significant burden. However, 20 years later, with inflation, experience, and increased earning power, the average monthly salary should be above NT$50,000, making the same mortgage payment much less burdensome.</p>
<p><strong>Therefore, young people investing in real estate with leverage shouldn&rsquo;t be overly concerned about the initial mortgage pressure.</strong> While NT$30,000+ per month might seem daunting, future income growth will gradually ease the burden within five to ten years.</p>
<p>A manager at an American bank said: &ldquo;The biggest problem with mortgages in the US is people defaulting on their loans.  In Taiwan, the biggest problem is people paying off their mortgages early.&rdquo;</p>
<p>Moderate mortgage pressure can be beneficial for financial management, promoting forced savings and reduced spending. As mentioned earlier, starting early with diligent saving and investing in high-yield assets like stocks and real estate lays a solid foundation for future financial success.</p>
<p>Therefore, young people with sufficient down payment and the ability to manage monthly payments should consider leveraged investment in a home. As long as borrowing is within reasonable limits, avoiding foreclosure, long-term leveraged investment in real estate is undoubtedly advantageous.</p>
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Personal Investment Bible: Investment Iron Law X</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1731056005969/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1731056005969/</guid><description>This article introduces three stock investment strategies: value investing, growth investing, and contrarian investing. Value investing emphasizes buying stocks when the price is below their intrinsic value and selling when the price is above. Growth investing focuses on the future earnings growth potential of companies, selecting companies with sustained high growth for investment. Contrarian investing suggests going against the general market sentiment, being greedy when others are fearful, and fearful when others are greedy. The article analyzes the advantages, disadvantages, and suitability of each strategy, pointing out that although these three strategies are theoretically effective, they are difficult to implement in practice. Ordinary investors are more suited to adopt a long-term buy-and-hold strategy of &amp;#34;buy any stock, buy at any time, and don&amp;#39;t sell.&amp;#34;</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[

<h2 class="relative group">Investment Iron Law X: Mastering the Tools of Stock Market Offense and Defense 
    <div id="investment-iron-law-x-mastering-the-tools-of-stock-market-offense-and-defense" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#investment-iron-law-x-mastering-the-tools-of-stock-market-offense-and-defense" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>Buy when Value is higher than Price.
Sell when Value is lower than Price.</p></blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">Value Investing 
    <div id="value-investing" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#value-investing" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>The strategy of &ldquo;buy any stock, buy at any time, and don&rsquo;t sell&rdquo; sounds simple, but most people can&rsquo;t follow it. Even if they acknowledge its potential for wealth creation, they lack the courage to implement it because it seems to contradict common investment beliefs and principles. Therefore, the author presents three superior investment strategies: value investing, growth investing, and contrarian investing. Before investing, using these strategies, you must ask yourself: Does the investment target hold this value? What is its future growth potential? Is everyone investing in it? These three investment strategies can help you make better decisions.</p>
<p><strong>Verifying Value Ensures Profitability</strong></p>
<p>During the 1920s, Florida&rsquo;s real estate prices skyrocketed daily, triggering a buying frenzy. One fortunate investor managed to secure a plot of land. Most buyers didn&rsquo;t care about the land&rsquo;s quality, but this investor prudently asked a real estate agent to show him the purchased land. He was shocked to discover it was swampland.  &ldquo;Can anyone live here?&rdquo; he exclaimed. The agent calmly replied, &ldquo;Why worry about that? As long as the price goes up.&rdquo;</p>
<p>&ldquo;Human behavior and decision-making are perfectly rational&rdquo; is a fundamental assumption in academic research and theoretical development. Generally, consumers won&rsquo;t rush to buy unless a product offers exceptional value. For instance, no one would pay $5 million for a car worth $500,000 unless they were foolish. Investment decisions, involving money and future wealth, are even more critical than buying a car. Logically, people should be more rational and cautious, making decisions only after careful calculations.</p>
<p>However, are investors truly rational?  In July 1985, China Development Corporation&rsquo;s stock price was NT$14 per share. Four years later, in September 1989, it reached NT$1075, a nearly 80-fold increase.  Remarkably, in 1985, when the price was low, investors shunned the stock, resulting in low trading volume. Conversely, in 1989, when the price soared to over NT$1000, investors rushed in, fearing they would miss out, driving trading volume to its peak.</p>
<p>Are these investment behaviors rational?  Consider the difference between China Development Corporation at NT$14 in 1985, at over NT$1000 in 1989, or even at NT$50 in 1983.  Essentially, the difference was minimal; it was the same company, managed by practically the same people, with similar assets. Why such a drastic price difference? The answer lies not in the company&rsquo;s intrinsic changes but in investors&rsquo; behavioral and decision-making biases.</p>
<p>Between 1989 and 1990, during the Taiwan stock market&rsquo;s peak, investors continued pouring in. The author often asked friends and family, &ldquo;Do you think the stocks you&rsquo;re buying are worth the price?&rdquo;  Most found the question perplexing and avoided answering. Some reluctantly admitted, &ldquo;Probably not.&rdquo;  The author would then ask, &ldquo;Why buy them then?&rdquo;  Their confident reply: &ldquo;They&rsquo;ll go up!&rdquo;</p>
<p>Some also questioned the author&rsquo;s lack of participation in this lucrative market.  The response: &ldquo;I&rsquo;ll wait until after 4000 points to invest.&rdquo; The author believed the Taiwan stock market&rsquo;s true value was below 4000 points (in 1989).  Those who heard this scoffed, &ldquo;Keep waiting.&rdquo;  As it turned out, overvalued assets cannot rise indefinitely. In August 1990, the Taiwan stock index plummeted to around 2000 points, proving the author&rsquo;s point.  No investment&rsquo;s price can remain perpetually above or below its true value.</p>
<p><strong>Buy When Value Exceeds Price</strong></p>
<p>Value investing, introduced by Benjamin Graham in his 1933 book <em>Security Analysis</em>, was later championed by his students, including Warren Buffett and John Templeton.  In the 1980s, value investing gained prominence in the US, becoming the strategy of choice for many successful long-term investors.</p>
<p>Value investing posits that every stock has an intrinsic value.  Price fluctuations arise from investor trading.  Prices exceeding intrinsic value will eventually revert, and prices falling below will eventually recover.</p>
<p>The principle is simple: buy when the value is higher than the price, regardless of market fluctuations.  If it&rsquo;s cheap, buy it. Conversely, sell when the value is lower than the price.  In short, buy low, sell high.  Sell when prices significantly exceed value amidst widespread buying, minimizing holdings. Buy when prices fall drastically below value amidst widespread fear, increasing holdings.</p>
<p>Typically, investors focus solely on price appreciation, neglecting value.  People meticulously research cars, refrigerators, or stereos for months, comparing models, reading reviews, and seeking advice, constantly evaluating value for money.  They&rsquo;ll wait for a sale if the price is too high.  Yet, when buying stocks, often on a whim based on a tip or hearsay, they overlook value, making hasty decisions involving sums far exceeding appliance purchases.</p>
<p><strong>Invest with an Owner&rsquo;s Mindset</strong></p>
<p>Warren Buffett&rsquo;s investment philosophy emphasizes investing with an owner&rsquo;s mindset and a long-term perspective. This involves buying stocks of companies with stable earnings growth, positive prospects, high asset value, or simply when the intrinsic value exceeds the price.</p>
<p>Crowds flock to department stores during sales and clearances. The steeper the discounts, the larger the crowds.  Conversely, shopping is most pleasant when there are no sales, as stores are less crowded.  This is because consumers are motivated by value, buying when prices are below perceived worth.</p>
<p>However, in stock markets, the opposite occurs. Brokerage houses are deserted when stock prices are at their lowest.  Conversely, they are packed when prices are soaring. Investors are motivated by rising prices.  A stock falling from $100 to $50 attracts little interest, while rapid price increases fuel buying frenzy.</p>
<p>The assumption of rational economic behavior applies well to consumer choices but not to investment behavior.  As illustrated, investment decisions are often driven by irrational emotions, impulses, and intuition.</p>
<p>Value investing advises emulating consumer behavior: buy when stocks are &ldquo;on sale,&rdquo; and avoid the herd when prices are inflated.</p>
<p><strong>Developing the Ability to Calculate Asset and Earnings Value</strong></p>
<p>The key to successful value investing is the ability to calculate a company&rsquo;s intrinsic value, encompassing asset value and earnings value.  Asset value represents the liquidation value of the company&rsquo;s assets per share. Earnings value represents the present value of the company&rsquo;s projected future earnings.  Estimating future earnings is challenging, requiring the development of forecasting skills.</p>
<p>Calculating intrinsic value is not easy.  Investing in familiar companies simplifies this process.  Taiwanese businesswoman Shirley Wang, CEO of FIC Global, primarily invested in FIC and related IT and semiconductor companies.  Her familiarity with the industry allowed her to better grasp its dynamics.</p>
<p>Many successful investors adhere to Buffett&rsquo;s philosophy, investing only in familiar companies.  Li-Ching Hsu, former Taiwan head of ING Group, frequently advised investors to focus on companies in their own industry or related sectors.</p>
<p>Investment decisions should always involve value analysis. Buy when the value is present or the price is attractive; sell otherwise.  Value investing encourages adopting consumer-like behavior in the stock market, buying low and selling high.</p>
<p><em>1. When investing in stocks, ask &ldquo;Is it worth buying?&rdquo; not just &ldquo;Will it go up?&rdquo;</em></p>
<p><em>2.  Learn from consumer behavior: buy when prices are discounted.</em></p>
<blockquote>
<p>Choose a great company, and if it keeps growing, you&rsquo;ll almost never have to sell.</p></blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">Growth Investing 
    <div id="growth-investing" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#growth-investing" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>Valuing a company is challenging.  Some professional investors therefore focus on earnings growth rate, a primary driver of value, as their investment criterion. Growth investing has been successfully employed by renowned investors, notably Peter Lynch, former manager of Fidelity&rsquo;s Magellan Fund, who achieved the highest 15-year return among hundreds of US mutual funds.</p>
<p><strong>Investing in High-Growth Potential Stocks</strong></p>
<p>Simply put, growth investing involves buying stocks of companies with high future growth potential and selling when that potential diminishes.  A key characteristic is maintaining full investment, ideally diversified.  Growth investors acknowledge their inability to predict short-term market movements but believe in the long-term upward trend of stocks, especially those with high growth potential.</p>
<p>They invest all their capital in high-growth stocks.  Peter Lynch maintained a nearly 100% invested portfolio during his tenure at Magellan Fund, keeping minimal cash reserves for redemptions.</p>
<p>The key to successful growth investing lies in identifying companies with high growth potential.  This is the challenge: finding high-growth stocks.  Investing in IBM 30 years ago, Microsoft 15 years ago, or Cathay Life Insurance in Taiwan would have yielded multifold returns.</p>
<p>However, countless seemingly high-growth companies fizzle out. No one can predict the future with certainty. Even Peter Lynch admitted that only half of his stock picks were truly successful, but that was enough.  Therefore, diversification is crucial for mitigating the higher risks of growth investing.</p>
<p>Growth investing believes that a company&rsquo;s real growth drives stock price appreciation.  Investment returns depend on the earnings over the next few years. For high returns, choose investments with 5-10 year growth potential. Invest in companies in high-growth industries with excellent performance and a sustainable growth outlook. Their stock prices are likely to rise with the company&rsquo;s growth, offering substantial long-term gains.</p>
<p><strong>Choosing the Right Industry is More Important Than Choosing the Right Company</strong></p>
<p>Growth investors prioritize future earnings growth potential.  Industry growth is crucial for a company&rsquo;s earnings.  Choosing the right industry is therefore more important than choosing the right company.  Consider the future 5-10 year demand for the company&rsquo;s products, focusing on the industry&rsquo;s growth potential. Peter Lynch advised against selling good stocks prematurely for small profits and recommended selling stocks of companies with deteriorating growth prospects, even at a loss.  This approach allows gains from successful picks to offset losses from unsuccessful ones, resulting in overall profit.</p>
<p>Peter Lynch advocated for a &ldquo;common sense&rdquo; approach to investing, illustrated in his book <em>One Up On Wall Street</em>. He profited from observing his wife&rsquo;s preference for certain hosiery and dish soap brands, and his children&rsquo;s preference for certain sneakers, leading him to invest in those companies.  This approach can be explained by market efficiency theory.  Retailers and observant consumers are often the first to notice a product&rsquo;s popularity, before analysts.  By adopting a consumer perspective and noticing trends overlooked by experts, investors can gain an edge.</p>
<p>In early 1996, after a frugal, retired court clerk passed away, her family discovered her substantial wealth. She had consistently invested small amounts in Coca-Cola stock for decades, capitalizing on its growth and share price appreciation. This illustrates the power of long-term investment in growing companies.</p>
<p><strong>Don&rsquo;t Just Focus on Price Fluctuations</strong></p>
<p>Many investors are unclear about their investment rationale.  If you can&rsquo;t explain your investment&rsquo;s business and growth potential in five minutes, you shouldn&rsquo;t own it.  Focus on monitoring the validity of your investment thesis, not daily price fluctuations.</p>
<p>Many investors prefer startups or pre-IPO companies. However, established, profitable companies with growth potential are often better investments. Peter Lynch suggested capturing the middle five years of a company&rsquo;s 15-year growth trajectory, rather than the initial or mature phases.  If a stock has the potential to rise from $2 to $200, wait until it reaches $8 before buying. The potential gains are still substantial, and the risk is lower.  Losing money in the stock market is quick, but making money takes time. Most stocks take 3-5 years to rise significantly.</p>
<p>Regarding industry growth potential, in Taiwan, IT, communications, and semiconductors within the electronics industry are promising. Pharmaceuticals and biotechnology are also attractive due to increasing health consciousness. Taiwan&rsquo;s ten emerging industries (specialty chemicals, environmental protection, aerospace, telecommunications, semiconductors, IT, pharmaceuticals, precision machinery, etc.) offer future growth opportunities.  In the service sector, securities and investment trust, construction, and shipping also have good prospects.  <strong>Savvy investors should anticipate future trends, popular products, internet-driven products, and leverage their own consumer insights to identify investment opportunities.</strong></p>
<p>Growth investing is suitable for non-professional investors.  It requires no specialized training or constant monitoring.  To identify growth stocks, consider a company&rsquo;s potential performance over the next 5-10 years. Invest in companies with strong growth potential and hold them long-term, selling only when they transition from growth to maturity.  This strategy allows even amateur investors with limited time and expertise to achieve good results.</p>
<p><em>1. Real earnings growth drives stock price appreciation.</em></p>
<p><em>2. Diversify investments in companies with sustainable 5-10 year growth potential, patiently awaiting substantial returns.</em></p>
<blockquote>
<p>Don&rsquo;t follow the crowd; be rational. Figure out what most people are doing, then don&rsquo;t do it.</p></blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">Contrarian Investing 
    <div id="contrarian-investing" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#contrarian-investing" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>Many ask, &ldquo;Is there a better time to buy than &lsquo;any time&rsquo;?&rdquo; Research suggests there is: contrarian investing, a time-tested and remarkably effective strategy.</p>
<p><strong>Buy Straw Hats in Winter, Boats in a Drought</strong></p>
<p>A 19th-century American tycoon, when asked about his wealth-building secret, replied, &ldquo;Buy straw hats in winter.&rdquo;  Similarly, Fan Li, a wealthy merchant in ancient China, followed the principle of &ldquo;buying fur coats in summer, selling in winter; buying boats in a drought, selling when it rains.&rdquo;  These are examples of contrarian investing.</p>
<p>This investment concept originated in ancient China. According to <em>Records of the Grand Historian</em>, Ji Ran, an economist during the Warring States period, proposed the contrarian strategy of &ldquo;invest in boats during drought, invest in carts during floods.&rdquo;  He argued that during droughts, when everyone invests in cart production, one should invest in boats.  The oversupply of carts would lower prices and profits.  When the rains return, boat demand would surge, raising prices and profits.  Conversely, during floods, when everyone invests in boats, one should invest in carts.</p>
<p>Contrarian investing means investing when most people aren&rsquo;t and selling when everyone is eager to buy.  The concept is simple: go against the crowd.  However, implementing it is challenging. It requires overcoming human nature, resisting herd mentality, cultivating independent judgment, and enduring loneliness. Most investors follow the crowd, while contrarian investors look for opportunities when others are fearful.  This strategy relies on the belief that widespread consensus is often wrong and that reversals can be powerful.</p>
<p><strong>Don&rsquo;t Be Deceived by Net Buying or Selling</strong></p>
<p>Contrarian investing works because when most people are bullish, available capital is already invested, leading to overinflated prices.  With everyone already in the market, poised to sell, potential supply outweighs demand. Any negative news can trigger a sharp decline.</p>
<p>Conversely, when most people are bearish, selling pressure is minimal as most have already sold.  With potential buyers waiting on the sidelines, demand outweighs supply.  Any positive news can trigger a sharp rise.</p>
<p>Investors tend to extrapolate past trends, especially when reinforced by market sentiment. During initial market declines, most see it as temporary, while a few predict further declines. As the market continues falling, bears are rewarded, and bulls suffer.  At severely oversold levels, widespread pessimism creates buying opportunities.  Conversely, during initial market rallies, most see it as temporary, while a few predict further gains. As the market continues rising, bulls are rewarded, and bears suffer. At severely overbought levels, widespread optimism leads to overvaluation.</p>
<p><strong>Bullish When Rising, Bearish When Falling</strong></p>
<p>People tend to become more optimistic during optimistic periods and more pessimistic during pessimistic periods.  They rely on memory to predict the future.  A rising market breeds bullishness, and a falling market breeds bearishness.</p>
<p>At the peak of the Taiwan stock market in late 1989, the author taught an investment course. During one lecture, a student requested the author refrain from discussing stocks.  Surprised, the author asked why. The student explained that every class, from political science to calculus, included discussions about stocks.</p>
<p>Another anecdote from that period involves a professor asking his class the time. A student instinctively replied, &ldquo;9865 points, up 65 points.&rdquo;  Students were constantly monitoring stock prices during lectures. This illustrates the pervasive stock market mania at the time.  As it turned out, this widespread obsession was a harbinger of the impending crash.</p>
<p><strong>Great investments often involve defying conventional wisdom, selling when others are buying, and buying when others are selling.  Be bearish before others when everyone is bullish, and be bullish before others when everyone is bearish. As a Wall Street adage goes, &ldquo;Markets are born in despair, grow in skepticism, mature in optimism, and die in euphoria.&rdquo;</strong></p>
<p>Contrarian investing doesn&rsquo;t require constantly opposing the majority. It encourages resisting herd mentality and cultivating independent thinking.  The best buying opportunities may arise when most are afraid to buy, but buying solely for that reason is as foolish as following the crowd. The crowd isn&rsquo;t always wrong.  Develop independent judgment.  True contrarians don&rsquo;t blindly oppose the majority but wait for the dust to settle and buy when no one is paying attention.</p>
<p>Contrarian investing applies to stock selection. David Dreman, in his book <em>Contrarian Investment Strategies</em>, argued that unpopular companies often outperform expectations, while popular companies are susceptible to minor setbacks.</p>
<p>Timing the market is difficult. Mastering the principles of contrarian investing can be highly rewarding.</p>
<p><em>1. Invest when others aren&rsquo;t; sell when everyone is eager to invest.</em></p>
<p><em>2. Don&rsquo;t follow the crowd; buy when investor sentiment has cooled and no one is paying attention.</em></p>
<p><strong>Value, Growth, and Contrarian Strategies are Best Suited for Experts</strong></p>
<p>These seemingly disparate strategies are not mutually exclusive. Investors can choose or combine strategies based on their individual characteristics.  The most effective strategy is subjective and depends on individual circumstances. The author recommends value investing for those skilled in financial analysis, growth investing for those with foresight, and contrarian investing for independent, emotionally disciplined individuals.</p>
<p>Value investing is considered the most sophisticated technique, requiring strong financial knowledge and valuation skills. Most investors lack this expertise. Even among analysts, few truly understand valuation.  Growth investing requires foresight to identify high-growth industries and companies, which is also challenging.  Contrarian investing requires no specialized knowledge but is the hardest to implement due to its counterintuitive nature.  Most people are trend followers. Few can buy when everyone is selling or sell when everyone is buying.</p>
<p>These three strategies can enhance returns if mastered and applied correctly.  Countless self-proclaimed &ldquo;investment experts&rdquo; populate the market, but few consistently outperform using these strategies.  Misapplied, these strategies can lead to short-term speculation and losses.  Therefore, the author still recommends the simple, yet effective, long-term buy-and-hold strategy of &ldquo;buy any stock, buy at any time, and don&rsquo;t sell&rdquo; for most investors.</p>
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Personal Investment Bible: Investment Iron Law XI</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1731056005970/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1731056005970/</guid><description>This article explains why short-term stock trading should be avoided. The core argument is that long-term holding is the key to gaining returns from the stock market. It analyzes the disadvantages of short-term trading, including high transaction costs, profits being taken by market makers and large investors, and investment failures caused by human weaknesses. The article emphasizes that the primary source of profit from stock investment is the company&amp;#39;s earnings, not price fluctuations. It advises investors to adopt a buy-and-hold strategy of “buy any stock, buy anytime, don&amp;#39;t sell” to truly benefit from the stock market.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[

<h2 class="relative group">Investment Iron Law XI: Avoid Short-Term Trading 
    <div id="investment-iron-law-xi-avoid-short-term-trading" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#investment-iron-law-xi-avoid-short-term-trading" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>The greatest enemy of investment activity is human weakness: greed, fear, and herd mentality.</p></blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">The Pitfalls of Buying Low and Selling High 
    <div id="the-pitfalls-of-buying-low-and-selling-high" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#the-pitfalls-of-buying-low-and-selling-high" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>Stock prices fluctuate in the short term, leading many investors to intuitively believe that profits can be made by simply &ldquo;buying low and selling high.&rdquo; Undeniably, the allure of price differences is strong. A limit-up day can bring thousands of dollars in profit, and buying ten lots could cover a month&rsquo;s salary. However, once captivated by this temptation and engaging in the game of short-term trading, you unknowingly enter a losing battle. While luck might bring short-term gains, long-term losses are inevitable.</p>
<p><strong>Stock Profits Are More Than Just Price Differences</strong></p>
<p>Many stock investors hold the misconception that profits come solely from price fluctuations. In reality, the primary source of profit lies in sharing the company&rsquo;s earnings, not capitalizing on short-term price swings. Stock investments generate returns because the invested companies&rsquo; earnings are ultimately distributed to investors.  The immense time and effort spent researching entry and exit points, diligently watching the market, and constantly chasing trends contribute nothing to the company&rsquo;s earnings.</p>
<p>The Taiwan Weighted Stock Index rose from 100 points in early 1967 to 6200 points at the end of August 1996, a 62-fold increase.  Using the end of 1986 as a base period, when the index was around 700 points, the rise to 6200 points by the end of August 1996 represents an increase of over 8 times. The Taiwan stock market&rsquo;s astonishing growth and substantial returns should have made every investor wealthy.  However, the reality is quite the opposite. Few Taiwanese investors have profited from stocks, while countless have suffered losses. According to a 1988 survey by Professor Lin Quanyuan, 27% of investors experienced losses, and 78% earned returns below the market average.  Private surveys suggest even higher loss rates.  The question arises: &ldquo;Where did the substantial stock market profits go?&rdquo;</p>
<p><strong>Short-Term Trading is Gambling</strong></p>
<p>Short-term stock trading is speculation and gambling, both characterized by a high probability of loss. We often see short-term traders boastful after successful speculations but disappear or remain silent after losses. This creates the false impression that short-term trading is profitable. In truth, these traders usually end up losing money.</p>
<p>Long-term stock holding yields an average annual return of over 15%, but only if the stocks are held and not sold. The biggest problem with short-term trading is the transaction costs incurred with each trade.  Investors often overlook these costs, believing they are insignificant compared to potential price differences. In the Taiwanese securities market, the transaction cost for each round trip (buy and sell) is approximately 0.6% of the transaction amount. While a single transaction cost seems small, the cumulative effect is substantial. Imagine trading more than 25 times a year, or every two weeks. The 15% annual return would be almost entirely eroded, making it worse than keeping the money in a bank.  Moreover, short-term traders often exceed 25 trades per year.  Factor in a few losses, and the return becomes negative.  Frequent trading inevitably diminishes returns, and negative returns are no different from gambling.</p>
<p>Therefore, if you cannot resist the urge to chase short-term price differences, it&rsquo;s best to avoid stock investment altogether and keep your money in the bank.  While you may not become rich, it&rsquo;s better than losing it all in the stock market.</p>
<p>In 1989, the total after-tax earnings of all listed companies in Taiwan were 110.3 billion NTD.  In the same year, securities transaction taxes were 152.4 billion NTD, and transaction fees totaled 76.2 billion NTD. This means the combined earnings of listed companies were insufficient to cover these costs, leaving investors with an additional 118.3 billion NTD in transaction costs. It&rsquo;s no wonder most stock investors suffer losses. The solution is simple: adopt a long-term holding strategy and minimize unnecessary trading. Long-term stock market investment offers high returns and lower risk. By holding long term, there&rsquo;s no need for worry or fear, and wealth can be accumulated over one or two decades.</p>
<p><strong>Short-Term Trading Creates Wealth for Intermediaries</strong></p>
<p>To achieve investment success, one must overcome &ldquo;greed during market upswings and fear during downswings.&rdquo;</p>
<p>A book from the 1940s in the US, titled <em>Where Are the Customer&rsquo;s Yachts?</em>, tells the story of a stockbroker taking a major client to a marina. Pointing at the luxurious yachts, the broker says, &ldquo;These yachts belong to our firm&rsquo;s brokers.&rdquo; The client then asks, &ldquo;Are any of them owned by your clients?&rdquo; The broker is speechless, as none of the yachts belonged to clients. (Note: yachts were a status symbol of wealth in American society at that time).</p>
<p>It seems unlikely that valuable clients of brokerage firms would be wealthy. This story illustrates that while stock market profits are substantial, most are earned by intermediaries.  Those who frequently trade and generate significant profits for brokerage firms rarely become yacht owners themselves.</p>
<p>Merrill Lynch annually has a dozen or so brokers earning over a million dollars.  However, their truly valuable clients are not exceptionally wealthy individuals. Wealthy people are usually busy making money and don&rsquo;t have the time for frequent trading.  They wouldn&rsquo;t be considered valuable clients. Only those who constantly engage in short-term trading are the major contributors to transaction fees and the most loyal customers of brokerage firms.</p>
<p>In 1990, a scholar wrote a bestselling book on securities investment, earning about 1 million NTD.  He was overjoyed, as it was a considerable sum for a writer.  However, his friend at a brokerage firm mocked him, saying, &ldquo;Your three years of hard work only earned you the equivalent of one month&rsquo;s salary for a broker in our company.&rdquo;</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Retail investors, your name is weakness.</p></blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">A Losing Game 
    <div id="a-losing-game" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#a-losing-game" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>The stock market comprises four main participants: intermediaries, major shareholders, large investors, and retail investors. Intermediaries include brokerage firms, the government, and information providers like newspapers, magazines, financial channels, and software companies.  Regardless of market outcomes, intermediaries always profit, and their profits increase with trading volume and frequency. Major shareholders are company management or those with significant equity stakes.  They have ample capital, resources, and information, giving them a winning edge. Large investors have more capital than retail investors, affording them a higher probability of success.</p>
<p><strong>Intermediaries and Large Investors Are the Winners</strong></p>
<p>The original purpose of financial markets was to channel funds from the public to businesses, which then invest and share profits with investors.  However, based on the analysis above, listed companies&rsquo; earnings are insufficient to cover the costs of intermediaries, let alone distribute profits to retail investors. For retail investors to profit, they must outperform the other three players.  In short-term trading, retail investors face intermediaries who always win, major shareholders who are guaranteed to win, and large investors with a higher probability of winning.  In this game, retail investors have no chance.</p>
<p>Most short-term trading failures are attributed to lack of skill or bad luck. In reality, a calm analysis reveals a guaranteed losing game.</p>
<p><strong>How to Win Without Fighting</strong></p>
<p>As a retail investor, how can you navigate this game against major shareholders, intermediaries, and large investors? The simplest solution: &ldquo;Don&rsquo;t play!&rdquo;</p>
<p>Listed companies, on average, generate profits annually, and successful companies grow increasingly profitable.  Therefore, not investing idle funds means missing out on long-term gains. The &ldquo;don&rsquo;t play&rdquo; strategy doesn&rsquo;t advocate avoiding the stock market altogether. Instead, it encourages investing and then leaving it alone, minimizing short-term trading.</p>
<p>By consistently investing available funds and holding long-term, investors can benefit from both company earnings and overall economic growth. This long-term holding strategy, avoiding the trading game played by intermediaries and large investors, can dramatically shift the investment landscape.  If investors buy and hold, intermediaries and major shareholders lose their advantage.  Even with substantial capital and insider information, their attempts to manipulate prices won&rsquo;t lure disciplined retail investors into their traps, eliminating the disadvantage faced by smaller investors.  Major shareholders, large investors, and retail investors would then stand on equal footing, sharing the benefits of long-term market growth.</p>
<p>This &ldquo;immovable mountain&rdquo; strategy transforms retail investors&rsquo; disadvantage into an advantage, shifting the disadvantage to the other players, particularly intermediaries. If investors stop trading frequently, brokerage firms lose transaction fees, the government loses taxes, and financial information providers lose business.  With no one to &ldquo;feed&rdquo; them, they might be forced to become buy-and-hold investors themselves.</p>
<p><strong>The correct investment philosophy is to profit together, not to defeat others.</strong>  The truly intelligent strategy is to avoid the competition.  As Sun Tzu&rsquo;s <em>Art of War</em> states, &ldquo;The supreme art of war is to subdue the enemy without fighting.&rdquo;  The primary consideration in investment strategy should not be defeating others but maximizing profits.</p>
<p>How can everyone win? If every investor adopts the strategy presented in this book—&ldquo;buy any stock, buy anytime, don&rsquo;t sell&rdquo;—and adheres to this simple principle, a win-win situation for all can be achieved.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Futures markets make casinos pale in comparison.</p></blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">Avoid Futures and Margin Trading 
    <div id="avoid-futures-and-margin-trading" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#avoid-futures-and-margin-trading" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>In 1995, a single trader&rsquo;s mismanagement of futures trading resulted in a $1.1 billion loss, causing the collapse of Barings Bank, one of Britain&rsquo;s oldest banks. This is not an isolated incident. With the rise of derivative financial products like futures and margin trading (forex, bond margin trading, etc.), such incidents of company collapses or personal bankruptcies due to mismanagement have become increasingly common.  Several high-performing listed companies in Taiwan have also faced near-bankruptcy due to losses in futures or margin trading.</p>
<p><strong>Either Big Wins or Big Losses</strong></p>
<p>What makes futures and margin trading so dangerous?  The core issue is the margin trading system itself, which has a high degree of leverage, leading to either significant gains or devastating losses in the short term. The high risk also encourages frequent trading, often multiple times a day. These transaction costs, relative to the margin, are extremely high.  The combined effect of frequent trading and high transaction costs pushes the returns from futures and margin trading into significant negative territory.</p>
<p>A saying circulates in the US securities market: &ldquo;Futures markets make casinos pale in comparison.&rdquo;  In other words, futures markets are even more of a gamble than casinos. After paying substantial transaction costs to intermediaries, what profits are left for investors?  The author has extensively studied investment history across various countries and has personally participated in the securities market for over a decade.  I have never heard of any investor consistently profiting from long-term participation in futures or margin trading.  On the contrary, almost everyone I know involved in such activities has ultimately lost money.</p>
<p>The purpose of futures and margin trading markets is to provide hedging tools for businesses.  Individual investors rarely have such hedging needs.  For them, these markets become &ldquo;even more of a gamble than casinos&rdquo; due to the temptation of short-term trading. The author strongly advises readers to avoid futures and margin trading entirely. If reading this book leads you to stay away from these activities, then the book&rsquo;s price has already been repaid, and the author&rsquo;s efforts have been worthwhile.</p>
<p><strong>Often a Waste of Effort</strong></p>
<p>The biggest obstacle to successful financial management is not the difficulty of understanding but the difficulty of implementing what is understood.  The principles discussed above are easy to grasp, but understanding doesn&rsquo;t guarantee implementation.  In the volatile investment world, faced with fluctuating prices, investors are often tempted by greed to chase short-term gains or driven by fear to react to price swings. They unknowingly fall into the trap of short-term trading. While the process can be thrilling, it often ends in wasted effort. The true beneficiaries of this game are usually the brokerage firms and the major shareholders manipulating the stocks, leaving retail investors with losses.</p>
<p><strong>Many people invest in stocks not to build wealth but to prove their intelligence, knowledge, and predictive abilities to others.</strong> They constantly analyze and research, overemphasizing market trends and predictions. This leads to impatience, chasing rising prices and selling during dips, attempting to profit from short-term fluctuations.  However, this constant buying and selling consumes time, energy, and money in the form of hefty transaction costs, while also creating opportunities for major shareholders and large investors to manipulate stocks.  The ultimate result is often a waste of time and money. While knowledge and experience might increase, wealth does not.</p>
<p><strong>To succeed in the fast-paced and lucrative investment world, you must cultivate self-discipline.</strong> The secret to investment success lies not in knowledge or skill, nor in intelligence or luck, but in self-control. Your investment acumen allows your assets to generate returns, and your patience in long-term holding allows the power of compounding to take you to new levels of wealth. Before succumbing to the temptation of short-term trading, ask yourself: &ldquo;Which wealthy person achieved their fortune through continuous short-term trading?&rdquo; and &ldquo;Which successful stock market investor didn&rsquo;t rely on long-term holding?&rdquo;</p>
<p><strong>Temporary Glory Leads to Crushing Debt</strong></p>
<p>In the history of the Taiwan stock market, it&rsquo;s difficult to find examples of individuals who built wealth through short-term trading. There are many who gained fame through short-term speculation, like Lei Bolong, but they often ended up heavily in debt and even faced imprisonment.  This is not unique to Taiwan; the same holds true for the US stock market.  The author has studied renowned American investors and has never found a prominent figure whose strategy primarily involved short-term trading.  Long-term wealth accumulation through short-term trading is virtually unheard of.</p>
<p>Stock investment is a vital path to personal wealth creation and a crucial source of long-term capital for businesses. However, using the wrong approach can lead to financial ruin instead of prosperity. Listed companies issue stocks to raise capital, and if these funds are then misused in speculative games, it can be detrimental to individuals, society, and the nation.</p>
<p>Stockholders are company owners with the inherent rights to profit sharing and residual asset distribution.  Therefore, the company&rsquo;s profits will eventually be distributed to shareholders as dividends. With patience, the wealth generated by the company ultimately belongs to the investors.</p>
<p>Therefore, I urge all readers to avoid the game of short-term trading.  Throughout history, no renowned investor has achieved wealth through short-term speculation. Based on the author&rsquo;s observations, the vast majority of those who engage in short-term trading lose money, and many face financial ruin.</p>
<p><em>1. True profits come not from short-term trading skills but from the discipline of long-term holding.</em></p>
<p><em>2. In the long run, short-term traders inevitably lose. There are no exceptions.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Personal Investment Bible: Investment Iron Law Ⅸ</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1731056005968/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1731056005968/</guid><description>This article explores common misconceptions in investment and financial management, particularly the reliance on forecasting and technical analysis. The author argues that technical analysis cannot consistently help investors achieve excess returns and instead often leads to the trap of short-term trading. The article advocates a long-term investment strategy of &amp;#39;buy any stock, buy anytime, and don&amp;#39;t sell,&amp;#39; emphasizing that the key to successful investing lies in selecting the right investment targets and holding them for the long term, rather than attempting to predict short-term market fluctuations.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[

<h2 class="relative group">Investment Iron Law Ⅸ: Grasping the General Market Trend 
    <div id="investment-iron-law--grasping-the-general-market-trend" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#investment-iron-law--grasping-the-general-market-trend" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>Basing investment decisions on technical analysis<br>
often indicates a lack of experience.<br>
In most cases, it won&rsquo;t make you money.</p></blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">The Blind Spots of Forecasting and Analysis 
    <div id="the-blind-spots-of-forecasting-and-analysis" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#the-blind-spots-of-forecasting-and-analysis" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>The reason many investors engage in frequent short-term trading, besides being attracted by price fluctuations, is mainly due to the so-called &ldquo;experts&rdquo; who flood the investment market with constant analysis and forecasts, providing investors with specious advice. This leads investors to frantically chase the &ldquo;buy low, sell high&rdquo; principle.  Let&rsquo;s discuss whether forecasting and analysis are truly effective. Can they genuinely help investors make a fortune?</p>
<p><strong>Is Technical Analysis Effective?</strong></p>
<p>In April 1993, the Taiwan <em>Economic Daily</em> published an article titled, &ldquo;Success in Stocks Depends on Entry and Exit Timing.&rdquo; This led many to believe that the most crucial task in investment analysis is determining the right moments to buy and sell.</p>
<p>The average investor believes the golden rule for wealth in the stock market is &ldquo;buy low, sell high.&rdquo;  They also believe the key to success lies in accurately grasping these timing opportunities. Consequently, countless investors try every means to predict future stock price trends to determine optimal buying and selling points.  In their quest for the Midas touch, various methods, from the scientific to the absurd, and even the supernatural, such as astrology and market horoscopes, have emerged.  Currently, the most widely used method is &ldquo;technical analysis.&rdquo;</p>
<p>In the author&rsquo;s humble opinion, technical analysis&rsquo;s popularity in the global investment market, and its continued prevalence among Taiwanese investors, stems from the fact that it appears sophisticated yet not overwhelmingly complex, thus attracting many novice investors.  These beginners often believe they must possess some secret technique to navigate the stock market, leading them to prioritize learning technical analysis upon entering the market.</p>
<p>Technical analysis originated from the Dow Theory in the 1930s, after which various technical analysis methods sprung up like mushrooms.  From the 1940s to the 1960s, technical analysis was highly popular in the US stock market.  However, with the advent of the Random Walk Theory, and the observation that most users of technical analysis ended up worse off, its popularity began to wane.  By the 1980s, when the author was studying investment analysis in the US stock market, established investment analysts rarely mentioned technical analysis.  At the time, if an investor claimed to use technical analysis for investment decisions, it implied inexperience and a high probability of losing money.</p>
<p>Technical analysis involves studying and analyzing past price trends and volume data to determine buying and selling timings. Its fundamental assumption is that history repeats itself. Therefore, by identifying the patterns of stock price movements, one can accurately predict future trends.</p>
<p><strong>Beating the Market is a Pipe Dream</strong></p>
<p>Numerous empirical studies by scholars have revealed many problems and controversies surrounding technical analysis.  Briefly summarized:</p>
<ul>
<li>
<ol>
<li>Historical patterns don&rsquo;t always repeat. Even if technical analysis has been effective for decades, it doesn&rsquo;t guarantee future success.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol start="2">
<li>If a particular technical analysis method consistently succeeds, its widespread adoption will eliminate its potential profits.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol start="3">
<li>The collective actions of technical analysts can create price patterns.  This means the price isn&rsquo;t reflecting a correct prediction but rather the analysts&rsquo; actions.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol start="4">
<li>Some technical indicators rely on comparisons with past data.  These values can change due to time and environment, making past standards inapplicable to the present.</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ul>
<p>If you were given a past stock chart and asked to devise a profitable investment strategy, everyone would understand &ldquo;buy low, sell high.&rdquo;  Profiting from trading in such a scenario would be easy.  However, investing is about the future. Future price movements are complex and unpredictable; no one possesses a future stock chart.  So, is &ldquo;buy low, sell high&rdquo; still a suitable investment strategy?  The answer is no.  The reason is simple: no one can predict market highs and lows in advance.</p>
<p>Using previously successful technical analysis methods doesn&rsquo;t guarantee future success in beating the market, as excess returns can be random.  Furthermore, concluding that technical analysis is effective based on occasional or random excess returns is misleading. While technical analysis might yield short-term gains, it cannot consistently outperform the market in the long run.</p>
<p>A student once asked me, if the market follows a random walk and technical analysis is ineffective, why are some technical analysis methods accurate at times?  Claiming technical analysis is ineffective means it can&rsquo;t generate long-term excess profits, not that its predictions are always wrong.  Technical analysis can sometimes be accurate, just like random guesses can be accurate.  Therefore, technical analysis isn&rsquo;t necessarily inaccurate; its accuracy is comparable to guessing.</p>
<p><strong>The Trap of Short-Term Trading</strong></p>
<p>Another significant drawback of technical analysis is that its methods focus on identifying buy and sell points.  These points constantly emerge, forcing investors to frequently buy and sell, trapping them in short-term trading and eroding returns through transaction costs. The ineffectiveness of technical analysis means that, on average, it doesn&rsquo;t generate excess returns over the long term. In other words, while sometimes accurate, it ultimately underperforms the market&rsquo;s average return (buy-and-hold strategy).</p>
<p>You might have used technical analysis methods with seemingly good results.  I admit some methods can be effective, but investors often overlook transaction costs.  Considering these costs, returns from technical analysis are unlikely to be high.  Furthermore, the effectiveness of any technical analysis method is inconsistent, making long-term high returns improbable.</p>
<p>Technical analysis exhausts investors, leading to significant losses.  Investors should abandon it and adopt a long-term &ldquo;buy-and-hold&rdquo; strategy to benefit from long-term market growth.  It&rsquo;s crucial to understand that market risk is inherent in any investment strategy.  Investors should be mentally prepared and avoid excessive optimism about short-term returns.  Profitable investing relies on correctly judging the overall market direction.  Obsessively seeking investment rules from past data, even if profitable, will likely incur time and effort costs exceeding the returns.</p>
<p>If you still believe technical analysis can lead to riches, ask yourself: who has become wealthy solely through technical analysis?</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Blind faith in predictions is worse than no prediction at all.
Prediction is more art than science.</p></blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">The Only Certainty is Uncertainty 
    <div id="the-only-certainty-is-uncertainty" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#the-only-certainty-is-uncertainty" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>The biggest mistake in investment strategies is overconfidence in prediction. If you&rsquo;ve tirelessly searched for prediction methods without success, or your developed methods are unreliable and unprofitable, don&rsquo;t be discouraged. All predictions face the same challenges.</p>
<p>Like you, forecasting experts cannot predict the future.  If they possessed a crystal ball, they would be wealthy, not making a living from predictions.  If this logic isn&rsquo;t convincing, ask yourself: &ldquo;Which self-made millionaire or consistently successful long-term investor has relied solely on prediction?&rdquo;  The answer is none.</p>
<p><strong>Investment Performance is Unrelated to Predictive Ability</strong></p>
<p>People often assume investment success hinges on predictive ability.  Those who predict better supposedly perform better, while investment failures are attributed to poor prediction. However, this isn&rsquo;t true. Most successful investors admit their inability to predict the future. They have no preconceived notions, and their success stems from sound strategies, not accurate predictions.</p>
<p>During my studies in the US, when I first dabbled in the US stock market, I shared the common belief that Wall Street analysts were remarkable and highly skilled at predicting market trends. After graduating from UC Berkeley in 1987, I left academia for a position at a major US brokerage firm, largely driven by the desire to learn from renowned analysts at Merrill Lynch.</p>
<p>At Merrill Lynch, I witnessed these analysts firsthand. After numerous interactions, I realized they couldn&rsquo;t accurately predict future stock prices. Some didn&rsquo;t even invest in stocks themselves. I often called analysts, asking which stocks to buy and when the market would rise. One analyst, perhaps tired of my persistent inquiries, frankly told me, &ldquo;Think about it. If I knew which stocks would rise and when the market would go up, would I be stuck working as an analyst?&rdquo;  It was then I understood that analysts don&rsquo;t possess predictive powers.</p>
<p>Upon returning to Taiwan, I observed that local newspapers and magazines were filled with &ldquo;Expert Predictions&rdquo; or &ldquo;Analyst Market Forecasts.&rdquo;  I interacted with several well-known analysts, studying their predictions carefully. My conclusion: there were no superior predictions in the Taiwan stock market.  These analysts and experts couldn&rsquo;t accurately grasp the market&rsquo;s future direction.</p>
<p><strong>Analysts Rely on Hype</strong></p>
<p>Why do so many analysts and experts constantly make predictions in the media? The reason is simple: supply follows demand. Readers crave these predictions, prompting newspapers and magazines to create dedicated columns.  Experts often publish predictions not because they possess foresight but because readers believe experts have superior knowledge of the future and eagerly seek their opinions.  Newspapers cater to this demand by soliciting expert articles.  Similarly, why do brokerage firms employ so many analysts to interpret market trends for clients? To meet customer needs.  In a competitive environment, analyst insights are considered a crucial service. Brokerage firms readily provide this service because research indicates that investors guided by experts tend towards short-term trading, generating higher commissions for the firms.</p>
<p>This demonstrates investors&rsquo; heavy reliance on expert predictions, which arise from investor demand. The problem is that the stock market is unpredictable.  No one can make accurate predictions, a widely acknowledged fact.  Yet, most investors still believe in expert forecasts.</p>
<p>A US poll once asked, &ldquo;Who lies to the public the most?&rdquo; The results: weather forecasters, stock analysts, and economic commentators.  This reveals not that expert predictions are always inaccurate but the public&rsquo;s unwavering faith in them, leading to heightened expectations.  These professions often require making future predictions under the assumption that &ldquo;experts must be able to predict; those who can&rsquo;t predict aren&rsquo;t experts.&rdquo;  This pressure compels many researchers and analysts to publish future predictions, despite the inherent uncertainty.  Being wrong is inevitable, and being perceived as liars arises from the public&rsquo;s initial belief in their predictions, leading to feelings of deception when they prove incorrect.</p>
<p>You might question this, citing instances of analysts who made remarkably accurate predictions, causing stocks to surge upon their recommendations.  However, have you noticed that these seemingly prophetic &ldquo;experts&rdquo; are rarely the same person and often disappear after a while?  In reality, these experts, unless backed by market manipulators who profit from deceiving retail investors, are simply experiencing probability at play.  Occasional streaks of accuracy are possible but not sustainable.</p>
<p><strong>Strategies to Lure Retail Investors</strong></p>
<p>Market manipulators aiming to pump and dump a stock, besides securing cooperation from major shareholders, must create a forecasting &ldquo;expert&rdquo; who, through media appearances, convinces retail investors to buy in.  As major shareholders lock up their shares and more investors join, it creates the illusion that the &ldquo;expert&rsquo;s&rdquo; predictions are coming true, causing the stock price to surge.</p>
<p>Joseph Granville was a popular technical analyst in the early 1980s.  His remarkably accurate market predictions in the late 1970s made him famous.  His large following gave him considerable market influence; his words could move the market by tens of points.  However, in early 1982, he predicted a major market crash, advising his followers to sell all their stocks.  Instead, the market surged from around 700 to over 1200 points within five months.  Those who heeded his advice missed a significant bull market, and Granville faded into obscurity.</p>
<p>I advise investors to avoid stocks being manipulated. Even if you make small profits initially, one loss could wipe out all gains and more.  Another reason: manipulated stocks involve major shareholder intervention.  These shareholders, instead of focusing on business operations and profits, are interested in quick gains through market manipulation, indicating poor management.  Such companies aren&rsquo;t worth investing in. Their scheme relies on retail investors&rsquo; money; retail investors have little chance of winning.  If retail investors could profit from this game, what would be the point for the major shareholders?</p>
<p>Another possibility for accurate predictions is simply probability.  Predictions are often diverse and contradictory, with some bullish, some bearish, and some expecting consolidation.  Inevitably, someone will be right, purely due to luck or higher guessing probability.</p>
<p><strong>More Wrong Guesses Than Right</strong></p>
<p>However, most people don&rsquo;t think this way.  When experts make several consecutive correct predictions, they gain credibility and are hailed as &ldquo;prophets.&rdquo;  People easily forget past incorrect predictions, treating the &ldquo;prophet&rsquo;s&rdquo; words as gospel.  This is extremely dangerous. Investors overlook the possibility of future incorrect predictions.</p>
<p>I&rsquo;m not entirely dismissing analysts and experts.  In the unpredictable investment world, many investors need expert guidance.  Analyst data and forecasts can be valuable reference material. My point is, regardless of your attitude towards expert predictions, remember: the future is dynamic and unpredictable.  Investment risk is an unavoidable reality and must be managed.</p>
<p>In early 1990, as the market peaked, most experts predicted continued growth. A prominent &ldquo;market prophet&rdquo; confidently proclaimed the market would reach 15,000 points within six months and 20,000 within a year.  Major media outlets reported this prediction.  The reality was starkly different.  Within six months, the market plummeted 2,000 points, shocking all experts.  Did these experts disappear?  No.  Newspapers and magazines still feature expert market forecasts.  The reason is simple: investors are &ldquo;used to&rdquo; hearing these predictions and many remain captivated by them.</p>
<p>I don&rsquo;t advocate completely ignoring predictions.  Predictions have value, and good predictions are worth considering.  However, whether you believe in predictions or not, and regardless of the predictor&rsquo;s reputation, remember: the future is fluid and unpredictable.  Investment risk is an inherent part of investing and must be managed.</p>
<p>You don&rsquo;t need predictive abilities to invest well or make money in the market. In this complex and volatile market, the only certainty is uncertainty.  In the investment world, profits come from choosing the right investments and holding them long-term, not from predicting market movements.  In summary, consider expert predictions, but remember they are just predictions.  Don&rsquo;t blindly trust them.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>There are no experts in the stock market, only winners and losers.</p></blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">Trust Yourself, Not the Experts 
    <div id="trust-yourself-not-the-experts" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#trust-yourself-not-the-experts" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>Some believe that lacking professional expertise makes achieving wealth through investment incredibly difficult. Yet, many who don&rsquo;t understand stocks or real estate still achieve financial success through investing.  Most successful investors aren&rsquo;t investment professionals, and investment professionals aren&rsquo;t necessarily successful investors.  This shows that expertise isn&rsquo;t a prerequisite for wealth creation through investment.</p>
<p>Investment and financial management aren&rsquo;t inherently complex.  The perceived complexity and reliance on experts stem from investors&rsquo; inability to cope with uncertainty, overcomplicating simple matters and turning financial management into a source of anxiety and confusion.  This anxiety hinders rational decision-making, leading people to constantly seek external opinions.</p>
<p><strong>10 Experts, 11 Opinions</strong></p>
<p>The inability to handle uncertainty creates the illusion that foresight or profound analytical skills are necessary for successful investing, leading to the belief that only &ldquo;experts&rdquo; can manage finances effectively. Consequently, many entrust their financial decisions to experts, who often offer conflicting &ldquo;expert opinions.&rdquo; Ten experts can have eleven different views, further complicating the investment world and adding to investor confusion.</p>
<p>Basing your financial decisions solely on expert opinions is extremely dangerous. Ultimately, investment responsibility lies with the individual. Investors should enhance their financial literacy and become their own experts.  Financial management doesn&rsquo;t require extensive professional knowledge. By following a few basic principles outlined in this book and acting accordingly, you can achieve wealth without relying on experts.  With the right investment philosophy, you might even outperform them.</p>
<p>Therefore, I urge investors to take immediate action, start investing, and stop asking questions like &ldquo;When will the market rise?&rdquo; &ldquo;Which stock should I buy?&rdquo; or &ldquo;Should I sell my xxx stock now?&rdquo;  These questions are pointless; no one knows the correct answers.</p>
<p>In 1983, when I began my doctoral studies at UC Berkeley, I started helping Taiwanese entrepreneurs invest in US stocks.  To excel at this, I dedicated immense effort to stock analysis, often neglecting sleep and meals. For one to two years, I practically lived in the Berkeley Haas School of Business library, devouring every investment book and analyzing all available stock information. I learned various technical, fundamental, and market analysis techniques.  To develop my unique investment analysis and prediction methods, I utilized Berkeley&rsquo;s advanced computers and extensive stock databases, writing programs to simulate various investment approaches.  This proved futile; I couldn&rsquo;t find a satisfactory method.  It was all for naught.</p>
<p>If anyone truly knew when the market would rise or which stock to buy, they would be wealthy enough not to need a job as an analyst or expert.  I reiterate: even without knowing &ldquo;when the market will rise&rdquo; or &ldquo;which stock to buy,&rdquo; you can still achieve wealth through investing.  Stop wasting time on these questions. Countless people have dedicated their lives to researching them since the inception of the stock market. They became stock experts but didn&rsquo;t achieve wealth through investing.</p>
<p><strong>Inaction and Effortless Gains</strong></p>
<p>Financial management doesn&rsquo;t require excessive time. Those who spend less time on it often perform better.</p>
<p>Statistics show that Taiwanese stock investors spend an average of 3.12 hours daily on stock analysis and market watching. Is stock picking difficult? Is making money in the stock market challenging?  Constantly chasing price fluctuations, what are your returns?  Those who diligently study stocks often lose the most money.</p>
<p>A common investor mistake is giving up.  They eagerly enter during bull markets and become disheartened during bear markets, abandoning the market entirely.  Lacking patience and perseverance, they rarely succeed.  Conversely, those with less financial acumen, admitting their inability to time the market, often persevere and ultimately fare better.</p>
<p>The path to investment wealth is simple: effortless gains. The investment strategy presented—&ldquo;buy any stock, buy anytime, don&rsquo;t sell&rdquo;—can be summarized as &ldquo;do nothing, gain effortlessly.&rdquo;</p>
<p>Who wouldn&rsquo;t want effortless gains? Surprisingly, most investors can&rsquo;t achieve this.  &ldquo;There&rsquo;s no such thing as a free lunch&rdquo; is a widely known principle. Applying this to investment, people assume they must master complex techniques and work harder than others to profit.  Intuitively, they believe more knowledge and effort equate to higher returns. This might hold true in other areas, but in finance, the opposite is often true. Knowledge and effort don&rsquo;t significantly contribute to investment returns.  Knowing more and constantly monitoring the market encourages impulsive trading, leading to &ldquo;effort without gain.&rdquo;</p>
<p><strong>Inaction is Superior to Action</strong></p>
<p>Even investment gurus like Warren Buffett and Peter Lynch admit they can&rsquo;t predict market movements. Admitting ignorance might seem foolish, but it&rsquo;s the beginning of financial wisdom.  Being &ldquo;foolish&rdquo; enough to &ldquo;buy any stock, buy anytime, don&rsquo;t sell&rdquo; is the starting point of wealth creation. Confucius said, &ldquo;Great wisdom appears foolish.&rdquo;  This refers to highly learned individuals who achieve mastery through natural means, without contrivance or cunning.  They appear unintelligent but are truly wise.  Lao Tzu also said, &ldquo;Great skill appears clumsy,&rdquo; and advocated for &ldquo;governing by non-interference.&rdquo;  This strategy, applied to the volatile investment environment, is a sound approach. Unless you have strong conviction about future trends, it&rsquo;s better to ignore the chaos and remain inactive.</p>
<p>Therefore, you don&rsquo;t need to be an investment expert or possess sophisticated techniques.  &ldquo;Do nothing, gain effortlessly&rdquo; is the key to financial wealth. You might think this sounds too simple, even boring.  Indeed, it is. But this simplicity is the path to riches and becoming a millionaire.  Before acting, ask yourself: &ldquo;Do I want wealth or to be a stock market expert?&rdquo;  If you want wealth through stocks, emulate the many who became rich by simply investing and then ignoring the market.  Decades later, compounding will make you wealthy. You could also dedicate yourself to becoming a stock market expert, but this rarely leads to riches.</p>
<p>My point is, even without knowing &ldquo;when the market will rise&rdquo; or &ldquo;which stock to buy,&rdquo; you can still achieve wealth through investing. Short-term market fluctuations are unpredictable, but the long-term trend is upward. Long-term investing is the key to profit.</p>
<p>&ldquo;Buy any stock, buy anytime, don&rsquo;t sell&rdquo;—so simple, effortless, and seemingly undeserved.  While it feels like unearned gain, don&rsquo;t feel guilty.  Investing in stocks contributes to economic development.  Constant trading harms individual wealth and offers no benefit to the overall economy or society.</p>
<p><strong>Easier Said Than Done</strong></p>
<p>Some worry and ask, &ldquo;You advise against saving money in banks.  If your book becomes a bestseller and this idea spreads, wouldn&rsquo;t it cause a nationwide bank run?&rdquo; This is an unnecessary concern. I&rsquo;ve been advocating against saving money in banks for three years, even before this book&rsquo;s publication. Many who hear this idea nod in agreement, as if enlightened, yet days, months, or years later, their money remains untouched in bank accounts.</p>
<p>Others question whether my &ldquo;buy any stock, buy anytime, don&rsquo;t sell&rdquo; theory, if widely adopted, would force brokerage firms to close, depriving the government of transaction taxes.  Again, there&rsquo;s no need for such concerns.  Those who frequently engage in short-term trading in stocks, futures, or margin accounts, even after understanding that it only benefits intermediaries, often can&rsquo;t resist continuing their behavior.  Like gambling, everyone knows the odds are stacked against them, yet gambling persists.</p>
<p><strong>I understand that &ldquo;don&rsquo;t save money in banks,&rdquo; &ldquo;avoid short-term trading,&rdquo; and &ldquo;diversify and hold long-term,&rdquo; are simple in theory but difficult in practice.  Nevertheless, I sincerely hope readers can integrate knowledge and action, diversifying most of their assets into stocks and real estate, holding them long-term. Achieving financial freedom is within reach.</strong></p>
]]></content:encoded></item></channel></rss>