<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Children's Education on QQQ Investor</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/tags/childrens-education/</link><description>Recent content in Children's Education on QQQ Investor</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 30 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jomonylw.github.io/en/tags/childrens-education/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>00529 Raising Children is Better Than Maintaining a House: The Truth About Reverse Mortgages and Retirement Cash Flow</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1756605737350/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1756605737350/</guid><description>In this session, Teacher James shares the core mindset of investing: the market always goes up, and investors should focus on their own lives rather than external distractions. The content covers life philosophy, children&amp;#39;s education, asset allocation, reverse mortgages, and pledged loans, emphasizing the importance of intrinsic value and a long-term perspective.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<lite-youtube videoid="6znudRqitcQ" playlabel="6znudRqitcQ" params=""></lite-youtube>



<h2 class="relative group">I. Main Theme 
    <div id="i-main-theme" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-main-theme" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This session&rsquo;s theme revolves around &ldquo;The market always goes up, live for yourself.&rdquo; The core idea is that the essence of investing is very simple: believe in the market&rsquo;s long-term upward trend and hold on. The real challenge is psychological. Therefore, we should not be disturbed by short-term market fluctuations, financial news, world events, or other external information. Instead, we should shift our focus back to life itself—concentrating on health, happiness, family, and personal values, viewing money as a tool to achieve freedom and abundance in life, not as the ultimate goal.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">II. Briefing Content 
    <div id="ii-briefing-content" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii-briefing-content" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Life is More Important Than Investing 
    <div id="life-is-more-important-than-investing" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#life-is-more-important-than-investing" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Wealth and Happiness</strong>: Wealth is a gift, happiness is a human right, and health is the foundation. Money is just a tool to achieve a free, abundant, and happy life; investing itself is not the purpose of life.</li>
<li><strong>Children&rsquo;s Education</strong>:
<ul>
<li>Focus on cultivating the right values in children (not stealing, robbing, breaking the law, or taking drugs) and appreciating their talents, rather than just focusing on academic performance.</li>
<li>Parents should not impose their own expectations or unfulfilled dreams on their children, such as forcing them to study abroad. This puts immense pressure on the children.</li>
<li>A true home is where the parents are. Children should be encouraged to pursue their own ideals, not to satisfy their parents&rsquo; expectations.</li>
<li>Compared to buying a house for a child, it&rsquo;s better to have and raise the child first, because wealth can be created, but childbirth has a time window.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Live in the Present, Focus on Yourself</strong>:
<ul>
<li>In life, focus on your own goals. Don&rsquo;t get sidetracked by trivial matters (like fussing over exchange rates or searching for better investments), as this will only delay the process of achieving financial freedom.</li>
<li>Teacher James uses his own management experience as an example: At the company, he focused on only the three most important tasks each day. Once completed, he could go home. This approach is efficient and goal-oriented. Conversely, trying to do everything results in being busy all day with nothing accomplished.</li>
<li>Live your own life, not one led by the media and online information. Cutting off useless external information will not result in any loss.</li>
<li>True living is about &ldquo;presence&rdquo;—living in the moment. Whether eating, gardening, or traveling, you should be fully engaged and feel the beauty of life itself. External distractions, like what Trump said, have no bearing on our lives or investments.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Investment Strategies and Financial Tools 
    <div id="investment-strategies-and-financial-tools" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#investment-strategies-and-financial-tools" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Do the Right Thing and Persist</strong>: The secret to successful investing is to &ldquo;do the right thing and stick with it for the long term.&rdquo; For example, invest whenever you have money, regardless of the exchange rate, without timing the market. Once you have identified the right path (like investing in QQQ), you should forge ahead without looking back.</li>
<li><strong>Reverse Mortgage</strong>:
<ul>
<li>This is an excellent tool for &ldquo;activating assets&rdquo; and is not just for people short on cash.</li>
<li>It provides a steady cash flow, as if the house is working for you. This money can be used for investment, thus increasing your assets while retaining the property.</li>
<li>It&rsquo;s a great option for parents with insufficient retirement funds, allowing them to live better lives without their children needing to provide financial support.</li>
<li>For elderly individuals with weak financial management skills and only one house left, a reverse mortgage is more stable than selling the house to invest, avoiding the risk of losing their last home.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>The Power of Borrowing to Invest</strong>:
<ul>
<li>An example: If you use your own $30,000 to buy a car, the potential value of that money in 50 years (about $32 million) is lost. But if you take a pledged loan of $30,000 to buy the car and invest your own $30,000, in 50 years you will have $32 million in assets, while the debt is only $340,000.</li>
<li>Conclusion: Make good use of financial leverage. Borrow for consumption or investment, and let your own money continue to grow.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Example of Leveraged Asset Allocation</strong>:
<ul>
<li>Teacher James shares his asset allocation model: 40% QQQ (1x), 15% QLD (2x), 10% TQQQ (3x), and 35% cash.</li>
<li>The Beta value of this portfolio is calculated as: (40% * 1) + (15% * 2) + (10% * 3) = 0.4 + 0.3 + 0.3 = 1.0.</li>
<li>This allocation, while having an overall risk comparable to holding 100% QQQ (Beta=1.0), retains a large amount of cash (35%) for risk control and rebalancing during market downturns.</li>
<li><strong>Key Point</strong>: Any asset allocation that includes leveraged funds <strong>must</strong> implement a smart rebalancing strategy.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">III. Q&amp;A Session 
    <div id="iii-qa-session" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii-qa-session" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Cady 
    <div id="cady" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#cady" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: She once went against everyone&rsquo;s advice to support her sister&rsquo;s dream of a working holiday in Australia. Now, her sister is living very happily in Germany. She has come to realize that since her child doesn&rsquo;t want to study abroad, she&rsquo;ll save the money for her own study tours in retirement. She is practicing not imposing her expectations on her child.
<ul>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo;s Comment: That&rsquo;s excellent. One must live for oneself, not for others. Don&rsquo;t impose your expectations on people. For children, parents only have the duty to agree, not the right to disagree. Your child&rsquo;s life is not under your jurisdiction.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chen Feng 
    <div id="chen-feng" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chen-feng" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing:
<ol>
<li>He has compiled his years of learning from the teacher into the &ldquo;Great Way is Simple Investment Method&rdquo; and created the &ldquo;Chen Feng Leads the Way&rdquo; website to share it.</li>
<li>He summarizes the CLEC investment method into three simple but not easy things: <strong>Asset Allocation</strong> (70/30 for beginners, eventually 433), <strong>Rebalancing</strong> (once a year), and <strong>Living off Pledged Loans</strong>.</li>
<li>He believes the hardest part of investing is psychology, which is why the teacher insists on holding weekly classes to help everyone adjust their mindset.</li>
<li>He announced his official retirement in August 2025 and will have more time in the future to share his experiences and help more people achieve the ideal that &ldquo;wealth is a gift, happiness is a human right.&rdquo;</li>
</ol>
<ul>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo;s Comment: Thank you to Chen Feng (a senior executive at a high-tech company in Taiwan) for his sharing and contributions. He has done a lot for the community (website, AI training) and actively helps everyone in the LINE group. Teacher James announced that he is making him a community Moderator.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Hai Wai Gu Zhong 
    <div id="hai-wai-gu-zhong" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#hai-wai-gu-zhong" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: After renting out a house he owns, he recently took it back for his own use and found being a landlord very troublesome. He had to deal with various damages and cleaning for walls, doors, and windows, and deeply realized that the actual return on real estate investment is not as high as it seems.</li>
<li>Question 1: Since the house was bought by his family, he can&rsquo;t sell it freely. He&rsquo;s thinking of taking out a mortgage-like loan on the house (interest-only payments) and investing the cash into 00662. Is this idea feasible?
<ul>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo;s Reply: Absolutely correct, you should do it immediately. Borrow any money you can as soon as possible. The power of borrowing to invest is immense. He demonstrated the huge opportunity cost difference by calculating the 50-year outcomes of buying a car with $30,000 versus borrowing $1 million.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2: The teacher advises young people to invest first and buy a house later when they are &ldquo;old.&rdquo; What age does &ldquo;old&rdquo; approximately refer to?
<ul>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo;s Reply: You will know when the time comes; you don&rsquo;t need someone else to tell you. When you are wealthy enough, buying a house will be as easy as buying slippers, and you can even use borrowed money to buy one casually. At that point, you could also choose to live in a luxurious retirement community—the choice is yours.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">May 
    <div id="may" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#may" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question: She is in her fifties/sixties and wants to take out a pledged loan in China on her fully paid-off house, but banks only offer a maximum term of 3-5 years, which is too risky. How does the teacher obtain long-term loans?
<ul>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo;s Reply: The best long-term loan is a &ldquo;stock-pledged loan,&rdquo; which can be structured to never pay back the principal, and even the interest can be rolled into the principal. Mortgages and personal loans have fixed terms and are not suitable. For short-term loans (like 3-5 years), don&rsquo;t borrow unless you are confident you can repay even if the market crashes. He suggests she sell her house in China, even at a lower price, as long as she can liquidate it. Abroad, she can try using Interactive Brokers (IB) for stock-pledged loans.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Rui 
    <div id="rui" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#rui" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Inspired by the teacher, he successfully borrowed a large sum of money from the bank against his assets and discovered that car loans don&rsquo;t count towards his debt ratio. He plans to use a 2% pledged loan to pay off the car loan, thereby investing more funds into the 433 allocation. He now feels that the speed of his asset growth has surpassed his annual salary.</li>
<li>Question: He saw a YouTuber say that Chinese engineers in Silicon Valley are unhappy due to endless &ldquo;comparisons&rdquo; (of degrees, companies, salaries, houses, wives, children). As someone with a master&rsquo;s degree, he also felt insecure in an environment full of PhDs. How does the teacher view &ldquo;comparison&rdquo;? And how can the teacher confidently pay his subordinates a higher salary than his own?
<ul>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo;s Reply: Quoting Munger, &ldquo;Envy is a really stupid sin.&rdquo; Don&rsquo;t compare; the key is a strong inner self. You must affirm from within that you are the best. The way you see yourself is more important than how others see you. He uses his own experience of leading a team of PhDs without a PhD himself, and designing Microsoft&rsquo;s Media architecture and the computer Hibernate patent, to illustrate that success is unrelated to academic degrees but is related to confidence and intellect.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Mindy 
    <div id="mindy" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#mindy" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question 1: She is 60 and retired. As recommended, she has allocated TQQQ in her smaller Roth IRA account. However, the AI on Chen Feng&rsquo;s website advises her not to use leverage at her age and to keep many years of cash. How much cash should a retiree actually keep? Is it 30% or 15 years&rsquo; worth of living expenses?
<ul>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo;s Reply: Don&rsquo;t fully trust the AI; follow the teacher&rsquo;s instruction. Her allocation (TQQQ in Roth, cash in Traditional IRA) is correct. Retirees should keep <strong>30% cash</strong>, which is approximately equivalent to <strong>15 years&rsquo; worth</strong> of living expenses. This is not due to pessimism about the market; on the contrary, the market may rise even faster in the future. This is the result of the CLEC investment system&rsquo;s &ldquo;DNA evolution&rdquo; after being tested by the market, making it better able to withstand future extreme risks.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2: She saw other financial bloggers advocating for market timing using &ldquo;economic indicator signals&rdquo; and is worried that buying TQQQ at a market high will lead to significant decay.
<ul>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo;s Reply: Don&rsquo;t refer to other people&rsquo;s investment systems; they won&rsquo;t be compatible. Within the 433 asset allocation, there is no so-called &ldquo;decay&rdquo; problem for TQQQ because the large cash reserve acts as a buffer, and the actual drop of the portfolio during a downturn will be less than that of 100% QQQ.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Tina 
    <div id="tina" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#tina" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question 1: She is 43 and just immigrated to the US. Her 401k and IRA accounts have very little money. To implement the 433 allocation, it seems she can only buy leveraged ETFs in a taxable brokerage account. Is this acceptable?
<ul>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo;s Reply: Yes. In the early stages when funds are insufficient, you can use a 433 allocation in a brokerage account to maintain a higher Beta and sufficient cash. Although rebalancing will generate taxes, the priority is to &ldquo;make money first.&rdquo; However, you must <strong>do smart rebalancing every year</strong>, because a 30% leveraged position is very risky and cannot be left unattended.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2: For dollar-cost averaging for an 11-year-old child, the teacher previously recommended QLD. Why not the better TQQQ?
<ul>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo;s Reply: TQQQ has extremely high volatility. Calculating from the 2000 peak, it might take over 20 years to break even, whereas QLD breaks even faster. For a child&rsquo;s long-term investment of over 20 years, both are acceptable, but the premise is that you <strong>must persist in buying continuously</strong>, regardless of market ups and downs. If the investment horizon is uncertain or you want to be more conservative, QLD is the safer choice.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Xin 
    <div id="xin" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#xin" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question: Should high-net-worth families be concerned about the 40% US estate tax? Should they set up an irrevocable trust in advance to avoid it?
<ul>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo;s Reply: First, the US estate tax exemption has been permanently set at $15 million per person, meaning a couple has a $30 million exemption. Most families don&rsquo;t need to worry. Second, he does not recommend setting up an irrevocable charitable trust because they usually require an annual donation of 5% of assets, which is a huge burden and constraint on the children. A better way is to use the annual gift tax exclusion (e.g., $20,000) and start gifting early. Over the long term, the growth of the gifted assets will far exceed the estate tax exemption amount.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Bill 
    <div id="bill" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#bill" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question: When the market drops and rebalancing is needed for the TQQQ in a Roth account, if the annual contribution limit of $7,000 is not enough, can funds be converted from a Traditional IRA?
<ul>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo;s Reply: Yes, that is exactly the correct operation. You can use the annual contribution limit, and if that&rsquo;s not enough, use a Roth Conversion to supplement the cash.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Lucy 
    <div id="lucy" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#lucy" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question: She (in Canada) obtained extra cash for investment through a home refinance. Can the interest on this portion of the loan be deducted as an investment expense for tax purposes?
<ul>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo;s Reply: Only when you sell an asset and generate a realized capital gain do you have taxable investment income against which related expenses might be deducted. If you just hold and don&rsquo;t sell, there is no taxable event. Canada&rsquo;s Tax-Free Savings Account (TFSA) is similar to the US Roth IRA, and investment and rebalancing operations should be conducted within it.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Vincent 
    <div id="vincent" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#vincent" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question (from the comment section): With 30 million TWD in assets, if I withdraw 2% for living expenses, 600,000 per year is not enough. Do I have to wait until my assets double to 60 million to live a good life?
<ul>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo;s Reply: Not necessarily. You can increase the withdrawal rate by adjusting your asset allocation. For example, you can change the 433 allocation (Beta=1) to a 424 or 514 allocation with a higher cash percentage, which lowers the portfolio&rsquo;s volatility (Beta&lt;1). Once the volatility is reduced, the annual withdrawal rate can be safely increased to 3% or 3.5%.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Student 
    <div id="student" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#student" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question (from the comment section): Is it okay for a 12-year-old child to dollar-cost average into 00670L (a 2x leveraged ETF in Taiwan)?
<ul>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo;s Reply: If you can ensure continuous investment for over 20 years (e.g., until age 32), it is acceptable. However, if the investment horizon is shorter (e.g., until they become independent at 24), it is recommended to do half-and-half (half leveraged, half non-leveraged) or invest entirely in the non-leveraged ETF to reduce risk.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">IV. Highlighted Quotes 
    <div id="iv-highlighted-quotes" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv-highlighted-quotes" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>Wealth is a gift, happiness is a human right, and health is the foundation of life.
&ndash; Teacher James</p></blockquote>
<p>Context: At the beginning of the class, the teacher explained the relationship between investment and life, emphasizing that our ultimate goals are happiness and health, while wealth is an innate right and a tool to achieve those goals.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Are you living your own life, or a life defined by the external environment? Don&rsquo;t be led by outside information.
&ndash; Teacher James</p></blockquote>
<p>Context: The teacher advised students not to be engrossed in media and online information all day, as that is living a life defined by others, not their own. One should return to their inner self and focus on their own life.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Envy is a really stupid sin.
&ndash; Teacher James (quoting Charlie Munger)</p></blockquote>
<p>Context: When answering a student&rsquo;s question about &ldquo;comparison,&rdquo; the teacher quoted Munger&rsquo;s famous line, pointing out that comparing oneself to others is a source of unhappiness and a foolish act.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>You are what you think you are, and that is more important than how others see you. If you don&rsquo;t even believe in what you are, how can others believe in what you are?
&ndash; Teacher James</p></blockquote>
<p>Context: The teacher encouraged students to build self-confidence. He believes that personal value is determined by self-perception, not by external evaluations or labels like academic degrees.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>When borrowing money, we don&rsquo;t fear high interest rates; we fear that the term is too short.
&ndash; Teacher James</p></blockquote>
<p>Context: When answering a question about loans, the teacher stressed the importance of the loan term. As long as the term is long enough, even with a higher interest rate, the long-term growth of assets is sufficient to cover the costs, whereas short-term loans carry immense risk.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Be clear about what you want. For everything else that is different from what you want, you don&rsquo;t need to care, you don&rsquo;t need to mind, and you don&rsquo;t need to compare.
&ndash; Chen Feng</p></blockquote>
<p>Context: Student Chen Feng shared this perspective when explaining how he avoids the &ldquo;comparison&rdquo; mindset. He believes that as long as you are clear about your own goals, you will not be disturbed by external factors unrelated to them.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>If you keep following our DNA, your DNA will evolve. This is how you can prepare for potential future risks and changes.
&ndash; Teacher James</p></blockquote>
<p>Context: When explaining why he now recommends holding more cash (30%), the teacher compared the CLEC investment system to a biological DNA. This system continuously evolves after being tested by the market, becoming better adapted to various future environments. Therefore, students need to keep learning to acquire this &ldquo;evolved&rdquo; and robust system.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>If you are 100% in leveraged funds, you might go to hell; it would be like a dream that ends in 30 years.
&ndash; Teacher James</p></blockquote>
<p>Context: When reminding students of the risks of leveraged funds, the teacher seriously pointed out that being fully invested in leveraged funds without asset allocation and rebalancing could ultimately lead to a total loss in a major market crash.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">V. Summary 
    <div id="v-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#v-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This session once again emphasized the core of the CLEC investment philosophy: investing is simple, mindset is supreme. Starting from a high-level life philosophy, Teacher James guided everyone to shift their focus from the complex noise of the market to the simple purity of their personal lives, fostering the belief to &ldquo;live for yourself.&rdquo; The course not only shared profound insights on children&rsquo;s education and self-worth realization but also delved into the practical application of financial tools like &ldquo;reverse mortgages&rdquo; and &ldquo;pledged loans.&rdquo; It also provided detailed explanations on the risk control and long-term operational principles of asset allocation (especially the 433 strategy involving leveraged funds). Through active questions and sharing from students, many practical confusions—such as allocation in different accounts, tax issues, and retirement cash flow planning—were clearly answered. Ultimately, the course returned to a fundamental point: build a strong inner self and adhere to the right principles, and wealth will naturally follow.</p>

  



<div
  
    class="flex px-4 py-3 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900"
  >

  <span
    
      class="text-primary-400 ltr:pr-3 rtl:pl-3 flex items-center"
    >

    

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M506.3 417l-213.3-364c-16.33-28-57.54-28-73.98 0l-213.2 364C-10.59 444.9 9.849 480 42.74 480h426.6C502.1 480 522.6 445 506.3 417zM232 168c0-13.25 10.75-24 24-24S280 154.8 280 168v128c0 13.25-10.75 24-23.1 24S232 309.3 232 296V168zM256 416c-17.36 0-31.44-14.08-31.44-31.44c0-17.36 14.07-31.44 31.44-31.44s31.44 14.08 31.44 31.44C287.4 401.9 273.4 416 256 416z"/></svg>

  </span>


  </span>

  <span
    
      class="dark:text-neutral-300"
    ><strong>Disclaimer:</strong> This article is for personal learning notes only and does not constitute any investment advice.</span>
</div>

]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>00493 Financial Risks and Investment Wisdom: How to Accumulate and Utilize Assets; Stock Pledge and Asset Allocation: Smart Choices for Risk Reduction</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1733026874385/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1733026874385/</guid><description>In this episode, James reiterates the current market highs and advises investors to remain patient, adhere to long-term investment strategies, and avoid being swayed by short-term fluctuations. He also addresses questions from students regarding asset allocation, stock pledging, insurance, annuities, children&amp;#39;s education, and how to cope with market volatility, sharing his understanding of Modern Monetary Theory (MMT).</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<lite-youtube videoid="V0d8y8-Jl-w" playlabel="V0d8y8-Jl-w" params=""></lite-youtube>



<h2 class="relative group">I. Main Topic 
    <div id="i-main-topic" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-main-topic" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>The market continues to reach new highs.  Investing doesn&rsquo;t require constant attention; the key is to stick to a long-term investment strategy, maintain a well-diversified asset allocation, and remain patient. The real risk isn&rsquo;t short-term volatility, but the inability to accumulate sufficient wealth over the long term, and not knowing how to utilize accumulated wealth effectively.  Furthermore, it&rsquo;s crucial to be wary of various financial traps and maintain rational investment practices.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">II. Briefing Content 
    <div id="ii-briefing-content" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii-briefing-content" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Market Trends and Investment Strategies 
    <div id="market-trends-and-investment-strategies" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#market-trends-and-investment-strategies" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>The market is at a new high. Don&rsquo;t waste time over-analyzing; stick to long-term investing, buy and hold.  The market generally trends upwards; instead of predicting pullbacks, enter the market early.</li>
<li>Investing doesn&rsquo;t require excessive time. After placing your order, step away and let time work its magic through compounding.</li>
<li>Be wary of scams. Don&rsquo;t trust any investment advice that guarantees stable returns or daily gains.  Be extremely cautious of &ldquo;guaranteed profit&rdquo; schemes.</li>
<li>Ignore the advice of financial advisors and insurance agents. They rarely have the investor&rsquo;s best interests at heart and are often motivated by their own profits. Many financial products are designed to benefit the seller, not the investor.</li>
<li>Investing isn&rsquo;t simple. Even asset allocation within a Nasdaq 100 index fund requires in-depth research and adjustments based on individual circumstances.</li>
<li>Investors should always remain optimistic. The market will eventually rise. Patiently await wealth accumulation. Time is an investor&rsquo;s friend.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Risk Management and Wealth Goals 
    <div id="risk-management-and-wealth-goals" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#risk-management-and-wealth-goals" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>The biggest risks are not market fluctuations, but the failure to accumulate sufficient wealth over the long term and not knowing how to utilize accumulated wealth effectively. The ultimate goal of investing is to achieve financial freedom and enjoy life.</li>
<li>Avoid the instinctive reaction to short-term losses. Overcome fear and don&rsquo;t panic sell. Market downturns are normal and present buying opportunities.</li>
<li>View bear markets as opportunities. Buying low translates to higher future returns. Learn to think contrarily and utilize market fluctuations for mindless rebalancing.</li>
<li>The investment objective is to mitigate the risk of financial hardship, not to maximize returns. A sound investment strategy is more crucial than chasing high returns.</li>
<li>Choose a simple, low-cost, passive index investment strategy, such as a Nasdaq 100 index fund, and hold a portion in cash to maintain psychological balance and cope with market volatility.</li>
<li>Holding safe assets (like certificates of deposit and money market funds) can mitigate short-term risks, stabilize emotions during market fluctuations, and provide a sense of security.</li>
<li>The proportion of safe assets held should be adjusted based on age and risk tolerance. Retirees are advised to hold cash equivalent to 5 years of living expenses, while those yet to retire can hold more.</li>
<li>Young people should prioritize term life insurance to protect their families and avoid other types of insurance to prevent being misled by insurance companies.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Other Advice 
    <div id="other-advice" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#other-advice" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Be skeptical of all information, especially regarding money. Learn to think independently and don&rsquo;t blindly trust so-called &ldquo;experts.&rdquo;</li>
<li>Don&rsquo;t buy insurance or annuities for investment purposes. The essence of insurance is protection, not investment; annuities have high fees and low returns.</li>
<li>Don&rsquo;t disclose your wealth to your children. Encourage them to strive independently and create wealth through their own abilities.</li>
<li>Engage in rational discussions, view investments with a mathematical mindset, and analyze investment results with data.</li>
<li>Avoid over-investing in real estate. Maintain ample cash flow. Real estate has poor liquidity and is difficult to liquidate.</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">III. Q&amp;A Session 
    <div id="iii-qa-session" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii-qa-session" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Ke An 
    <div id="ke-an" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ke-an" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: 16 years old, living in the Netherlands.  Thanked James for his investment methods, which allowed her parents to take her on trips throughout Europe. She also shared that she finds her business management classes easier to understand than her classmates, thanks to James&rsquo;s teachings.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s comments: Praised Ke An&rsquo;s travel experiences and learning attitude, encouraging her to continue learning and explore her career interests.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question: Concerned about starting investing late, wants to open an account and start investing soon. Has saved NT$200,000 and plans to invest in 00662.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s reply: Affirmed the advantage of starting to invest at 16, emphasizing that time is the greatest asset.  Advised her to balance learning, life, and investment, and to enjoy her youth.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Ji Ya 
    <div id="ji-ya" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ji-ya" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question: Has savings equivalent to 8 years of living expenses. Working 40 hours a week only covers expenses. Driving for Uber could increase income but wants more free time. Unsure how to balance work and life and whether early retirement is possible. Is currently 42 years old.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s reply: In 15 years, the 8x annual expenses will grow to 50x due to compounding, enabling retirement. Suggested a BETA of 1.2 to increase investment returns, or driving for Uber a few hours a week to accelerate wealth accumulation and achieve early retirement.  Emphasized that pursuing early retirement shouldn&rsquo;t be the sole focus and that finding a balance between work and life is important. Health is paramount.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chun Xia 
    <div id="chun-xia" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chun-xia" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question 1: Plans to invest a loan of NT$7 million and aims for a return of NT$20-30 million within 10-15 years. Should the investment be lump-sum or staggered?  Has additional monthly income of NT$30,000-40,000.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s reply: Based on a 14% annualized return, there will be NT$67 million after 15 years, reaching the NT$20-30 million target within 10 years. Recommended a lump-sum investment to capitalize on market growth.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2: Wants to share investment philosophy with family in China.  Inquired about account opening procedures and trading software options in China.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s reply: Suggested Chun Xia email him for an introduction to a leader familiar with the Chinese market who can provide specific guidance on account opening and software selection.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Peter 
    <div id="peter" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#peter" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question: How to persuade family members to invest? They&rsquo;ve heard the advice but haven&rsquo;t acted, finding it difficult.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s reply: Acknowledged the &ldquo;familiarity bias&rdquo; that makes it difficult for family members to accept advice. Suggested Peter lead by example, sharing his investment philosophy and success stories. Encourage them to start with a small investment, like $100,000 in QQQ, and offer to cover any losses to build their confidence. He particularly recommended starting with retirement accounts and broad market index funds.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Ling 
    <div id="ling" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ling" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question:  Regarding children&rsquo;s education fund investment plan. Initially planned to invest all children&rsquo;s allowances in 00662 with monthly contributions, but has doubts after hearing James&rsquo;s lessons on children&rsquo;s education.  Should the plan be adjusted?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s reply: Advised prioritizing personal wealth accumulation and achieving financial freedom before focusing on children&rsquo;s education funds. Suggested redirecting the monthly contributions to personal investments to accelerate wealth growth.  Income like Lunar New Year red envelopes can continue to be invested for the children.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Dennis 
    <div id="dennis" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#dennis" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing 1: An insurance agent passed away due to financial problems, highlighting the importance of risk management, even for insurance professionals.</li>
<li>Sharing 2: Family recommended a video by an MIT professor about national debt, who argued that national debt is another form of taxation.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s reply: Explained Modern Monetary Theory (MMT).  U.S. national debt represents savings held by the public. The U.S. government&rsquo;s debt is repaid by Americans. The value of the dollar lies in its credit and the goods and services it can buy, not the level of debt. The government can stimulate the economy by issuing national debt without worrying about excessive debt.  Issuing national debt and lottery tickets are essentially providing investment channels, not just taxation.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Sharing 3: Wants to learn more about MMT.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s reply: Recommended Dennis search for books and materials on &ldquo;Modern Monetary Theory&rdquo; for a deeper understanding of its principles and applications.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Hao Xin 
    <div id="hao-xin" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#hao-xin" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question:  Are the P/E ratios of QQQ and SPY overvalued? How to deal with market fluctuations? Concerned that a prolonged stagnant market will cause borrowing interest to exceed cash reserves.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s reply: P/E ratios are unreliable and unpredictable. Recommended passive rebalancing.  Cash reserves will increase as the market rises; reinvest during downturns. Suggested simulating the 2000-2009 market scenario to test the robustness of the asset allocation strategy. If the market does stagnate for a long time, adjust lifestyle, reduce expenses, or consider other income sources. In the long run, the market will always go up; maintain confidence.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Sharing: Received a suspected scam call where the caller claimed to be from the bank and requested personal information verification.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s comments:  Commended Hao Xin&rsquo;s vigilance and reminded everyone to be cautious of calls requesting personal information to avoid being scammed.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">IV. Key Takeaways 
    <div id="iv-key-takeaways" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv-key-takeaways" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;The first investment earns the most; that performance can never be replicated.&rdquo;
&ndash; Monica</p></blockquote>
<p>Monica&rsquo;s statement highlights the importance of early investment and the difficulty of timing the market. Early investments enjoy higher returns, and over time, even with the same investment strategy, it&rsquo;s hard to replicate those early gains.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;The U.S. government&rsquo;s debt is the public&rsquo;s savings.&rdquo;
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>This perspective challenges the traditional understanding of national debt, emphasizing the unique nature of U.S. Treasury bonds.  U.S. national debt represents dollar-denominated assets held by U.S. citizens and global investors, reflecting confidence in the American economy.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;Survival is key, not maximizing returns.&rdquo;
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>This statement pinpoints the core goal of investing, reminding investors not to be tempted by high returns at the expense of risk management. Preserving capital is more important than chasing high returns during market fluctuations.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;Time is an investor&rsquo;s friend.&rdquo;
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>Only long-term investments can fully benefit from the power of compounding. Time is an investor&rsquo;s best ally.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">V. Summary 
    <div id="v-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#v-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>In this episode, James once again emphasized the importance of long-term investing and risk management, offering personalized advice tailored to each student&rsquo;s circumstances. His clear explanations helped students better understand market trends, investment strategies, and the essence of wealth management. He also shared his understanding of Modern Monetary Theory (MMT) and awareness of various financial traps, reminding investors to remain rational and avoid blindly chasing high returns.</p>

  



<div
  
    class="flex px-4 py-3 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900"
  >

  <span
    
      class="text-primary-400 ltr:pr-3 rtl:pl-3 flex items-center"
    >

    

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M506.3 417l-213.3-364c-16.33-28-57.54-28-73.98 0l-213.2 364C-10.59 444.9 9.849 480 42.74 480h426.6C502.1 480 522.6 445 506.3 417zM232 168c0-13.25 10.75-24 24-24S280 154.8 280 168v128c0 13.25-10.75 24-23.1 24S232 309.3 232 296V168zM256 416c-17.36 0-31.44-14.08-31.44-31.44c0-17.36 14.07-31.44 31.44-31.44s31.44 14.08 31.44 31.44C287.4 401.9 273.4 416 256 416z"/></svg>

  </span>


  </span>

  <span
    
      class="dark:text-neutral-300"
    ><strong>Disclaimer:</strong> This article is for personal learning notes only and does not constitute any investment advice.</span>
</div>

]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>00479 Three Easy Examples of Getting Rich, The Power of Starting Early and Compound Interest</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1728391134352/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1728391134352/</guid><description>In this session, James reiterates the importance of long-term index fund investing, illustrating the power of compounding interest with multiple examples. He also explains how to avoid common investment pitfalls to achieve financial freedom. Additionally, James addresses audience questions on asset allocation, real estate investment, trusts, and children&amp;#39;s education funds.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<lite-youtube videoid="1VSo2I6xqG0" playlabel="1VSo2I6xqG0" params=""></lite-youtube>



<h2 class="relative group">I. Main Topic 
    <div id="i-main-topic" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-main-topic" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This session focuses on long-term index fund investing. The core message is: hold index funds firmly, ignore market fluctuations, maintain a proper asset allocation, and leverage the compounding effect of time to achieve financial freedom.  James also warns against investment scams and emphasizes avoiding unnecessary risks, while offering advice on investing in children&rsquo;s education funds.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">II. Presentation Summary 
    <div id="ii-presentation-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii-presentation-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<ul>
<li><strong>Advantages of Index Funds:</strong> Long-term index fund investing eliminates the need to follow short-term market fluctuations, international affairs, financial reports, and economic data.  Focus on asset allocation and consistent investment.</li>
<li><strong>The Power of Compounding:</strong> James uses several examples to illustrate the magic of compounding:  A monthly investment of 1000 TWD can grow to 17.3 million TWD in 40 years; a lump-sum investment of 100,000 TWD can reach 18.8 million TWD in 40 years;  starting early is crucial, as a 10-year delay significantly impacts final returns; one share of QQQ at 500 USD will become 25,000 USD in 30 years and 94,000 USD in 40 years.</li>
<li><strong>Safe Asset Allocation:</strong> Asset allocation is more critical than any market commentary. James recommends deleveraging and reducing debt for those nearing retirement, holding a larger cash position.  For younger individuals with stable income, leveraging can be considered. He suggests using a beta of 1.0 as a benchmark, reducing beta when the market is overheated, and increasing it back to 1.0 during market downturns.  For cash allocation, he references Buffett and suggests a sample allocation (Scenario 3): 40% index funds, 30% 2x leveraged funds, and 30% cash.</li>
<li><strong>Beware of Investment Scams:</strong>  Don&rsquo;t trust investment information from unknown accounts or websites. Choose legitimate financial institutions.</li>
<li><strong>Don&rsquo;t Give Money Directly to Children:</strong> James uses personal anecdotes and case studies to caution against putting assets directly in children&rsquo;s names, as this may discourage their initiative or cause family conflicts.  However, investing children&rsquo;s &ldquo;lucky money&rdquo; (red envelopes) for them is recommended as an educational fund.</li>
<li><strong>Risks of Real Estate Investment:</strong> James reiterates his advice against early homeownership for young people, arguing that real estate is illiquid, high-risk, and ties up capital that could be used for other investments.  He highlights the added risk in Taiwan, where mortgage debt remains even after foreclosure.</li>
<li><strong>Recommended Learning Resources:</strong> He recommends a YouTube channel called &ldquo;什么值得读&rdquo; (What&rsquo;s Worth Reading) for valuable content on value investing.</li>
<li><strong>Emergency Fund:</strong> Maintain a cash reserve equivalent to six months of living expenses in a money market fund account. Investing this emergency fund in stocks is not recommended.</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">III. Q&amp;A Session 
    <div id="iii-qa-session" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii-qa-session" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p><strong>Jeff:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Shares:  Highlights misconceptions about investing held by two listeners and emphasizes the importance of carefully studying James&rsquo;s lecture notes, particularly the chart on page two.</li>
<li>James&rsquo;s response:  Affirms Jeff&rsquo;s points and re-emphasizes the importance of a solid investment philosophy to avoid being swayed by market noise.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Cat:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Shares: A listener holding 35 million TWD in 00662 still finds the 2% withdrawal rate insufficient. Discusses the spending needs and inheritance considerations of single individuals.</li>
<li>James&rsquo;s response: Different indices have different volatility and dividend yields, requiring adjustments to withdrawal rates. For higher withdrawals, consider ETFs with higher dividend yields, such as 0056, which yields around 4-5%.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>H:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Question:  High rental costs for young people, should they buy a house?  Mortgages offer tax deductions, while renting does not.  Concerned about insufficient funds for leveraged investing.</li>
<li>James&rsquo;s response:  Recommends watching the &ldquo;30 Years of Different Destinies&rdquo; video, which analyzes the pros and cons of renting versus buying.  Young people should prioritize investing in index funds to build wealth through compounding and consider buying a house later.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Yonglin:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Question: Should money be invested in children&rsquo;s names for long-term holding?  Should a mortgage-free house be sold to invest in index funds after retirement?</li>
<li>James&rsquo;s response:  Advises against putting money directly in children&rsquo;s names.  Retirees should deleverage, and selling a mortgage-free house to invest in index funds is a viable option.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Mike:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Shares: Success story of investing his children&rsquo;s education fund in QQQ.  Gives the example of Taoyuan Language in Taiwan, suggesting potential leveraged investment through real estate mortgages.</li>
<li>Question: How to establish a family trust and manage generational wealth like the Rockefeller family?</li>
<li>James&rsquo;s response:  Recommends contacting Lisa for trust advice when assets reach a certain level and age. For now, focus on investing. Trusts can be considered around 70-80 years old. Single individuals or those without children should rely on trusts, appointing guardians and executors.  Those with children can consider Trust 2.0, with the bank as executor and children as supervisors.  Family foundations managed by professional institutions are also an option.  Recommends the Walmart family&rsquo;s living trust as a model.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Becky, Jessie, and Other Participants:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Becky: Difficulties of renting at an older age.</li>
<li>Jessie: How to balance saving for an emergency fund, paying off a mortgage, and investing simultaneously.</li>
<li>Other Participants: Questions about real estate investment, cash management, insurance, Bitcoin, and Japanese government bonds.</li>
<li>James&rsquo;s response:  Addresses each question and reiterates his investment philosophy.  For example, young people should avoid real estate and insurance due to high risks; long-term bonds and municipal bonds are not suitable for emergency funds.</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">IV. Key Takeaways 
    <div id="iv-key-takeaways" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv-key-takeaways" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>Time is the source of all power.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>James uses examples like the evolution of Earth&rsquo;s ecosystem and human evolution to illustrate the power of time and emphasize the importance of long-term investing.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Don&rsquo;t casually help others with money.  People will resent you for it for a lifetime.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>Cautions against testing human nature with money and emphasizes setting boundaries with financial assistance.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The earlier you invest, the better.  Keep enough emergency funds. The earlier you invest, the lower the risk.
&ndash; Jeff</p></blockquote>
<p>Emphasizes the importance of early investing and maintaining an emergency fund.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Laugh a little; how long a scammer can scam is determined by the fool.
&ndash; Mike</p></blockquote>
<p>A cynical comment on the prevalence of scammers and a reminder to stay vigilant.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">V. Conclusion 
    <div id="v-conclusion" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#v-conclusion" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>The core message of this session remains long-term index fund investing. James uses clear language and vivid examples to reiterate the power of compounding and the importance of starting early. He also addresses audience questions on asset allocation, real estate, trusts, emergency funds, and children&rsquo;s education funds, sharing advice on avoiding common investment traps and achieving financial freedom.  He further recommends learning resources and provides commentary on social phenomena.</p>

  



<div
  
    class="flex px-4 py-3 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900"
  >

  <span
    
      class="text-primary-400 ltr:pr-3 rtl:pl-3 flex items-center"
    >

    

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M506.3 417l-213.3-364c-16.33-28-57.54-28-73.98 0l-213.2 364C-10.59 444.9 9.849 480 42.74 480h426.6C502.1 480 522.6 445 506.3 417zM232 168c0-13.25 10.75-24 24-24S280 154.8 280 168v128c0 13.25-10.75 24-23.1 24S232 309.3 232 296V168zM256 416c-17.36 0-31.44-14.08-31.44-31.44c0-17.36 14.07-31.44 31.44-31.44s31.44 14.08 31.44 31.44C287.4 401.9 273.4 416 256 416z"/></svg>

  </span>


  </span>

  <span
    
      class="dark:text-neutral-300"
    ><strong>Disclaimer:</strong> This document is for personal learning notes only and does not constitute any investment advice.</span>
</div>

]]></content:encoded></item></channel></rss>