<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Long-Term Investment on QQQ Investor</title>
    <link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/tags/long-term-investment/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Long-Term Investment on QQQ Investor</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jomonylw.github.io/en/tags/long-term-investment/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>00493 Financial Risks and Investment Wisdom: How to Accumulate and Utilize Assets; Stock Pledge and Asset Allocation: Smart Choices for Risk Reduction</title>
      <link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1733026874385/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1733026874385/</guid>
      <description>In this episode, James reiterates the current market highs and advises investors to remain patient, adhere to long-term investment strategies, and avoid being swayed by short-term fluctuations. He also addresses questions from students regarding asset allocation, stock pledging, insurance, annuities, children&amp;#39;s education, and how to cope with market volatility, sharing his understanding of Modern Monetary Theory (MMT).</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<lite-youtube videoid="V0d8y8-Jl-w" playlabel="V0d8y8-Jl-w" params=""></lite-youtube>



<h2 class="relative group">I. Main Topic 
    <div id="i-main-topic" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-main-topic" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>The market continues to reach new highs.  Investing doesn&rsquo;t require constant attention; the key is to stick to a long-term investment strategy, maintain a well-diversified asset allocation, and remain patient. The real risk isn&rsquo;t short-term volatility, but the inability to accumulate sufficient wealth over the long term, and not knowing how to utilize accumulated wealth effectively.  Furthermore, it&rsquo;s crucial to be wary of various financial traps and maintain rational investment practices.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">II. Briefing Content 
    <div id="ii-briefing-content" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii-briefing-content" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Market Trends and Investment Strategies 
    <div id="market-trends-and-investment-strategies" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#market-trends-and-investment-strategies" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>The market is at a new high. Don&rsquo;t waste time over-analyzing; stick to long-term investing, buy and hold.  The market generally trends upwards; instead of predicting pullbacks, enter the market early.</li>
<li>Investing doesn&rsquo;t require excessive time. After placing your order, step away and let time work its magic through compounding.</li>
<li>Be wary of scams. Don&rsquo;t trust any investment advice that guarantees stable returns or daily gains.  Be extremely cautious of &ldquo;guaranteed profit&rdquo; schemes.</li>
<li>Ignore the advice of financial advisors and insurance agents. They rarely have the investor&rsquo;s best interests at heart and are often motivated by their own profits. Many financial products are designed to benefit the seller, not the investor.</li>
<li>Investing isn&rsquo;t simple. Even asset allocation within a Nasdaq 100 index fund requires in-depth research and adjustments based on individual circumstances.</li>
<li>Investors should always remain optimistic. The market will eventually rise. Patiently await wealth accumulation. Time is an investor&rsquo;s friend.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Risk Management and Wealth Goals 
    <div id="risk-management-and-wealth-goals" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#risk-management-and-wealth-goals" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>The biggest risks are not market fluctuations, but the failure to accumulate sufficient wealth over the long term and not knowing how to utilize accumulated wealth effectively. The ultimate goal of investing is to achieve financial freedom and enjoy life.</li>
<li>Avoid the instinctive reaction to short-term losses. Overcome fear and don&rsquo;t panic sell. Market downturns are normal and present buying opportunities.</li>
<li>View bear markets as opportunities. Buying low translates to higher future returns. Learn to think contrarily and utilize market fluctuations for mindless rebalancing.</li>
<li>The investment objective is to mitigate the risk of financial hardship, not to maximize returns. A sound investment strategy is more crucial than chasing high returns.</li>
<li>Choose a simple, low-cost, passive index investment strategy, such as a Nasdaq 100 index fund, and hold a portion in cash to maintain psychological balance and cope with market volatility.</li>
<li>Holding safe assets (like certificates of deposit and money market funds) can mitigate short-term risks, stabilize emotions during market fluctuations, and provide a sense of security.</li>
<li>The proportion of safe assets held should be adjusted based on age and risk tolerance. Retirees are advised to hold cash equivalent to 5 years of living expenses, while those yet to retire can hold more.</li>
<li>Young people should prioritize term life insurance to protect their families and avoid other types of insurance to prevent being misled by insurance companies.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Other Advice 
    <div id="other-advice" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#other-advice" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Be skeptical of all information, especially regarding money. Learn to think independently and don&rsquo;t blindly trust so-called &ldquo;experts.&rdquo;</li>
<li>Don&rsquo;t buy insurance or annuities for investment purposes. The essence of insurance is protection, not investment; annuities have high fees and low returns.</li>
<li>Don&rsquo;t disclose your wealth to your children. Encourage them to strive independently and create wealth through their own abilities.</li>
<li>Engage in rational discussions, view investments with a mathematical mindset, and analyze investment results with data.</li>
<li>Avoid over-investing in real estate. Maintain ample cash flow. Real estate has poor liquidity and is difficult to liquidate.</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">III. Q&amp;A Session 
    <div id="iii-qa-session" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii-qa-session" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Ke An 
    <div id="ke-an" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ke-an" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: 16 years old, living in the Netherlands.  Thanked James for his investment methods, which allowed her parents to take her on trips throughout Europe. She also shared that she finds her business management classes easier to understand than her classmates, thanks to James&rsquo;s teachings.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s comments: Praised Ke An&rsquo;s travel experiences and learning attitude, encouraging her to continue learning and explore her career interests.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question: Concerned about starting investing late, wants to open an account and start investing soon. Has saved NT$200,000 and plans to invest in 00662.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s reply: Affirmed the advantage of starting to invest at 16, emphasizing that time is the greatest asset.  Advised her to balance learning, life, and investment, and to enjoy her youth.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Ji Ya 
    <div id="ji-ya" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ji-ya" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question: Has savings equivalent to 8 years of living expenses. Working 40 hours a week only covers expenses. Driving for Uber could increase income but wants more free time. Unsure how to balance work and life and whether early retirement is possible. Is currently 42 years old.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s reply: In 15 years, the 8x annual expenses will grow to 50x due to compounding, enabling retirement. Suggested a BETA of 1.2 to increase investment returns, or driving for Uber a few hours a week to accelerate wealth accumulation and achieve early retirement.  Emphasized that pursuing early retirement shouldn&rsquo;t be the sole focus and that finding a balance between work and life is important. Health is paramount.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chun Xia 
    <div id="chun-xia" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chun-xia" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question 1: Plans to invest a loan of NT$7 million and aims for a return of NT$20-30 million within 10-15 years. Should the investment be lump-sum or staggered?  Has additional monthly income of NT$30,000-40,000.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s reply: Based on a 14% annualized return, there will be NT$67 million after 15 years, reaching the NT$20-30 million target within 10 years. Recommended a lump-sum investment to capitalize on market growth.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2: Wants to share investment philosophy with family in China.  Inquired about account opening procedures and trading software options in China.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s reply: Suggested Chun Xia email him for an introduction to a leader familiar with the Chinese market who can provide specific guidance on account opening and software selection.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Peter 
    <div id="peter" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#peter" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question: How to persuade family members to invest? They&rsquo;ve heard the advice but haven&rsquo;t acted, finding it difficult.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s reply: Acknowledged the &ldquo;familiarity bias&rdquo; that makes it difficult for family members to accept advice. Suggested Peter lead by example, sharing his investment philosophy and success stories. Encourage them to start with a small investment, like $100,000 in QQQ, and offer to cover any losses to build their confidence. He particularly recommended starting with retirement accounts and broad market index funds.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Ling 
    <div id="ling" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ling" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question:  Regarding children&rsquo;s education fund investment plan. Initially planned to invest all children&rsquo;s allowances in 00662 with monthly contributions, but has doubts after hearing James&rsquo;s lessons on children&rsquo;s education.  Should the plan be adjusted?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s reply: Advised prioritizing personal wealth accumulation and achieving financial freedom before focusing on children&rsquo;s education funds. Suggested redirecting the monthly contributions to personal investments to accelerate wealth growth.  Income like Lunar New Year red envelopes can continue to be invested for the children.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Dennis 
    <div id="dennis" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#dennis" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing 1: An insurance agent passed away due to financial problems, highlighting the importance of risk management, even for insurance professionals.</li>
<li>Sharing 2: Family recommended a video by an MIT professor about national debt, who argued that national debt is another form of taxation.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s reply: Explained Modern Monetary Theory (MMT).  U.S. national debt represents savings held by the public. The U.S. government&rsquo;s debt is repaid by Americans. The value of the dollar lies in its credit and the goods and services it can buy, not the level of debt. The government can stimulate the economy by issuing national debt without worrying about excessive debt.  Issuing national debt and lottery tickets are essentially providing investment channels, not just taxation.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Sharing 3: Wants to learn more about MMT.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s reply: Recommended Dennis search for books and materials on &ldquo;Modern Monetary Theory&rdquo; for a deeper understanding of its principles and applications.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Hao Xin 
    <div id="hao-xin" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#hao-xin" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question:  Are the P/E ratios of QQQ and SPY overvalued? How to deal with market fluctuations? Concerned that a prolonged stagnant market will cause borrowing interest to exceed cash reserves.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s reply: P/E ratios are unreliable and unpredictable. Recommended passive rebalancing.  Cash reserves will increase as the market rises; reinvest during downturns. Suggested simulating the 2000-2009 market scenario to test the robustness of the asset allocation strategy. If the market does stagnate for a long time, adjust lifestyle, reduce expenses, or consider other income sources. In the long run, the market will always go up; maintain confidence.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Sharing: Received a suspected scam call where the caller claimed to be from the bank and requested personal information verification.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s comments:  Commended Hao Xin&rsquo;s vigilance and reminded everyone to be cautious of calls requesting personal information to avoid being scammed.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">IV. Key Takeaways 
    <div id="iv-key-takeaways" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv-key-takeaways" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;The first investment earns the most; that performance can never be replicated.&rdquo;
&ndash; Monica</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Monica&rsquo;s statement highlights the importance of early investment and the difficulty of timing the market. Early investments enjoy higher returns, and over time, even with the same investment strategy, it&rsquo;s hard to replicate those early gains.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;The U.S. government&rsquo;s debt is the public&rsquo;s savings.&rdquo;
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This perspective challenges the traditional understanding of national debt, emphasizing the unique nature of U.S. Treasury bonds.  U.S. national debt represents dollar-denominated assets held by U.S. citizens and global investors, reflecting confidence in the American economy.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;Survival is key, not maximizing returns.&rdquo;
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This statement pinpoints the core goal of investing, reminding investors not to be tempted by high returns at the expense of risk management. Preserving capital is more important than chasing high returns during market fluctuations.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;Time is an investor&rsquo;s friend.&rdquo;
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Only long-term investments can fully benefit from the power of compounding. Time is an investor&rsquo;s best ally.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">V. Summary 
    <div id="v-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#v-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>In this episode, James once again emphasized the importance of long-term investing and risk management, offering personalized advice tailored to each student&rsquo;s circumstances. His clear explanations helped students better understand market trends, investment strategies, and the essence of wealth management. He also shared his understanding of Modern Monetary Theory (MMT) and awareness of various financial traps, reminding investors to remain rational and avoid blindly chasing high returns.</p>

  



<div
  
    class="flex px-4 py-3 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900"
  >

  <span
    
      class="text-primary-400 ltr:pr-3 rtl:pl-3 flex items-center"
    >

    

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M506.3 417l-213.3-364c-16.33-28-57.54-28-73.98 0l-213.2 364C-10.59 444.9 9.849 480 42.74 480h426.6C502.1 480 522.6 445 506.3 417zM232 168c0-13.25 10.75-24 24-24S280 154.8 280 168v128c0 13.25-10.75 24-23.1 24S232 309.3 232 296V168zM256 416c-17.36 0-31.44-14.08-31.44-31.44c0-17.36 14.07-31.44 31.44-31.44s31.44 14.08 31.44 31.44C287.4 401.9 273.4 416 256 416z"/></svg>

  </span>


  </span>

  <span
    
      class="dark:text-neutral-300"
    ><strong>Disclaimer:</strong> This article is for personal learning notes only and does not constitute any investment advice.</span>
</div>

]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Personal Investment Bible: Investment Iron Law Ⅸ</title>
      <link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1731056005968/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1731056005968/</guid>
      <description>This article explores common misconceptions in investment and financial management, particularly the reliance on forecasting and technical analysis. The author argues that technical analysis cannot consistently help investors achieve excess returns and instead often leads to the trap of short-term trading.  The article advocates a long-term investment strategy of &amp;#39;buy any stock, buy anytime, and don&amp;#39;t sell,&amp;#39; emphasizing that the key to successful investing lies in selecting the right investment targets and holding them for the long term, rather than attempting to predict short-term market fluctuations.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[

<h2 class="relative group">Investment Iron Law Ⅸ: Grasping the General Market Trend 
    <div id="investment-iron-law--grasping-the-general-market-trend" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#investment-iron-law--grasping-the-general-market-trend" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>Basing investment decisions on technical analysis<br>
often indicates a lack of experience.<br>
In most cases, it won&rsquo;t make you money.</p>
</blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">The Blind Spots of Forecasting and Analysis 
    <div id="the-blind-spots-of-forecasting-and-analysis" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#the-blind-spots-of-forecasting-and-analysis" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>The reason many investors engage in frequent short-term trading, besides being attracted by price fluctuations, is mainly due to the so-called &ldquo;experts&rdquo; who flood the investment market with constant analysis and forecasts, providing investors with specious advice. This leads investors to frantically chase the &ldquo;buy low, sell high&rdquo; principle.  Let&rsquo;s discuss whether forecasting and analysis are truly effective. Can they genuinely help investors make a fortune?</p>
<p><strong>Is Technical Analysis Effective?</strong></p>
<p>In April 1993, the Taiwan <em>Economic Daily</em> published an article titled, &ldquo;Success in Stocks Depends on Entry and Exit Timing.&rdquo; This led many to believe that the most crucial task in investment analysis is determining the right moments to buy and sell.</p>
<p>The average investor believes the golden rule for wealth in the stock market is &ldquo;buy low, sell high.&rdquo;  They also believe the key to success lies in accurately grasping these timing opportunities. Consequently, countless investors try every means to predict future stock price trends to determine optimal buying and selling points.  In their quest for the Midas touch, various methods, from the scientific to the absurd, and even the supernatural, such as astrology and market horoscopes, have emerged.  Currently, the most widely used method is &ldquo;technical analysis.&rdquo;</p>
<p>In the author&rsquo;s humble opinion, technical analysis&rsquo;s popularity in the global investment market, and its continued prevalence among Taiwanese investors, stems from the fact that it appears sophisticated yet not overwhelmingly complex, thus attracting many novice investors.  These beginners often believe they must possess some secret technique to navigate the stock market, leading them to prioritize learning technical analysis upon entering the market.</p>
<p>Technical analysis originated from the Dow Theory in the 1930s, after which various technical analysis methods sprung up like mushrooms.  From the 1940s to the 1960s, technical analysis was highly popular in the US stock market.  However, with the advent of the Random Walk Theory, and the observation that most users of technical analysis ended up worse off, its popularity began to wane.  By the 1980s, when the author was studying investment analysis in the US stock market, established investment analysts rarely mentioned technical analysis.  At the time, if an investor claimed to use technical analysis for investment decisions, it implied inexperience and a high probability of losing money.</p>
<p>Technical analysis involves studying and analyzing past price trends and volume data to determine buying and selling timings. Its fundamental assumption is that history repeats itself. Therefore, by identifying the patterns of stock price movements, one can accurately predict future trends.</p>
<p><strong>Beating the Market is a Pipe Dream</strong></p>
<p>Numerous empirical studies by scholars have revealed many problems and controversies surrounding technical analysis.  Briefly summarized:</p>
<ul>
<li>
<ol>
<li>Historical patterns don&rsquo;t always repeat. Even if technical analysis has been effective for decades, it doesn&rsquo;t guarantee future success.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol start="2">
<li>If a particular technical analysis method consistently succeeds, its widespread adoption will eliminate its potential profits.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol start="3">
<li>The collective actions of technical analysts can create price patterns.  This means the price isn&rsquo;t reflecting a correct prediction but rather the analysts&rsquo; actions.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol start="4">
<li>Some technical indicators rely on comparisons with past data.  These values can change due to time and environment, making past standards inapplicable to the present.</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ul>
<p>If you were given a past stock chart and asked to devise a profitable investment strategy, everyone would understand &ldquo;buy low, sell high.&rdquo;  Profiting from trading in such a scenario would be easy.  However, investing is about the future. Future price movements are complex and unpredictable; no one possesses a future stock chart.  So, is &ldquo;buy low, sell high&rdquo; still a suitable investment strategy?  The answer is no.  The reason is simple: no one can predict market highs and lows in advance.</p>
<p>Using previously successful technical analysis methods doesn&rsquo;t guarantee future success in beating the market, as excess returns can be random.  Furthermore, concluding that technical analysis is effective based on occasional or random excess returns is misleading. While technical analysis might yield short-term gains, it cannot consistently outperform the market in the long run.</p>
<p>A student once asked me, if the market follows a random walk and technical analysis is ineffective, why are some technical analysis methods accurate at times?  Claiming technical analysis is ineffective means it can&rsquo;t generate long-term excess profits, not that its predictions are always wrong.  Technical analysis can sometimes be accurate, just like random guesses can be accurate.  Therefore, technical analysis isn&rsquo;t necessarily inaccurate; its accuracy is comparable to guessing.</p>
<p><strong>The Trap of Short-Term Trading</strong></p>
<p>Another significant drawback of technical analysis is that its methods focus on identifying buy and sell points.  These points constantly emerge, forcing investors to frequently buy and sell, trapping them in short-term trading and eroding returns through transaction costs. The ineffectiveness of technical analysis means that, on average, it doesn&rsquo;t generate excess returns over the long term. In other words, while sometimes accurate, it ultimately underperforms the market&rsquo;s average return (buy-and-hold strategy).</p>
<p>You might have used technical analysis methods with seemingly good results.  I admit some methods can be effective, but investors often overlook transaction costs.  Considering these costs, returns from technical analysis are unlikely to be high.  Furthermore, the effectiveness of any technical analysis method is inconsistent, making long-term high returns improbable.</p>
<p>Technical analysis exhausts investors, leading to significant losses.  Investors should abandon it and adopt a long-term &ldquo;buy-and-hold&rdquo; strategy to benefit from long-term market growth.  It&rsquo;s crucial to understand that market risk is inherent in any investment strategy.  Investors should be mentally prepared and avoid excessive optimism about short-term returns.  Profitable investing relies on correctly judging the overall market direction.  Obsessively seeking investment rules from past data, even if profitable, will likely incur time and effort costs exceeding the returns.</p>
<p>If you still believe technical analysis can lead to riches, ask yourself: who has become wealthy solely through technical analysis?</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Blind faith in predictions is worse than no prediction at all.
Prediction is more art than science.</p>
</blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">The Only Certainty is Uncertainty 
    <div id="the-only-certainty-is-uncertainty" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#the-only-certainty-is-uncertainty" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>The biggest mistake in investment strategies is overconfidence in prediction. If you&rsquo;ve tirelessly searched for prediction methods without success, or your developed methods are unreliable and unprofitable, don&rsquo;t be discouraged. All predictions face the same challenges.</p>
<p>Like you, forecasting experts cannot predict the future.  If they possessed a crystal ball, they would be wealthy, not making a living from predictions.  If this logic isn&rsquo;t convincing, ask yourself: &ldquo;Which self-made millionaire or consistently successful long-term investor has relied solely on prediction?&rdquo;  The answer is none.</p>
<p><strong>Investment Performance is Unrelated to Predictive Ability</strong></p>
<p>People often assume investment success hinges on predictive ability.  Those who predict better supposedly perform better, while investment failures are attributed to poor prediction. However, this isn&rsquo;t true. Most successful investors admit their inability to predict the future. They have no preconceived notions, and their success stems from sound strategies, not accurate predictions.</p>
<p>During my studies in the US, when I first dabbled in the US stock market, I shared the common belief that Wall Street analysts were remarkable and highly skilled at predicting market trends. After graduating from UC Berkeley in 1987, I left academia for a position at a major US brokerage firm, largely driven by the desire to learn from renowned analysts at Merrill Lynch.</p>
<p>At Merrill Lynch, I witnessed these analysts firsthand. After numerous interactions, I realized they couldn&rsquo;t accurately predict future stock prices. Some didn&rsquo;t even invest in stocks themselves. I often called analysts, asking which stocks to buy and when the market would rise. One analyst, perhaps tired of my persistent inquiries, frankly told me, &ldquo;Think about it. If I knew which stocks would rise and when the market would go up, would I be stuck working as an analyst?&rdquo;  It was then I understood that analysts don&rsquo;t possess predictive powers.</p>
<p>Upon returning to Taiwan, I observed that local newspapers and magazines were filled with &ldquo;Expert Predictions&rdquo; or &ldquo;Analyst Market Forecasts.&rdquo;  I interacted with several well-known analysts, studying their predictions carefully. My conclusion: there were no superior predictions in the Taiwan stock market.  These analysts and experts couldn&rsquo;t accurately grasp the market&rsquo;s future direction.</p>
<p><strong>Analysts Rely on Hype</strong></p>
<p>Why do so many analysts and experts constantly make predictions in the media? The reason is simple: supply follows demand. Readers crave these predictions, prompting newspapers and magazines to create dedicated columns.  Experts often publish predictions not because they possess foresight but because readers believe experts have superior knowledge of the future and eagerly seek their opinions.  Newspapers cater to this demand by soliciting expert articles.  Similarly, why do brokerage firms employ so many analysts to interpret market trends for clients? To meet customer needs.  In a competitive environment, analyst insights are considered a crucial service. Brokerage firms readily provide this service because research indicates that investors guided by experts tend towards short-term trading, generating higher commissions for the firms.</p>
<p>This demonstrates investors&rsquo; heavy reliance on expert predictions, which arise from investor demand. The problem is that the stock market is unpredictable.  No one can make accurate predictions, a widely acknowledged fact.  Yet, most investors still believe in expert forecasts.</p>
<p>A US poll once asked, &ldquo;Who lies to the public the most?&rdquo; The results: weather forecasters, stock analysts, and economic commentators.  This reveals not that expert predictions are always inaccurate but the public&rsquo;s unwavering faith in them, leading to heightened expectations.  These professions often require making future predictions under the assumption that &ldquo;experts must be able to predict; those who can&rsquo;t predict aren&rsquo;t experts.&rdquo;  This pressure compels many researchers and analysts to publish future predictions, despite the inherent uncertainty.  Being wrong is inevitable, and being perceived as liars arises from the public&rsquo;s initial belief in their predictions, leading to feelings of deception when they prove incorrect.</p>
<p>You might question this, citing instances of analysts who made remarkably accurate predictions, causing stocks to surge upon their recommendations.  However, have you noticed that these seemingly prophetic &ldquo;experts&rdquo; are rarely the same person and often disappear after a while?  In reality, these experts, unless backed by market manipulators who profit from deceiving retail investors, are simply experiencing probability at play.  Occasional streaks of accuracy are possible but not sustainable.</p>
<p><strong>Strategies to Lure Retail Investors</strong></p>
<p>Market manipulators aiming to pump and dump a stock, besides securing cooperation from major shareholders, must create a forecasting &ldquo;expert&rdquo; who, through media appearances, convinces retail investors to buy in.  As major shareholders lock up their shares and more investors join, it creates the illusion that the &ldquo;expert&rsquo;s&rdquo; predictions are coming true, causing the stock price to surge.</p>
<p>Joseph Granville was a popular technical analyst in the early 1980s.  His remarkably accurate market predictions in the late 1970s made him famous.  His large following gave him considerable market influence; his words could move the market by tens of points.  However, in early 1982, he predicted a major market crash, advising his followers to sell all their stocks.  Instead, the market surged from around 700 to over 1200 points within five months.  Those who heeded his advice missed a significant bull market, and Granville faded into obscurity.</p>
<p>I advise investors to avoid stocks being manipulated. Even if you make small profits initially, one loss could wipe out all gains and more.  Another reason: manipulated stocks involve major shareholder intervention.  These shareholders, instead of focusing on business operations and profits, are interested in quick gains through market manipulation, indicating poor management.  Such companies aren&rsquo;t worth investing in. Their scheme relies on retail investors&rsquo; money; retail investors have little chance of winning.  If retail investors could profit from this game, what would be the point for the major shareholders?</p>
<p>Another possibility for accurate predictions is simply probability.  Predictions are often diverse and contradictory, with some bullish, some bearish, and some expecting consolidation.  Inevitably, someone will be right, purely due to luck or higher guessing probability.</p>
<p><strong>More Wrong Guesses Than Right</strong></p>
<p>However, most people don&rsquo;t think this way.  When experts make several consecutive correct predictions, they gain credibility and are hailed as &ldquo;prophets.&rdquo;  People easily forget past incorrect predictions, treating the &ldquo;prophet&rsquo;s&rdquo; words as gospel.  This is extremely dangerous. Investors overlook the possibility of future incorrect predictions.</p>
<p>I&rsquo;m not entirely dismissing analysts and experts.  In the unpredictable investment world, many investors need expert guidance.  Analyst data and forecasts can be valuable reference material. My point is, regardless of your attitude towards expert predictions, remember: the future is dynamic and unpredictable.  Investment risk is an unavoidable reality and must be managed.</p>
<p>In early 1990, as the market peaked, most experts predicted continued growth. A prominent &ldquo;market prophet&rdquo; confidently proclaimed the market would reach 15,000 points within six months and 20,000 within a year.  Major media outlets reported this prediction.  The reality was starkly different.  Within six months, the market plummeted 2,000 points, shocking all experts.  Did these experts disappear?  No.  Newspapers and magazines still feature expert market forecasts.  The reason is simple: investors are &ldquo;used to&rdquo; hearing these predictions and many remain captivated by them.</p>
<p>I don&rsquo;t advocate completely ignoring predictions.  Predictions have value, and good predictions are worth considering.  However, whether you believe in predictions or not, and regardless of the predictor&rsquo;s reputation, remember: the future is fluid and unpredictable.  Investment risk is an inherent part of investing and must be managed.</p>
<p>You don&rsquo;t need predictive abilities to invest well or make money in the market. In this complex and volatile market, the only certainty is uncertainty.  In the investment world, profits come from choosing the right investments and holding them long-term, not from predicting market movements.  In summary, consider expert predictions, but remember they are just predictions.  Don&rsquo;t blindly trust them.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>There are no experts in the stock market, only winners and losers.</p>
</blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">Trust Yourself, Not the Experts 
    <div id="trust-yourself-not-the-experts" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#trust-yourself-not-the-experts" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>Some believe that lacking professional expertise makes achieving wealth through investment incredibly difficult. Yet, many who don&rsquo;t understand stocks or real estate still achieve financial success through investing.  Most successful investors aren&rsquo;t investment professionals, and investment professionals aren&rsquo;t necessarily successful investors.  This shows that expertise isn&rsquo;t a prerequisite for wealth creation through investment.</p>
<p>Investment and financial management aren&rsquo;t inherently complex.  The perceived complexity and reliance on experts stem from investors&rsquo; inability to cope with uncertainty, overcomplicating simple matters and turning financial management into a source of anxiety and confusion.  This anxiety hinders rational decision-making, leading people to constantly seek external opinions.</p>
<p><strong>10 Experts, 11 Opinions</strong></p>
<p>The inability to handle uncertainty creates the illusion that foresight or profound analytical skills are necessary for successful investing, leading to the belief that only &ldquo;experts&rdquo; can manage finances effectively. Consequently, many entrust their financial decisions to experts, who often offer conflicting &ldquo;expert opinions.&rdquo; Ten experts can have eleven different views, further complicating the investment world and adding to investor confusion.</p>
<p>Basing your financial decisions solely on expert opinions is extremely dangerous. Ultimately, investment responsibility lies with the individual. Investors should enhance their financial literacy and become their own experts.  Financial management doesn&rsquo;t require extensive professional knowledge. By following a few basic principles outlined in this book and acting accordingly, you can achieve wealth without relying on experts.  With the right investment philosophy, you might even outperform them.</p>
<p>Therefore, I urge investors to take immediate action, start investing, and stop asking questions like &ldquo;When will the market rise?&rdquo; &ldquo;Which stock should I buy?&rdquo; or &ldquo;Should I sell my xxx stock now?&rdquo;  These questions are pointless; no one knows the correct answers.</p>
<p>In 1983, when I began my doctoral studies at UC Berkeley, I started helping Taiwanese entrepreneurs invest in US stocks.  To excel at this, I dedicated immense effort to stock analysis, often neglecting sleep and meals. For one to two years, I practically lived in the Berkeley Haas School of Business library, devouring every investment book and analyzing all available stock information. I learned various technical, fundamental, and market analysis techniques.  To develop my unique investment analysis and prediction methods, I utilized Berkeley&rsquo;s advanced computers and extensive stock databases, writing programs to simulate various investment approaches.  This proved futile; I couldn&rsquo;t find a satisfactory method.  It was all for naught.</p>
<p>If anyone truly knew when the market would rise or which stock to buy, they would be wealthy enough not to need a job as an analyst or expert.  I reiterate: even without knowing &ldquo;when the market will rise&rdquo; or &ldquo;which stock to buy,&rdquo; you can still achieve wealth through investing.  Stop wasting time on these questions. Countless people have dedicated their lives to researching them since the inception of the stock market. They became stock experts but didn&rsquo;t achieve wealth through investing.</p>
<p><strong>Inaction and Effortless Gains</strong></p>
<p>Financial management doesn&rsquo;t require excessive time. Those who spend less time on it often perform better.</p>
<p>Statistics show that Taiwanese stock investors spend an average of 3.12 hours daily on stock analysis and market watching. Is stock picking difficult? Is making money in the stock market challenging?  Constantly chasing price fluctuations, what are your returns?  Those who diligently study stocks often lose the most money.</p>
<p>A common investor mistake is giving up.  They eagerly enter during bull markets and become disheartened during bear markets, abandoning the market entirely.  Lacking patience and perseverance, they rarely succeed.  Conversely, those with less financial acumen, admitting their inability to time the market, often persevere and ultimately fare better.</p>
<p>The path to investment wealth is simple: effortless gains. The investment strategy presented—&ldquo;buy any stock, buy anytime, don&rsquo;t sell&rdquo;—can be summarized as &ldquo;do nothing, gain effortlessly.&rdquo;</p>
<p>Who wouldn&rsquo;t want effortless gains? Surprisingly, most investors can&rsquo;t achieve this.  &ldquo;There&rsquo;s no such thing as a free lunch&rdquo; is a widely known principle. Applying this to investment, people assume they must master complex techniques and work harder than others to profit.  Intuitively, they believe more knowledge and effort equate to higher returns. This might hold true in other areas, but in finance, the opposite is often true. Knowledge and effort don&rsquo;t significantly contribute to investment returns.  Knowing more and constantly monitoring the market encourages impulsive trading, leading to &ldquo;effort without gain.&rdquo;</p>
<p><strong>Inaction is Superior to Action</strong></p>
<p>Even investment gurus like Warren Buffett and Peter Lynch admit they can&rsquo;t predict market movements. Admitting ignorance might seem foolish, but it&rsquo;s the beginning of financial wisdom.  Being &ldquo;foolish&rdquo; enough to &ldquo;buy any stock, buy anytime, don&rsquo;t sell&rdquo; is the starting point of wealth creation. Confucius said, &ldquo;Great wisdom appears foolish.&rdquo;  This refers to highly learned individuals who achieve mastery through natural means, without contrivance or cunning.  They appear unintelligent but are truly wise.  Lao Tzu also said, &ldquo;Great skill appears clumsy,&rdquo; and advocated for &ldquo;governing by non-interference.&rdquo;  This strategy, applied to the volatile investment environment, is a sound approach. Unless you have strong conviction about future trends, it&rsquo;s better to ignore the chaos and remain inactive.</p>
<p>Therefore, you don&rsquo;t need to be an investment expert or possess sophisticated techniques.  &ldquo;Do nothing, gain effortlessly&rdquo; is the key to financial wealth. You might think this sounds too simple, even boring.  Indeed, it is. But this simplicity is the path to riches and becoming a millionaire.  Before acting, ask yourself: &ldquo;Do I want wealth or to be a stock market expert?&rdquo;  If you want wealth through stocks, emulate the many who became rich by simply investing and then ignoring the market.  Decades later, compounding will make you wealthy. You could also dedicate yourself to becoming a stock market expert, but this rarely leads to riches.</p>
<p>My point is, even without knowing &ldquo;when the market will rise&rdquo; or &ldquo;which stock to buy,&rdquo; you can still achieve wealth through investing. Short-term market fluctuations are unpredictable, but the long-term trend is upward. Long-term investing is the key to profit.</p>
<p>&ldquo;Buy any stock, buy anytime, don&rsquo;t sell&rdquo;—so simple, effortless, and seemingly undeserved.  While it feels like unearned gain, don&rsquo;t feel guilty.  Investing in stocks contributes to economic development.  Constant trading harms individual wealth and offers no benefit to the overall economy or society.</p>
<p><strong>Easier Said Than Done</strong></p>
<p>Some worry and ask, &ldquo;You advise against saving money in banks.  If your book becomes a bestseller and this idea spreads, wouldn&rsquo;t it cause a nationwide bank run?&rdquo; This is an unnecessary concern. I&rsquo;ve been advocating against saving money in banks for three years, even before this book&rsquo;s publication. Many who hear this idea nod in agreement, as if enlightened, yet days, months, or years later, their money remains untouched in bank accounts.</p>
<p>Others question whether my &ldquo;buy any stock, buy anytime, don&rsquo;t sell&rdquo; theory, if widely adopted, would force brokerage firms to close, depriving the government of transaction taxes.  Again, there&rsquo;s no need for such concerns.  Those who frequently engage in short-term trading in stocks, futures, or margin accounts, even after understanding that it only benefits intermediaries, often can&rsquo;t resist continuing their behavior.  Like gambling, everyone knows the odds are stacked against them, yet gambling persists.</p>
<p><strong>I understand that &ldquo;don&rsquo;t save money in banks,&rdquo; &ldquo;avoid short-term trading,&rdquo; and &ldquo;diversify and hold long-term,&rdquo; are simple in theory but difficult in practice.  Nevertheless, I sincerely hope readers can integrate knowledge and action, diversifying most of their assets into stocks and real estate, holding them long-term. Achieving financial freedom is within reach.</strong></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Personal Investment Bible: Investment Iron Law VIII</title>
      <link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1731056005967/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1731056005967/</guid>
      <description>This article explores a simple long-term investment strategy: buy randomly, buy anytime, and don&amp;#39;t sell.  The author argues that due to the unpredictable nature of stock market fluctuations, it&amp;#39;s better to diversify investments and hold them long-term rather than painstakingly selecting stocks and timing the market.  The article uses the example of the Hou brothers and the Random Walk Hypothesis to support this viewpoint, emphasizing the importance of long-term holding and diversification.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[

<h2 class="relative group">Investment Iron Law VIII:  Profit When You Buy, Profit When You Sell 
    <div id="investment-iron-law-viii--profit-when-you-buy-profit-when-you-sell" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#investment-iron-law-viii--profit-when-you-buy-profit-when-you-sell" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>Some people do nothing all day,<br>
understand nothing about investing,<br>
yet become billionaires.</p>
</blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">Buy Randomly, Buy Anytime, Don&rsquo;t Sell 
    <div id="buy-randomly-buy-anytime-dont-sell" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#buy-randomly-buy-anytime-dont-sell" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>You may already understand the principle of wealth creation: invest money in high-return investment vehicles and hold them for the long term. But you might still have questions: How should you invest? When should you buy? What should you buy? When should you sell?</p>
<p><strong>The Highest Realm of Financial Management</strong></p>
<p>I propose an investment strategy here. This method is arguably the simplest, as everyone can do it; yet it is also the hardest, as few can truly follow it. This strategy is: &ldquo;<strong>Buy randomly, buy anytime, don&rsquo;t sell.</strong>&rdquo;  You might ask, &ldquo;What&rsquo;s so difficult about buying randomly, buying anytime, and not selling?&rdquo;  If you think it&rsquo;s easy, try it yourself. If you can genuinely do it, then congratulations! You have grasped the essence of investment and financial management, reaching the highest level of investing prowess.</p>
<p>The average investor&rsquo;s favorite questions are: &ldquo;What to buy?&rdquo; &ldquo;When to buy?&rdquo; &ldquo;When to sell?&rdquo; Imagine if someone knew the answers, they would surely keep it a secret and profit themselves. Would they tell you first?  Investors often assume experts know when the market will rise or fall, and which stocks to buy.  It&rsquo;s as if those who don&rsquo;t know these things are not worthy of being called experts or analysts. However, only true experts admit they don&rsquo;t know when the market will rise or fall. <strong>Precisely because no one knows future market movements, investing is worthwhile. It&rsquo;s this uncertainty that creates the potential for high returns. Otherwise, all investment profits would be taken by those with foreknowledge.</strong></p>
<p>Most people believe that to profit from investing, you must accurately predict market timing, select the right investment targets, and know when to sell.  But based on my more than ten years of experience in investment, investment management, and investment research, capturing the perfect entry point is nearly impossible. Even investment gurus like Warren Buffett and Peter Lynch admit they don&rsquo;t know when stocks will rise or when to sell.</p>
<p>You might be puzzled by how some people, seemingly doing nothing and lacking investment knowledge, become incredibly wealthy. The three principles presented in this book – &ldquo;buy randomly, buy anytime, don&rsquo;t sell&rdquo; – are the key factors to their success.</p>
<p><strong>The Wealth Creation Method of Hou Boming, Executive Director of Tainan Spinning</strong></p>
<p>The three Hou brothers, Boming, Boyu, and Boyi, are the largest shareholders of Tainan Spinning, possessing a fortune exceeding 15 billion. Despite being major tycoons in Southern Taiwan, they maintain a low profile.  Hou Boming, in his 40s, can sometimes be found playing pinball at night markets.</p>
<p>Hou Boming&rsquo;s grandfather, Hou Yuli, was a founding figure of Tainan Spinning.  After the successive deaths of his grandfather and father, Hou Yongdu, Hou Boming, his two older brothers, and his mother inherited a quarter of Tainan Spinning&rsquo;s shares. They remained passive shareholders, not participating in the company&rsquo;s management, staying completely silent. Their immense wealth only came to light when Hou Yuli&rsquo;s daughter, Hou Yingzu, sued her brothers, Hou Yongdu and Hou Yongsong, and her nephew, Hou Boming, for allegedly misappropriating family assets.</p>
<p>The Hou brothers&rsquo; investment strategy is simple: buy stocks and hold them long-term, accumulating wealth through dividends. Some criticize them for lacking business acumen and real estate development skills, but with this simple method, they became one of the top 20 richest families in Taiwan.</p>
<p>Had they heeded others&rsquo; advice and sold their stocks to pursue business ventures, they might have lost their position among the top 20 wealthiest, perhaps becoming another example of &ldquo;wealth not lasting three generations.&rdquo; If they had deposited their money in the bank, the wealth accumulated by their grandfather 40 years ago might have dwindled to almost nothing due to inflation.  With a real return rate of zero in a bank, depositing NT$500,000 annually would take 200 years to reach NT$100 million.</p>
<p>To the average person, the Hou brothers&rsquo; approach may seem unremarkable. Yet, their wealth hasn&rsquo;t diminished due to inflation; instead, it has grown year after year.  Their grandfather was a multi-millionaire 30 years ago, but their generation has become multi-billionaires. The key lies in investing in high-return vehicles – stocks – and holding them long-term.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Blindfolded, throw a dart,<br>
Buy whichever stock it hits.</p>
</blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">What to Buy - Buy Randomly 
    <div id="what-to-buy---buy-randomly" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#what-to-buy---buy-randomly" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>Everyone says choosing the right investment target is crucial for success, and I agree. But how to choose is a difficult and complex question.  The strategy I propose is exceptionally simple, so simple that you might not be able to follow it: &ldquo;Buy randomly.&rdquo;</p>
<p><strong>More Accurate than a Broker&rsquo;s Eye</strong></p>
<p>&ldquo;Buy randomly&rdquo; is so simple!  Some suggest pinning the stock market section of <em>The Wall Street Journal</em> to a wall and throwing darts at it, buying whichever stock the dart hits.  Scholars conducted an experiment where a monkey, blindfolded, threw darts at stock listings.  The resulting portfolio performed remarkably well, even outperforming portfolios managed by professional fund managers.</p>
<p>Why is &ldquo;buying randomly&rdquo; a good stock selection method? If you&rsquo;ve studied portfolio diversification theory in finance, you&rsquo;ll understand that as the number of stocks in a portfolio increases (beyond 10), the impact of individual stock factors diminishes.  In other words, <strong>as long as you diversify, stock selection ability becomes less important. Random selection works.</strong>  Especially with 30 or 40 different stocks, the overall performance will closely mirror the market.</p>
<p>Buying randomly sounds simple, even a monkey or a fool could do it. But in reality, it&rsquo;s extremely difficult, so difficult that only a fool could actually do it. I must admit, while I believe in the principle of &ldquo;buying randomly,&rdquo; I can&rsquo;t bring myself to do it when investing my own money.</p>
<p>As mentioned earlier, to help my child reach billionaire status by their 40s, I buy them stocks worth tens of thousands of dollars annually. To practice &ldquo;buying randomly,&rdquo; I spread out the stock market section of the newspaper and ask my 4-year-old to pick a stock.  However, each time they point to one, I move their hand, saying, &ldquo;Why did you pick this one?&rdquo;  Then I ask them to pick another, but I&rsquo;m still not satisfied. This is because I can&rsquo;t bring myself to buy the stocks my child randomly selects. In the end, it&rsquo;s me, the self-proclaimed &ldquo;investment expert&rdquo; dad, who selects a stock after careful analysis and research.</p>
<p>Despite this, I record the first stock my child picks each year. It&rsquo;s been five years now, and I haven&rsquo;t sold any of the five stocks.  Surprisingly, the performance of the five stocks I carefully selected is about the same as the five randomly picked by my child. This further validates that &ldquo;random selection&rdquo; is not only simple but also performs well in the long run.</p>
<p><strong>No One Can Guarantee Gains or Losses</strong></p>
<p>The purpose of suggesting &ldquo;random selection&rdquo; is not to encourage you to literally throw darts at stock listings, though it&rsquo;s not a bad method.  My real intention is to highlight that random selection is sufficient when choosing investments.  You don&rsquo;t need excessive caution or to follow expert advice that demands painstaking research.  The reason is simple: as mentioned, if you had chosen Cathay Life Insurance 20 years ago and held it, you would be a billionaire today. Conversely, if you had chosen Kuosheng 10 years ago and held it, you would have lost everything. Many experts use this to justify advising investors to be extremely cautious and meticulous in stock selection. The problem is, no matter how knowledgeable or cautious you are, you can&rsquo;t guarantee picking the next Cathay Life Insurance or avoiding the next Kuosheng.</p>
<p>A key point to consider: You don&rsquo;t need to pick the perfect stock like Cathay Life Insurance to become wealthy. <strong>As long as your investment returns are close to the overall market average, you can still become a billionaire.</strong>  To achieve this, you simply need to &ldquo;diversify and choose randomly.&rdquo;</p>
<p>Average investors often fail to understand this, leading them to be overly cautious, spending significant time, effort, and money on analysis, research, seeking hot tips, and consulting experts. This usually leads to two outcomes:</p>
<ol>
<li><strong>Confusion:</strong>  Opinions on which investments are good vary widely, leading to indecision. Unable to find a &ldquo;safe&rdquo; investment, investors often resort to the riskiest long-term move – leaving their money in the bank.</li>
<li><strong>False Sense of Security:</strong>  Sometimes, an investment appears excellent from all angles, with most experts endorsing it. This perceived safety often attracts cautious investors, but these &ldquo;safe&rdquo; investments can be the most dangerous. Remember: <strong>Investments everyone considers good are often the worst.</strong> In mid-1995, almost everyone viewed semiconductor stocks like TSMC and UMC favorably. Many cautious investors flocked to these stocks.  A year later, the market was up 30% on average, while TSMC and UMC plummeted, halving in value.</li>
</ol>
<p>While simple, buying randomly is a difficult investment philosophy to embrace.  But it teaches us a valuable lesson: <strong>Don&rsquo;t overthink stock selection.  Diversify your portfolio and choose randomly. Investing can be that simple.</strong></p>
<blockquote>
<p>The ratio of up days to down days in the stock market is approximately 55:45.</p>
</blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">When to Buy - Buy Anytime 
    <div id="when-to-buy---buy-anytime" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#when-to-buy---buy-anytime" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>Many claim that choosing the right entry point is crucial for investment success, and I agree. However, timing the market is equally difficult and complex.  My proposed strategy is simple, so simple you might find it hard to follow: &ldquo;Buy anytime.&rdquo;</p>
<p>&ldquo;Buy anytime&rdquo; means investing your money whenever you have it, regardless of the day or time.  In other words, don&rsquo;t keep your money in the bank.  Invest any surplus funds beyond your daily needs, regardless of whether you think prices will rise or fall.</p>
<p><strong>Buy and Wait for the Opportunity</strong></p>
<p>Investors often ask, &ldquo;When should I start investing?&rdquo; My answer is &ldquo;Now!&rdquo; Short-term stock prices fluctuate wildly and are unpredictable. You could say, &ldquo;The only predictable thing is unpredictability.&rdquo; Since stocks generally rise in the long term, and future price movements are uncertain, the best approach is to invest and hold long-term, regardless of short-term fluctuations, and wait for the long-term upward trend to emerge.</p>
<p>Stocks tend to have higher returns over the long term, with a higher probability of rising than falling. Statistically, the ratio of up days to down days is approximately 55:45.  Therefore, if you ask me if the market will rise or fall tomorrow, my answer is usually: &ldquo;I don&rsquo;t know, and nobody in the world knows.&rdquo; But if you insist on a guess, the statistically safer bet is that it will rise.</p>
<p>Since the guess is always for a rise, the safest approach is to buy whenever you have money.  When the probability of rising is higher than falling, and you can&rsquo;t predict tomorrow&rsquo;s movement, the best strategy is to &ldquo;buy and wait for the opportunity,&rdquo; not &ldquo;wait for the opportunity to buy.&rdquo;</p>
<p>We often hear older people lamenting, &ldquo;If only I had invested in that stock 30 years ago, I would be&hellip;&rdquo; Perhaps the best time to invest was 20 or 30 years ago, but the second-best time is now.  Act as soon as you have the funds, lest you have the same regrets in a few decades. Life is short; how many decades can we afford to waste?  How long can we allow ourselves to squander precious time?</p>
<p>Buying anytime sounds simple, but it&rsquo;s also very difficult. Try it yourself. If you can do it, you possess the basic qualities for investment success. As long as you adhere to the principles of long-term holding and diversified timing, you can buy stocks anytime.</p>
<p><strong>When to Sell - Don&rsquo;t Sell</strong></p>
<p><em>Before investing, prepare to hold for 20 years, research carefully, and after buying, put it aside and forget about it.</em></p>
<p>A common investor dilemma is: &ldquo;When should I sell?&rdquo; Some experts say, &ldquo;Choosing the right entry point is hard, choosing the right exit point is even harder.&rdquo;  Investment guru Philip Fisher famously advised, &ldquo;If the job has been correctly done when a common stock is purchased, the time to sell it is—almost never.&rdquo; Warren Buffett, who became the richest man in America in 1982 through stock investments, exemplifies this. He holds stocks for an average of 4.5 years. So, my advice on when to sell is: &ldquo;Don&rsquo;t sell.&rdquo;  Hold long-term and minimize trading.</p>
<p>Long-term holding avoids frequent trading costs that erode returns. My research shows that with high-return investments like stocks, the longer the holding period, the lower the risk of loss.  For example, with sufficient diversification, investing in the Taiwan stock market has never resulted in returns lower than bank interest rates for holding periods exceeding 11 years. This demonstrates that &ldquo;diversify and hold long-term,&rdquo; while seemingly simple, is an optimal investment strategy.</p>
<p>What&rsquo;s so hard about not selling? It seems easy enough.  But this is the most challenging of all investment rules and the most crucial factor for investment success. The difficulty lies in remaining unwavering, regardless of price fluctuations. This requires achieving the highest realm of financial management:  &ldquo;<strong>Own the stock, but not the stock price.</strong>&rdquo;</p>
<p>The typical investor&rsquo;s habit is to ignore a stock after buying it if the price falls, allowing it to continue declining and becoming a long-term loss. Conversely, if the price rises, they happily calculate their profits and readily sell after a 5% to 20% gain.  Thus, &ldquo;long-term investing&rdquo; becomes synonymous with being trapped at a high price.  There&rsquo;s nothing remarkable about holding a losing stock long-term. <strong>The real key to investment success is remaining steadfast even when you&rsquo;re profiting.</strong></p>
<p>Jesse Livermore, author of <em>Reminiscences of a Stock Operator</em>, wrote:  &ldquo;I&rsquo;ve been in Wall Street for many years, made fortunes, and lost them. My fortune-making has never depended on my forecasting ability but on my ability to hold positions firmly, unfazed by market fluctuations. You might find many people in the stock market who are incredibly accurate at predicting entry and exit points, yet they don&rsquo;t make much money. It&rsquo;s rare to find someone who can remain unmoved during a sustained market rally, and I&rsquo;ve found this to be the hardest thing to learn in stock investing.  Only by mastering this essence can investors make a fortune.&rdquo;</p>
<p><strong>Endure the Falls, Wait Out the Rises</strong></p>
<p>Traditional thinking dictates:  Buy low, sell high.  However, a new perspective redefines investing as:  <strong>selecting appropriate investment targets and holding them long-term.</strong>  Successful investing requires mastering the eight-character mantra: &ldquo;<strong>Endure the falls, wait out the rises.</strong>&rdquo;  Never be disheartened by price drops or tempted to sell at the first sign of a rally.  Maintain a long-term perspective.</p>
<p>Why do most fortunes come from real estate, while fewer are made from stocks? The key is visibility. Real estate prices are largely invisible, while stock prices are constantly displayed.  Real estate investors often achieve the &ldquo;don&rsquo;t sell&rdquo; mentality, while stock investors, influenced by price fluctuations, rarely do.  If stock investors could embrace the &ldquo;buy and hold&rdquo; approach, stock investing would be as powerful as real estate.</p>
<p>In the past 20 years, Cathay Life Insurance has consistently been among the top-performing listed companies in Taiwan. What&rsquo;s their secret?  They own real estate and stocks, and they buy and hold. This is their business philosophy, and it also applies to personal finance.</p>
<p>Look at the success stories of investors like Lien Chan, Tsai Wan-lin, and Wang Yung-ching.  They all adhered to the principle of &ldquo;don&rsquo;t sell.&rdquo; Tsai Wan-lin&rsquo;s success stemmed from treating stocks like real estate. The Lien family&rsquo;s success in stocks and real estate comes from their ability to hold long-term and remain unmoved.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The more complex the market fluctuations, the simpler the investment method.</p>
</blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">Random Walk and Efficient Market Hypothesis 
    <div id="random-walk-and-efficient-market-hypothesis" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#random-walk-and-efficient-market-hypothesis" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>I must emphasize that &ldquo;buy randomly, buy anytime, don&rsquo;t sell&rdquo; isn&rsquo;t just a catchy phrase; it has a theoretical basis. In the 1950s, the American financial and investment community developed a prominent theory: the Random Walk Hypothesis.</p>
<p><strong>Random Selection is the Best Strategy</strong></p>
<p>It&rsquo;s generally agreed that stock prices, like other commodities, fluctuate unpredictably. The Random Walk Hypothesis states that stock price movements are so complex that they resemble random changes, nearly impossible to predict.  This hypothesis highlights the unpredictable nature of stock prices and, more importantly, leads to a simple yet crucial investment method: the Buy-and-Hold strategy, which is essentially &ldquo;buy randomly, buy anytime, don&rsquo;t sell.&rdquo;</p>
<p>The Buy-and-Hold strategy means investing available funds immediately upon availability (rather than predicting market upswings), holding those investments long-term without selling (locking them away and ignoring short-term fluctuations), and selling only when funds are needed (not in anticipation of market downturns).  In short, the Buy-and-Hold strategy advocates investing consistently, holding long-term, and selling only when necessary, without trying to time the market. If stock price movements follow the Random Walk Hypothesis, the best investment strategy is random selection and long-term holding – the very essence of &ldquo;buy randomly, buy anytime, don&rsquo;t sell.&rdquo;</p>
<p>Another implication of &ldquo;buy randomly, buy anytime, don&rsquo;t sell&rdquo; is that analysis and prediction are futile. The Efficient Market Hypothesis states that in an efficient market, all information that could affect stock prices is quickly and fully reflected in those prices. By the time you receive information from analysis reports or publications, it&rsquo;s already outdated and incorporated into the price. In other words, in an efficient market, stock prices are always in equilibrium, and no investor can consistently beat the market by collecting and analyzing information to gain excess returns.</p>
<p><strong>In-depth Analysis is a Waste of Time</strong></p>
<p>The Efficient Market Hypothesis, introduced by renowned financial expert Eugene Fama in the 1970s, emphasizes that you don&rsquo;t need to be an analyst or expert to build wealth through investing.  Painstakingly researching and analyzing stocks is a waste of time because most useful information is already reflected in the price. Studying this information offers no advantage. It&rsquo;s better to invest your money and hold long-term.</p>
<p>The Efficient Market Hypothesis teaches us: <strong>Ignore the noise. Don&rsquo;t waste time, effort, and money gathering information, as it&rsquo;s mostly already priced in and thus worthless.  There&rsquo;s no need to learn complex analysis methods because most are ineffective.</strong></p>
<p>By adopting the strategy advocated in this book – diversification, buying randomly, buying anytime, and not selling – you can achieve excellent returns.</p>
<p><em>1. Short-term stock price movements are random, making it impossible to predict when prices will rise or fall.</em></p>
<p><em>2. Although short-term stock prices are unpredictable, the long-term trend is upward due to continuous economic growth.  Buying and holding stocks long-term, with the compounding effect offsetting risks over time, yields considerable average returns.</em></p>
<p><em>3. Almost all publicly available information is already reflected in stock prices, making it unhelpful for investors.</em></p>
<p><em>4. Most analytical methods used by investors are already factored into stock prices.  Using commonly employed analysis techniques will not generate excess returns, meaning you won&rsquo;t outperform the buy-and-hold strategy in the long run.</em></p>
<p>For years, facing the ever-changing investment world, I&rsquo;ve sought a method that transcends the &ldquo;busyness and blindness&rdquo; of financial management.  &ldquo;Buy randomly, buy anytime, don&rsquo;t sell&rdquo; is the principle of simplifying complex problems.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Personal Investment Bible: Investment Iron Law Ⅶ</title>
      <link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1731056005966/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1731056005966/</guid>
      <description>This article explores the long-term value of stock investment, using the example of Liu Qiude, Vice President of Cathay Life Insurance, to illustrate the advantages of holding high-quality stocks for the long term.  It analyzes the reasons for the high return rate of stocks, arguing that corporate profitability and asset appreciation are the main drivers of stock price increases.  The article also compares the advantages and disadvantages of stock investment and real estate investment, pointing out that stock investment has advantages such as smaller investment units, lower taxes, and easier trading.  In addition, the article discusses the future development trend of the Taiwan stock market and the characteristics of different types of stocks, recommending that investors prioritize listed stocks or mutual funds and avoid margin trading.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[

<h2 class="relative group">Investment Iron Law Seven: Mastering Stock Investment 
    <div id="investment-iron-law-seven-mastering-stock-investment" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#investment-iron-law-seven-mastering-stock-investment" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>Choose the right stocks, hold them long-term, and watch their value grow.</p>
</blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">The Secret to Liu Qiude&rsquo;s Fortune 
    <div id="the-secret-to-liu-qiudes-fortune" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#the-secret-to-liu-qiudes-fortune" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>It is said that Tsai Wan-lin, once Taiwan&rsquo;s richest man and the world&rsquo;s fifth wealthiest individual, declared at a Cathay Life Insurance executive meeting, &ldquo;I don&rsquo;t just want to be rich; I want those who strive with me to be rich as well.  Those of you present with less than ten million in assets, please raise your hands.&rdquo;  The executives remained silent. Not because no one dared to raise their hands, nor because no one possessed such wealth, but because for Cathay Life&rsquo;s senior management, many boasted fortunes exceeding one hundred million.</p>
<p>Liu Qiude, the current Vice President, who joined Cathay Life in his twenties, became a billionaire by following the right person and investing in the right stock. From the beginning of his career, besides the company&rsquo;s stock options, he consistently invested any spare cash in buying shares from colleagues looking to sell. When Taiwan faced political or economic crises, and some Cathay employees rushed to sell their holdings, he bought them all.  Holding these shares for two to three decades, without ever selling, he effortlessly became a billionaire.  He himself couldn&rsquo;t say exactly how many shares he owned, stating, &ldquo;I won&rsquo;t know the exact number of Cathay Life shares until they are all transferred.&rdquo;</p>
<p><strong>Unsure of His Own Dividend Earnings</strong></p>
<p>In 1981, the average price of a Cathay Life share (1000 shares) was about NT$45,000. After 15 years of stock dividends, by 1996, this had increased to 48.7 shares (see table below).  Calculated at a market price of NT$160,000 per share, the market value would be approximately NT$7.795 million, a 171-fold increase in 15 years. This impressive growth doesn&rsquo;t even include the cash dividends received over the years.  With such a staggering rate of return, it&rsquo;s no wonder Liu Qiude is unsure of his exact share count.  He&rsquo;s likely worth well over a billion, perhaps even ten billion or more.</p>
<p><em>Cathay Life Insurance 15-Year Stock Dividend and Capital Increase</em></p>
<table>
  <thead>
      <tr>
          <th style="text-align: left">Year</th>
          <th style="text-align: left">Cash Dividend</th>
          <th style="text-align: left">Stock Dividend</th>
          <th style="text-align: left">Accumulated Shares (Assuming 1 share purchased in 1981)</th>
      </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
      <tr>
          <td style="text-align: left">1981</td>
          <td style="text-align: left">3</td>
          <td style="text-align: left">-</td>
          <td style="text-align: left">1</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td style="text-align: left">1982</td>
          <td style="text-align: left">2</td>
          <td style="text-align: left">0</td>
          <td style="text-align: left">1</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td style="text-align: left">1983</td>
          <td style="text-align: left">1</td>
          <td style="text-align: left">150</td>
          <td style="text-align: left">1.15</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td style="text-align: left">1984</td>
          <td style="text-align: left">1</td>
          <td style="text-align: left">300</td>
          <td style="text-align: left">1.50</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td style="text-align: left">1985</td>
          <td style="text-align: left">1</td>
          <td style="text-align: left">300</td>
          <td style="text-align: left">1.94</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td style="text-align: left">1986</td>
          <td style="text-align: left">1.2</td>
          <td style="text-align: left">300</td>
          <td style="text-align: left">2.53</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td style="text-align: left">1987</td>
          <td style="text-align: left">1</td>
          <td style="text-align: left">300</td>
          <td style="text-align: left">3.28</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td style="text-align: left">1988</td>
          <td style="text-align: left">1</td>
          <td style="text-align: left">400</td>
          <td style="text-align: left">4.60</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td style="text-align: left">1989</td>
          <td style="text-align: left">1</td>
          <td style="text-align: left">500</td>
          <td style="text-align: left">6.90</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td style="text-align: left">1990</td>
          <td style="text-align: left">1</td>
          <td style="text-align: left">500</td>
          <td style="text-align: left">10.35</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td style="text-align: left">1991</td>
          <td style="text-align: left">1.5</td>
          <td style="text-align: left">500</td>
          <td style="text-align: left">15.52</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td style="text-align: left">1992</td>
          <td style="text-align: left">1.2</td>
          <td style="text-align: left">300</td>
          <td style="text-align: left">20.18</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td style="text-align: left">1993</td>
          <td style="text-align: left">0</td>
          <td style="text-align: left">250</td>
          <td style="text-align: left">25.22</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td style="text-align: left">1994</td>
          <td style="text-align: left">1.5</td>
          <td style="text-align: left">400</td>
          <td style="text-align: left">35.31</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td style="text-align: left">1995</td>
          <td style="text-align: left">1.5</td>
          <td style="text-align: left">200</td>
          <td style="text-align: left">42.37</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td style="text-align: left">1996</td>
          <td style="text-align: left">1.5</td>
          <td style="text-align: left">150</td>
          <td style="text-align: left">48.42</td>
      </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>
<p><em>Source: (Taiwan) Economic Daily News</em></p>
<p>The Tsai family themselves followed a similar strategy. To maintain control of Cathay Life, they held their shares long-term through investment companies.  Tsai Chen-yu, Chairman of First Commercial Bank, pointed out that selling these shares was practically impossible; they had become like real estate.  One of the main reasons Tsai Wan-lin became Taiwan&rsquo;s richest man was his ability to hold Cathay Life stock long-term.</p>
<p>Cathay Life isn&rsquo;t the only company that has created immense wealth for ordinary white-collar workers. Professional managers at several other large Taiwanese companies also accumulated significant fortunes. According to the Taiwan Stock Exchange, from the end of 1990 to April 30, 1996, the average return on all stocks was 35.41%.  During this period, holding United Microelectronics Corporation (UMC) stock would have yielded a return of 726.04%, Acer 421.54%, Tatung 335.88%, China Development Financial Holding Corporation 225.55%, Uni-President Enterprises Corporation 191.30%, and Nan Ya Plastics Corporation 123.77%.  These examples demonstrate that long-term investment in blue-chip stocks can lead to substantial gains.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The higher the economic growth rate, the higher the average long-term stock market return.</p>
</blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">Why Stocks Offer High Returns 
    <div id="why-stocks-offer-high-returns" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#why-stocks-offer-high-returns" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>Why is long-term stock investment profitable?  First, I must clarify a key concept that all stock investors should understand. Investing in stocks generates profits primarily because the companies you invest in earn money, which ultimately belongs to the shareholders.  Your profit doesn&rsquo;t rely on other investors losing money.</p>
<p>Stocks represent ownership in a company. Stockholders are shareholders of the enterprise, and they have two inherent rights: the right to share in the company&rsquo;s profits and the right to distribute remaining assets. If the company is profitable, the profits ultimately go to the shareholders. Similarly, when a company owns assets, those assets ultimately belong to the shareholders.  Therefore, investing in profitable or asset-rich companies can, in the long run, not only yield dividends from corporate earnings but also a share of the value when assets are liquidated.</p>
<p><strong>Average Stock Market Return of 17%-18%</strong></p>
<p>The long-term price appreciation of stocks is primarily based on two factors:</p>
<p><em>(1) Increased corporate profitability leads to higher dividends for shareholders, thus driving up stock prices.</em></p>
<p><em>(2)  An increase in the value of a company&rsquo;s assets, such as real estate or investments in other stocks, ultimately benefits shareholders, therefore causing stock prices to rise.</em></p>
<p>Consequently, if a company&rsquo;s profitability continues to rise, or the value of its assets, like real estate, continues to appreciate, stock prices will inevitably rise in the long run, and shareholder returns will increase accordingly.</p>
<p>Over the past few decades, Taiwanese companies have experienced stable profit growth and rising real estate prices, resulting in stock market returns far exceeding bank deposit interest rates.  Data shows that over the past 25 years, the average annual return on the Taiwan stock market has been around 17%-18%.  In Europe, the United States, Japan, and other developed countries, the average annual return over a 10-year period is typically between 12%-17%. Simply put, the higher the economic growth rate, the higher the average long-term stock market return.</p>
<p>According to research by several scholars, the Taiwan Weighted Stock Index, starting at 100 points in 1966, reached 12,682 points over 27 years, before falling back to 2,458 points by the end of 1993.  This translates to an average annual return of over 17%.  These calculations assume that investors consistently bought stocks whenever they had funds and held them until the present without selling.</p>
<p>The Taiwan Stock Exchange conducted another study showing that if you had invested in the stock market 20 years ago and held your investments until the end of 1994 without trading, your return would have been at least 13.7 times your initial investment, with a maximum potential return of 1,384 times. This demonstrates the impressive potential of the Taiwan stock market.</p>
<p>Learning from the past can inform the future. The Taiwan stock market has historically delivered high long-term returns.  Even in recent years, investors who avoided the frenzy of speculative buying and instead opted for diversified, long-term holdings have seen decent returns.  Looking ahead, I firmly believe that readers who adhere to the principles of diversification and long-term holding can still achieve substantial results through stock investment.</p>
<p><strong>Stock Investment vs. Real Estate Investment</strong></p>
<p>This book recommends two investment tools with high potential returns: stocks and real estate.  Which is better?  The answer depends on individual financial circumstances, product knowledge, risk tolerance, and tax situation. There&rsquo;s no one-size-fits-all solution. However, stock investment offers several advantages over real estate:</p>
<ol>
<li>
<p>Real estate investment requires larger capital, often over NT$1 million, which can be a barrier for young people entering the workforce.  Stock investment, on the other hand, can be started with just tens of thousands, or even a few thousand NT dollars.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Long-term stock investment generally incurs lower taxes than real estate.  In Taiwan, stock investments are exempt from capital gains tax, with the primary tax being securities transaction tax.  Long-term investors who avoid frequent trading pay limited taxes, and capital gains upon selling are tax-free.  Real estate investment requires annual property and land taxes, and transaction taxes upon sale.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Stock trading is simpler than real estate transactions.  Buying or selling listed stocks requires just a phone call, and payment is made via remittance. Purchased shares are held by a centralized depository, adding to the convenience. Real estate transactions involve complex procedures for transferring ownership, which can be time-consuming.  Property management and maintenance can also be demanding.</p>
</li>
</ol>
<p>In conclusion, for investors who diversify and hold long-term, stocks are an excellent investment tool for individuals and families. Unfortunately, most stock investors are unable to withstand the fluctuations of the market and the temptation of short-term gains.  Frequent trading often leads to losses due to high transaction costs.  This explains why, despite the high average long-term returns of the stock market, few people become wealthy through stock investment.</p>
<p><strong>Can Stocks Maintain High Returns in the Future?</strong></p>
<p>Investors often ask me, &ldquo;The high average annual returns of over 20% in the past were due to Taiwan&rsquo;s rapid economic growth over the past two to three decades.  Now that Taiwan&rsquo;s economic growth has slowed, can we still expect such high returns in the future?&rdquo;</p>
<p>If the question is whether the Taiwan stock market can maintain an average annual return of over 30%, I believe that&rsquo;s unlikely.  A country or region&rsquo;s stock market return is directly influenced by the profitability of its companies, which is essentially linked to the economic growth rate. Taiwan&rsquo;s economy is maturing.  While the average annual growth rate was around 9% for the past few decades, it&rsquo;s now around 6%, and this trend is expected to continue.</p>
<p>With a declining economic growth rate, it&rsquo;s improbable that the stock market will maintain returns above 20%.  However, I estimate that future stock returns should remain above 15%.  This is based on the observation that in developed economies like the US, Japan, and Europe, long-term stock returns remain between 10%-15% even after their economies mature. Although Taiwan&rsquo;s economic growth rate may decrease, a 10% growth rate is still impressive compared to other regions, making Taiwanese stocks a worthwhile investment.  Furthermore, Taiwan&rsquo;s increasing financial liberalization is likely to attract foreign investment, which will further boost the stock market&rsquo;s performance.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Untapped gold mines are plentiful; careful selection leads to boundless profits.</p>
</blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">Choosing the Right Stocks 
    <div id="choosing-the-right-stocks" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#choosing-the-right-stocks" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>Generally, stocks can be categorized into four types: listed stocks, over-the-counter (OTC) stocks, unlisted stocks, and mutual funds.  Each type has distinct characteristics that investors should understand to avoid regrets.</p>
<p><strong>Varying Returns, Liquidity, and Security</strong></p>
<p>Listed stocks are traded on the Taiwan Stock Exchange.  They offer high long-term average returns, good liquidity, transparent financial and business operations, centralized trading with fair market pricing, low taxes for long-term investors (exempt from capital gains tax), and dividends eligible for tax exemptions. Listed stocks offer greater security than unlisted stocks.  I recommend that readers with long-term savings consider diversifying their investments in listed stocks and holding them long-term.</p>
<p>OTC stocks are traded on the over-the-counter market through negotiated pricing.  The trading mechanism is similar to listed stocks, but with lower trading volume and liquidity.  Generally, the listing requirements for OTC stocks are less stringent than for listed stocks, with lower requirements for capital and profitability, resulting in lower security. One disadvantage of OTC stocks is that their dividends are not eligible for tax exemptions.</p>
<p>Unlisted stocks are not traded on either the stock exchange or the OTC market.  They have lower liquidity, no fair market price, lack transparent financial and business operations, and are not subject to regulatory oversight by the Securities and Futures Bureau (SFB) and the stock exchange, resulting in higher risk and lower security. Their dividends are also ineligible for tax exemptions.  While unlisted stocks offer higher potential returns and the possibility of discovering hidden gems, their lack of oversight makes them risky.  I recommend focusing on listed stocks, which are sufficient for building wealth.  Invest in unlisted stocks only if you have a thorough understanding of the company, its valuation, and trust in its management.</p>
<p><strong>The Best Tool for Beginner Stock Investors</strong></p>
<p>Mutual funds, or investment trust funds, pool money from small investors, entrusting it to professional investment management companies.  Investment experts manage these funds with a diversified approach, and the returns belong to the original investors.  Mutual funds are classified into open-end and closed-end funds based on their issuance and trading methods.</p>
<p>Open-end funds allow investors to buy and sell shares at any time based on the net asset value.  The total amount of the fund fluctuates as investors buy and sell shares. Closed-end funds have a fixed number of shares. Investors wishing to purchase these funds must buy from existing shareholders.  Similarly, existing shareholders must sell their shares on the open market; they cannot redeem them from the issuing company.  Funds traded on the stock exchange are closed-end funds, and their transaction tax is only 1%.</p>
<p>Mutual funds are professionally managed by experts and offer diversification, generally providing good returns.  However, their long-term average returns may be lower than the overall market due to management fees, custodian fees, transaction fees, and other expenses.  Because of their smaller investment units and lower risk compared to listed stocks, mutual funds are an ideal investment tool for beginners. To avoid long-term fees, I recommend index funds, such as the Formosa Fund or CTBC Financial ETF 0050, which offer better long-term returns.</p>
<p>This book primarily recommends investing in listed stocks due to their stable long-term average returns.  Unless you have specific reasons for investing in other types of stocks, you should allocate most of your funds to listed stocks or stock mutual funds.  The most important reason is that long-term investment in listed stocks is sufficient for building wealth.</p>
<p><strong>Margin Trading is Unsuitable for Listed Stock Investment</strong></p>
<p>Some investors ask, &ldquo;If the long-term return on stocks is higher than the margin interest rate, shouldn&rsquo;t margin trading accelerate wealth accumulation?&rdquo;  Theoretically, yes. If you can diversify and hold listed stocks long-term, margin trading can leverage financial leverage to accelerate wealth growth. However, in practice, most people who use margin trading for stock investment lose money.</p>
<p>Why?  The reason is simple.  It&rsquo;s the same reason why many investors lose money in the stock market despite its high long-term average returns.  Daily stock price fluctuations tempt investors to chase short-term gains.  They become driven by greed and fear, leading to frequent trading, often buying high and selling low, which ultimately results in losses.</p>
<p>This behavior is already prevalent with fully funded stock purchases.  Margin trading exacerbates the problem. The leverage magnifies the gains and losses, further tempting investors to chase short-term profits while increasing the psychological pressure.  This leads to even more frequent trading and ultimately greater losses.</p>
<p>My research on margin trading balances for listed stocks shows that margin balances are lower when stock prices are low.  When prices rise significantly, investors begin using margin, with margin balances peaking when stock prices are high. This indicates that investors are often hesitant to use margin when they should, and aggressively use it when they shouldn&rsquo;t, when prices are already high.  In short, margin trading for listed stocks often leads to mistakes and should generally be avoided.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Personal Investment Bible: Investment Iron Law III</title>
      <link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1731056005962/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1731056005962/</guid>
      <description>This article explores the importance of investing and managing finances, emphasizing the principle of &amp;#39;the sooner, the better.&amp;#39; It points out that procrastination is the primary cause of financial failure and encourages young people to start managing their finances early, rather than waiting until middle or old age.  The article uses the success stories of Warren Buffett and Jeffrey Koo Jr. to illustrate the power of long-term investment and compound interest. It also emphasizes that even with limited funds, one should start managing their finances and learn how to utilize high-return investment tools to grow their wealth.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[

<h2 class="relative group">Investment Iron Law III: Invest Sooner Rather Than Later 
    <div id="investment-iron-law-iii-invest-sooner-rather-than-later" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#investment-iron-law-iii-invest-sooner-rather-than-later" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>Invest first, then wait for the opportunity,<br>
rather than waiting for the opportunity to invest.</p>
</blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">Procrastination: The Primary Cause of Financial Failure 
    <div id="procrastination-the-primary-cause-of-financial-failure" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#procrastination-the-primary-cause-of-financial-failure" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>The mentality of &ldquo;things will work out&rdquo; and a passive approach to financial management is the most common obstacle to personal finance. It&rsquo;s also the main reason why many people struggle to achieve financial independence by retirement.  Many individuals adopt a passive attitude towards financial planning, believing that things will naturally fall into place. As they age and witness the rapid growth of others&rsquo; wealth, they finally realize the importance of financial management.  However, by then, time is often limited, the power of compound interest cannot be fully utilized, and it becomes too late, even if they understand the principles of financial management.</p>
<p><strong>Financial Management Is Not Just for the Middle-Aged</strong></p>
<p>Many young people believe that financial management is something for middle-aged or wealthy individuals, and that it&rsquo;s not too late to worry about it in old age.  Here, I want to remind readers that the ability to build wealth through financial management has little correlation with the amount of money one possesses, but a significant correlation with the length of time invested.  People often reach middle age, facing retirement with some savings, and only then start thinking about preparing for their financial future. However, at this point, it&rsquo;s often too late. The reason is insufficient time to allow compound interest to work its magic.  Turning small amounts of money into substantial wealth requires at least two to three decades.  Recall the previous example: 10 years is not enough time to see significant growth.  A much longer period is needed for remarkable results.</p>
<p>Since we know that building wealth through investment requires investing in high-return assets and leveraging the long-term effects of compound interest, our approach, besides enriching our investment knowledge and skills, should involve immediate action.  Financial planning should start as early as possible, cultivating patience and a long-term perspective.</p>
<p>The reason for many financial failures today is the lack of knowledge about how to utilize funds effectively to achieve the goal of making money work for you and building wealth through investment. This is a flaw in our education system. Schools dedicate significant time to teaching students how to earn a living but fail to teach them how to manage their earnings.  College students exploring financial management through stock investment are often viewed as engaging in speculative and greedy behavior. In a future dominated by finance, the lack of proper financial knowledge not only erodes the dream of wealth accumulation but also harms the financial operations of businesses and the overall prosperity of society.</p>
<p>Don&rsquo;t delay your financial plan using the excuse of uncertain future price trends.  Who can predict when real estate or stock prices will rise?  Past price surges always lead to regret for those who missed out. There are no clear signs before prices start to rise, and no one will announce it with fanfare. <strong>For investments that are unpredictable in the short term but offer high expected returns in the long term, the safest strategy is to invest first and then wait for the opportunity, not the other way around.</strong></p>
<p><strong>Warren Buffett Started Investing at Age 11</strong></p>
<p><em>I believe every business school graduate should sign a contract pledging to make no more than 20 major decisions in their lifetime. If your career spans 40 years, that&rsquo;s one decision every two years.</em></p>
<p>Warren Buffett, ranked the second richest man in America by Forbes magazine in 1996, is widely regarded as the god of stock investment. He claims that more than half of his net worth is attributed to about ten investment decisions. He believes the key to investment is to buy stocks of good companies at good prices and hold them for the long term. As long as these companies continue to perform well, don&rsquo;t sell their stocks.</p>
<p>Buffett, with a net worth of $9 billion, amassed his fortune entirely from the stock market.  At 68, he held an MBA from Columbia University and was the son of a stockbroker-turned-congressman.  Buffett made his first investment at the age of 11, putting his and his sister&rsquo;s small savings into the stock market. Initially, he lost money, and his sister criticized him, but he insisted that it would take three to four years to see profits. His sister sold her shares, while he held on, ultimately proving his point.</p>
<p>At 20, while studying at Columbia University, Buffett immersed himself in finance books and insurance industry statistics while his peers focused on leisure activities.  Lacking capital and disliking borrowing, he often sold stocks prematurely to reinvest in others. Despite the limitations of his funds, his wealth continued to grow.</p>
<p>In 1954, he joined Professor Graham&rsquo;s investment firm. Two years later, he raised $100,000 from family and friends and established his own firm. After its assets increased thirtyfold, he dissolved the company in 1969, returned the partners&rsquo; money, and focused on his own investments.</p>
<p>He is a true stock market tycoon and has been America&rsquo;s richest man for years. Other wealthy Americans, like Bill Gates and Henry Lea Hillman, built their fortunes through businesses, while Buffett focused on stock investment. As long as the US economy continues to grow, his wealth will continue to increase.</p>
<p>Buffett&rsquo;s immense wealth, accumulated through nearly 60 years of investing, is a testament to the power of compound interest.  His early experiences with trial and error played a crucial role in honing his investment acumen.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Financial management is like farming.<br>
A bountiful harvest in the future depends on diligent sowing and watering today.</p>
</blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">Start Investing Today 
    <div id="start-investing-today" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#start-investing-today" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>If time is an indispensable element of financial management, the best strategy is to act now. Start managing your finances today!</p>
<p><strong>Don&rsquo;t Wait Until Your Hair Turns White</strong></p>
<p>The earlier you start investing, the sooner you&rsquo;ll achieve your financial goals and enjoy the fruits of your labor with your family. Furthermore, starting early maximizes the time for compound interest to work, requiring smaller initial investments and making financial management easier and more enjoyable.</p>
<p>Starting later requires significantly higher monthly investments to reach the same goals. The following table is based on these assumptions: an annual return of 15%, a target amount of 100 million yuan, and a retirement age of 65. It calculates the required monthly investment for different starting ages.</p>
<p><em>Monthly Investment Required to Become a Millionaire, by Starting Age</em></p>
<table>
  <thead>
      <tr>
          <th style="text-align: left">Starting Age</th>
          <th style="text-align: left">Monthly Investment (Yuan)</th>
      </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
      <tr>
          <td style="text-align: left">20</td>
          <td style="text-align: left">2324</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td style="text-align: left">25</td>
          <td style="text-align: left">4684</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td style="text-align: left">30</td>
          <td style="text-align: left">9458</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td style="text-align: left">35</td>
          <td style="text-align: left">19863</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td style="text-align: left">40</td>
          <td style="text-align: left">39163</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td style="text-align: left">45</td>
          <td style="text-align: left">81348</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td style="text-align: left">50</td>
          <td style="text-align: left">175143</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td style="text-align: left">55</td>
          <td style="text-align: left">410428</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td style="text-align: left">60</td>
          <td style="text-align: left">1235959</td>
      </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>
<p>The table clearly demonstrates that youth is a valuable asset in wealth accumulation. The younger you are, the better positioned you are to achieve the dream of building wealth from small investments.  Starting financial planning in old age requires monthly investments that are beyond the reach of most people. In short, start saving for retirement early. Don&rsquo;t wait until your hair turns white; time waits for no one.</p>
<p>Your future financial well-being depends on your actions today. Don&rsquo;t let hesitation hold you back. Follow the principles outlined in this book, invest your funds in the stock market, real estate, or other high-return investment vehicles, and over time, you too can become wealthy.</p>
<p><em>1. The earlier you start investing, the longer the time for compound interest to work, and the sooner you&rsquo;ll achieve your wealth goals.</em></p>
<p><em>2. Only young people can dream of building wealth from small investments.</em></p>
<p><em>3. The best time to start managing your finances is as early as possible.</em></p>
<p><strong>Jeffrey Koo Jr.&rsquo;s Path to Wealth</strong></p>
<p>Jeffrey Koo Jr., the eldest son of Jeffrey Koo Sr., chairman of Chinatrust Commercial Bank in Taiwan, and current Vice President of Chinatrust, is actively uniting the third generation of Taiwanese entrepreneurs. He organized a luncheon club primarily for the third generation of prominent Taiwanese business families to network and exchange information. To expand its influence, Koo Jr. has also strengthened the luncheon club&rsquo;s connections with Southeast Asian politicians and the second and third generations of overseas Chinese business families.</p>
<p>Koo Jr. is a representative figure among Taiwan&rsquo;s third-generation entrepreneurs and the heir apparent to his father. Many assume his wealthy background afforded him a comfortable financial situation. However, Koo Sr. instilled frugal habits in his children and didn&rsquo;t provide excessive allowances.  Koo Jr. had to find his own ways to become financially independent.</p>
<p>Sent to Japan for his education by his father, Koo Jr. returned to Taiwan for university after graduating high school with only his accumulated New Year&rsquo;s money, around NT$100,000, in his bank account. In early 1987, as the weighted stock price index climbed from 1,000 points, many people invested in the stock market. Koo Jr., then a junior in college, followed suit, investing all his savings.  His grandmother&rsquo;s daily routine of asking him to recite the stock market index further influenced him.  His frequent interactions with entrepreneurs from various industries provided him with business opportunities, enabling him to grow his NT$100,000 capital to NT$10 million during the bull market.</p>
<p>When the stock market crashed from over 10,000 points in 1990, he was already pursuing his Master&rsquo;s degree at the Wharton School of Business in the US. His father, hoping for him to join the family business sooner, disapproved of his overseas studies and threatened to withhold financial support. Koo Jr. confidently assured his father that he could support himself financially. He successfully completed his studies in the US and even bought his dream car, a Porsche, with his own money.  Koo Jr.&rsquo;s knack for investment and financial management from a young age made his dreams a reality. If you aspire to be wealthy, start now!</p>
<p><strong>Youth Is the Greatest Asset for Financial Success</strong></p>
<p>Successful people have a habit: they delay, but don&rsquo;t give up, the enjoyment of the fruits of their labor.</p>
<p>In Louis Cha&rsquo;s novel <em>The Book and the Sword</em>, the Qianlong Emperor tells his sworn brother, &ldquo;I don&rsquo;t envy anything about you except your youth.&rdquo; Even the emperor envied youth.</p>
<p>Similarly, from a financial perspective, youth is the most important asset. I often tell college students, &ldquo;Young people, your name is wealth!&rdquo;  The compound interest formula clearly shows that time is money, and youth is wealth.</p>
<p>The compound interest chart provides a clear roadmap for financial planning: focus on increasing income and saving during your youth and start investing early. Money saved during youth contributes significantly to wealth in old age.  NT$10,000 saved in your youth can grow to over NT$2.3 million in 30 years.  The same amount saved in old age will only grow to NT$60,000 in 10 years. Whether the statement &ldquo;Young people, your name is wealth&rdquo; becomes a reality depends on whether young people manage their finances wisely. Poor financial management, even with the advantage of youth, will not bring wealth.</p>
<p>The prevalent notion among young people today is that it&rsquo;s fine to indulge in enjoyment while young and worry about financial planning later. This is a misguided perspective. Many young people believe retirement is far off and their funds are limited, so there&rsquo;s no need to consider investment. They often miss the opportunity to start early.</p>
<p>In reality, starting financial planning in old age, even with some savings, is often too late due to limited time. The correct approach is: <strong>investing and managing finances is the job of young people, while managing wealth is the job of old age.</strong>  However, many young people prioritize immediate gratification, spending their money on sports cars, high-end audio systems, or travel, believing they can enjoy life now and worry about finances later.</p>
<p>If you understand the role of time in financial management, it&rsquo;s easy to see why such individuals are destined for mediocrity.  Countless examples in society demonstrate how prioritizing enjoyment in youth leads to poverty in old age. The key is their neglect of the importance of early financial planning. By the time they realize it, it&rsquo;s often too late.</p>
<p>As Taiwan&rsquo;s population ages and smaller family structures become the norm, future generations will rely on their own financial resources for living expenses. Therefore, the concept of starting financial planning in youth becomes increasingly critical.</p>
<p><strong>Youth Is the Best Time for Taking Risks</strong></p>
<p>Young people possess the most valuable asset in financial management - time. Youth is also the best time to take risks because family responsibilities are generally lighter. Young people should embrace a risk-taking mindset because the cost of failure is lower.  You can recover from setbacks more easily. Moreover, with limited funds, potential losses are smaller, providing valuable learning experiences.  Most importantly, young people have ample time for compound interest to work its magic.</p>
<p>Before 50, one shouldn&rsquo;t adopt an overly conservative approach to investment and financial management. The best time to learn about financial management is as early as possible. Sound financial judgment comes from experience, and experience comes from mistakes. Since developing good judgment requires making some mistakes along the way, why not gain this experience while you&rsquo;re young and the stakes are lower?  By the time you have more capital, you can apply your honed financial judgment effectively.</p>
<p>Young people should not just spend money but also understand the importance of saving. Start saving, and once you have a few thousand or tens of thousands of yuan, consider long-term, high-return investments, even if they carry some risk.</p>
<p>Some may feel they are no longer young and their current income is low, leaving no surplus for investment. Indeed, older individuals have less time to benefit from compound interest. However, don&rsquo;t be discouraged. Money can buy time, and you might still have opportunities to catch up.  By following sound financial principles, you can achieve unexpected gains. If you are past 50, help your children by sharing these fundamental wealth-building concepts so they don&rsquo;t miss out on the opportunity to build wealth early in their lives.  Instead of giving your next generation money, teach them the knowledge of making money work for them.</p>
<p><em>1. Youth is the greatest asset for building wealth through financial management. 2. Young people should embrace risk-taking because the cost of failure is lower.</em> <em>3. Invest when you&rsquo;re young to maximize the benefits of compound interest over time.</em></p>
<blockquote>
<p>Playing a good hand well is nothing special; playing a bad hand well is what deserves admiration.</p>
</blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">Don&rsquo;t Neglect Financial Management Due to Limited Funds 
    <div id="dont-neglect-financial-management-due-to-limited-funds" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#dont-neglect-financial-management-due-to-limited-funds" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>Some believe that financial management is exclusive to the wealthy and high-income families, requiring substantial capital to even consider it.  Indeed, financial management is about making money work for you. It&rsquo;s not about turning stone into gold or creating something from nothing, so you need some initial capital. However, what many don&rsquo;t realize is that the most influential factors on future wealth, according to the compound interest formula, are the rate of return and the length of the investment period, not the current amount of capital or future contributions.</p>
<p><strong>Small Beginnings Can Lead to Great Fortunes</strong></p>
<p>With the right approach, even a small amount of money can generate significant wealth over time, as illustrated in previous examples.  Even someone with no initial capital, by investing 14,000 yuan annually, can become a millionaire in 40 years.  <strong>The principle of investment and financial management is this: understanding how to utilize high-return tools and the long-term effects of compound interest is more important than the amount of money invested.</strong></p>
<p>A common misconception is that financial planning is only necessary after accumulating a large sum of money. In reality, the key factors influencing future wealth are the rate of return and the length of investment period, not the amount of capital.  The key to successful financial management lies in maximizing returns and holding investments for the long term.  While having more capital can accelerate wealth accumulation, it&rsquo;s not the decisive factor.</p>
<p>Perhaps you&rsquo;ve considered investing but dismissed the idea due to limited funds. By doing so, you&rsquo;ve missed a valuable opportunity to enhance your investment skills.  The focus of investment should not be on &ldquo;how much money is earned&rdquo; but on &ldquo;the rate of return&rdquo; at which money is earned.  For example, earning 5,000 yuan on a principal of 100,000 yuan represents a 5% return, which is a poor investment. Earning 2,000 yuan on a principal of 10,000 yuan represents a 20% return, which is a good investment.  Over time, the latter will significantly outperform the former.  Therefore, the earlier you learn financial management, the better. It allows limited funds to leverage the power of compound interest and create substantial wealth.</p>
<p><strong>Those with Less Should Strive Harder</strong></p>
<p>Some may question how to invest with only a few thousand or tens of thousands of yuan. In today&rsquo;s developed financial markets, investment units are highly divisible. Around 10,000 yuan can buy a lower-priced stock, and a few thousand yuan can be invested in mutual funds.  Real estate is also moving towards securitization. In short, there will be more investment options for smaller amounts in the future.  Therefore, any idle funds not needed in the short term, even a few thousand yuan, should be invested.</p>
<p>Are people truly too poor to manage small amounts of money?  During the Chang Hwa Credit Cooperative bank run, many ordinary people withdrew hundreds of thousands of yuan.  Statistics also show that the average bank deposit is 600,000 yuan, which is more than enough for investment purposes.</p>
<p>Even those with no current savings or expecting limited future income shouldn&rsquo;t underestimate themselves and give up on financial planning. While wealthy or high-income individuals have a head start, those with fewer assets or lower incomes should understand the principles of financial management and leverage it to compensate for their financial disadvantages, ultimately improving their lifetime financial situation.</p>
<p>Moreover, individuals from humble beginnings and with modest incomes can achieve a greater sense of accomplishment by building wealth through diligent financial management.  As the saying goes, &ldquo;<strong>There&rsquo;s nothing remarkable about playing a good hand well; it&rsquo;s playing a bad hand well that deserves admiration.</strong>&rdquo; If you truly have no money, find ways to increase income and reduce expenses, save some money, and then start managing your finances. Remember, even a small amount of money is enough to begin. While the path to wealth may be longer and more challenging with limited initial funds, the goal is still achievable, and the journey itself is valuable.</p>
<p><em>1. Investment and financial management are not exclusive to the wealthy or high-income earners.</em></p>
<p><em>2. Those with limited assets or low incomes should leverage financial management to catch up.</em></p>
<p><em>3. The amount of money you have when you start doesn&rsquo;t matter. Less money might even be better, allowing you to experiment with smaller investments initially and gradually increase your investment as you become more comfortable with risk.</em></p>
<p><em>4. Leverage other people&rsquo;s money to accelerate wealth building.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Personal Investment Bible: Preface</title>
      <link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1731056005958/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1731056005958/</guid>
      <description>This book aims to help readers establish a correct view of wealth management, learn financial knowledge, master easy wealth management techniques, and ultimately achieve financial freedom, even becoming millionaires. Author Huang Peiyuan uses the story of the Lien Chan family&amp;#39;s wealth management as an example, explaining the importance of wealth management in a simple and profound way, and combining his rich experience and academic research, proposes the key elements of wealth accumulation: regular savings, pursuing high returns, and long-term waiting. In addition, this book also emphasizes the inadequacy of financial education and the importance of continuous learning and adaptation in a rapidly changing investment environment.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[
  



<div
  
    class="flex px-4 py-3 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900"
  >

  <span
    
      class="text-primary-400 ltr:pr-3 rtl:pl-3 flex items-center"
    >

    

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M256 0C114.6 0 0 114.6 0 256s114.6 256 256 256s256-114.6 256-256S397.4 0 256 0zM256 128c17.67 0 32 14.33 32 32c0 17.67-14.33 32-32 32S224 177.7 224 160C224 142.3 238.3 128 256 128zM296 384h-80C202.8 384 192 373.3 192 360s10.75-24 24-24h16v-64H224c-13.25 0-24-10.75-24-24S210.8 224 224 224h32c13.25 0 24 10.75 24 24v88h16c13.25 0 24 10.75 24 24S309.3 384 296 384z"/></svg>

  </span>


  </span>

  <span
    
      class="dark:text-neutral-300"
    ><strong>Synopsis</strong><br>
Written by Mr. Huang Peiyuan from Taiwan, this book&rsquo;s greatest strength lies in its departure from traditional thinking. It uses clear and easy-to-understand language to teach correct wealth management methods. The book outlines thirteen ironclad rules for effortless wealth management, guiding readers on how to establish a correct view of financial management. Many people strive to make money but don&rsquo;t know how.  Many possess the conditions for wealth but miss opportunities due to a lack of financial literacy. Even worse, some lose everything due to investment mistakes. The author draws on practical experience and extensive academic research, exploring these thirteen ironclad rules to help you &ldquo;enjoy wealth management, achieve wealth with ease,&rdquo; and confidently join the ranks of millionaires.
<br>
<br>
<strong>About the Author</strong><br>
<strong>Huang Peiyuan</strong>, Ph.D. in Business Administration from the University of California, Berkeley, General Manager of Sancai Construction and Real Estate Co., Ltd. Former Director of the Institute of Business Administration, Tunghai University, Deputy Director of the Project Business Department, China Development Trust Company, Vice President of East-West Securities, USA, Investment Manager at Merrill Lynch, USA, and financial advisor to numerous companies.</span>
</div>



<h2 class="relative group">Learning Wealth Management from the Lien Chan Family 
    <div id="learning-wealth-management-from-the-lien-chan-family" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#learning-wealth-management-from-the-lien-chan-family" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>The people of Taiwan are not only surprised by the enormous wealth of the Lien Chan family, the former chairman of the Kuomintang, but also harbor doubts. How could two generations of civil servants, with their meager salaries, accumulate wealth comparable to that of tycoon families?</p>
<p>This suspicion is deeply ingrained, but the Lien family is a prominent political family in Taiwan, and no one wants to antagonize them by probing too deeply.</p>
<p>As a journalist, the Lien family&rsquo;s wealth has always been a puzzle to me. I even made a determined effort to uncover the truth, but to no avail.  Six months ago, Professor Huang Peiyuan, then director of the Institute of Business Administration at Tunghai University, spoke about his desire to combine theory and practice and publish a &ldquo;Personal Investment Bible.&rdquo; After reading Professor Huang&rsquo;s manuscript, the mystery of the Lien family&rsquo;s wealth became clear to me.  The Lien family is a perfect example of the principles in this &ldquo;Personal Investment Bible.&rdquo; Perhaps Lien Ya-tang, in his early years, wrote not only the renowned &ldquo;General History of Taiwan,&rdquo; but also a &ldquo;Wealth Management Manual&rdquo; passed down only within the family.</p>
<p>According to Professor Huang&rsquo;s (his title at the time; now he is in business) &ldquo;Personal Investment Bible,&rdquo; the first rule is &ldquo;Don&rsquo;t keep your money in the bank.&rdquo; The second is that if you want to get rich, invest in stocks and real estate.  This gives you the opportunity, with the income of an average office worker, to become a multimillionaire after 40 years of wealth management.</p>
<p>By this standard, the Lien family is indeed the most faithful follower of the &ldquo;Personal Investment Bible.&rdquo; When they had little wealth, Lien&rsquo;s mother (Lien Chan&rsquo;s mother) invested solely in stocks and real estate.  Over the past few decades, the Lien family remained steadfast, waiting for the appreciation of their stocks and real estate, which naturally led to the vast wealth that now arouses public suspicion.</p>
<p>Several decades ago, there were many business people who possessed similar wealth to the Lien family.  These individuals also worked hard to manage their businesses and accumulate more wealth.  However, compared to the Lien family now, most of them lament their inferiority in terms of wealth. The Lien family&rsquo;s role as pure investors fully demonstrates that &ldquo;as long as the concepts and methods are correct, wealth will naturally follow.&rdquo;</p>
<p>In fact, the theories and methods in the &ldquo;Personal Investment Bible&rdquo; have been discussed by countless scholars and experts in mature Western societies, but not many have truly adhered to them and become millionaires as a result.  The reason lies not in the inadequacy of the theories and methods, but in the lack of confidence and patience of those who apply them, leading them to give up halfway.</p>
<p>Therefore, I advise all readers of this book to truly believe in the theories presented, have long-term patience, and adhere to them unwaveringly in order to succeed.</p>
<p>We wish all readers the ability to enjoy a happy retirement with sufficient financial resources, which is perhaps the greatest contribution of the &ldquo;Personal Investment Bible&rdquo; to the public! (This article is written by the president of Business Weekly Taiwan)</p>


<h2 class="relative group">The Joy of Wealth Management, Achieving Wealth with Ease 
    <div id="the-joy-of-wealth-management-achieving-wealth-with-ease" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#the-joy-of-wealth-management-achieving-wealth-with-ease" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>When I was young, I thought that money was the most important thing in life; now that I am old, I know that it is.</p>
<p>— Oscar Wilde, British playwright</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This book is written for those who are determined to become wealthy and strive for financial independence. If you have tried every possible way to get rich and your home is filled with investment books, but you still can&rsquo;t figure out how to achieve wealth in your lifetime, congratulations! You have found the book you need. The investment and financial management concepts and methods described in this book are absolutely understandable and achievable for everyone. As long as you put them into practice, becoming a millionaire is not difficult.</p>
<p>I see many people working tirelessly to make money, hoping to improve their own and their families&rsquo; financial situation, but they can&rsquo;t find the right way. Many people clearly have the conditions to become rich through financial management, but they don&rsquo;t know how to manage their finances, resulting in missed opportunities.  Others know that investment and financial management can lead to wealth, but the problem is that what they know is not true, leading them astray and suffering from financial mismanagement.  The author sees these phenomena and often feels sorry for them.</p>
<p>The biggest problem in Taiwan at present is the serious lack of financial education. The public lacks a correct concept of financial management. They either don&rsquo;t know how to manage their finances and neglect it, or they use the wrong methods. As a result, some people not only fail to achieve wealth through financial management, but even fail to achieve basic financial independence.  Insufficient or incorrect financial concepts are harmful not only to one&rsquo;s own financial situation, but also to the public. This is the main motivation for the author to write this book, and what this book offers readers is the correct basic concept of investment and financial management.</p>
<p>As a scholar and a practitioner of financial management, I feel obligated to share my years of investment research results and practical experience in financial management with everyone, helping the public to easily manage their finances and achieve wealth through investment. The message this book wants to convey is: Financial management is actually very simple. Not only can everyone do it easily, but almost all young people have the conditions to achieve wealth through financial management.</p>
<p>This book is based on 20 years of practical financial management experience in the United States and Taiwan, 6 years of investment research at Tunghai University, and 15 years of experience as a financial advisor.  In fact, the concepts and practices in this book were developed 3 years ago.  For the past 3 years, the author has given lectures on this topic in various places and received tremendous feedback.  Many listeners have continuously requested that I compile these concepts and action guidelines into a book.  I personally also feel that these financial management concepts and action guidelines are indeed beneficial to the public and there is indeed a need to publish a book.</p>
<p>However, putting these concepts into words is a difficult task for me, so I have procrastinated for 3 years. Recently, thanks to the repeated urging of Mr. He, President of Business Weekly Cultural Enterprise, and Ms. Sun Meiqing, and the examples and suggestions provided by Ms. Shen Wenci, and especially the efforts of Mr. Yang Weikai, who spent several months helping me revise and proofread, this book has finally been completed. I express my sincere gratitude here.</p>
<p>If this book can be read by the general public, and if they can accept the concepts and financial management methods described in the book, then all the author&rsquo;s efforts will have been truly worthwhile. Good ideas should be shared with everyone. I hope everyone can benefit from them and easily become millionaires through financial management.</p>
<p>Finally, I dedicate this book to my parents, Mr. Huang Minting and Ms. Huang Juzhi, who raised and nurtured me.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">Preface 
    <div id="preface" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#preface" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>In recent years, Taiwan&rsquo;s economy has grown rapidly.  While continuous economic growth is certainly gratifying, the problem of uneven wealth distribution has become increasingly serious. Some blame inappropriate government policies, while others believe it&rsquo;s due to speculation, which has caused stock and housing prices to rise, widening the gap between rich and poor. The author believes that these factors are not the main cause. The real reason for the widening wealth gap is the significant disparity in financial literacy among the public.</p>
<p>Starting in 1986, Taiwan officially entered an era of abundant capital and a focus on wealth management.  The New Taiwan dollar slowly appreciated from 40 to 27 against the US dollar, and during this period, a large amount of foreign exchange flowed into Taiwan, creating a situation where &ldquo;money overflowed in Taiwan.&rdquo;</p>
<p>Due to the excess capital, people began to shift their money towards investing in stocks and real estate. The huge influx of funds into the stock and housing markets caused stock and housing prices to soar. Between 1986 and 1989, housing prices increased by an average of two to four times, and the weighted stock market index rose from over 700 points in early 1986 to 12,680 points in February 1990, an increase of 18 times.  Investing in stocks and participating in the capital market is inherently meaningful, and rising stock prices are a natural consequence of economic growth. Unfortunately, most investors adopted the wrong approach, believing that to profit in the stock market, they must buy low and sell high, earning the difference.  In reality, short-term trading is not only time-consuming and laborious but also incurs huge transaction costs, resulting in most investors losing money. The stock market is almost equated with a casino.</p>
<p>The purpose of this book is to enlighten the public&rsquo;s financial mindset by providing new perspectives, concepts, and methods to cope with the important yet complex investment environment. The author sincerely hopes that after reading this book, readers will develop a new financial mentality and adopt correct financial management methods.</p>
<p>&ldquo;Getting rich&rdquo; is almost everyone&rsquo;s desire, and most people think that their monthly income is not much, and the amount they can save is even less. At this rate of wealth accumulation, it seems impossible to get rich. But in fact, with enough time and proper financial management, becoming a millionaire is not impossible.  Wealth accumulation through financial management requires only three basic conditions: regular savings, the pursuit of high returns, and long-term waiting.</p>
<p>The easiest way to achieve wealth through financial management is to learn from those who have done so. What are their methods? The secret of most successful wealth managers is not that they are smarter, harder working, or luckier than others, but that they have the habits and practices of wealth creation.</p>
<p>In the past, family financial management was rarely mentioned in school education.  Perhaps this is because investment and financial management involve money, and most people think that making money with money has a connotation of getting something for nothing.  In formal school education, teachers avoid mentioning it, believing that talking about money in education may corrupt people&rsquo;s minds, especially making money with money, which doesn&rsquo;t seem noble.  However, long-term avoidance of this issue has only exacerbated the problem.</p>
<p>The people of Taiwan, through years of joint efforts, have created an economic miracle and accumulated a large amount of wealth. However, most individuals and families only know how to make money but not how to manage it, let alone how to use it wisely.  After acquiring wealth, individuals, families, and even the entire society have suffered rather than benefited. For example, in recent years, money games have been prevalent.  Many people are busy speculating in stocks and real estate, and various forms of gambling such as the Mark Six lottery, futures, and foreign exchange margin trading are still popular and becoming increasingly rampant.  Many people are obsessed with money games, all for the purpose of making money and improving their family&rsquo;s financial situation.  However, if we calmly review the investment results of the past few years, it is not difficult to find that in the end, few have profited, many have lost, and even more have gone bankrupt.  Everyone has worked in vain, and the result is only a rapid redistribution of wealth and a prevalence of unhealthy speculation in society. The wealth of individuals and society as a whole does not increase. This is all due to the public&rsquo;s lack of clear understanding of financial management concepts.</p>
<p>The consequence of poor financial literacy is not only personal loss and family misfortune but also a waste of overall social resources.  Let&rsquo;s face this issue that is crucial to individuals, families, and the entire society: family financial management.</p>
<p>As the saying goes, &ldquo;When a couple is poor, everything is sad.&rdquo;  This shows that if a family&rsquo;s financial situation cannot meet the needs of family life, or if finances are not managed properly, happiness is hard to come by. Of course, there are many factors that contribute to a happy family, and wealth is only one of them, as many family problems cannot be solved with money. There is a saying: &ldquo;Money is not everything, but without money, you can do nothing.&rdquo; Although money is not the center of a family, in our real society, most good things require money. Wealthy families are not necessarily happy, but families without money are usually even less so. To make ourselves and our families happier, investment and financial management are indeed imperative. Investment and financial management can not only improve the financial situation of an individual or a family, but it is also a good way to accumulate wealth.  Using financial management to achieve wealth is achievable for everyone, and it is something everyone should do.</p>
<p>Future wealth depends on the future investment environment, and the biggest characteristic of the investment environment, in a word, is change.  The entire financial environment is ever-changing and unpredictable. This has been true in the past and will be even more so in the future. In the world of investment and financial management, there is constant change. It can be said that &ldquo;the only constant is change.&rdquo; It is foreseeable that the changes in the next 10 years will exceed those of the previous 50 years. Changes are not only becoming faster, but also more complex, diversified, and international. Whether we like it or not, we are already in a rapidly changing environment.</p>
<p>Facing change, you can remain calm, adapt, and adopt the appropriate mental attitude. However, if you know how change will affect you, you may not dare to take it lightly. Because the natural consequence of any change is redistribution, including wealth, power, markets, personnel&hellip; In terms of wealth, any change in the investment environment will naturally affect the flow of money at all levels.  Indeed, in financial markets, capital markets, commodity markets, spot or futures markets worldwide, billions of dollars are traded every day, and wealth is constantly being redistributed.  Your wealth may increase significantly during the redistribution process, or it may shrink rapidly.  After long-term redistribution, you may become a billionaire, or you may become penniless, depending on how you face and deal with the changes.</p>
<p>Any change and the resulting redistribution poses a &ldquo;crisis&rdquo; to your wealth to a greater or lesser extent. The Chinese characters for &ldquo;crisis&rdquo; are profound and often quoted in foreign books because they contain both danger and opportunity. &ldquo;Wei&rdquo; represents the threat to wealth, and &ldquo;Ji&rdquo; represents the opportunity for wealth creation.</p>
<p>We can wait for changes and redistribution to determine our future wealth level, or we can make good use of the opportunities brought about by change and try to reduce its destructive power.  In this era of accelerating change, cultivating the ability to manage and respond to change is essential to controlling our own future.</p>
<p>Looking ahead, changes in business, economy, finance, politics, society, and other aspects will accelerate. The overall financial environment will become more complex and unpredictable, and it is foreseeable that future wealth redistribution will inevitably accelerate. Therefore, for ourselves, our families, and society, everyone should play the role of a financial manager.</p>
<p>This is an era of rapid change and abundant wealth, and it is also an era that forces us to manage our finances.  Everyone desires to become rich and improve their living standards or achieve their life goals. There are many ways to get rich, but the concept the author wants to elaborate on in this book is: Investment and financial management is one of the effective methods to achieve wealth. As long as you have the correct financial management concepts and put them into practice, whether you are rich or poor now, over time, you may become a millionaire through investment and financial management.</p>
<p>In this critical era related to our future wealth, you can no longer remain indifferent to financial management or ignorant of investment.  You must adopt the correct financial concepts as early as possible, constantly acquire new knowledge, and avoid mistakes in order to win in the process of wealth redistribution.</p>
<p><strong>The Story of the Mailman Who Got Rich</strong></p>
<p>My brother-in-law has a friend in Taichung, a middle-aged man with a dark complexion and an occasional shy smile. My first impression of him wasn&rsquo;t memorable until he drove away in a new BMW. The second time we met, he arrived in a Mercedes-Benz, which made me admire him.  I realized that appearances can be deceiving and quickly asked him what kind of big business he was in. He said he wasn&rsquo;t a businessman, just an ordinary office worker.  I pressed him further, asking which big company he worked for. He said he worked at the post office. I thought he must be a senior executive to be so prestigious and own two luxury cars.  The answer, however, was surprising. He replied, &ldquo;I&rsquo;m a mailman. I deliver mail by motorcycle in the morning, with a monthly salary of NT$30,000-40,000.&rdquo; I secretly speculated that he must specialize in delivering registered mail and was pocketing some of the contents.  He then told me his story. His previous generation were poor farmers who left behind some land, which he had always regarded as ancestral property and kept without selling. No one expected that recent land consolidation would increase the value of his land by dozens of times. Now, just by renting out houses, he earns NT$500,000 in rent every month.  This 48-year-old mailman didn&rsquo;t rely on increasing income and reducing expenditure, but simply by putting his assets in the right place, he now has assets of more than NT$300 million. This is one of the examples of wealth accumulation through financial management in Taiwanese society.</p>
<p>Similar stories seem to happen frequently around us. Before I taught at the university, I worked for an investment company. Once, during the election of directors and supervisors at a shareholders&rsquo; meeting, I discovered that a major shareholder holding more than NT$200 million worth of shares was actually a clerk in the company&rsquo;s personnel department.  It turned out that 35 years ago, when she joined the company as an employee, her salary was very low and her life was insecure, so she saved her meager salary. When company employees had fractional shares to transfer, she would buy them. After many years, this woman in her 50s, although unremarkable and not looking like a rich woman, now has a net worth of more than NT$200 million, enough to enjoy her retirement. In fact, there are countless examples of such ordinary office workers who have become wealthy through investment and financial management. Many people say that office workers cannot become rich, but in reality, wealthy office workers mostly don&rsquo;t like to show off, so the way to get rich through investment and financial management is often overlooked.</p>
<p><strong>What Differentiates the Rich from the Poor?</strong></p>
<p>Many hardworking office workers who toil daily for money have had the common experience of watching rich people in expensive clothes, living in luxurious villas, and driving by in luxury cars, looking impressive and enviable. While admiring them, you may have wondered: &ldquo;What makes them rich, but not me?&rdquo;</p>
<p>Many people attribute the wealth of these rich people directly to their being born rich, their successful entrepreneurial ventures, their being smarter, harder working, or luckier than others. However, family background, entrepreneurship, intelligence, hard work, and luck cannot explain all the reasons for wealth accumulation. We have all encountered many rich people, such as &ldquo;nouveau riche&rdquo; or &ldquo;landowners.&rdquo; They were not born into wealthy families, nor are they businessmen. They are not necessarily very smart, haven&rsquo;t received much higher education, and are not more frugal than us. Some of them even idle around all day. The only thing they seem to be better at than you is that they are rich.</p>
<p>What special skills do these rich people possess that are lacking in those office workers who diligently save money and work hard every day? How can they accumulate such enormous wealth in their lifetime? This is the question the author has been eager to explore for many years.  I have tried to explain their wealth with factors such as family background, entrepreneurship, occupation, education, IQ, and effort, but all seem to have failed. After years of observation, induction, and academic research, I have discovered a very important factor that is often overlooked by most people: the ability to invest and manage finances. At the same time, I have also discovered the following three facts:</p>
<p><em>1. One of the important factors that distinguishes the rich from the poor is: the ability to invest and manage finances.</em></p>
<p><em>2. Everyone can achieve wealth through investment and financial management.</em></p>
<p><em>3. The first thing to do to improve your financial situation is: to understand the basic concepts of investment and financial management.</em>
content_copy
Use code with caution.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>00484 Buying at the market price immediately when you have money is the best investment strategy: a market with an unbreakable asset allocation doesn&#39;t exist</title>
      <link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1728261371758/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1728261371758/</guid>
      <description>This live session focused on long-term investment strategies, delving into investment philosophy, risk management, and values.  James shared personal experiences and insights, offering valuable guidance on understanding the nature of investing and its inherent risks, emphasizing the importance of being rational, patient, and vigilant.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<lite-youtube videoid="UGUV4GIqKVg" playlabel="UGUV4GIqKVg" params=""></lite-youtube>



<h2 class="relative group">I. Topic of the Session 
    <div id="i-topic-of-the-session" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-topic-of-the-session" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>The session centered on the core principle of long-term investment strategies. James reiterated his investment philosophy: &ldquo;Buy QQQ whenever you have money and hold it for the long term.&rdquo; The discussion expanded to cover aspects like investment philosophy, risk management, and values, incorporating current events and questions from attendees. James also shared insights from legendary investors like Warren Buffett, encouraging attendees to cultivate a sound investment mindset.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">II. Briefing Highlights 
    <div id="ii-briefing-highlights" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii-briefing-highlights" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<ol>
<li><strong>Buying at the Dip vs. Buying When You Have Money:</strong> James cited research from ChatGPT, indicating that even with the ability to accurately predict and buy at market dips, the long-term returns differed minimally compared to simply buying when one has available funds. Over a 20-year period, the difference was merely 8%, translating to a difference in annualized returns of less than 0.2%. Hence, rather than expending time and effort predicting market bottoms, it&rsquo;s more effective to seize opportunities and buy QQQ when you have the money.</li>
<li><strong>Risks of Leveraged Funds:</strong>  Using the 2000 tech bubble as an example, James explained how leveraged funds can accelerate losses in bear markets, potentially leading to devastating financial setbacks, even bankruptcy. He simulated a scenario where an investor repeatedly buys more leveraged funds as the market declines, culminating in financial ruin. This served as a cautionary tale against the &ldquo;buy the dip&rdquo; strategy with leveraged funds, emphasizing the importance of risk management.</li>
<li><strong>Keys to Investment Success:</strong> James emphasized that the key to successful investment lies in overcoming human weaknesses. Maintaining a detached and &ldquo;unfeeling&rdquo; attitude towards invested capital and short-term market fluctuations is crucial for adhering to a long-term investment approach.</li>
<li><strong>Market Cycles:</strong> James stated he wouldn&rsquo;t teach attendees about predicting market cycles or any trading techniques. He considers these unimportant and prone to misinterpretation and misapplication, potentially leading to increased risks. He advocated for a long-term investment strategy, likening it to riding a cable car, a smooth and steady ascent to the summit of financial success.</li>
<li><strong>Money and Values:</strong> Acknowledging that individuals have different values regarding money, James advised understanding and respecting diverse values, discouraging attempts to impose one&rsquo;s own values upon others. He used the example shared by an attendee about a mother preferring a financial subsidy over a family trip to illustrate the diverse ways people assign value to things.</li>
</ol>


<h2 class="relative group">III. Q&amp;A Session 
    <div id="iii-qa-session" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii-qa-session" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p><strong>IIM:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Shared:</strong> A story about a deceased friend, leading to reflections on money and values, and expressing confusion about balancing personal values with those of others.</li>
<li><strong>Question 1:</strong>  How to understand some people&rsquo;s &ldquo;frugality&rdquo; with money while being &ldquo;generous&rdquo; towards their pets.
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response:</strong> People manage their finances differently based on what they consider important and valuable. What might be significant to one person may hold little value for another.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question 2:</strong> How to understand a mother who prioritizes money over a family trip? How to better understand the needs of others?
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response:</strong>  This mother might have certain unmet needs, possibly requiring material security before pursuing leisurely experiences. Understanding true needs involves offering more choices (e.g., money plus a trip). Avoid trying to change others&rsquo; values; focus on understanding and respecting them.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Brian:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Shared:</strong> Encountering a friend who suggested leveraging to purchase Nvidia stock, leading to questions about investment advice.</li>
<li><strong>Question:</strong> How to evaluate investment advice received from others?
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response:</strong>   The validity of investment advice depends on individual judgment and risk tolerance. It&rsquo;s important to avoid blindly following the advice of others and to think independently.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Iny:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Shared:</strong>  Experiencing a sense of calm and reduced anxiety after adopting James&rsquo;s investment approach.  This newfound peace of mind allows for dedicating more time to important matters like family, and interestingly, focusing on work has led to increased income.</li>
<li><strong>Question:</strong>  How to understand the phenomenon of increased income resulting from a dedicated focus on work?
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response:</strong> This exemplifies the principle that altruism ultimately benefits oneself. By focusing on serving clients and enhancing product or service quality, one ultimately gains client recognition and rewards, leading to higher income and a sense of accomplishment.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Haoqing:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Shared 1:</strong>  An experience with check fraud, prompting concerns about bank security and the risks of using checks.
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response:</strong>  Banks do not verify the identity of check depositors. Checks present security vulnerabilities, making it advisable to use safer online banking and digital payment methods like Apple Pay.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Shared 2:</strong> Thoughts on the decline of US manufacturing and the rise of Asia, attributing this to factors like US regulations, labor laws, and unions.
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response:</strong> The decline of US manufacturing and the rise of Asia are multifaceted issues stemming from a complex interplay of factors, including national policies, labor laws, and unions. While Asian countries might resort to suppressing labor rights and environmental regulations to gain a competitive edge, the US places a higher value on worker well-being and environmental protection. This divergence in values contributes to different developmental paths.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Becky:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Shared:</strong> Based on personal experience working in a digital payment company, Becky recommended that everyone stop using checks due to inherent security risks. Digital payment methods offer greater security and convenience, with features such as spending alerts that enable prompt response and recovery in case of issues.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Mike:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Shared:</strong> As a long-time follower of James, Mike witnessed the evolution of his investment philosophy, from initially holding 30% SPY to converting to 100% QQQ, and eventually incorporating leveraged funds. He also shared personal investment experiences, like selling NIO and allocating a portion of his portfolio to private market investments.</li>
<li><strong>Question 1:</strong> Is investing in Intel after its acquisition worthwhile?
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response:</strong>  James advised against investing in large companies that are acquisitive. Acquisitions often lack efficiency, posing integration challenges and potentially hindering productivity. While acquiring smaller companies for technological advantages makes sense, acquiring large companies is akin to amassing a pile of scrap metal.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question 2:</strong>  How to view the supply chain security concerns stemming from the US outsourcing 3C product manufacturing, citing examples like the BBB Call explosion and walkie-talkie incidents?
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response:</strong> Espionage is ubiquitous, and supply chain security is just one facet of this broader issue. Governments might implant spy codes in chips and software for surveillance purposes. Explosions are a relatively rudimentary form of espionage; more sophisticated methods can be extremely difficult to detect and prevent.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question 3:</strong> Is it possible to offer advanced courses for more experienced attendees? He suggested using portfolio sharing as a means to differentiate attendees&rsquo; learning progress.
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response:</strong> James stated he wouldn&rsquo;t differentiate between attendees nor offer advanced courses. Assessing whether a student is genuinely learning is primarily based on their attitude, not investment returns or holding duration. Even portfolio sharing can&rsquo;t truly gauge learning progress. James mentioned his personal sensitivity to words and language, enabling him to discern learning attitudes from attendees&rsquo; emails and the way they pose questions.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">IV. Noteworthy Insights 
    <div id="iv-noteworthy-insights" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv-noteworthy-insights" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>The best time to buy is when you have money.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Many obsess over finding the perfect entry point, but research indicates that even if you could perfectly time market dips, the long-term returns barely differ from simply buying when funds are available. Instead of wasting time trying to predict the market, seize the opportunity and act promptly.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>To succeed in investing, you must be indifferent to the money you invest and the fluctuations in stock prices.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Overcoming the human tendency to fixate on money and fear short-term market swings is essential for maintaining a long-term investment strategy and achieving stable returns.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>To achieve effortless investing, you need to be numb to money.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>When investing becomes a habit, free from emotional impulses and external distractions, you can achieve optimal results.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The concept of a &ldquo;benefactor&rdquo; is relative.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>People perceive and absorb information differently. Who you consider a benefactor might not be perceived as such by others.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Don&rsquo;t try to change other people&rsquo;s values.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Everyone has their own values and ways of life. It&rsquo;s important to understand and respect diverse choices.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Espionage is everywhere.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Information security is a growing concern. Be vigilant and protect your personal data.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Acquisitions of large companies are generally inefficient, and leaders who are fond of acquisitions usually have inflated egos.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Integration complexities and high management costs associated with mergers often outweigh the benefits gained.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The US excels in areas such as finance and technology design, while Asian countries can only substitute and supplement in specific aspects.
&ndash; Haoqing</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Within the global division of labor, different countries have distinct strengths and weaknesses, leading to divergent paths of development.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The best judgments are validated by facts.
&ndash; Mike</p>
</blockquote>
<p>The success of an investment philosophy is ultimately determined by its long-term returns, not short-term fluctuations or gut feelings.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Your attitude determines my response.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>James adjusts his responses based on the learning attitude of the attendees. Attendees who are truly dedicated to learning will receive greater guidance.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Investing in individual stocks will ultimately lead to bankruptcy; holding onto individual stocks will also ultimately lead to bankruptcy.<br>
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Companies have lifecycles.  Holding onto a single stock long term significantly increases the risk of encountering bankruptcy. Diversification is key in investing.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">V. Summary 
    <div id="v-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#v-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This live session once again emphasized the importance of long-term investing while reminding attendees to stay rational, patient, and vigilant. James addressed attendees&rsquo; questions regarding investment strategies, risk management, and the relationship between money and values, sharing personal experiences and insights. Key takeaways include avoiding market timing, leveraged funds, and individual stock investments, and embracing an attitude of indifference towards money. Attendees actively shared their own investment experiences and reflections, prompting deeper contemplation on investment, money, life, and more. The session also delved into the philosophies of renowned investors like Warren Buffett and discussed various social phenomena, creating a rich and informative experience.</p>

  



<div
  
    class="flex px-4 py-3 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900"
  >

  <span
    
      class="text-primary-400 ltr:pr-3 rtl:pl-3 flex items-center"
    >

    

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M506.3 417l-213.3-364c-16.33-28-57.54-28-73.98 0l-213.2 364C-10.59 444.9 9.849 480 42.74 480h426.6C502.1 480 522.6 445 506.3 417zM232 168c0-13.25 10.75-24 24-24S280 154.8 280 168v128c0 13.25-10.75 24-23.1 24S232 309.3 232 296V168zM256 416c-17.36 0-31.44-14.08-31.44-31.44c0-17.36 14.07-31.44 31.44-31.44s31.44 14.08 31.44 31.44C287.4 401.9 273.4 416 256 416z"/></svg>

  </span>


  </span>

  <span
    
      class="dark:text-neutral-300"
    ><strong>Disclaimer:</strong> This transcript serves as personal learning notes only and does not constitute investment advice.</span>
</div>

]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>00479 Three Easy Examples of Getting Rich, The Power of Starting Early and Compound Interest</title>
      <link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1728391134352/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1728391134352/</guid>
      <description>In this session, James reiterates the importance of long-term index fund investing, illustrating the power of compounding interest with multiple examples. He also explains how to avoid common investment pitfalls to achieve financial freedom.  Additionally, James addresses audience questions on asset allocation, real estate investment, trusts, and children&amp;#39;s education funds.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<lite-youtube videoid="1VSo2I6xqG0" playlabel="1VSo2I6xqG0" params=""></lite-youtube>



<h2 class="relative group">I. Main Topic 
    <div id="i-main-topic" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-main-topic" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This session focuses on long-term index fund investing. The core message is: hold index funds firmly, ignore market fluctuations, maintain a proper asset allocation, and leverage the compounding effect of time to achieve financial freedom.  James also warns against investment scams and emphasizes avoiding unnecessary risks, while offering advice on investing in children&rsquo;s education funds.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">II. Presentation Summary 
    <div id="ii-presentation-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii-presentation-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<ul>
<li><strong>Advantages of Index Funds:</strong> Long-term index fund investing eliminates the need to follow short-term market fluctuations, international affairs, financial reports, and economic data.  Focus on asset allocation and consistent investment.</li>
<li><strong>The Power of Compounding:</strong> James uses several examples to illustrate the magic of compounding:  A monthly investment of 1000 TWD can grow to 17.3 million TWD in 40 years; a lump-sum investment of 100,000 TWD can reach 18.8 million TWD in 40 years;  starting early is crucial, as a 10-year delay significantly impacts final returns; one share of QQQ at 500 USD will become 25,000 USD in 30 years and 94,000 USD in 40 years.</li>
<li><strong>Safe Asset Allocation:</strong> Asset allocation is more critical than any market commentary. James recommends deleveraging and reducing debt for those nearing retirement, holding a larger cash position.  For younger individuals with stable income, leveraging can be considered. He suggests using a beta of 1.0 as a benchmark, reducing beta when the market is overheated, and increasing it back to 1.0 during market downturns.  For cash allocation, he references Buffett and suggests a sample allocation (Scenario 3): 40% index funds, 30% 2x leveraged funds, and 30% cash.</li>
<li><strong>Beware of Investment Scams:</strong>  Don&rsquo;t trust investment information from unknown accounts or websites. Choose legitimate financial institutions.</li>
<li><strong>Don&rsquo;t Give Money Directly to Children:</strong> James uses personal anecdotes and case studies to caution against putting assets directly in children&rsquo;s names, as this may discourage their initiative or cause family conflicts.  However, investing children&rsquo;s &ldquo;lucky money&rdquo; (red envelopes) for them is recommended as an educational fund.</li>
<li><strong>Risks of Real Estate Investment:</strong> James reiterates his advice against early homeownership for young people, arguing that real estate is illiquid, high-risk, and ties up capital that could be used for other investments.  He highlights the added risk in Taiwan, where mortgage debt remains even after foreclosure.</li>
<li><strong>Recommended Learning Resources:</strong> He recommends a YouTube channel called &ldquo;什么值得读&rdquo; (What&rsquo;s Worth Reading) for valuable content on value investing.</li>
<li><strong>Emergency Fund:</strong> Maintain a cash reserve equivalent to six months of living expenses in a money market fund account. Investing this emergency fund in stocks is not recommended.</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">III. Q&amp;A Session 
    <div id="iii-qa-session" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii-qa-session" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p><strong>Jeff:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Shares:  Highlights misconceptions about investing held by two listeners and emphasizes the importance of carefully studying James&rsquo;s lecture notes, particularly the chart on page two.</li>
<li>James&rsquo;s response:  Affirms Jeff&rsquo;s points and re-emphasizes the importance of a solid investment philosophy to avoid being swayed by market noise.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Cat:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Shares: A listener holding 35 million TWD in 00662 still finds the 2% withdrawal rate insufficient. Discusses the spending needs and inheritance considerations of single individuals.</li>
<li>James&rsquo;s response: Different indices have different volatility and dividend yields, requiring adjustments to withdrawal rates. For higher withdrawals, consider ETFs with higher dividend yields, such as 0056, which yields around 4-5%.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>H:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Question:  High rental costs for young people, should they buy a house?  Mortgages offer tax deductions, while renting does not.  Concerned about insufficient funds for leveraged investing.</li>
<li>James&rsquo;s response:  Recommends watching the &ldquo;30 Years of Different Destinies&rdquo; video, which analyzes the pros and cons of renting versus buying.  Young people should prioritize investing in index funds to build wealth through compounding and consider buying a house later.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Yonglin:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Question: Should money be invested in children&rsquo;s names for long-term holding?  Should a mortgage-free house be sold to invest in index funds after retirement?</li>
<li>James&rsquo;s response:  Advises against putting money directly in children&rsquo;s names.  Retirees should deleverage, and selling a mortgage-free house to invest in index funds is a viable option.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Mike:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Shares: Success story of investing his children&rsquo;s education fund in QQQ.  Gives the example of Taoyuan Language in Taiwan, suggesting potential leveraged investment through real estate mortgages.</li>
<li>Question: How to establish a family trust and manage generational wealth like the Rockefeller family?</li>
<li>James&rsquo;s response:  Recommends contacting Lisa for trust advice when assets reach a certain level and age. For now, focus on investing. Trusts can be considered around 70-80 years old. Single individuals or those without children should rely on trusts, appointing guardians and executors.  Those with children can consider Trust 2.0, with the bank as executor and children as supervisors.  Family foundations managed by professional institutions are also an option.  Recommends the Walmart family&rsquo;s living trust as a model.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Becky, Jessie, and Other Participants:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Becky: Difficulties of renting at an older age.</li>
<li>Jessie: How to balance saving for an emergency fund, paying off a mortgage, and investing simultaneously.</li>
<li>Other Participants: Questions about real estate investment, cash management, insurance, Bitcoin, and Japanese government bonds.</li>
<li>James&rsquo;s response:  Addresses each question and reiterates his investment philosophy.  For example, young people should avoid real estate and insurance due to high risks; long-term bonds and municipal bonds are not suitable for emergency funds.</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">IV. Key Takeaways 
    <div id="iv-key-takeaways" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv-key-takeaways" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>Time is the source of all power.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>James uses examples like the evolution of Earth&rsquo;s ecosystem and human evolution to illustrate the power of time and emphasize the importance of long-term investing.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Don&rsquo;t casually help others with money.  People will resent you for it for a lifetime.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Cautions against testing human nature with money and emphasizes setting boundaries with financial assistance.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The earlier you invest, the better.  Keep enough emergency funds. The earlier you invest, the lower the risk.
&ndash; Jeff</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Emphasizes the importance of early investing and maintaining an emergency fund.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Laugh a little; how long a scammer can scam is determined by the fool.
&ndash; Mike</p>
</blockquote>
<p>A cynical comment on the prevalence of scammers and a reminder to stay vigilant.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">V. Conclusion 
    <div id="v-conclusion" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#v-conclusion" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>The core message of this session remains long-term index fund investing. James uses clear language and vivid examples to reiterate the power of compounding and the importance of starting early. He also addresses audience questions on asset allocation, real estate, trusts, emergency funds, and children&rsquo;s education funds, sharing advice on avoiding common investment traps and achieving financial freedom.  He further recommends learning resources and provides commentary on social phenomena.</p>

  



<div
  
    class="flex px-4 py-3 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900"
  >

  <span
    
      class="text-primary-400 ltr:pr-3 rtl:pl-3 flex items-center"
    >

    

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M506.3 417l-213.3-364c-16.33-28-57.54-28-73.98 0l-213.2 364C-10.59 444.9 9.849 480 42.74 480h426.6C502.1 480 522.6 445 506.3 417zM232 168c0-13.25 10.75-24 24-24S280 154.8 280 168v128c0 13.25-10.75 24-23.1 24S232 309.3 232 296V168zM256 416c-17.36 0-31.44-14.08-31.44-31.44c0-17.36 14.07-31.44 31.44-31.44s31.44 14.08 31.44 31.44C287.4 401.9 273.4 416 256 416z"/></svg>

  </span>


  </span>

  <span
    
      class="dark:text-neutral-300"
    ><strong>Disclaimer:</strong> This document is for personal learning notes only and does not constitute any investment advice.</span>
</div>

]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
