<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Leveraged Investing on QQQ Investor</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/tags/leveraged-investing/</link><description>Recent content in Leveraged Investing on QQQ Investor</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jomonylw.github.io/en/tags/leveraged-investing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>00550 Not Everyone Is Suited to Get Rich Using Borrowed Money; Psychological Resilience Is More Important Than Rate of Return!</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1766882241089/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1766882241089/</guid><description>In this episode, Teacher James emphasizes the mindset of extreme optimism and ignoring market noise for investors, drawing analogies to Elon Musk&amp;#39;s entrepreneurial spirit. The content covers warnings against specific Chinese ETFs, discussions on currency hegemony vs. personal purchasing power, and a deep dive into the conflict between reason and emotion in leveraged investing. The Q&amp;amp;A session discusses retirement planning, asset allocation, tax issues, alternatives to QQQI for non-US residents, and the profound impact of the AI era on education, social interaction, and the future of humanity.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<lite-youtube videoid="ZVH7mwiVa9w" playlabel="ZVH7mwiVa9w" params=""></lite-youtube>



<h2 class="relative group">I. Theme of the Episode 
    <div id="i-theme-of-the-episode" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-theme-of-the-episode" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>The core of this livestream lies in exploring and shaping the correct mindset for investors. Teacher James emphasizes that successful investors, like excellent entrepreneurs, should always remain <strong>extremely optimistic</strong>, always <strong>face the sunshine</strong>, and firmly believe that the market will eventually rise. Investors need to learn to filter out all external noise—such as market volatility, international situations, and analyst predictions—and focus on the asset allocation and long-term strategies they can control. At the same time, the course delves into how to balance the rational potential for gain with emotional anxiety when facing leveraged investing, ultimately emphasizing that <strong>mental health should take precedence over potential financial gains</strong>.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">II. Briefing Content 
    <div id="ii-briefing-content" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii-briefing-content" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Core Mindset &amp; Principles for Investors 
    <div id="core-mindset--principles-for-investors" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#core-mindset--principles-for-investors" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Filtering Invalid Information</strong>: Teacher James points out from the start that market volatility, international situations, market analysis, financial reports, and economic conditions are all noise. Investors should not waste time on these unpredictable or uncontrollable factors. Any analysis is either hindsight or guesswork, with accuracy no better than a coin toss.</li>
<li><strong>Maintaining Extreme Optimism</strong>: The mindset of a successful investor is similar to that of an entrepreneur (like Elon Musk). Although Musk&rsquo;s companies have repeatedly faced bankruptcy, he has always remained extremely optimistic. Investors should do the same, firmly believing that the market moves upward in the long term and that technology and human society will continue to develop.</li>
<li><strong>Investor&rsquo;s Beliefs</strong>:
<ol>
<li>Investors are always extremely optimistic.</li>
<li>Investors always face the sunshine.</li>
<li>The market will eventually rise.</li>
<li>Investing requires patience; wealth is worth the wait.</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Important Reminders &amp; Clarifications 
    <div id="important-reminders--clarifications" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#important-reminders--clarifications" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Correction Regarding Chinese ETFs</strong>: Teacher James solemnly apologized and corrected his previous view, pointing out that products like the &ldquo;Southern Dividend Low Volatility 50 ETF&rdquo; (515450) in mainland China are misleading. The yield charts displayed on their websites include dividend reinvestment, while the actual stock price may be falling. He explicitly advises <strong>not to invest</strong> in such products and stated that he is still looking for suitable high-dividend solutions for investors in mainland China and Hong Kong.</li>
<li><strong>Beware of Scams</strong>: The teacher emphasized that he will not actively DM anyone on Clubhouse or other platforms, nor will he have any paid groups or manage money for others. For example, there are fake IDs in Clubhouse like <code>cchc.james</code> followed by an <code>m</code> or <code>cec.chairman</code>. Any unsolicited greetings or requests for money transfers are scams.</li>
<li><strong>Communication Channels</strong>: Questions should be submitted via YouTube comments or Email; the teacher will try to reply within two days.</li>
<li><strong>No Official Groups</strong>: CLEC has no official groups. Although some students have established WeChat groups out of goodwill, there are risks of bans and scammers infiltrating them. It is suggested that investors form small, closed groups composed of friends and family for discussion, but no group represents CLEC.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Discussion on Currency &amp; Exchange Rates 
    <div id="discussion-on-currency--exchange-rates" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#discussion-on-currency--exchange-rates" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>The Hegemonic Status of the US Dollar</strong>: Discussed how the status of the US dollar as an international reserve currency is hard to shake. For a country&rsquo;s currency to internationalize, its industrial strength and comprehensive national power must be strong enough to provide the products and services the world needs, which is precisely the hardest part.</li>
<li><strong>Impact of Exchange Rates on Individuals</strong>: For ordinary people, whether their domestic currency is an international currency matters little. Exchange rates mainly affect national <strong>purchasing power</strong>. For example, the depreciation of the New Taiwan Dollar against the US Dollar means the cost of traveling abroad will be higher. Exchange rate issues are complex political economics, involving industry, policy, history, and many other factors.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Reason vs. Emotion in Leveraged Investing 
    <div id="reason-vs-emotion-in-leveraged-investing" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#reason-vs-emotion-in-leveraged-investing" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Case Analysis</strong>: A student wrote in to share his psychological conflict. Through rational analysis, he believes that leveraged investing via credit loans or mortgages can quickly accumulate principal and is a correct decision.</li>
<li><strong>Emotional Obstacles</strong>: However, when he prepared to actually borrow the money, he began to feel extreme anxiety and irritability. He couldn&rsquo;t help but watch the market every day, and even small fluctuations made him restless and unable to sleep.</li>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s Advice</strong>:
<ul>
<li><strong>Mental Health First</strong>: The teacher explicitly pointed out that if borrowing money to invest causes you such great psychological pressure, then <strong>do not borrow</strong>. Mental health is far more important than potential financial returns.</li>
<li><strong>The Challenge of Unity of Knowledge and Action</strong>: This case is typical of the conflict of &ldquo;wanting to get rich but afraid to carry leverage.&rdquo; Investing is like taking medicine; even if it is good medicine, if the side effects are fatal (like the severe anxiety in this case), it must absolutely not be taken.</li>
<li><strong>Self-Assessment</strong>: The fact that he thinks about details like watching the market daily and percentage fluctuations indicates that this investor has a naturally nervous personality and is not suitable for bearing the psychological pressure brought by leverage. Investing peacefully without borrowing money is the path more suitable for him.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">III. Q&amp;A Session 
    <div id="iii-qa-session" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii-qa-session" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Huizhen 
    <div id="huizhen" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#huizhen" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing</strong>: She is a civil servant (nurse). After listening to the teacher&rsquo;s channel, she canceled several matured investment-type insurance policies and put all funds into 00662 and 00670L for a 433 asset allocation. Because she feels her future pension is secured, she decided to retire early this year at 55 and no longer consume herself for work.
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s Comment</strong>: An excellent decision. The teacher confirmed she has done asset allocation and kept a cash position (00865B), and her assets are more than 15 times her living expenses. Since her monthly pension is enough to cover daily expenses, the investment portion can grow peacefully without being touched. The teacher encouraged her to retire early and experience more of life, such as spending time with family, reading, and studying philosophy.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Supplementary Point</strong>:
<ul>
<li>The teacher quoted Elon Musk: &ldquo;Humans were not born to work; they were born to think about problems,&rdquo; encouraging everyone to think and learn more.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Leo 
    <div id="leo" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#leo" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing</strong>: Having followed the teacher&rsquo;s channel for over a year, he has internalized the concepts of pledging and long-term investing, and is now indifferent to workplace politics and others&rsquo; opinions. He mentioned the positive news from TSMC&rsquo;s earnings call, stating that while most funds are still in the teacher&rsquo;s 433 allocation, he also allocated a small amount to 0050 Leveraged (2x) because he is bullish on Taiwan&rsquo;s tech strength. He is very grateful to the teacher and the community for the benevolent knowledge that allows everyone to grow together.
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s Comment</strong>: AI is currently a money printer, and TSMC is at the core of the AI supply chain. It is the only non-US company in the global top ten by market cap (excluding oil companies), which is the pride of Taiwan. However, he also reminded that the growth of a great company takes a long time; TSMC, Apple, and Nvidia all went through three or four decades of development. Therefore, investing is not true investing if it&rsquo;s not for more than thirty years.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Angela 
    <div id="angela" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#angela" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing</strong>: She and her husband used to be very frugal people who lacked security regarding money. After encountering the teacher&rsquo;s investment philosophy, their mindset changed, and they recently took their family on a nine-day independent trip to Japan. However, she still felt guilty when spending money, feeling that she wasn&rsquo;t spending money earned through hard work.</li>
<li><strong>Question</strong>: How to break out of this old mindset that &ldquo;spending money makes one feel guilty&rdquo;?
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s Reply</strong>: First, the teacher suggests she can think of it as &ldquo;spending borrowed money,&rdquo; which reduces the psychological burden. This is the rule of the capitalist game. Second, having the wealth to enjoy life is a gift and luck, and there is no need to feel guilty about it. Most importantly, happiness is good for health. Happy experiences like travel, exercise, and meditation can promote the growth of &ldquo;hippocampus&rdquo; nerve cells in the brain, helping to keep thinking clear and delay aging. Therefore, spending money for happiness and health is very worthwhile.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Steven 
    <div id="steven" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#steven" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Question</strong>: His son opened a company in the US in 2025 and is confused about tax filing. The company has dividends; should he file corporate tax or personal income tax? How to plan to save more on taxes?
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s Reply</strong>: This is a tax planning issue. Suggestions:
<ol>
<li>Keep most of the profits in the company and pay the relatively lower corporate tax (about 18%).</li>
<li>The son can take a portion of the salary from the company as personal income, keeping the marginal tax rate for personal income tax at a lower level (e.g., within 22%), roughly over a hundred thousand dollars.</li>
<li>Many company expenses can be used for tax deductions.</li>
<li>Regarding retirement accounts, <strong>it is strongly recommended to only use Roth 401K and Roth IRA; absolutely do not use Traditional (pre-tax) accounts</strong> to avoid high tax rates during future conversions.</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Winnie 
    <div id="winnie" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#winnie" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Question</strong>: She has three years until retirement. She plans to convert $300,000 from her Traditional IRA to a Roth IRA annually after retirement, estimating a tax of $120,000 per year for 8 years. Currently, she can only save enough for two or three years of taxes in advance and asks how to prepare for this tax payment.
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s Reply</strong>:
<ol>
<li><strong>Do not deliberately save money to pay taxes</strong>; solve this through asset allocation and financial tools.</li>
<li>The preferred solution is <strong>stock pledging (securities-based lending)</strong> to pay taxes. <strong>Absolutely do not sell assets in the Investment Account (Blockage Account)</strong>, because selling will generate new capital gains tax, complicating the issue.</li>
<li>Your total assets include Blockage, Roth, and Traditional accounts. Calculate if 2% of your total assets is enough to cover the annual tax.</li>
<li>If the pledging limit is insufficient, consider transferring part of the funds to Roth and another part to the Blockage account during the Roth Conversion to increase the assets available for collateral.</li>
<li>The last choice is to use tax withholding directly from the Traditional IRA during conversion, but this will lose the compound interest growth on that portion of the principal.</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">SJ 
    <div id="sj" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#sj" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Question</strong>:
<ol>
<li>She is a new student who just repatriated funds from overseas (IB, Schwab) to Taiwan, ready to put them into the 433 allocation. Facing the current market highs, she is hesitant: should she invest a lump sum?</li>
<li>She plans to invest 20,000 monthly in the future; how should she allocate it?</li>
<li>There is a large expense at the end of March (about 9% of total assets); is it feasible to pay via pledging? How to repay the interest?</li>
<li>Should the emergency fund be independent of 00865B (cash position)?</li>
</ol>
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s Reply</strong>:
<ol>
<li><strong>Invest immediately</strong>. Do not time the market. According to your 433 asset allocation plan, buy at market price as soon as the funds arrive. The market is very likely to rise significantly in the future.</li>
<li>The monthly DCA amount is small, so you can buy freely. For example, buy more leverage if the market drops, replenish the cash position if it rises, and review/balance uniformly at the end of the year.</li>
<li>Paying for large expenses via pledging is completely feasible. Interest is also paid by borrowing more money through pledging; do not touch the principal.</li>
<li><strong>There is no independent emergency fund</strong>. All cash should be within your asset allocation (i.e., 00865B). We do not hold non-yielding cash. Just sell the necessary living expenses from 00865B at the beginning of each month.</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Yonglin 
    <div id="yonglin" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#yonglin" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Question</strong>: She has held a Green Card in the US for 20 years. Recently, she heard that Green Card holders are being scrutinized at customs, so she is considering whether to naturalize. The reason for hesitation is that naturalizing in the US means giving up Chinese citizenship.
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s Reply</strong>: <strong>Naturalize immediately, do not delay!</strong> This is very clear and firm advice. To visit family in China, just apply for a visa with a US passport; there is no inconvenience.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">S 
    <div id="s" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#s" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Question</strong>: He is from Malaysia and wants to invest in QQQI for cash flow, but faces a 30% dividend withholding tax which cannot be refunded. Which is better, buying QQQ or QQQI?
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James &amp; Ling&rsquo;s Discussion Reply</strong>:
<ol>
<li><strong>When to choose QQQI/JEPQ.L</strong>: If you are retired or semi-retired and need stable cash flow to cover living expenses, then this type of high-dividend ETF is suitable. It sacrifices some growth for cash flow. If you are young and have salary income, you should not touch such products and should focus on asset appreciation by investing fully in QQQ.</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Ling 
    <div id="ling" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ling" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing</strong>:
<ol>
<li>Regarding S&rsquo;s question, she shared the situation in Singapore: Like Malaysia, there is no tax treaty with the US, and the 30% tax is also non-refundable. She found an alternative: <strong>JPMorgan&rsquo;s <code>JEPQ.L</code> listed on the London Stock Exchange</strong>. This is a DL (distributing/dividend-paying) ETF. Because it is listed in the UK (likely Irish-domiciled UCITS structure), Singaporean investors do not face withholding tax issues when buying it, and the final yield is similar to QQQI, perhaps even slightly higher.</li>
<li>After discussing with her family, they decided to choose larger cash flow rather than leaving a larger inheritance, believing that enjoying life in the present is more important.</li>
<li>For investors whose assets are not massive but have a relatively high demand for cash flow, a mixed strategy can be considered. For example, adding 10% QQQI/JEPQ to the portfolio can increase cash flow, and because QQQI has lower volatility, it can effectively <strong>lower the volatility of the entire portfolio</strong>, thereby reducing the risk of stock pledging.</li>
</ol>
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s Comment</strong>: Ling&rsquo;s point is very correct. The <code>JEPQ.L</code> solution she provided is excellent and solves pain points for non-US tax residents. At the same time, adding QQQI to reduce overall asset volatility is also a very good risk management concept.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Cathy 
    <div id="cathy" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#cathy" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing</strong>: She recently started using an AI model trained on all of Teacher James&rsquo;s content (J-Men-AI) for conversation and felt the experience was very good, with replies more precise than general GPT models. She suggests everyone try using this AI to sort out their investment questions.
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s Comment</strong>: Highly encourages everyone to learn to converse with AI. Suggests creating independent chat windows for different aspects of life (such as financial management, health management), continuously feeding the AI your personal information (such as financial status, medical reports, diet records), and letting it become your exclusive personal consultant.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Jenny 
    <div id="jenny" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#jenny" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing</strong>: She is a university lecturer and observes that students nowadays tend to use AI as an object for socializing and confiding, lacking the willingness and ability to interact with people in reality. She feels worried about this.</li>
<li><strong>Question</strong>: How does the teacher view the impact of AI on the social life and education of the younger generation?
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s Reply</strong>: This is a common phenomenon, but there is no need to panic excessively. He used a <strong>historical analogy</strong>: If you went back to the Ming Dynasty and told people then that there would be mobile phones, airplanes, and cars in the future, they would also be terrified, worrying that carriage drivers and weavers would lose their jobs and society would collapse. But the fact is, human society adapted to technological progress, and life became better. AI is the same; it will make our lives better and better. We should embrace the future optimistically instead of peddling fear.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Flo 
    <div id="flo" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#flo" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Question</strong>: For young long-term investors, after investing 30% cash during a market pullback, how can they &ldquo;earn back&rdquo; this portion of cash? Is it by reducing DCA amounts?
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s Reply</strong>: This is a conceptual misunderstanding.
<ol>
<li><strong>Young investors do not need to keep 30% cash</strong>. The so-called 30% cash (in the 433 allocation) is mainly prepared for retirement or those who cannot bear high volatility risk.</li>
<li>For young investors in the US, the correct approach is: <strong>Prioritize maxing out Roth 401K and Roth IRA</strong>. With the remaining money, after keeping about half a year&rsquo;s living expenses, <strong>invest strictly 100% immediately</strong> into your Brokerage Account whenever you have money. Do not keep cash waiting for a pullback.</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">A-Gan 
    <div id="a-gan" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#a-gan" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Question</strong>:
<ol>
<li>Finland&rsquo;s capital gains tax is very high (over 30%). Should she send money back to Taiwan for investment?</li>
<li>She heard that lending is easier at Yuanta Securities in Taiwan, while Cathay United Bank gives her a high rate (8%-9%).</li>
<li>Should she buy all 00662 in Taiwan?</li>
<li>The file regarding the Global Nasdaq 100 ETF the teacher emailed her before cannot be opened.</li>
</ol>
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s Reply</strong>:
<ol>
<li>Funds can be sent back to Taiwan for investment. Taiwan has no tax on capital gains, which is very friendly.</li>
<li>Operational process: Assets can continue to be held at <strong>Cathay United Securities</strong>, then go to <strong>Yuanta Securities Finance</strong> to open an account for stock pledging. Cathay&rsquo;s stocks can be used as collateral directly at Yuanta Securities Finance. Transferring funds in and out is convenient, and there is no need to transfer the stocks themselves.</li>
<li>Buying all 00662 is acceptable.</li>
<li>Asked her to send another email, and the teacher will resend the link.</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Shani 
    <div id="shani" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#shani" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Question</strong>: In the AI era, degrees are devalued, and jobs are being replaced, causing anxiety for many. What guidance does the teacher have for adapting to this new era?
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s Reply</strong>: Used a <strong>historical analogy</strong> again. We are experiencing a migration from one era to another, just like moving from ancient times to modern times. Old jobs will be eliminated, but new opportunities and better lifestyles will follow. Degree devaluation does not mean not learning, but rather learning how to think and adapt. We should welcome the future optimistically and enjoy the dividends brought by technology. The two most important things in the future are <strong>wealth and health</strong>.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Winnie 
    <div id="winnie-1" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#winnie-1" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Question</strong>: If assets exceed 100 million in the future, the annual dividend tax will be high. What should be done?
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s Reply</strong>:
<ol>
<li><strong>Taxes must be planned in advance</strong>. Most assets can be allocated to low-dividend growth assets, such as QQQ (dividend yield only 0.6%).</li>
<li>Make full use of retirement accounts (IRA, 401K), where dividends are tax-free or tax-deferred.</li>
<li>For taxes that must be paid, pay them with a peaceful mind, because it means you made money. More importantly, <strong>use money borrowed via pledging to pay taxes</strong>, rather than using your own principal.</li>
<li>The teacher added his view on money: Money is for spending, especially borrowed money. He gives cash directly to elderly people in need on the street; this direct giving is more effective than donating to charities.</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">IV. Highlighted Views 
    <div id="iv-highlighted-views" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv-highlighted-views" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>An investor&rsquo;s mindset is like that of an entrepreneur: always extremely optimistic, always facing the sunshine; the market will eventually rise.
&ndash; Teacher James</p></blockquote>
<p>Context: Teacher James analogizes the investor&rsquo;s mindset to Elon Musk&rsquo;s optimism when facing potential bankruptcy, emphasizing the importance of belief for long-term investing.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Your mental health is superior to potential profit. If there is a wonderful medicine (elixir), but taking it causes fatal side effects, do you take it or not? Of course, you don&rsquo;t take it!
&ndash; Teacher James</p></blockquote>
<p>Context: Commenting on a student who felt extreme anxiety due to leveraged investing, the teacher emphasized that psychological endurance is the key to determining investment strategy, and one cannot sacrifice mental health for theoretical high returns.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Humans were not born to work; humans are here to think about problems.
&ndash; Elon Musk (Quoted by Teacher James)</p></blockquote>
<p>Context: Discussing the potential for mass unemployment caused by AI, Teacher James quoted this to suggest that human value lies in thinking, creation, and problem-solving, not repetitive labor.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>You go traveling, stay in nice hotels, you feel happy, and many thoughts become clear&hellip; It is worth spending this money, and we are not spending our own money; when I go to Taiwan, it&rsquo;s all borrowed money.
&ndash; Teacher James</p></blockquote>
<p>Context: Answering Angela&rsquo;s question about feeling guilty spending money, the teacher explained the importance of enjoying life from psychological and health perspectives and introduced the concept of &ldquo;spending borrowed money&rdquo; to alleviate psychological burden.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>What you are worried about now is exactly how people 500 years ago would look terrified when thinking about the future. Don&rsquo;t worry; after it arrives, humanity will live better.
&ndash; Teacher James</p></blockquote>
<p>Context: Responding to questions about social anxiety triggered by the AI era, Teacher James used historical analogies to comfort everyone, explaining that disruptions brought by technological progress always seem scary at the time but always push human society forward in the long run.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>People who are retiring are actually looking for a balance: do you want a larger cash flow, or do you want a larger inheritance?
&ndash; Ling</p></blockquote>
<p>Context: Discussing high-dividend products like QQQI, Ling shared her decision-making process with her family, pointing out a very core trade-off point in retirement planning.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>If you pledge in Singapore and borrow SGD, the interest rate is about 2.1%. But in Asia, very few of you understand borrowing money to invest in the Nasdaq 100 Index, so money becomes very cheap. This is the opportunity.
&ndash; Ling &amp; Teacher James</p></blockquote>
<p>Context: Comparing borrowing rate differences between the US and Singapore/Asia, revealing that due to information asymmetry and different investment philosophies, the cost of funds in parts of Asia is extremely low, creating huge opportunities for investors who know how to use financial tools.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>When you understand what &lsquo;government&rsquo; is, you will know whether you want to pay more taxes.
&ndash; Teacher James</p></blockquote>
<p>Context: Discussing tax issues, the teacher hinted at a critical view of government efficiency and wealth redistribution, advocating that investors should engage in reasonable tax avoidance within legal limits.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Taxes are planned. The fact that the money you earn is taxed is actually a good thing because you have a profit. Pay what you owe, and your heart will be at peace.
&ndash; Student &amp; Teacher James</p></blockquote>
<p>Context: Discussing high dividend taxes, combining the views of the student and teacher, emphasizing the need for reasonable tax planning while also maintaining a positive attitude toward unavoidable tax burdens, as they represent investment success.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The financial industries in Taiwan, Hong Kong, and Singapore are very strong. Friends in these three regions should seize this; the ships are sturdy and the cannons sharp, and the bullets are free!
&ndash; Teacher James</p></blockquote>
<p>Context: After comparing the financial environments of the West and Asia, the teacher highly praised the low-cost credit and stock pledging tools available to retail investors in these three regions, encouraging local investors to use them boldly.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">V. Summary 
    <div id="v-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#v-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This episode starts from the foundation of investment mindset, systematically constructing a worldview that a long-term investor should have: one built on a firm belief in human technological progress and the long-term upward trend of the market, thereby enabling one to ignore short-term noise and stick to established strategies. Through specific cases, Teacher James deeply analyzed the psychological game of leveraged investing and gave the valuable advice of &ldquo;mental health supreme.&rdquo; The Q&amp;A session was extremely rich, not only solving specific problems for many students regarding asset allocation, retirement planning, and cross-border taxation but also extending to profound reflections on personal development and social change in the AI era, ultimately returning to a positive attitude of optimistically embracing the future. This course is a perfect combination of investment philosophy and practical operation, pointing out a clear, firm, and confident path for investors in a complicated world.</p>

  



<div
  
    class="flex px-4 py-3 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900"
  >

  <span
    
      class="text-primary-400 ltr:pr-3 rtl:pl-3 flex items-center"
    >

    

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M506.3 417l-213.3-364c-16.33-28-57.54-28-73.98 0l-213.2 364C-10.59 444.9 9.849 480 42.74 480h426.6C502.1 480 522.6 445 506.3 417zM232 168c0-13.25 10.75-24 24-24S280 154.8 280 168v128c0 13.25-10.75 24-23.1 24S232 309.3 232 296V168zM256 416c-17.36 0-31.44-14.08-31.44-31.44c0-17.36 14.07-31.44 31.44-31.44s31.44 14.08 31.44 31.44C287.4 401.9 273.4 416 256 416z"/></svg>

  </span>


  </span>

  <span
    
      class="dark:text-neutral-300"
    ><strong>Disclaimer:</strong> This article is for personal study notes only and does not constitute any investment advice.</span>
</div>

]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>00498 Asset Allocation and Pledge Strategy: Achieving Wealth Management on Autopilot</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1736644508160/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1736644508160/</guid><description>This episode covers index investment strategies, the safety of leveraged investing, asset allocation recommendations and practical methods, long-term investment philosophy, understanding capitalism, and Q&amp;amp;A sessions with personal investment experiences. It particularly emphasizes the importance of long-term holding of the Nasdaq 100 index fund and the specific methods to achieve wealth appreciation through correct asset allocation and leverage strategies.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<lite-youtube videoid="u5ODPQxWrF0" playlabel="u5ODPQxWrF0" params=""></lite-youtube>



<h2 class="relative group">I. Episode Theme 
    <div id="i-episode-theme" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-episode-theme" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This episode focuses on <strong>long-term investment in the Nasdaq 100 index fund</strong>, emphasizing the importance of <strong>avoiding interference from market fluctuations, international situations, financial statements, and economic situations</strong>. It delves into the <strong>safety of leveraged investing</strong> and <strong>correct asset allocation methods</strong>, including the 433 and 442 asset allocation strategies. Additionally, it discusses the <strong>psychological preparation</strong> in the investment process, <strong>deep understanding of capitalism</strong>, and shares how to achieve <strong>financial and personal freedom</strong> through investment.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">II. Briefing Content 
    <div id="ii-briefing-content" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii-briefing-content" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Market Fluctuations and Investment Strategies 
    <div id="market-fluctuations-and-investment-strategies" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#market-fluctuations-and-investment-strategies" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Market fluctuations, international situations, market analysis, financial statements, economic situations, etc., are irrelevant to individual investment returns.</strong> Teacher James emphasizes that these factors are often overhyped by the media and financial institutions but have minimal impact on long-term investors&rsquo; returns. Investors should focus on long-term trends rather than short-term fluctuations.</li>
<li><strong>Investors should avoid being influenced by market noise and news.</strong> Misleading information in the market can easily lead investors to make wrong decisions. In the long run, these short-term fluctuations are offset by the market&rsquo;s long-term growth trend.</li>
<li><strong>Investment should be based on a strategy of long-term holding of the Nasdaq 100 index fund, without frequent trading.</strong> Frequent trading not only generates high transaction costs but also increases investment risk. The long-term holding strategy can reduce risks and enjoy the benefits of compound interest.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Asset Allocation and Leverage 
    <div id="asset-allocation-and-leverage" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#asset-allocation-and-leverage" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>The risk of leveraged investing is lower than that of non-leveraged investing.</strong> Teacher James explains that those who use leverage have more cash reserves in times of crisis, making them more resilient than those without cash reserves. The key is whether the borrowed money is invested in the right assets, such as stocks of high-quality companies.</li>
<li><strong>Investors are advised to borrow early and incorporate the funds into their asset allocation.</strong> Early borrowing allows funds to be invested in the market, enjoying longer compound interest growth. Even keeping the borrowed money as a backup is safer than not being able to obtain a loan when needed.</li>
<li><strong>Newly listed funds have larger tracking errors; it is recommended to invest in established funds.</strong> Newly listed funds, due to their smaller size, require more hedging operations, resulting in larger tracking errors that affect investment returns. It is advisable to choose established funds like 00662, which have larger scale and smaller tracking errors.</li>
<li><strong>Asset allocation should be based on individual circumstances, such as the 433 or 442 strategies, with intelligent rebalancing.</strong> The 433 strategy refers to 40% core fund (e.g., QQQ), 30% leveraged fund (e.g., QLD), and 30% cash. The 442 strategy refers to 40% core fund, 40% leveraged fund, and 20% cash. Intelligent rebalancing involves transferring a portion of the profits from the leveraged fund to cash in rising years and transferring a portion of cash to the leveraged fund in declining years.</li>
<li><strong>Borrowing should not exceed a certain percentage of total assets and should be combined with asset allocation to achieve automatic navigation.</strong> The amount of new borrowing each year can be gradually increased. For example, in the first year, you can borrow 1%-2% of the total assets, and then increase it slightly each year. The specific proportion depends on the individual&rsquo;s debt tolerance. In the long-term investment process, total assets grow at a rate of more than 10% per year, while debt grows at a rate of 2% per year. Therefore, borrowing money is very safe in the long run. Through intelligent rebalancing, the automatic navigation of the investment portfolio can be achieved without frequent adjustments.</li>
<li><strong>Investors should be extremely optimistic.</strong> Regardless of any disasters or market downturns, investors should remain optimistic because the market will eventually rise and break new highs.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Real Estate and Natural Disasters 
    <div id="real-estate-and-natural-disasters" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#real-estate-and-natural-disasters" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Real estate is a high-risk asset, subject to risks such as windstorms, floods, earthquakes, and fires.</strong> In the United States, in addition to the above risks, there are also risks of tornadoes, hurricanes, and other natural disasters. These disasters can lead to significant depreciation or even complete loss of property value.</li>
<li><strong>In contrast, the Nasdaq 100 index fund includes 100 companies, does not require payment of taxes, maintenance fees, insurance fees, and is not affected by natural disasters.</strong> These 100 companies are among the best in the United States and even globally, with high long-term investment returns.</li>
<li><strong>It is recommended to transfer the risk of real estate to the landlord by renting instead of owning property to avoid risks.</strong> Owning property requires various maintenance costs, taxes, and risks from natural disasters. Renting can transfer these risks to the landlord, and you only need to pay rent.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Long-Term Investment and Life Goals 
    <div id="long-term-investment-and-life-goals" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#long-term-investment-and-life-goals" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Investment should control emotions, understand history, and look at the present from the future.</strong> Investing requires rationality, avoiding emotional decisions. By understanding historical market fluctuations and economic cycles, one can better grasp investment opportunities. Looking at the present from the future can strengthen confidence in long-term investment.</li>
<li><strong>The value of the Nasdaq 100 index fund will far exceed its current value in the future, and long-term holding will bring substantial returns.</strong> With the advancement of technology and economic development, the value of the Nasdaq 100 index fund will continue to grow.</li>
<li><strong>The most important goal in life is to fulfill one&rsquo;s mission, not to pursue money, fame, and power.</strong> Money is only a tool to achieve life goals, not the goal itself. One should consider how to use wealth to realize one&rsquo;s life values.</li>
<li><strong>Money is a tool, and one should learn to spend money, especially for wealthy retirees; spending money is a virtue.</strong> Retirees should learn to enjoy life and use their wealth to improve their quality of life and achieve their life goals. At the same time, spending money can promote economic flow and create more opportunities for young people.</li>
<li><strong>Elderly people who have retired and are very wealthy should spend money as a moral duty.</strong> Spending money can stimulate the economy, allowing young people to earn more, and they may also consider having children and getting married.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Cycles and Investment Experience 
    <div id="cycles-and-investment-experience" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#cycles-and-investment-experience" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Predicting cycles is difficult and requires more than 40 years of market experience to fully understand a cycle.</strong> Market cycles are usually long, and it is difficult for people with insufficient investment experience to accurately predict changes in cycles.</li>
<li><strong>Invest in the US Nasdaq 100 index fund because the US is the source of the world&rsquo;s strongest currency and innovative technology.</strong> The United States has strong economic strength and innovation capabilities. In the long run, investing in the US market has a high potential for return.</li>
<li><strong>In addition to listening to the opinions of Buffett and Peter Lynch, one should also learn from the experiences of failures.</strong> By learning from the lessons of failures, one can avoid making the same mistakes and improve the probability of investment success.</li>
<li><strong>Probability, accidents, and randomness:</strong> Even if there is a 99.99% chance of success and only a 0.1% chance of failure, do not do it because when you do it, it is random.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Capitalism and Wealth 
    <div id="capitalism-and-wealth" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#capitalism-and-wealth" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>In capitalism, if you have money, buy index funds, and you will become rich.</strong> In a capitalist society, investment is an important way to achieve wealth growth. Due to their diversified investment characteristics, index funds can reduce risks and obtain average market returns.</li>
<li><strong>To become a millionaire, one needs to understand borrowing.</strong> Moderate borrowing can amplify investment returns and accelerate wealth accumulation. However, it should be noted that borrowing must be based on safety and controllability.</li>
<li><strong>Real estate loans require repayment of principal and interest, and retirees should avoid such loans.</strong> The income source of retirees is usually relatively fixed, and the pressure to repay principal and interest is greater, which may affect the quality of life.</li>
<li><strong>Convert mortgages to home equity lines of credit to reduce monthly expenses.</strong> Home equity lines of credit only require interest payments, not principal repayment, which can reduce monthly repayment pressure.</li>
<li><strong>The US borrows money to develop its domestic investment economy.</strong> The US can borrow a little more money and repay it in 20 or 30 years. In fact, the US does not want to repay the debt. It borrows new debt to repay old debt. The money is never repaid, and the currency will depreciate.</li>
<li><strong>Borrowing without principal repayment is acceptable.</strong> Suppose you have 30 million in retirement savings, at 2%, you can spend 600,000 a year, or 50,000 a month.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Practice of Asset Allocation 
    <div id="practice-of-asset-allocation" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#practice-of-asset-allocation" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>According to Monte Carlo simulations, the intelligent rebalancing strategy can maintain the same return as 100% investment in QQQ while reducing risk.</strong> Through historical data simulation, the intelligent rebalancing strategy has proven to be an effective asset allocation method.</li>
<li><strong>Questions about asset allocation should be resolved through learning and practice, rather than simply relying on the advice of others.</strong> Investment is a process of continuous learning and practice. Only through one&rsquo;s own practice can one truly understand the principles and methods of asset allocation.</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">III. Q&amp;A Session 
    <div id="iii-qa-session" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii-qa-session" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Cat 
    <div id="cat" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#cat" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question: Details of the 433 asset allocation strategy, especially the specific steps for rebalancing at the end of the year, and how to understand the concept of &ldquo;automatic navigation.&rdquo; Many students are confused about how to readjust the asset allocation back to the 433 ratio.</li>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo;s reply: When rebalancing at the end of the year, <strong>only the leveraged fund (Q2D) and cash portions need to be adjusted, without touching the core fund (QQQ)</strong>.
<ul>
<li>
<p><strong>In a rising year</strong>:</p>
<ol>
<li>Calculate the annual return of Q2D (year-end asset - beginning-year asset). If there were additional investments during the year, subtract the amount of additional investments.</li>
<li>Transfer 1/3 of the annual return of Q2D to the cash account.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>In a declining year</strong>:</p>
<ol>
<li>Calculate 2% of the total assets.</li>
<li>Transfer 2% of the total assets from the cash account to the Q2D account.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Automatic navigation</strong> means that once the initial asset allocation and annual intelligent rebalancing are completed, there is no need to frequently monitor or adjust the asset ratio, allowing the investment portfolio to operate automatically according to the preset strategy.</p>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Pin 
    <div id="pin" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#pin" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Share: Pin shared a book called &ldquo;Die with Zero,&rdquo; which puts forward a novel point of view: <strong>every meaningful experience in life is an investment, similar to financial investment. These experiences can bring spiritual returns, and these returns will increase over time.</strong> The book compares this kind of experience investment to financial investment. Every positive experience is like depositing the &ldquo;principal&rdquo; into the memory bank. Every time you recall or share these experiences afterward, you can get &ldquo;interest&rdquo;—happiness and satisfaction. As we age, these memories become more and more precious, just like compound interest in financial investment, whose value continues to grow. Pin took herself as an example. She decided to quit her job to accompany her elderly parents. Although this was a difficult decision financially, she regarded this experience as a valuable investment, and its return would far exceed the loss of money.
<ul>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo;s comment: Teacher James agreed with Pin&rsquo;s sharing and further explained that <strong>the purpose of life is to convert material energy into spiritual energy</strong>. Money is just a tool. The real purpose is to obtain spiritual satisfaction and happiness. We should use money to create beautiful experiences, not just accumulate numbers. He took a chart in the &ldquo;One Billion Investment Lecture&rdquo; as an example to illustrate how to convert material energy into spiritual energy and emphasized that ultimately we should pursue spiritual abundance.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Sunny 
    <div id="sunny" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#sunny" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question 1: Three years ago, she mortgaged a house and borrowed 10 million NTD in a home equity line of credit, but this money has not been used. Now she has some concerns. After these three years, she wonders if she should be braver and use this money, but she is worried about her nervous personality.
<ul>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo;s reply: Teacher James believes that Sunny&rsquo;s personality is too nervous and not suitable for complex investment operations. And pointed out that if you have a nervous personality, you are not suitable for investment.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2: Previously, she listened to some suggestions in the market and bought a large number of 20-year long-term bonds, resulting in a relatively high proportion of bonds in the current investment portfolio, and it is currently in a state of loss. Now that the market trend has changed and she is facing losses, how should she deal with this bond investment?
<ul>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo;s reply: Teacher James pointed out that Sunny should not invest in long-term bonds and emphasized that funds should be concentrated on assets that can make money. He suggested that Sunny watch investment course videos to learn the correct investment strategy instead of blindly following various suggestions in the market.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 3: Should she sell all the bonds now and transfer all the proceeds to buy QQQ?
<ul>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo;s reply: Considering that Sunny is retired and has a fixed monthly pension, it is recommended that she reallocate all assets (including bonds, cash, etc.), invest 80% of the assets in 00662 (Taiwan ETF tracking the Nasdaq 100 Index), and invest 20% of the assets in 00864B (Taiwan&rsquo;s short-term bond ETF, equivalent to cash).</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 4: She still has 20-30% cash on hand. Should these cash continue to be invested in 00662 and 00864B according to the 80/20 ratio?
<ul>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo;s reply: Teacher James আবারও emphasized that all assets need to be added up for calculation to ensure that the final investment ratio of 00662 is 80% and the investment ratio of 00864B is 20%. If the cash ratio is insufficient, she may need to sell some bonds to increase the cash ratio.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo;s additional explanation: Teacher James emphasized the importance of investment education and suggested that Sunny spend time watching course videos to systematically learn investment knowledge instead of just seeking a simple answer. He pointed out that there is no shortcut to investment and it takes time and energy to learn and understand.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Eugene 
    <div id="eugene" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#eugene" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question 1: When transferring a 401k account from one institution to another (TIAA), TIAA charged a 0.3% account management fee. He asked whether this fee was reasonable and whether it was too high.
<ul>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo;s reply: Teacher James believes that the 0.3% management fee is reasonable and not too high. When conducting account transfers, such fees are normal and are necessary expenses.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2: Does the asset allocation strategy mentioned earlier include all types of assets, such as retirement accounts (such as 401k), real estate, etc.?
<ul>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo;s reply: Teacher James clearly pointed out that the asset allocation strategy only includes liquid assets, that is, assets that can be easily bought and sold, such as 401k, IRA, personal brokerage accounts (which can buy and sell stocks, funds, ETFs, etc.). Real estate is not a liquid asset, so it is not included in the scope of asset allocation.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Zhang Yong 
    <div id="zhang-yong" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#zhang-yong" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Share: Zhang Yong shared his deep understanding of Teacher James&rsquo;s concept of &ldquo;wealth is a talent, and happiness is a human right.&rdquo; He found that in reality, many people&rsquo;s behaviors are contrary to this concept, based on his work and life experience. He realized that many people, including himself, are misled by the traditional financial system and engage in unreasonable financial behaviors such as forced savings. He believes that Teacher James&rsquo;s course system and philosophy are truthful and can help people achieve financial freedom.
<ul>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo;s comment: Teacher James agreed with Zhang Yong&rsquo;s sharing and further explained the essence of the capitalist system and financial system. He pointed out that the history of the development of capitalism, especially after the Industrial Revolution, led to the emergence of the working class and gradually evolved into an invisible &ldquo;slavery&rdquo; system. The government, financial institutions, and capitalists have jointly built a &ldquo;Truman&rsquo;s World&rdquo; where most people live according to a set script without realizing it. Teacher James used the movie &ldquo;The Truman Show&rdquo; as an example to point out that this &ldquo;script&rdquo; was jointly set by capitalists, the government, and financial institutions to make most people become laborers and serve the capitalist system. Most people, including senior executives in the financial industry, do not even realize that they are &ldquo;actors&rdquo; in this system. Only a few people can see the truth and achieve true financial freedom. Teacher James emphasized that the purpose of his course is to help everyone recognize the existence of this &ldquo;scam&rdquo; and find ways to achieve financial freedom.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question: Many people are busy working and living, but their behaviors and ideas are contrary to the concept of achieving financial freedom. Most people seem to be misled by the traditional financial system and make unreasonable financial plans. Zhang Yong wants to know the essential reasons for this widespread phenomenon and how to change this situation.
<ul>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo;s reply: Teacher James explained that the root cause of this phenomenon is the capitalist system itself. Since the Industrial Revolution, the capitalist system has gradually turned most people into laborers and built a complete system to maintain this state. This system instills the concepts of &ldquo;work hard, save, and invest&rdquo; in people through multiple channels such as education, media, and financial institutions, but in fact, it is &ldquo;enslaving&rdquo; most people. He pointed out that this is a &ldquo;war without sound and breath&rdquo; and most people do not realize that they are in it. Teacher James believes that to change this situation, we must first recognize the existence of this &ldquo;scam&rdquo;, and then gradually achieve financial freedom by learning the correct investment concepts and methods. He emphasized that we cannot change the entire system, but we can change ourselves and let ourselves and our families live a better life.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Tina 
    <div id="tina" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#tina" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question 1: Tina has currently invested most of her assets in 00662 (Taiwan) and NDQ (Australia) ETFs, and plans to transfer her Australian retirement fund to NDQ in the future. She asked whether she should conduct asset allocation after completing all investments or start considering the allocation of other assets now.
<ul>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo;s reply: Teacher James suggested that Tina conduct asset allocation as soon as possible, rather than considering it after all funds are invested in specific assets. He believes that asset allocation should be a quick decision-making process that can be completed within a day. For those who have not retired and have not borrowed money, they can choose the 433 or 442 asset allocation strategy; for those who are close to retirement or have retired, they should use the 80/20 asset allocation strategy.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2: If according to the 442 strategy, Tina has allocated 40% of her assets to 00662 and NDQ, then after transferring the Australian retirement fund next month, should she invest in 00670L (Taiwan&rsquo;s leveraged ETF)? If the funds are kept in Australia, how should they be allocated?
<ul>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo;s reply: Teacher James suggested that Tina treat the Australian retirement fund as a cash portion and allocate it according to tax factors. If in Australia, since the dividends of NDQ need to be taxed and the tax rate is high, it is not recommended to invest all retirement funds in NDQ. The Australian retirement fund can be used as a cash reserve, while the core fund (such as 00662) is allocated in Taiwan. If the cash reserve in Australia is not enough to meet the proportion of asset allocation, a portion of the funds can be remitted from Taiwan to Australia. He suggested that Tina consider tax factors and decide the specific asset allocation ratio according to her place of residence and post-retirement life arrangements.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Wen Zhang 
    <div id="wen-zhang" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#wen-zhang" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question: Wen Zhang&rsquo;s younger sister invested in a fund in Canada that tracks the Nasdaq 100 Index. The fund has a high management fee of 2.95% but promises to return 75% of the principal if the Nasdaq 100 Index falls. Wen Zhang&rsquo;s younger sister is worried that she cannot control her investment behavior and may buy and sell frequently, so she is interested in this high-management-fee but guaranteed fund. Wen Zhang wants to know Teacher James&rsquo;s opinion on this fund and whether there are better investment options.
<ul>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo;s reply: Teacher James first pointed out that if investors cannot control their investment behavior, then investing in any product may face risks. He believes that the investor&rsquo;s mentality and self-control are the key factors for investment success. Regarding specific investment advice, Teacher James suggested investing in the Canadian version of QQQ, such as QQC or XQQ. These ETFs directly track the Nasdaq 100 Index, have lower management fees, and have higher long-term investment returns. However, Teacher James also emphasized that the final investment choice should be based on the investor&rsquo;s risk tolerance and investment experience. If Wen Zhang&rsquo;s younger sister cannot overcome the impulse to buy and sell frequently, then any investment advice may be invalid.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Jenny 
    <div id="jenny" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#jenny" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question: Jenny does not have much money in her Roth IRA because her income is too high to contribute directly. She currently faces a higher tax rate and is considering whether she should convert all the funds deposited in her Traditional IRA (up to $7,000 per year) to a Roth IRA, even if she needs to pay higher taxes.
<ul>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo;s reply: Teacher James thinks this is a good idea. Since Jenny&rsquo;s Traditional IRA amount is already large, she will face a higher tax rate when withdrawing in the future. By converting funds to a Roth IRA, she can enjoy future tax-free growth. He suggested that Jenny make the conversion, even if she needs to pay taxes now, but it is worthwhile in the long run.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2: In addition to the annual limit of $7,000, can more be converted?
<ul>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo;s reply: Yes.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Additional explanation: Teacher James further explained why a Roth IRA is needed. He suggested buying leveraged funds (such as QLD) in the Roth IRA and allocating an equivalent amount of cash in the Traditional IRA or other taxable accounts. This can reduce the growth rate of the Traditional IRA, thereby reducing future tax burdens. For example, if there is $500,000 of QLD in the Roth IRA, then $500,000 of cash can be allocated in the Traditional IRA. As the Roth IRA grows, the cash allocation in the Traditional IRA can be increased accordingly.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Julie 
    <div id="julie" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#julie" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question: Julie observed that the recent volatility of QQQ is relatively large, with daily gains and losses often exceeding 1%. She wants to know the reasons behind this phenomenon and whether this high volatility will continue in the future. She believes that the volatility of QQQ in previous years was relatively small, and there would not be such large daily gains and losses unless there were major events.
<ul>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo;s reply: Teacher James first pointed out that Julie&rsquo;s observation has a &ldquo;recency bias&rdquo;, that is, people tend to pay too much attention to recent events while ignoring long-term trends. He showed the long-term trend chart of QQQ (including linear and logarithmic charts) to illustrate that in the long run, the volatility of QQQ has not increased significantly. The recent large fluctuations are because the price of QQQ has risen to a higher level, so even a 1% fluctuation is larger in absolute terms than in the past. Teacher James emphasized that a logarithmic chart should be used to observe long-term trends because the logarithmic chart can more accurately reflect the magnitude of asset price fluctuations.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Houqi 
    <div id="houqi" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#houqi" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Share: Houqi shared the investment experience of a friend. This friend started participating in the company&rsquo;s 401k plan when he was young, but he didn&rsquo;t pay much attention at first, just investing according to the company&rsquo;s match. Many years later, he was surprised to find that his 401k account had accumulated more than one million US dollars in assets. This case illustrates the power of compound interest. Even small regular investments can generate huge returns after a long period of accumulation.
<ul>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo;s comment: Teacher James agreed with Houqi&rsquo;s sharing and further explained the power of compound interest. He took the US 401k plan as an example, assuming an annual investment of 20,000 US dollars, calculated at a 14% annualized rate of return, it can accumulate to 30 million US dollars after 40 years. Even if calculated at a lower 10% annualized rate of return in the past, it can also accumulate to 9 million US dollars. This example illustrates that long-term investment and compound interest are the key factors for achieving wealth growth.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">IV. Wonderful Views 
    <div id="iv-wonderful-views" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv-wonderful-views" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>People who borrow money are the ones with lower risks, and people who do not borrow money have extremely high risks.
&ndash; Teacher James</p></blockquote>
<p>Because people with cash reserves can use funds immediately in an emergency, while those without cash reserves may face the risk of a broken capital chain. Those who have loans have more cash reserves in the face of crises and have stronger risk resistance than those who do not have cash reserves.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>A house is a consumer product. It is a kind of money-eating support, not an investment, and it is a very high-risk support.
&ndash; Teacher James</p></blockquote>
<p>This sentence emphasizes the attribute of real estate as a consumer product rather than an investment product, as well as its potential high risks, including natural disasters and maintenance costs.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>To succeed in investing, you must control your emotions. The first thing is to control your emotions. If you cannot control your emotions, please do not invest.
&ndash; Teacher James</p></blockquote>
<p>Emphasizes the importance of emotional control in investing. Investing requires rationality, avoiding emotional decisions.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>In capitalism, if you have money, buy index funds, and you will become rich.
&ndash; Teacher James</p></blockquote>
<p>Emphasizes that in a capitalist society, long-term investment in index funds is an effective way to achieve wealth growth. Due to their diversified investment characteristics, index funds can reduce risks and obtain average market returns.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>You have to recognize that real estate is a high-risk support, so it is very strange that everyone thinks that directly investing in 100 companies is very risky, but buying a house with all their assets is also very special.
&ndash; Teacher James</p></blockquote>
<p>This view challenges people&rsquo;s general perception of real estate as a safe asset. Real estate is a high-risk asset with risks such as windstorms, floods, earthquakes, and fires.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>If you have been speculating, then you will go bankrupt in this market. There is no need to say that if you do too much, you will go bankrupt.
&ndash; Teacher James</p></blockquote>
<p>This sentence warns of the risks of speculative behavior and emphasizes the importance of long-term investment. Frequent trading not only generates high transaction costs but also increases investment risk.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Money is not our purpose. Money is not our purpose. The whole experience of life requires money. That is our purpose.
&ndash; Teacher James</p></blockquote>
<p>This sentence emphasizes the essence of money as a tool, and the real purpose of life is experience and spiritual satisfaction. We should use money to create a better experience, not just accumulate numbers.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>All passers-by, all the dogma of the financial industry are deceiving you.
&ndash; Teacher James</p></blockquote>
<p>Criticism of the traditional financial system and dogma. Only you don&rsquo;t know. Capitalists know it, politicians know it, but only the workers don&rsquo;t know it. 99.99% of the workers think that they are living in reality and in a real environment. In fact, you are living in a scripted life without knowing it.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Suppose you start working today, then you can borrow $20,000 every year. Then how much more will you have? You will have an extra $30 million.
&ndash; Teacher James</p></blockquote>
<p>This view quantifies the huge impact of leveraged investing on wealth growth. Moderate borrowing can amplify investment returns and accelerate wealth accumulation.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>This is the power of compound interest, and let me give you an example. In the United States, 401K is $20,000. Suppose you invest $20,000 every year when you are young. With an annualized rate of return of 14%, in 40 years, you will have $30 million. You just invest without doing anything.
&ndash; Teacher James</p></blockquote>
<p>This view reveals the great power of compound interest in long-term investment. Even a small amount of money can accumulate into amazing wealth through long-term compound interest growth.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">V. Summary 
    <div id="v-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#v-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This episode revolves around <strong>long-term investment in the Nasdaq 100 index fund</strong>, emphasizing the importance of <strong>avoiding market noise and adhering to long-term investment strategies</strong>. It delves into the <strong>principles and methods of asset allocation</strong>, especially the <strong>specific operations of 433 and 442 strategies and intelligent rebalancing</strong>. At the same time, it also emphasizes the <strong>feasibility and safety of leveraged investing</strong> and how to accelerate wealth accumulation through <strong>reasonable borrowing strategies</strong>. In addition, Teacher James also conducted a profound reflection on the <strong>capitalist system and financial system</strong>, pointing out that most people are living according to a set script, and proposed a path to <strong>achieve financial freedom and personal freedom</strong>.</p>
<p>In the Q&amp;A session, Teacher James answered various questions encountered by different students in the investment process in detail, including <strong>asset allocation, tax planning, investment psychology</strong>, etc. He emphasized the importance of <strong>learning and practice</strong>, encouraging students to systematically learn investment knowledge by <strong>watching course videos, reading related materials</strong>, etc., and continuously summarize and improve in practice.</p>
<p>In short, the content of this episode aims to help investors establish <strong>correct investment concepts</strong>, master <strong>scientific investment methods</strong>, and ultimately achieve <strong>steady growth of wealth and freedom of life</strong> through <strong>long-term investment and reasonable asset allocation</strong>.</p>

  



<div
  
    class="flex px-4 py-3 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900"
  >

  <span
    
      class="text-primary-400 ltr:pr-3 rtl:pl-3 flex items-center"
    >

    

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M506.3 417l-213.3-364c-16.33-28-57.54-28-73.98 0l-213.2 364C-10.59 444.9 9.849 480 42.74 480h426.6C502.1 480 522.6 445 506.3 417zM232 168c0-13.25 10.75-24 24-24S280 154.8 280 168v128c0 13.25-10.75 24-23.1 24S232 309.3 232 296V168zM256 416c-17.36 0-31.44-14.08-31.44-31.44c0-17.36 14.07-31.44 31.44-31.44s31.44 14.08 31.44 31.44C287.4 401.9 273.4 416 256 416z"/></svg>

  </span>


  </span>

  <span
    
      class="dark:text-neutral-300"
    ><strong>Disclaimer:</strong> This article is only a personal study note and does not constitute any investment advice.</span>
</div>

]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Personal Investment Bible: Investment Iron Law IV</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1731056005963/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1731056005963/</guid><description>This article explores the financial strategy of &amp;#34;making money with other people&amp;#39;s money,&amp;#34; also known as leveraged investing. It analyzes the principle of financial leverage, emphasizing that the return on investment must be higher than the loan interest rate to be profitable. Case studies of entrepreneurs like Chen Youhao and Weng Damming illustrate the advantages and risks of leveraged investing. The article further discusses borrowing principles, how to build credit, how to avoid improper borrowing, and how to determine an appropriate level of debt. Finally, it points out that banks are a source of borrowing rather than a place to save money, and emphasizes the importance of prudent borrowing.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[

<h2 class="relative group">Investment Iron Law IV: Making Money with Other People&rsquo;s Money 
    <div id="investment-iron-law-iv-making-money-with-other-peoples-money" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#investment-iron-law-iv-making-money-with-other-peoples-money" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>By applying the principle of financial leverage, an investment of 500 million can double your business.</p></blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">Utilizing Leveraged Investing 
    <div id="utilizing-leveraged-investing" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#utilizing-leveraged-investing" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>The path to wealth through investment relies on &ldquo;making money with money.&rdquo;  Therefore, the prerequisite for investment is having capital.  A common dilemma faced by individuals when investing is, &ldquo;What if I don&rsquo;t have enough money?&rdquo; This can lead to missed opportunities. This book proposes a solution: &ldquo;If you don&rsquo;t have enough money, but someone else does and is willing to lend it to you, then borrow it.&rdquo; This is the highest realm of investment management—leveraged investing.</p>
<p><strong>Chen Youhao, President of the Tuntex Group: The Money-Making Method of Borrowing and Rolling</strong></p>
<p>Starting in the textile industry, Chen Youhao used financial leverage to rapidly expand the Tuntex Group into chemical fibers, construction, cement, hotels, petrochemicals, and other fields. With over 30 affiliated companies, it became one of the top 15 largest corporate groups in Taiwan. He also planned to invest nearly 7 billion USD in Taiwan and Thailand to expand chemical fiber plants.</p>
<p>Tuntex&rsquo;s growth never stopped, and its debt continued to rise. In 1995, Tuntex Group&rsquo;s core business, Tonwin Construction, had total assets of 59.6 billion TWD, revenue of 15.7 billion TWD, and net profit after tax of 2.6 billion TWD, but its debt ratio was still as high as 60.99%.</p>
<p>A graduate of the Department of Economics at National Taiwan University, Chen Youhao always prided himself on his sophisticated money-making method of borrowing and rolling. He had full confidence in Tuntex&rsquo;s financial management. His financial principles were: 1/3 self-owned capital, the rest borrowed from financial institutions; current assets must be greater than current liabilities, with a current ratio greater than 100%; and the ratio of self-owned capital to debt must not exceed 1/2.</p>
<p>Chen Youhao emphasized that whenever the company&rsquo;s debt ratio approached its limit, he would strictly control it, so the company&rsquo;s financial situation remained normal. However, whenever the construction industry was in a downturn, Tuntex would be plagued by rumors of financial difficulties. In June 1995, due to capital needs, Chen Youhao pledged 46.5 million shares of Tonwin, setting a record for the highest number of shares pledged by directors and supervisors that month. Chen Youhao repeatedly assured the public that Tuntex&rsquo;s finances were absolutely sound.</p>
<p>Despite the rumors damaging the company&rsquo;s image, Chen Youhao firmly believed that reasonable borrowing could enable the company to earn more profits. He was also confident that businesses funded by loans would be profitable because the return on investment was higher than the interest rate on loans.</p>
<p><strong>Is Borrowing to Invest Wrong?</strong></p>
<p>Is borrowing money for investment appropriate? Shakespeare wrote in Hamlet, &ldquo;Neither a borrower nor a lender be.&rdquo; This was once considered a golden rule. Our elders often warned their children not to borrow money from others or lend money to others; borrowing was not considered respectable and should be avoided unless absolutely necessary.</p>
<p>Indeed, most stories of financial ruin are caused by debt, such as the cases of Tsai Chen-chou of the Tenth Credit Cooperative and the stock market tycoon Lei Borong. Countless examples of bankruptcy caused by debt make people fear and avoid it.</p>
<p>However, among the famous wealthy individuals we know, such as Wang Yongqing, Kao Ching-yuan, Chang Yung-fa, and Wu Ho-Su, who didn&rsquo;t rely on borrowing to invest in their journey from rags to riches? The answer is &ldquo;none.&rdquo; Moreover, the more successful people are at making money, the more they tend to borrow. Looking at the financial statements of listed companies, are there any renowned high-performing enterprises in Taiwan, such as Formosa Plastics, Uni-President, and Evergreen, that have zero debt?  The message is clear: successful tycoons, like successful businesses, rarely achieve their wealth without using other people&rsquo;s money. In business management, appropriate borrowing is not only necessary but also reasonable.</p>
<p>If Shakespeare were alive in the 21st century and understood how capitalism works and how people become wealthy, he might change his words to: &ldquo;If you have no money, but others do and are willing to lend it to you, then borrow.&rdquo;</p>
<p>After reviewing these characteristics of success, reflect on your own financial situation. What percentage of your investment funds comes from borrowing? If, like most people, 100% of your investments are made with your own funds, you are overlooking an important tool for building wealth: borrowing.</p>
<p><strong>Borrowing is a Crucial Tool for Wealth Creation</strong></p>
<p>American investment consultant Robert Allen repeatedly emphasizes in his bestselling book <em>Creating Wealth</em>: &ldquo;You cannot become rich by investing without borrowing.&rdquo; I disagree with this argument. The examples in Chapter 1 of this book clearly demonstrate that with proper financial management, one can become a billionaire without relying on borrowed investments.  The American investment master Warren Buffett does not advocate leveraged investing.  Without debt, he is a prime example of building wealth solely through his own funds. However, there is a prerequisite for accumulating wealth using only your own funds: long-term patient waiting. Warren Buffett only rose to prominence after three to four decades of investing.</p>
<p>Although Robert Allen&rsquo;s argument that &ldquo;you cannot become rich without borrowing&rdquo; is incorrect, I must admit that the &ldquo;leveraged investing&rdquo; he advocates is an important means of building wealth, especially for those who want to accelerate the speed of wealth creation.  Leveraged investing is a tool that should not be ignored.</p>
<p>In conclusion, whether you want to accelerate wealth accumulation or can tolerate the pressure of leveraged investing, you must understand the nature and impact of leveraged investing before deciding if this tool is right for you.</p>
<ul>
<li>
<ol>
<li>Leveraged investing is a powerful tool, but it must be used wisely.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol start="2">
<li>It is possible to build wealth without borrowing.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol start="3">
<li>Leveraged investing, when used correctly, can accelerate wealth accumulation.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol start="4">
<li>Don&rsquo;t be afraid of leveraged investing, but be very careful.</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>Aim high with your business goals,
Once decided, go for it and never back down.
The key to success in business lies in courage and strategy.</p></blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">Weng Damming&rsquo;s Revival of the Family Business 
    <div id="weng-dammings-revival-of-the-family-business" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#weng-dammings-revival-of-the-family-business" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>In Taiwan, there are quite a few entrepreneurs skilled in financial leverage. Besides Chen Youhao, the president of the Tuntex Group, Weng Damming, the head of the Hualon Group, is also a master of this art.</p>
<p>Weng Damming, the head of the Hualon Group, became a highly controversial figure due to his unconventional style. After the death of his father, Weng Mingchang, Weng Damming shouldered the heavy responsibility of reviving the family business.  Starting in textiles, the Hualon Group owned Hualon Textile, Hualon Microelectronics, Yixin Trading, Jiashin Livestock, and Kuo Hua Life Insurance, among other affiliated companies.</p>
<p>Weng Damming adopted a high-leverage approach to business management. In 1994, the Hualon Group had total assets of 130 billion TWD and debts as high as over 50 billion TWD, of which over 30 billion TWD were short-term debts.  He used the stocks or real estate of affiliated companies as collateral for bank loans, with a pledge ratio of nearly 60%. Therefore, during the stock market crash and the real estate downturn, Weng Damming was troubled by rumors of financial difficulties.  Due to the sluggish stock and real estate markets, the collateral value of the Hualon Group was insufficient, requiring him to supplement the collateral or face the pressure of being &ldquo;liquidated.&rdquo; However, the seasoned Weng Damming, with his flexible financial management, once again demonstrated that the financial crisis was just a false alarm.</p>
<p>As Hualon Textile, the parent company of the Hualon Group, enjoyed stable profits and increased earnings with the gradual recovery of the textile industry, Weng Damming was able to borrow money fearlessly and aggressively expand into new businesses.  With a gambler&rsquo;s mentality, Weng Damming can be said to have maximized the principle of financial leverage. The story of this legendary figure shows us both the rewards and risks of leveraged investing.</p>
<p><strong>The Principle of Financial Leverage</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Act within your means; don&rsquo;t over-leverage, or you risk being shaken out.</li>
</ul>
<p>In finance, borrowing is known as &ldquo;financial leverage.&rdquo; Simply put, leverage is the principle of using a small force to achieve a large effect. Humans discovered the power of leverage early on and used it to move or lift heavy objects. The ancients used the principle of leverage to create magnificent engineering marvels such as the Great Wall and the pyramids. Modern wealthy individuals use the principle of financial leverage to create immense fortunes. Archimedes once said, &ldquo;Give me a place to stand, and I shall move the earth.&rdquo;  In investment management, financial leverage implies: &ldquo;Lend me enough money, and I can make any large investment.&rdquo;</p>
<p>Leveraged investing involves borrowing other people&rsquo;s money to make larger investments, thus utilizing the leverage effect.  Proper use of leverage can turn small amounts of money into large profits. Conversely, improper use can also lead to significant losses with small amounts of money. Here&rsquo;s an example to help readers understand how financial leverage works. Suppose you buy a house with 10 million in cash. A year later, you are fortunate enough to sell it for 13 million, making a 30% profit (R1). If you only paid 3 million in cash for the house and borrowed the remaining 7 million from the bank at a 10% interest rate, and then sold it for 13 million a year later, your profit margin would increase to 77% (R2).  Conversely, if the house price unfortunately drops by 30% after a year, and you sell it for 7 million, the person who bought it entirely in cash would lose 30% (R3). The investor who borrowed 7 million would see their loss expand to 123% (R4), meaning not only is the original investment lost, but they are also in debt. The calculation of the above rates of return is as follows:</p>
<p><math xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" display="block"><mtable displaystyle="true" columnalign="right center left" columnspacing="0 thickmathspace" rowspacing="3pt"><mtr><mtd><mi>R</mi><mn>1</mn></mtd><mtd><mi></mi><mo>=</mo></mtd><mtd><mi></mi><mo stretchy="false">(</mo><mn>1300</mn><mo>−</mo><mn>1000</mn><mo stretchy="false">)</mo><mrow><mo>/</mo></mrow><mn>1000</mn></mtd><mtd><mi></mi><mo>=</mo></mtd><mtd><mn>30</mn><mi mathvariant="normal">%</mi></mtd></mtr><mtr><mtd></mtd></mtr><mtr><mtd><mi>R</mi><mn>2</mn></mtd><mtd><mi></mi><mo>=</mo></mtd><mtd><mi></mi><mo stretchy="false">(</mo><mn>1300</mn><mo>−</mo><mn>1000</mn><mo>−</mo><mn>700</mn><mo>×</mo><mn>10</mn><mi mathvariant="normal">%</mi><mo stretchy="false">)</mo><mrow><mo>/</mo></mrow><mn>300</mn></mtd><mtd><mi></mi><mo>=</mo></mtd><mtd><mn>77</mn><mi mathvariant="normal">%</mi></mtd></mtr><mtr><mtd></mtd></mtr><mtr><mtd><mi>R</mi><mn>3</mn></mtd><mtd><mi></mi><mo>=</mo></mtd><mtd><mi></mi><mo stretchy="false">(</mo><mn>700</mn><mo>−</mo><mn>1000</mn><mo stretchy="false">)</mo><mrow><mo>/</mo></mrow><mn>1000</mn></mtd><mtd><mi></mi><mo>=</mo></mtd><mtd><mi></mi><mo>−</mo><mn>30</mn><mi mathvariant="normal">%</mi></mtd></mtr><mtr><mtd></mtd></mtr><mtr><mtd><mi>R</mi><mn>4</mn></mtd><mtd><mi></mi><mo>=</mo></mtd><mtd><mi></mi><mo stretchy="false">(</mo><mn>700</mn><mo>−</mo><mn>1000</mn><mo>−</mo><mn>700</mn><mo>×</mo><mn>10</mn><mi mathvariant="normal">%</mi><mo stretchy="false">)</mo><mrow><mo>/</mo></mrow><mn>300</mn></mtd><mtd><mi></mi><mo>=</mo></mtd><mtd><mi></mi><mo>−</mo><mn>123</mn><mi mathvariant="normal">%</mi></mtd></mtr><mtr><mtd></mtd></mtr><mtr><mtd><mo stretchy="false">(</mo><mo>Calculations in units of 10,000</mo><mo stretchy="false">)</mo></mtd></mtr></mtable></math></p>
<p>From the above example, we can clearly see how debt leverage exerts the power of &ldquo;using a small force to achieve a large effect.&rdquo; <strong>When the return on investment is higher than the interest rate on the loan, leveraged investing will increase the return on investment. When the return on investment is lower than the interest rate on the loan, the return on investment will decrease due to the borrowing.</strong></p>
<p>The main reason for the leverage effect is that loan interest is a cost that must be paid under any circumstances. Regardless of the investment return, the interest cost of borrowing remains fixed. Therefore, when the investment return is greater than the loan cost, the excess profit belongs to the borrower, creating a positive leverage effect and naturally increasing the return on investment of the principal. However, when the investment return is less than the loan interest cost, the borrower must bear the difference, resulting in a negative leverage effect, which reduces the return on the principal. This is especially true when the investment incurs a loss, as the borrowing cost will magnify the loss.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Financial leverage is like a seesaw,
It can lift you very high,
It can also cause you to fall hard.</p></blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">Two Major Principles of Borrowing 
    <div id="two-major-principles-of-borrowing" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#two-major-principles-of-borrowing" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>Financial leverage is like a seesaw: it can lift you very high or cause you to fall hard, depending on whether the leverage effect is positive or negative.  The key factor determining the direction of the leverage effect is which is higher: the return on investment or the interest rate on the loan. If the return on investment is greater than the interest rate, the leverage effect is positive. Conversely, if the return on investment is lower than the interest rate, the leverage effect becomes detrimental.</p>
<p><strong>Return on Investment Must Be Higher Than the Interest Rate</strong></p>
<p>Therefore, when deciding whether to use leveraged investing, the first things to consider are: What is the purpose of the loan? What is the expected return on investment for the target investment? Is it higher than the loan interest rate? If the return on investment of the targeted investment is significantly lower than the borrowing rate, the idea of leveraged investing should be dismissed early on. Otherwise, the result will certainly be detrimental rather than beneficial. If you can&rsquo;t understand what the expected return on investment is or whether the return is higher than the interest rate, then I advise you to understand these issues before borrowing!</p>
<p>Debt is synonymous with risk. Increasing debt increases risk and the possibility of personal or family bankruptcy. There are two major principles of leveraged investing:</p>
<ul>
<li>
<ol>
<li>The expected return on investment must be greater than the interest rate on the loan. For example, if the loan interest rate is 11%, it&rsquo;s only worthwhile if the after-tax return on investment is above 11%.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol start="2">
<li>In the worst-case scenario, your cash income must be sufficient to cover the principal and interest payments. For instance, if the investment price falls instead of rises after a few years, you must have enough cash income to repay the principal and interest on time.</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ul>
<p>Furthermore, investors must keep in mind that leveraged investing should not be based on the expectation that the price of the investment target will definitely rise, but rather on the preparation for a price drop.  Therefore, you should only engage in leveraged investing if you can still afford the interest payments even if the price continues to fall. You must also be able to withstand the psychological pressure that comes with leveraged investing.</p>
<p><strong>Avoiding Improper Borrowing</strong></p>
<p>Some readers may feel smug after reading this section because they are already engaged in what they consider leveraged investing. Upon further inquiry, however, it turns out they are borrowing money to buy lottery tickets, futures, or other speculative products, or even taking out loans to purchase consumer goods.  I must emphasize that these actions do not constitute proper &ldquo;leveraged investing.&rdquo;</p>
<p>Futures markets, margin trading (such as foreign exchange and bonds), or any gambling activities like lotteries and horse racing all have negative expected returns.  Long-term participation will inevitably lead to financial ruin.  Coupled with the deadly effect of borrowing, the result will undoubtedly be rapid bankruptcy.  Therefore, no matter how alluring these games are, remember:  It&rsquo;s okay to indulge occasionally for recreational purposes, but never borrow money to participate, or you will accelerate your path to bankruptcy with dire consequences.</p>
<p>Another point to remind readers of is to avoid borrowing money to purchase consumer goods. Borrowing to consume is like using future money to create &ldquo;false wealth.&rdquo; Unless absolutely necessary, the concept of borrowing for consumption should be avoided. Otherwise, the family&rsquo;s financial situation will be burdened.</p>
<p>For banks, consumer loans are extremely risky and require high interest rates.  Generally, consumer loan interest rates are above 10%.  Readers should understand that high-return investments have an amazing compounding effect.  Similarly, high-interest loans also have a dramatic compounding effect.  Take car loans, for example.  Assuming a 20% loan interest rate, after three and a half years, you will have to repay double the amount. This means that if you borrow money to buy a car now, three and a half years later, not only will the original car have depreciated significantly, but you will effectively have to pay for two new cars of the same model.  My advice on car loans is: don&rsquo;t take them. Wait until you can afford to pay in cash. Car loan interest rates are usually very high, often exceeding 15%, although there are occasional promotional periods with lower rates.  Fundamentally, except for commercial vehicles, cars are consumer goods with no investment return.  From an investment perspective, borrowing for car purchases is highly inadvisable.</p>
<p><strong>Uncontrolled Consumer Lending Easily Leads to Bankruptcy</strong></p>
<p>Credit cards, now a ubiquitous form of plastic currency worldwide, are also a typical example of consumer loans.  Since the popularization of credit cards, consumer behavior has undergone significant changes. While credit cards offer great convenience, their widespread use has led to a surge in bankruptcy cases among American families, with outstanding credit card debt exceeding 700 billion USD.  Some may wonder: how can credit cards lead to bankruptcy if you only spend what you have?  In fact, from a borrowing perspective, credit cards have an irresistible allure.</p>
<p>The greatest temptation of credit card borrowing lies in its simplicity.  With just a signature, you can make purchases in advance and even borrow cash from the bank, subtly inflating your spending power.  Remember: when using credit cards, never spend more than you can afford to repay each month.  Credit card interest rates are often above 20%, so you should always pay off your credit card balance promptly.  My advice is: &ldquo;If you can&rsquo;t control your spending urges, it&rsquo;s best not to apply for a credit card. If you apply for one for convenience, never use it for the sake of credit.  Use it only when it truly offers convenience.&rdquo;</p>
<p>While using credit cards for borrowing is convenient, those who entertain this idea should first understand the destructive power of a 20% interest rate. As mentioned earlier, if you save 14,000 per year and invest it in an investment tool with a 20% annual return, after 40 years, the 560,000 invested will grow to 102.81 million due to the power of compounding. Similarly, if someone borrows 14,000 per year on a credit card for 40 years, totaling 560,000, with a 20% interest rate, they will have to repay the bank 102.81 million after 40 years. This explains why the prevalence of credit card debt in the United States has historically led to numerous bankruptcies.</p>
<p>Another common type of loan is a mortgage.  Generally, mortgages are a sound form of leveraged investing because, in the long run, the average return on real estate is above 20%, while typical mortgage interest rates are around 10%, which meets the first principle of leveraged investing: the expected return on investment is higher than the interest rate on the loan. Whether it meets the second principle depends on the purchase conditions. In recent years, with the real estate market downturn and oversupply, some pre-sale housing promotions offer &ldquo;70% financing,&rdquo; allowing you to own a 10 million house with only a 3 million down payment. This is quite appealing, but investors often overlook the fact that while borrowing 7 million sounds great, they must be able to afford the monthly principal and interest payments of over 70,000. Without considering this, there is a risk of foreclosure and being forced to sell at a low price within months of purchase, suffering losses before enjoying any benefits of leveraged investing. Therefore, when purchasing real estate with borrowed funds, careful calculations must be made beforehand to choose a suitable house price that does not jeopardize the family&rsquo;s normal living expenses.</p>
<p>Although the initial burden of a mortgage is heavy, it becomes lighter over time as work experience and salary increase.  If you wait until you have saved enough money to buy a house, you might miss the opportunity entirely due to the rapid appreciation of house prices. Therefore, <strong>young people without real estate should consider buying a house as an investment. It not only forces them to save but also effectively combats inflation. Moreover, they can utilize the principle of financial leverage, using the bank&rsquo;s money to expand their credit and accumulate wealth.</strong></p>
<p><strong>How Much Debt Should You Take On?</strong></p>
<p>If you decide to use leveraged investing, the next question is: how much debt should you take on? This is a crucial question. Too much debt carries high risks, while too little debt fails to fully utilize the potential of making money with other people&rsquo;s money.</p>
<p>How much debt should a family take on?  Like &ldquo;how much debt should a company have,&rdquo; this is a question without a precise answer. In practice, it depends on the specific circumstances of each family. However, one thing is certain: if a family has the capacity to borrow but chooses not to, it is being too conservative and not managing its finances optimally. Conversely, excessive borrowing is too dangerous.  Before taking on debt, each family should consider its actual situation and make a wise judgment about its debt level.  As for how much to borrow, I recommend considering the following factors:</p>
<ul>
<li>
<ol>
<li>Income Stability:  Loan interest must be paid on time regardless of investment performance. If your income source is unstable, you may not be able to make regular interest payments, making high-leverage investments unsuitable. Similar to companies with stable income, they have a greater capacity to utilize more debt.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol start="2">
<li>Personal Assets: Borrowing from financial institutions requires tangible assets as collateral. Therefore, owning more assets suitable as collateral allows for larger leveraged investments.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol start="3">
<li>Return on Investment: Other things being equal, the higher the return on investment, the greater the benefits of financial leverage.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol start="4">
<li>Inflation Rate: Borrowing is more advantageous during periods of high inflation, as inflation allows you to repay debt with less valuable money.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol start="5">
<li>Risk Tolerance: Everyone has a different risk tolerance, related to personality and individual circumstances. Those with low risk tolerance should not over-leverage, even if it could lead to large profits, as the stress could take a toll.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol start="6">
<li>Market Interest Rate Levels: Generally, when market interest rates fall and bank funds are ample, not only is it easier for investors to borrow money, but the benefits of financial leverage are also greater. Therefore, falling interest rates present an opportune time for investors to consider leveraged investing.</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>Keeping money in the bank makes a person poor.</p></blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">The Bank is Not a Place for Saving Money 
    <div id="the-bank-is-not-a-place-for-saving-money" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#the-bank-is-not-a-place-for-saving-money" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>What is the function of a bank to you? Many people believe banks are for saving money. However, for those who truly understand investment management, banks are not a place to save money, but a source of borrowing.</p>
<p><strong>The function of a bank is to provide a place for those who are not good at managing money to save, so that those who are good at it can use that money to invest and make profits.</strong> Suppose someone deposits 14,000 per year into a bank at a 5% interest rate. After 40 years, the bank will owe this depositor 1.69 million. On the other hand, if an investor borrows 14,000 per year from the same bank at the same 5% interest rate and invests that money in stocks or real estate, achieving an average annual return of 20%, after 40 years, their investment would grow to 102.81 million, while they only need to repay the bank 1.69 million. In other words, the 101.12 million gained was made by utilizing the money of bank depositors.</p>
<p><strong>How to Build Credit</strong></p>
<p>In today&rsquo;s highly developed financial markets, there are numerous financing channels for businesses. However, for individuals, banks remain the primary source of borrowing.  Maintaining a close relationship with the bank and earning their trust is crucial for building personal credit.</p>
<p>Credit is the ability to borrow.  A person with high credit not only demonstrates a strong ability to repay loans but also indicates wealth. How do you build credit?  As the saying goes, &ldquo;Loan and repay, and borrowing again is easy.&rdquo; The first rule of building credit is to borrow money and repay it on time. Some people, to establish their creditworthiness (the ability to borrow), even borrow small sums of money for seemingly frivolous reasons, just to build a good borrowing record so they can borrow larger amounts in the future.</p>
<p>Discard the outdated notion that &ldquo;borrowing is not respectable.&rdquo; In the past, only those in dire financial straits would borrow money. Nowadays, such individuals can at most borrow small amounts from relatives and friends.  They would likely be unable to borrow a cent from a bank.  Today, those who can borrow from banks are typically wealthy individuals.</p>
<p>Based on current bank loan approval standards, without sufficient assets as collateral or evidence of stable future income and repayment ability, can anyone borrow money? Therefore, when I hear about someone heavily in debt, my first question is whether the source of the debt is banks or private loans.  If the source is entirely from banks, my immediate thought is: &ldquo;This person must be wealthy.&rdquo;</p>
<p><strong>Borrowing: A Double-Edged Sword</strong></p>
<p>Those who don&rsquo;t borrow cannot go bankrupt; similarly, those who don&rsquo;t borrow can hardly become immensely wealthy in a short period.  &ldquo;Debt&rdquo; appears in the lives of both the most successful and the most unsuccessful. While many wealthy individuals utilize debt to become rich, many poor people are ruined by misusing debt. Borrowing is a double-edged sword. Used correctly, it is a significant aid to investment and wealth creation. Used improperly, its destructive power can lead to complete ruin.  Prudence is essential when using it. It&rsquo;s like a double-edged sword that can save or harm, depending on how it&rsquo;s wielded.</p>
<p>I advise against rushing into leveraged investing before fully understanding its principles.  First, understand the nature of leveraged investing and carefully consider whether to use borrowing for investment.  Before borrowing, thoroughly understand how leveraged investing works. Only then can you truly achieve the goal of making money with other people&rsquo;s money without harming yourself.</p>
]]></content:encoded></item></channel></rss>