<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Personal Finance on QQQ Investor</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/tags/personal-finance/</link><description>Recent content in Personal Finance on QQQ Investor</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jomonylw.github.io/en/tags/personal-finance/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Personal Investment Bible: Conclusion</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1731056005974/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1731056005974/</guid><description>This article summarizes the core concepts of building wealth through personal finance, emphasizing that everyone can achieve financial freedom through proper money management. Key takeaways include the importance of financial planning, principles for setting financial goals, the value of long-term investing, overcoming common financial misconceptions, and balancing wealth with a fulfilling life. It encourages readers to acquire financial knowledge, adhere to long-term investment strategies, and ultimately achieve financial freedom and a better life.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[

<h2 class="relative group">Conclusion 
    <div id="conclusion" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#conclusion" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>What influences a person&rsquo;s future wealth the most,
is whether they have started managing their finances.</p></blockquote>
<p><strong>Everyone Can Achieve Wealth Through Personal Finance</strong></p>
<p>This book aims to illustrate a simple truth: investing and managing your finances can not only improve the financial situation of an individual or family, but is also an excellent path to wealth creation.  Furthermore, anyone can achieve wealth through personal finance. You don&rsquo;t need to be rich, have a high income, possess a high degree, have specialized knowledge or advanced skills, nor rely on luck. What you need is the desire for wealth, a correct investment philosophy (not just techniques), and the patience to wait for the long term.  Therefore, whether a person has money or not, or how high their income is, doesn&rsquo;t matter. What truly influences a person&rsquo;s future wealth is whether they have started managing their finances. This endeavor is not easy, but it&rsquo;s undoubtedly worth your effort!</p>
<p>Readers, please immediately review your current asset allocation. Is too much of your capital sitting in bank accounts or other &ldquo;guaranteed return&rdquo; investments?  Is your investment portfolio sufficiently diversified? Do you frequently buy and sell in the stock market?</p>
<p>After understanding your asset allocation, you should earnestly plan your financial goals and follow these five principles:</p>
<p><em>1. Clearly define the amount of wealth you hope to achieve and keep it in mind at all times. Simply thinking &ldquo;I want to be rich&rdquo; is not enough.</em></p>
<p><em>2. Set a specific date for achieving your goal.</em></p>
<p><em>3. Determine what price you&rsquo;re willing to pay and what actions you&rsquo;ll take to reach your ideal goal.</em></p>
<p><em>4. Think about your goal at least twice a day to reinforce your belief.</em></p>
<p><em>5.  Take action, whether you feel completely ready or not.</em></p>
<p>In Appendix II, readers can use the wealth creation formula and examples provided to calculate how to achieve their financial goals.</p>
<p>Your future wealth depends on what you do today. Don&rsquo;t let unnecessary hesitation cast a shadow on your heart. As long as you understand investment and financial management, you too can become wealthy in the future. Everyone possesses the necessary ingredients for wealth creation: a small amount of capital and a God-given resource—time. As long as you are willing to learn about personal finance, you have the potential to become a multi-millionaire.</p>
<p>When you find people around you feeling lost due to a lack of vision for the future, share with them the &ldquo;¥14,000 a year for 40 years can make you a multi-millionaire&rdquo; formula and help them reignite their hope.</p>
<p><strong>Financial Dependence Is Your Own Responsibility</strong></p>
<p>The unequal distribution of wealth in today&rsquo;s society is increasingly severe. Some blame flawed policies, others point to artificial market manipulation. I believe neither is the primary cause.  One of the main reasons for the wealth gap is the disparity in financial literacy among people.</p>
<p>The reason for poverty in modern times is not so much insufficient income, lack of thrift, or excessive spending, but rather improper financial management. In modern society, achieving financial independence after the age of 40 is a fundamental responsibility for everyone. Whether you want to or not, or whether you like it or not, investment and financial management have become essential knowledge for modern individuals. Remember, with our current income levels and investment opportunities, &ldquo;remaining poor after 40&rdquo; is self-inflicted, and &ldquo;not being a multi-millionaire after 70&rdquo; is due to a lack of financial knowledge.</p>
<p>Advances in modern medicine have increased human life expectancy, leading to an aging society.  Longer lifespans are a blessing, but enjoying a comfortable retirement is even more crucial. We must accumulate sufficient wealth to secure our lives in old age.</p>
<p><strong>Effortless Personal Finance, Enjoy the Process</strong></p>
<p>From the examples provided in this article, we can see that those who are good at managing their finances understand how to invest their assets in stocks and real estate with high long-term returns, and they avoid unnecessary short-term trading, thus achieving wealth with ease.  Those who are not good at managing their finances either focus solely on saving and keeping their assets in &ldquo;safe&rdquo; bank deposits or try to get rich quickly by engaging in short-term trading in the stock or futures markets. These individuals will eventually be left far behind in the race for financial success.</p>
<p>Most people keep their assets in financial institutions without investing them, and when they do start investing, they aim for quick riches.  As a result, their money stagnates in banks, and their pursuit of quick wealth often leads to substantial losses.  They fail to realize that with a little courage, by investing in stocks and real estate and patiently waiting for decades, they can naturally achieve wealth.</p>
<p>Simply put, building wealth through personal finance only requires two things: investing your capital in areas with high returns and having the patience to wait for the long term. The required investment is low, the probability of success is high, and the process is relaxed and enjoyable.</p>
<p>I advise readers not to rush to get rich through investment, causing anxiety and ultimately achieving the opposite of what they desire.  By following the methods described in this book, you can achieve financial success without expending excessive time and energy, allowing you to focus on your existing career.</p>
<p>Personal finance is a marathon, not a sprint. If you view the entire process from a long-term perspective, temporary setbacks don&rsquo;t signify failure, and momentary gains don&rsquo;t guarantee lasting success. With this mindset, you can maintain a more open perspective and avoid becoming overly attached to gains and losses.</p>
<p>I admit that consistently buying assets and holding them long-term can make personal finance seem dull and unbearable. However, before engaging in any financial activities, investors must clarify their objectives: is it to build wealth or to seek the thrill of gambling? Personal finance can not only lead to wealth but also bring joy and knowledge.  Everyone should learn how to manage their finances and find enjoyment in the process.</p>
<p><strong>Don&rsquo;t Feel Guilty About Being Wealthy</strong></p>
<p>Wealth should be acquired and used ethically. You don&rsquo;t need to apologize to others for your wealth. Only the pursuit of wealth through unscrupulous means is sinful and unfortunate.  Therefore, everyone should not only be confident but also feel obligated to earn wealth. There&rsquo;s no need to be secretive or ashamed about pursuing wealth. On the contrary, being financially dependent is a burden on society.  Moreover, wealthy individuals are more capable of contributing to society.  In short, if you can&rsquo;t find a good reason why getting rich is bad, why not allow yourself to become wealthy?</p>
<p>You earning more in the investment market doesn&rsquo;t mean others will earn less or lose more.  If everyone is proficient in managing their finances, not only can individuals prosper, but economic resources can also be utilized effectively, leading to rapid overall economic growth.  In a market economy, the wealth of society is built upon the wealth of its people. Only a prosperous populace can create a prosperous economy.</p>
<p>In today&rsquo;s financially driven world, whether for personal advancement or the benefit of society as a whole, everyone should strengthen their understanding of personal finance. When everyone is skilled in managing their finances, individuals and families can live prosperous lives, the wealth gap can be narrowed, and the nation can progress and flourish.</p>
<p><strong>Action Speaks Louder Than Words</strong></p>
<p>&ldquo;Knowing and not doing is not knowing.&rdquo; The biggest obstacle to personal finance is not that it&rsquo;s difficult to do, but that it&rsquo;s difficult to start.  The key to overcoming this is to act immediately.  One of the main reasons for failure in personal finance is avoiding decisions.  However, if you want to achieve your goal of building wealth through investment, there&rsquo;s no other way than to take action.</p>
<p>After reading the basic principles of investment and financial management outlined in this article, you should understand that building wealth is not only achievable but also not difficult.  So, act now! Time is money. The earlier you start, the sooner you&rsquo;ll reach your financial goals and share the fruits of your labor with your family.</p>
<p>Looking ahead, changes in society, politics, economics, and finance will accelerate, and the resulting redistribution of wealth will inevitably follow suit.  For yourself, your family, and society as a whole, managing your finances is a role everyone should embrace.</p>
<p><strong>Persistence Is Key</strong></p>
<p>For readers seeking quick riches, this book might disappoint you.  A more accurate title would be: &ldquo;How to Invest and Manage Your Finances to Slowly but Steadily Build Wealth.&rdquo;</p>
<p>Many believe that successful people are infallible—never failing, never experiencing losses.  Many also think they must be omniscient and possess sufficient knowledge before they can start investing and managing their finances.  Our most common flaw is our unwillingness to try repeatedly and to persevere. Building wealth through personal finance is not difficult! The reason most people don&rsquo;t achieve their goals is their inability to persevere and their lack of patience.</p>
<p>Persistence is essential for success in personal finance. Suppose you embark on a wealth-building plan and encounter setbacks along the way. Don&rsquo;t be discouraged. Some people regularly save and invest annually.  When prices rise, they are satisfied and continue their plan. But when prices fall, they panic and abandon their investment strategy.  They fail to understand that price fluctuations are inherent in the investment market, and investment results will inevitably fluctuate.</p>
<p>If, midway through your financial plan, you succumb to the temptation to spend your investment capital or give up due to repeated setbacks, all your previous efforts will be wasted.  <strong>Success in personal finance depends on endurance and resolve:  endurance to delay gratification and resist immediate consumption temptations; and resolve to withstand significant wealth fluctuations over long periods without losing your composure.  As long as you have perseverance and resolve, trust in compound interest, and believe in the &ldquo;wealth creation formula,&rdquo; the ultimate wealth will undoubtedly be yours.</strong></p>
<p>&ldquo;No dreams, no wealth.&rdquo;  Those who build wealth through personal finance must be driven by desire and ambition.  They also need sufficient courage, knowledge, patience, and perseverance.  A lack of courage, flawed methods, impatience, or giving up halfway will not work. Whether you can achieve wealth and financial independence in the future depends entirely on your actions and efforts today.</p>
<p><strong>Unlock Your Hidden Wealth Potential</strong></p>
<p>Believe it or not, the price of living a wealthy and successful life is no greater than the price of living a poor and miserable one. Achieving this depends entirely on wisdom, belief, and action. After reading this book, readers should understand that everyone can achieve wealth through personal finance. The reason most people are not wealthy is not due to low income, but rather a lack of understanding of how to create wealth through investment and financial management. The primary purpose of this book is to help everyone unlock their hidden wealth potential.</p>
<p>If, after reading this book, you still cannot effectively apply these investment principles to manage your money and improve your financial situation, then this book is a complete failure.  Financial education is not merely about imparting knowledge; its significance lies in genuinely changing the reader&rsquo;s financial behavior.</p>
<p>This is a book of action, not a textbook for enhancing investment knowledge or a &ldquo;decorative book&rdquo; for your bookshelf.  This book aims to inspire readers to change their mindset and behavior. Its success depends on readers taking action based on the core principles presented, breaking free from mediocrity, and embarking on the path to wealth. Therefore, at the end of most chapters, key points are summarized for readers to reflect upon and apply.</p>
<p>Investment and financial management can not only lead to wealth but also bring joy to investors. Everyone should learn how to manage their finances and reap the substantial rewards.  I believe most readers already possess the basic requirements for building wealth: a small amount of capital, sufficient time, and the investment knowledge gained from this book.  The world of personal finance, full of changes and opportunities, awaits you.  It is filled with treasures and pitfalls. Don&rsquo;t hesitate, and don&rsquo;t leave empty-handed.</p>
<p>The principles of building wealth through investment and financial management are neither profound nor mysterious. They are absolutely achievable for everyone, and many have indeed easily become wealthy through these methods.  As we&rsquo;ve mentioned before, &ldquo;If you&rsquo;re willing to learn, managing your finances is as simple as walking.&rdquo;</p>
<p>Among the financial principles presented in this book, you&rsquo;ll find many that contradict deeply ingrained investment concepts and financial habits, and some even go against human nature.  Therefore, to realize the ideal of wealth creation through investment and financial management, the first step is to break free from some &ldquo;deep-rooted and misguided&rdquo; investment concepts, common knowledge, and habits.  Almost none of these concepts and principles are easy to achieve. Therefore, I advise readers to not only read each chapter carefully but also to review, reflect, establish strict rules, and ultimately change their behavior.</p>
<p><strong>Wealth Is a Means to a Better Life</strong></p>
<p>Finally, this book must emphasize that <strong>wealth is not the purpose of life, but a means to create a better life.</strong>  The ultimate goal of investment and financial management is not just to become rich, but to use wealth to realize your life&rsquo;s aspirations.  Therefore, <strong>a fulfilling and balanced life is the starting point for personal finance.</strong></p>
<p>Everyone should actively and optimistically plan and execute their lifelong financial journey.  Based on the principles we&rsquo;ve presented, everyone can achieve substantial wealth through personal finance without sacrificing time, energy, work, or life.  However, it&rsquo;s crucial to remember that <strong>only those who balance career, life, health, family, and wealth can be considered truly successful in managing their finances.</strong>  Those who gain the world&rsquo;s riches but lose their health, family, and the meaning of life cannot be considered truly successful.  In today&rsquo;s society, many are lost in the pursuit of wealth, sacrificing more valuable things in life.  Therefore, this principle of balancing personal finance and life is particularly important and deserves careful consideration.</p>
<p>Although this book repeatedly emphasizes that success in personal finance depends on mindset, time, and action, not luck, I still congratulate you, the reader, on being fortunate enough to encounter this book. By adhering to the investment principles within, you are sure to become a multi-millionaire in the decades to come!</p>
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Personal Investment Bible: Investment Iron Law II</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1731056005961/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1731056005961/</guid><description>This article explains that the key to wealth accumulation through personal finance is patience. Using Li Ka-shing&amp;#39;s wealth accumulation as an example, it explains the power of compound interest and emphasizes the importance of long-term investment and time. At the same time, the article also points out the pitfalls of getting rich quickly and advises readers to choose entrepreneurship rather than speculation.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[

<h2 class="relative group">Investment Iron Law II: Patience is Key to Wealth Accumulation 
    <div id="investment-iron-law-ii-patience-is-key-to-wealth-accumulation" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#investment-iron-law-ii-patience-is-key-to-wealth-accumulation" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>Working hard is not about making more money,<br>
but about maintaining a state of mind<br>
— challenge, goals, struggle, and success.</p></blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">How Did Li Ka-shing Accumulate His Wealth? 
    <div id="how-did-li-ka-shing-accumulate-his-wealth" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#how-did-li-ka-shing-accumulate-his-wealth" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>Li Ka-shing, ranked among the top ten wealthiest Chinese in the world with a fortune of nearly $7 billion, is the chairman of Cheung Kong Holdings and Hutchison Whampoa Limited in Hong Kong. His legendary journey to wealth and his influence in Hong Kong&rsquo;s political and business circles have earned him another nickname — &ldquo;Superman Li.&rdquo;</p>
<p><strong>Capitalizing on the Plunging Property Market</strong></p>
<p>In 1939, 12-year-old Li Ka-shing moved to Hong Kong from his hometown of Chao&rsquo;an, Guangdong, with his father. After two years of schooling, Hong Kong fell due to the Pacific War. The following year, his father died of a serious illness, forcing Li Ka-shing, the eldest son, to drop out of school and support his family. After Hong Kong&rsquo;s liberation in 1945, he ended his odd-job career and became a salesman at a plastics factory, working over 16 hours a day. Three years later, at the age of 20, he was promoted to general manager. Two years after that, he used all his savings of HK$7,000 to start his own small plastics factory, &ldquo;Cheung Kong Industries,&rdquo; the predecessor of today&rsquo;s largest conglomerate in Hong Kong, Cheung Kong Holdings.</p>
<p>How did Li Ka-shing, without even a primary school diploma, take his first step toward becoming the richest man by producing plastic flowers? In 1958, due to a rent increase by the landlord of his factory, Li Ka-shing bought a piece of land in North Point and built his own factory. In the early 1960s, the plastic flower industry declined, and in 1967, Hong Kong property prices plummeted. Li Ka-shing seized the opportunity to acquire land at low prices. In 1972, the Hong Kong stock market soared, and Cheung Kong Industries went public, taking advantage of the opportunity to raise capital from the public to purchase more land. In the 10 years following the completion of his first factory in 1958, his real estate holdings increased 50-fold. Cheung Kong now holds approximately 1.48 million square meters of floor space. Li Ka-shing has been investing in real estate for over 40 years, and long-term investment has accumulated his enormous wealth.</p>
<p>Having strived for 50 years and achieved success in wealth accumulation, Li Ka-shing has unique insights into success. He said: &ldquo;Before the age of 20, 100% of career success comes from hard work; between 20 and 30, when a career has some foundation, 10% of success depends on good luck, and 90% still comes from diligence; after 30, the proportion of opportunity gradually increases; now, luck accounts for about 30% to 40%.&rdquo;</p>
<p>The same applies to wealth accumulation. Before 20, all money comes from hard work; between 20 and 30 is the time to work hard to earn and save money; after 30, the importance of investment and financial management gradually increases. By middle age, the money earned is less important, and how to manage money becomes more critical. Li Ka-shing has been fighting for his wealth all his life. To become rich, one must have enough patience.</p>
<p><strong>The Power of Compound Interest Takes Time</strong></p>
<p>Many people who have heard my lectures often ask the same questions: &ldquo;Saving 14,000 yuan a year to become a billionaire is indeed impressive, but according to your method, it takes 40 years, which is really discouraging!&rdquo; &ldquo;It takes 40 years to become a billionaire. By then, I might be dead. What&rsquo;s the point of having billions then?&rdquo; &ldquo;Can you teach some secrets to getting rich quickly?&rdquo;</p>
<p>Even I feel that 40 years is too long. At the repeated requests of the audience, I did spend some time studying this issue in depth. The result of the research is: <strong>Financial management requires a long time, and the effect is not visible in the short term.  It is impossible to get rich quickly through financial management.</strong></p>
<p>If someone starts now and saves 14,000 yuan at the end of each year, and if the money saved each year can be invested in stocks or real estate with an average annual return of 20%, we know that the wealth will grow to 102.81 million yuan after 40 years. Now, let&rsquo;s ask: How much wealth can he accumulate after 10 years? Most people think that with such a high return, even with a shorter time, after 10 years of compounding, it should be at least 5 million yuan, some even guess 10 million, and the most conservative guess is 1 million.  Similarly, this is a surprising answer: 360,000 yuan! The following calculation formula should be familiar to readers, but they will be surprised that the amount is so small.</p>
<p><math xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" display="block"><mtable displaystyle="true" columnalign="right center left" columnspacing="0 thickmathspace" rowspacing="3pt"><mtr><mtd><mn>14,000</mn><mo>×</mo><mfrac><mrow><msup><mrow><mo stretchy="false">(</mo><mn>1</mn><mo>+</mo><mn>0.20</mn><mo stretchy="false">)</mo></mrow><mrow><mn>10</mn></mrow></msup><mo>−</mo><mn>1</mn></mrow><mn>0.20</mn></mfrac></mtd><mtd><mi></mi><mo>=</mo></mtd><mtd><mn>360,000</mn></mtd></mtr><mtr><mtd><mn>14,000</mn><mo>×</mo><mfrac><mrow><msup><mrow><mo stretchy="false">(</mo><mn>1</mn><mo>+</mo><mn>0.20</mn><mo stretchy="false">)</mo></mrow><mrow><mn>40</mn></mrow></msup><mo>−</mo><mn>1</mn></mrow><mn>0.20</mn></mfrac></mtd><mtd><mi></mi><mo>=</mo></mtd><mtd><mn>102,810,000</mn></mtd></mtr></mtable></math></p>
<p>With the same 20% return, 14,000 yuan per year results in 102.81 million yuan after 40 years of financial management, but only 360,000 yuan after 10 years, which is unbelievable! The difference is more than 300 times! Fortunately, this concept is presented to readers in a timely manner. Otherwise, if readers use the methods mentioned in this book, save 14,000 yuan every year, and invest all of it in stocks, thinking that they can become billionaires, they would be shocked to find that after ten years of hard work, with an average annual return of 20%, they have only accumulated 360,000 yuan! They might feel cheated.  After struggling for 10 years, they can&rsquo;t even afford a car, let alone become billionaires!</p>
<p>What is 10 years? Ten years is a long time. After 10 years of struggle, there&rsquo;s only a little over 300,000 yuan. How discouraging! This is the frustration one inevitably encounters in the process of accumulating wealth through investment and financial management.  Investors must understand that financial management is a &ldquo;marathon&rdquo; rather than a &ldquo;sprint.&rdquo; It&rsquo;s about endurance, not explosive power.</p>
<p>The prerequisite for getting rich through investment and financial management is time, and a long time. You must go through a very long waiting period before you can see the results. If the invested capital is small, no results will be seen after 10 years.</p>
<p><strong>Earning Your Second 10 Million is Easier Than the First 1 Million</strong></p>
<p>Saving 14,000 yuan at the end of each year with an average investment return of 20%, even after 20 years, the assets will only accumulate to 2.61 million yuan.  At this point, one is still far from being a billionaire. It takes 30 years to accumulate 16.55 million yuan, barely reaching the millionaire level.  Only after 40 years of continuous struggle can one become a billionaire with 102.81 million yuan.</p>
<p><em>Annual Investment of 14,000 Yuan, Wealth Accumulation (20% Return, Unit/10,000 Yuan)</em></p>
<table>
  <thead>
      <tr>
          <th>Year</th>
          <th>Accumulated Amount at Year End</th>
          <th>Amount Increased in the Last Five Years</th>
      </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
      <tr>
          <td>5</td>
          <td>10</td>
          <td>10</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>10</td>
          <td>36</td>
          <td>26</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>15</td>
          <td>101</td>
          <td>65</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>20</td>
          <td>261</td>
          <td>160</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>25</td>
          <td>661</td>
          <td>400</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>30</td>
          <td>1655</td>
          <td>994</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>35</td>
          <td>4128</td>
          <td>2473</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>40</td>
          <td>10281</td>
          <td>6153</td>
      </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>
<p>From the table above, we can see: by saving 14,000 yuan annually with a 20% investment return, the wealth increased by 360,000 yuan in the first decade, 2.25 million yuan in the second decade, 13.94 million yuan in the third decade, and 86.26 million yuan in the fourth decade. This is the characteristic of geometric progression, and it is also the principle that people engaged in investment and financial management should understand.  Therefore, three important characteristics of investment and financial management can be summarized here:</p>
<ul>
<li>
<ol>
<li>Most wealth is created in the later stages. From the above example, we can see that only 41.28 million yuan was accumulated in the first 35 years, while 61.53 million yuan was created in the last 5 years.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol start="2">
<li>In terms of amount, your ability to make money through financial management increases over time. From the table above, it can be seen that doing the same thing, the amount of money earned increases, the only thing needed is patience.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol start="3">
<li>Earning the second 10 million yuan is often easier than the first 1 million yuan.</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>Wealth accumulation doesn&rsquo;t happen overnight.</p></blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">Patience Pays Off 
    <div id="patience-pays-off" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#patience-pays-off" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>A self-made man who got rich by investing in stocks once told me: &ldquo;Now that I&rsquo;ve made it, a stock price increase can easily bring in millions of yuan. Making money has suddenly become so easy, it&rsquo;s unstoppable. Thinking back to the days when I first entered the stock market 30 years ago, it took a lot of hard work to earn tens of thousands of yuan. I really don&rsquo;t know where the money went back then.&rdquo;</p>
<p>This experience is not unfamiliar to many who have struggled to build their fortunes from scratch.  Everything is difficult at the beginning.  During the initial struggle, money is hard to earn.  It takes a lot of effort to earn just tens of thousands of yuan. It&rsquo;s puzzling why money is so hard to earn.  Until success is achieved, and money comes rolling in, one wonders why making money has become so easy.</p>
<p><strong>Time is the Stepping Stone to Wealth Accumulation</strong></p>
<p>Everyone desires the ability to effortlessly earn their second million or ten million, reaching a state of abundant wealth.  The problem is, before earning the second million, you need to have the first million. But how can you earn the first million?  If you want to accumulate 1 million through investment and financial management, you need &ldquo;time.&rdquo; You have to go through a long period of hardship. If you can endure the difficult period of earning the first million, you can naturally enjoy the ease of earning the second million.</p>
<p>From the compound interest formula, we can see that time is an indispensable factor for compound interest to take effect.  Patient waiting is a prerequisite for investment and financial management.  Especially for wealth accumulation through financial management, the required patience is not a few months or years, but at least two or three decades, or even four or five decades.</p>
<p>The vast majority of wealthy people accumulate their huge fortunes gradually from small amounts of money over a long period. In the beginning, most people have very little capital, even negligible. However, success is woven from a series of small achievements. Great wealth is the accumulation of small wealth, coupled with the effect of compound interest.</p>
<p>The importance of time in investment and financial management is evident. Patience is essential for financial management. The more patient you are in enduring the long waiting period, the greater the power of wealth creation will be. This is the characteristic of &ldquo;compound interest.&rdquo; However, today we live in a &ldquo;fast food&rdquo; culture where everything emphasizes speed and efficiency: fast food restaurants for meals, express delivery for mail, highways for driving, one-hour photo processing, and crash courses for learning. People have become increasingly impatient and short-sighted, lacking patience.  In investment and financial management, they are also impatient and lack patience, wanting to see results immediately.  It may be more efficient to pursue speed in other matters, but investment and financial management cannot be rushed. Time is a necessary condition for financial management. The more you rush, the less you achieve.  Based on my observations, a common mistake among investors is giving up halfway. They get easily discouraged during bear markets and simply sell their stocks and real estate, completely leaving the stock and property markets, not knowing that lack of patience and perseverance makes it difficult to achieve anything.</p>
<ul>
<li>
<ol>
<li>Time is an indispensable factor in achieving wealth through financial management.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol start="2">
<li>The patience required for wealth accumulation is not a few months or years, but at least two or three decades.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol start="3">
<li>Patient waiting allows compound interest to take effect.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol start="4">
<li>How can investors achieve a state of abundant and unstoppable wealth? Long-term holding and patient waiting.</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>The Real Estate Investment Experience of Madam Chang Yao-Hung-Ying, Chairperson of Grand Pacific Construction</strong></p>
<p><em>&ldquo;Land I bought for hundreds of thousands in the past is now worth hundreds of millions.&rdquo;</em></p>
<p>Madam Chang Yao-Hung-Ying, chairperson of Grand Pacific Construction, pointed out: In the 1930s, a mainlander investing in land in Taiwan was often ridiculed. But it was with this small capital and perseverance that Madam Chang Yao-Hung-Ying, who left Shanghai for Taiwan in 1947, when her husband became disillusioned with his business, saw the development potential of Taiwan. She picked up their real estate business skills from Shanghai and started buying land.</p>
<p>After more than 40 years, her long-term investment in real estate finally paid off.  Her family&rsquo;s business is growing bigger and bigger, and they now own two listed companies: ASE Technology Holding and Grand Pacific Construction. ASE Technology Holding is now the second largest packaging factory in the world. As for Grand Pacific Construction, it launched the Earl&rsquo;s Court project in Xizhi in 1987, which boosted the real estate market in Xizhi and rapidly accumulated their family&rsquo;s wealth, making them one of the richest families in Taiwan.</p>
<p>Madam Chang Yao-Hung-Ying has now passed the baton to her son, Jason Chang. Jason Chang, chairman of ASE Technology Holding, seems to have inherited his mother&rsquo;s investment acumen. He&rsquo;s the kind of person who buys land wherever he goes, whether it&rsquo;s in Taiwan, Hong Kong, mainland China, or the United States. Perhaps in another two or three decades, Jason Chang will also say: &ldquo;I didn&rsquo;t expect that the land I bought for a few million back then would now be worth tens of billions.&rdquo;  However, Jason Chang&rsquo;s wealth accumulation speed will be much faster than his mother&rsquo;s because he has already laid a good foundation.  All he needs to do is go with the flow, and his wealth will increase geometrically, with money rolling in, unstoppable.</p>
<p><strong>Withstanding the Test of Time is the True Measure</strong></p>
<p><em>It&rsquo;s not your judgment that makes you a lot of money, but your patience.</em></p>
<p>A crucial factor in financial management is time. Without a correct understanding of it, impatience will naturally arise.  Impatience leads to taking significant risks, turning potential success into failure.</p>
<p>Whether it&rsquo;s the accumulation of wealth or experience, it&rsquo;s not something that can be accomplished overnight. It takes time. Fortunately, God is very fair in this regard. Regardless of whether one is born rich or poor, noble or humble, everyone has only 24 hours a day and an average lifespan of about 75 years. Time is the greatest wealth in life, and a person&rsquo;s honor, status, wealth, and happiness all depend on how they use this wealth.</p>
<p>To accumulate wealth through investment and financial management, time is an indispensable factor. It cannot be rushed.  Investment and financial management can lead to slow and steady wealth accumulation, but investing small amounts of money and wanting to earn billions of wealth in a short period is, I can say with certainty, &ldquo;impossible!&rdquo; Just imagine, can a mother give birth without going through ten months of pregnancy? Can a farmer shorten the growth period of rice seedlings?</p>
<p>The growth of wealth is like the growth of life.  It&rsquo;s formed bit by bit, day by day, month by month, year by year, under the effect of compound interest.  It cannot be achieved overnight. This is the law of nature, and God never changes his natural laws.</p>
<p><strong>Luck is Not a Long-Term Strategy</strong></p>
<p>Many investors make a fortune overnight and go bankrupt overnight. Their success is due to luck, and their failure is because &ldquo;you may be lucky for a while, but you cannot always be lucky.&rdquo; <strong>Any investment opportunity that promises overnight riches must hide a greater risk of overnight poverty.</strong> This is why most of those who fantasize about getting rich quickly through financial management end up losing everything.</p>
<p>As long as you are patient and invest your assets in the right investment vehicles, you don&rsquo;t need to actively manage or worry. Compound interest will naturally lead to wealth growth, and becoming a billionaire over time is almost a certainty. In investment and financial management, haste makes waste. &ldquo;Fast&rdquo; is definitely not good!</p>
<p>If you really want to get rich quickly, I suggest you try entrepreneurship instead of investment and financial management. If any of the readers want to get rich quickly, what should they do?  My sincere suggestion is to choose the path of entrepreneurship. I have studied the wealth accumulation process of many rich people throughout history and found that there are many examples of getting rich quickly through entrepreneurship. Bill Gates, the richest man in the United States, dropped out of college in his freshman year to found Microsoft and became the richest man in the United States in just 20 years.</p>
<p>However, the probability of success in getting rich through entrepreneurship is extremely low.  According to statistics from the Taiwan Entrepreneurship Association, the success rate of a person&rsquo;s first business venture is only about 7%, and entrepreneurial success does not necessarily mean getting rich. In other words, for every successful entrepreneur we see, there are at least dozens of unknown failures behind them.  Moreover, the entrepreneurial process is very arduous. Working more than ten hours a day seems to be a prerequisite for successful entrepreneurs.</p>
<p>On the contrary, as long as the method is correct, investing money in the stock market and property market, and waiting patiently for decades, the probability of getting rich through investment and financial management is very high. It&rsquo;s hard not to get rich, and the process is relatively easy and enjoyable!  Which method you choose to get rich is up to you. I must emphasize again that there is a possibility of getting rich quickly through entrepreneurship, but it is absolutely impossible to get rich quickly through financial management.</p>
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Just Keep Buying: Book Notes</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1728914740948/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1728914740948/</guid><description>This book answers the most common questions in the field of personal finance and investing. From saving to investing, it provides practical tips to teach you how to increase your income, invest in income-producing assets, manage your finances more wisely, and live a richer life.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[

<h2 class="relative group">I. Content Summary 
    <div id="i-content-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-content-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This book is divided into two parts: saving and investing. The <strong>saving</strong> section covers all aspects of saving money, including how much to save, how to save more, and how to spend money without guilt. The <strong>investing</strong> section covers many aspects of making money with money, including why you should invest, what you should invest in, and how often you should invest. The author answers the most common questions in the field of personal finance and investing, with each chapter exploring a topic in depth and providing practical tips.  Using a large amount of data and empirical research as evidence, the author arrives at reliable ways to save money and build wealth.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">II. Chapter Summary 
    <div id="ii-chapter-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii-chapter-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Chapter 1. Where Should You Start? 
    <div id="chapter-1-where-should-you-start" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chapter-1-where-should-you-start" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>The poor should focus on saving, and the rich should focus on investing.</p>
<ul>
<li>Recent graduates should focus on increasing their income and savings rate, rather than obsessing over investment decisions, because the growth rate of savings far exceeds the growth rate of investment.</li>
<li>People who have accumulated a certain amount of wealth should spend more time thinking about the details of their investment plan.</li>
<li>The author proposes a &ldquo;Save-Invest continuum&rdquo; concept to help you determine your current financial focus: calculate your expected savings and expected investment growth. Focus on whichever is greater.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chapter 2. How Much Should You Save? 
    <div id="chapter-2-how-much-should-you-save" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chapter-2-how-much-should-you-save" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>You probably need to save less than you think.</p>
<ul>
<li>Many saving recommendations are based on false assumptions: that people&rsquo;s incomes are stable and that everyone has the ability to achieve the same savings rate.</li>
<li>In fact, incomes become more unstable over time, and the biggest determinant of an individual&rsquo;s savings rate is their income level.</li>
<li>The best saving advice is: <strong>save what you can save.</strong></li>
<li>A large body of evidence suggests that retirees generally don&rsquo;t spend enough, with many even increasing their financial assets after retirement.</li>
<li>Today&rsquo;s younger generation is not creating wealth any slower than previous generations, so there is no need to worry too much about running out of money after retirement.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chapter 3. How to Save More Money? 
    <div id="chapter-3-how-to-save-more-money" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chapter-3-how-to-save-more-money" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>The biggest lie in personal finance: you can get rich just by saving.</p>
<ul>
<li>The effectiveness of reducing spending is limited. For low-income people, spending is already at its lowest level, making it difficult to reduce further. The author uses data from the U.S. Bureau of Labor Statistics Consumer Expenditure Survey to support this point.</li>
<li>Increasing income is more effective than reducing spending because as income increases, spending does not necessarily increase proportionately (diminishing marginal utility). The author calls this the &ldquo;law of the stomach.&rdquo;</li>
<li>Five ways to increase your income:
<ul>
<li>Sell your time/expertise: easy to do, but not scalable.</li>
<li>Sell a skill/service: higher income, but takes time to develop skills.</li>
<li>Teach: easy to scale, but highly competitive.</li>
<li>Sell a product: scalable, but requires a lot of upfront investment and ongoing marketing efforts.</li>
<li>Climb the career ladder: traditional but effective, can gain skills, experience and stable income growth.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>The most reliable way to get rich is: <strong>Increase your income and invest in income-producing assets.</strong></li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chapter 4. How to Spend Money Without Guilt? 
    <div id="chapter-4-how-to-spend-money-without-guilt" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chapter-4-how-to-spend-money-without-guilt" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Most financial advice uses guilt to make you question your spending decisions, causing you to be overly nervous about spending money.</li>
<li>Two tips to help you make financial decisions without worry and spend money without guilt:
<ul>
<li>The 2x rule: When you splurge, invest the same amount of money in income-producing assets or donate it to charity. For example, if you want to buy a pair of $400 shoes, buy $400 worth of stock at the same time.</li>
<li>Focus on maximizing satisfaction: Think about whether your purchase can bring autonomy, mastery, and purpose, thereby increasing your long-term satisfaction. For example, a daily latte might allow you to do your job better.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>The only right way to spend money is: <strong>the way that works for you</strong>. Think about what you want to get out of life, and make spending decisions accordingly. Research from the University of Cambridge shows that the more your spending patterns match your psychological state, the higher your life satisfaction, and this effect is greater than the happiness brought by your total income.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chapter 5. How Much Lifestyle Inflation Is Harmless? 
    <div id="chapter-5-how-much-lifestyle-inflation-is-harmless" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chapter-5-how-much-lifestyle-inflation-is-harmless" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Lifestyle inflation refers to the increase in spending that follows an increase in one&rsquo;s income.</li>
<li>Some lifestyle inflation is enjoyable, but too much lifestyle inflation will lead to having to delay retirement.</li>
<li>The author simulates the retirement plans of two investors with different savings rates after salary increases to arrive at these conclusions:
<ul>
<li>The lower your current savings rate, the higher your lifestyle inflation can be without affecting your original retirement plan.</li>
<li>The author recommends saving at least 50% of your future raises, a rule that is simple, practical, and suitable for most people.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chapter 6. Should You Go Into Debt? 
    <div id="chapter-6-should-you-go-into-debt" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chapter-6-should-you-go-into-debt" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>Debt is not necessarily good or bad, it depends on how you use it.</p>
<ul>
<li>Debt as a form of risk mitigation: Some people, even with savings, keep credit card debt as a strategy to reduce the risk of future funding shortages.</li>
<li>Debt as a behavioral pillar of forced savings: Some people use debt as a behavioral pillar to force themselves to save.</li>
<li>The two most useful types of debt:
<ul>
<li>To reduce risk: for example, keeping cash on hand for emergencies or fixing housing costs.</li>
<li>To earn a return higher than the cost of borrowing: for example, by taking out education loans, business loans, or mortgages to generate higher returns. The author uses data to demonstrate that getting a college degree is often worthwhile.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Debt can also have non-financial costs, such as psychological stress and health problems, so non-mortgage financial debt should be avoided as much as possible.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chapter 7. Should You Rent or Buy? 
    <div id="chapter-7-should-you-rent-or-buy" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chapter-7-should-you-rent-or-buy" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>The point of buying a home is not whether to buy it, but when to buy it.</p>
<ul>
<li>In addition to the mortgage, there are a number of one-time and ongoing costs associated with buying a home, such as down payment, closing costs, taxes, maintenance, and insurance. The author details these costs, concluding that buying a home is only cost-effective if the buyer intends to live in it for the long term.</li>
<li>In the short term, buying a home is riskier than renting, but in the long term, renters face greater long-term risks such as rent fluctuations, housing instability, and moving costs.</li>
<li>In the United States, the long-term return on  homeownership as an investment is not ideal, far lower than the stock market. The author uses the example of his grandparents buying a home to illustrate this point.</li>
<li>The right time to buy a home is when you:
<ul>
<li>plan to stay in that location for at least ten years;</li>
<li>have a stable personal and professional life;</li>
<li>can afford a 20% down payment and keep your debt-to-income ratio below 43%. The author recommends, if possible, to make a 20% down payment and buy a larger home in one step, because the transaction costs are lower in the long run.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chapter 8. How to Save For a Down Payment (and Other Big Purchases)? 
    <div id="chapter-8-how-to-save-for-a-down-payment-and-other-big-purchases" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chapter-8-how-to-save-for-a-down-payment-and-other-big-purchases" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>Why the length of time you save matters?</p>
<ul>
<li>Short-term saving for less than two years: Holding <strong>cash</strong> is the best option, as it has the lowest risk.</li>
<li>Long-term saving for more than two years: Investing in <strong>bonds</strong> is preferable to holding cash because bond returns can offset the effects of inflation. The author compares cash and bonds using two examples: &ldquo;Save $1,000 per month with a goal of $24,000&rdquo; and &ldquo;Save $1,000 per month with a goal of $60,000&rdquo;.</li>
<li>Longer-term saving for more than three years: You can choose to invest in <strong>stocks</strong>, but the risk is higher and you need to choose an appropriate portfolio based on your own risk tolerance. The author uses data to show that stocks have much higher long-term returns than bonds, but also greater volatility.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chapter 9. When Can You Retire? 
    <div id="chapter-9-when-can-you-retire" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chapter-9-when-can-you-retire" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>There&rsquo;s more to consider than just money when it comes to retirement.</p>
<ul>
<li>The 4% rule: When your retirement savings reach 25 times your expected annual expenses, you can retire.
<ul>
<li>You can withdraw 4% of your investment assets (half bonds and half stocks) in the first year of retirement, and increase the amount withdrawn by 3% each year to keep up with inflation.</li>
<li>If you have a pension or other guaranteed income, you only need to save 25 times your &ldquo;annual excess spending&rdquo; (expected annual expenses less future guaranteed income).</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>The crossover point rule: The point at which your monthly investment income is greater than your monthly expenses, you have reached the &ldquo;crossover point&rdquo; and achieved financial freedom.
<ul>
<li>&ldquo;Crossover Assets&rdquo; = Monthly Expenses / Monthly Investment Return.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Retirement is much more than just a financial decision, it&rsquo;s a lifestyle decision. You need to think about what you want to do and how you want to live after retirement. The author uses the examples of several celebrities to illustrate the confusion and emptiness that can exist after early retirement.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chapter 10. Why You Should Invest? 
    <div id="chapter-10-why-you-should-invest" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chapter-10-why-you-should-invest" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>Three reasons to make your money grow.</p>
<ul>
<li>Save for your future self: Investing allows you to have a pool of resources to draw from as you age. Human lifespans are increasing, and the concept of &ldquo;retirement&rdquo; has emerged accordingly. To ensure quality of life after retirement, it is necessary to invest in advance.</li>
<li>Fight inflation and maintain the purchasing power of your wealth: Investing can offset the impact of inflation and maintain or increase your purchasing power. The author uses data to show that investing can effectively combat the effects of inflation.</li>
<li>Replace your human capital with financial capital: Investing can turn your diminishing human capital into financial capital that can continue to generate returns. The author illustrates this with the example of professional athletes.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chapter 11. What Should You Invest In? 
    <div id="chapter-11-what-should-you-invest-in" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chapter-11-what-should-you-invest-in" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>There is no single right way to get rich.</p>
<ul>
<li>The author lists a variety of income-producing assets, including:
<ul>
<li>Stocks: One of the most reliable ways to build wealth over the long term, easy to own and trade, with low maintenance costs, but highly volatile and valuations easily influenced by market sentiment.</li>
<li>Bonds: Low volatility, safe principal, and helpful in rebalancing portfolios, but returns are generally lower than stocks, especially in a low interest rate environment.</li>
<li>Investment real estate: Returns are higher than stocks or bonds, especially when using leverage, but require more effort to manage and are difficult to diversify.</li>
<li>Real Estate Investment Trusts (REITs): Provide access to real estate investment income without needing to manage it yourself, but are more volatile and highly correlated with stocks and other risky assets during stock market crashes.</li>
<li>Farmland: Low correlation with stocks and bonds, low volatility, inflation-resistant, but low liquidity, higher fees, and requires &ldquo;accredited investor&rdquo; status to participate.</li>
<li>Small businesses/franchises/angel investing: Potential for high returns and the more effort you put in, the greater the return, but requires a significant time commitment and has a high failure rate.</li>
<li>Royalties: Can generate stable income that is uncorrelated with traditional financial assets, but sellers incur high fees and public taste changes are unpredictable.</li>
<li>Your own products: 100% ownership, personal satisfaction and achievement, can create a valuable brand, but very labor-intensive and no guarantee of return.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>The author also contrasts the characteristics of income-producing and non-income-producing assets (e.g., gold, cryptocurrency, art, etc.) and their respective advantages and disadvantages.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chapter 12. Why You Shouldn&rsquo;t Buy Individual Stocks? 
    <div id="chapter-12-why-you-shouldnt-buy-individual-stocks" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chapter-12-why-you-shouldnt-buy-individual-stocks" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>Why underperforming the market is the least of your worries?</p>
<ul>
<li>Most people (even professionals) can&rsquo;t beat the market. Data from the SPIVA report shows that active funds tend to underperform index funds over the long term.</li>
<li>Only a very small percentage of individual stocks outperform in the long run. Bessembinder&rsquo;s research indicates that since 1926, only 4% of stocks have generated returns that exceed U.S. Treasury bonds.</li>
<li>Even stocks that outperform are not always winners. West&rsquo;s statistical analysis suggests that many companies will disappear within a decade.</li>
<li>Choosing individual stocks is emotionally draining and stressful. The author uses the example of his friend Darren investing in GameStop stock to detail the emotional rollercoaster of stock trading.</li>
<li>It&rsquo;s hard to tell if you&rsquo;re really good at picking stocks. The link between stock picking decisions and outcomes is not significant, making it difficult to assess your stock picking skills. Even if you have performed well in the past, there is no guarantee that you will continue to do so in the future.</li>
<li>The risk of holding a concentrated position in a single stock is that the return is lower than the market. The author uses data on U.S. stock performance since 1963 to show that the median return of individual stocks is lower than that of index funds.</li>
<li>The author suggests buying index funds or ETFs to earn market average returns, which can lead to higher returns and less stress during the investment process.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chapter 13. How Early Should You Start Investing? 
    <div id="chapter-13-how-early-should-you-start-investing" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chapter-13-how-early-should-you-start-investing" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>Why buying early is better than buying late?</p>
<ul>
<li>Most markets tend to go up most of the time, so investing early allows for a longer period of compounding growth.</li>
<li>The author compares two investment strategies:
<ul>
<li>Buy now: Put all the money you can invest in immediately.</li>
<li>Average in: Invest the money you can invest in batches.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Conclusion: The <strong>buy now</strong> strategy is generally better than the average-in strategy. The author uses U.S. stock market data from 1997 to 2020, as well as U.S. stock market data from 1920 to 2020, to respectively prove this conclusion. The same results hold when testing other types of assets.</li>
<li>For risk-averse investors, you can choose to invest in a lower risk portfolio. For example, change an 80% stock / 20% bond portfolio to a 60% stock / 40% bond portfolio.</li>
<li>Even if market valuations are high, the buy now strategy is still better than the average in strategy. The author compares the two strategies using CAPE percentile categories, and the results show that the buy now strategy is still superior even during periods of high valuations.</li>
<li>For investors concerned about the risk of a lump sum investment, you can take a longer time to gradually adjust to your target asset allocation.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chapter 14. Why You Shouldn&rsquo;t Wait to Buy the Dip? 
    <div id="chapter-14-why-you-shouldnt-wait-to-buy-the-dip" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chapter-14-why-you-shouldnt-wait-to-buy-the-dip" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>Even God can&rsquo;t beat dollar-cost averaging.</p>
<ul>
<li>The buy the dip strategy only works if the market is about to have a big drop and you can accurately predict when it will happen.</li>
<li>Big market drops don&rsquo;t happen that often, so the buy the dip strategy has a small chance of beating dollar-cost averaging. The author simulates the two strategies using U.S. stock market data from between 1920 and 1980. The results show that in all forty-year investment periods, the buy-the-dip strategy underperformed dollar-cost averaging more than 70% of the time.</li>
<li>Even with perfect information, the buy the dip strategy often loses to dollar-cost averaging because the market may continue to rise while you miss out on compounding growth. The author simulates the two strategies using U.S. stock market data from 1975 onward, again proving this conclusion.</li>
<li>Even if the predicted time of the market bottom is off by only two months, the long-term investment performance of the buy-the-dip strategy still loses to dollar-cost averaging.</li>
<li>Conclusion: <strong>you should invest as early as possible and as often as possible</strong>.</li>
<li>Investment returns are heavily influenced by time, and the power of strategy is far less than the power of market change.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chapter 15. Why Does Investing Involve Luck? 
    <div id="chapter-15-why-does-investing-involve-luck" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chapter-15-why-does-investing-involve-luck" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>And why you shouldn&rsquo;t care.</p>
<ul>
<li>The year you were born influences your investment returns because markets fluctuate unpredictably. The author illustrates this with data on 10-, 20-, and 30-year investment returns in the U.S. stock market since 1910.</li>
<li>The sequence of investment returns also affects your final return because you invest more money in the later stages of your investment, so later returns are more important. The author illustrates the impact of return sequence with two cases of 20-year investment horizons with the same annualized return but in reverse order.</li>
<li>How to mitigate bad luck:
<ul>
<li>Hold low-risk assets (such as bonds) for the long term to diversify risk.</li>
<li>Withdraw less money during market downturns.</li>
<li>Consider getting a part-time job to supplement your income.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chapter 16. Why You Shouldn&rsquo;t Fear Market Volatility? 
    <div id="chapter-16-why-you-shouldnt-fear-market-volatility" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chapter-16-why-you-shouldnt-fear-market-volatility" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>The price of admission for successful investing.</p>
<ul>
<li>Avoiding too many market declines can limit your upside.</li>
<li>Using the analogy of a &ldquo;market genie&rdquo; that tells you the maximum intra-year drawdown for the coming year, the author simulates different risk aversion strategies. The conclusion is that if you want to maximize long-term wealth, you should accept some degree of intra-year market decline (0% to 15%) and avoid large intra-year market declines (greater than 15%).</li>
<li>Buying a diversified portfolio of income-producing assets over the long term is one of the best ways to combat market volatility as it rears its ugly head.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chapter 17. How to Buy During a Crisis? 
    <div id="chapter-17-how-to-buy-during-a-crisis" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chapter-17-how-to-buy-during-a-crisis" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>Why you should keep your cool when the market panics?</p>
<ul>
<li>Market crashes are opportunities to buy because every dollar you invest at this point will earn a higher return after the market recovers. The author uses the 1929 U.S. stock market crash as an example to illustrate the excess returns of investing at the bottom of the market.</li>
<li>The more the market falls, the higher the return you need to make up for the loss. The author illustrates this with a simple mathematical formula and chart.</li>
<li>Even if the market takes a long time to recover, buying during a crisis is still a good decision because you can earn a decent annualized return while you wait. The author proves this conclusion using examples of the U.S. stock market falling 30% and 50% between 1920 and 2020.</li>
<li>Most stock markets trend upwards most of the time, and even if a prolonged downturn occurs, the likelihood of losing money is significantly reduced if you make regular investments as most investors do, rather than a single lump sum investment. The author illustrates this with the example of the Japanese stock market.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chapter 18. When Should You Sell? 
    <div id="chapter-18-when-should-you-sell" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chapter-18-when-should-you-sell" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>About rebalancing, concentrated positions, and the purpose of investing.</p>
<ul>
<li>Three situations where you should consider selling an investment asset:
<ul>
<li>Rebalancing your portfolio.</li>
<li>Getting rid of a concentrated (or consistently losing) investment position.</li>
<li>Meeting your financial needs.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>You should have a plan in place before you consider selling investment assets to avoid emotional decisions.</li>
<li>Selling gradually (or selling later) is generally better than selling immediately, because in the long run, the market tends to go up.</li>
<li>Regularly rebalancing your portfolio can reduce risk, but it generally reduces returns. The author simulates two strategies, annual rebalancing and never rebalancing, using a portfolio of 60% stocks/40% bonds, and compares the returns and maximum drawdowns after 30 years.</li>
<li>Accumulative rebalancing is a better way to rebalance by buying asset classes that are underweight over time to avoid incurring tax liabilities. The author uses the same portfolio to simulate a strategy of adding investments each month, demonstrating that this strategy can effectively reduce the maximum drawdown.</li>
<li>For investors holding large concentrated positions, it is advisable to sell some of the assets to reduce risk and meet their own living needs. Selling strategies can range from selling a portion on a regular basis to selling based on price levels, as long as it is decided in advance.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chapter 19. Where Should Your Investments Be Held? 
    <div id="chapter-19-where-should-your-investments-be-held" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chapter-19-where-should-your-investments-be-held" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>On taxes, traditional 401(k) vs. Roth 401(k), and why you might not want to maximize your 401(k).</p>
<ul>
<li>Tax policy in the United States is constantly changing, and financial management should also be adjusted according to tax policy. The author reviews the history of income tax in the United States to illustrate this point.</li>
<li>When choosing between a traditional 401(k) and a Roth 401(k), the most important factor is whether your effective income tax rate is higher now (during your working years) or later (in retirement).</li>
<li>The author favors traditional 401(k)s because they offer more flexibility and allow you to convert funds to a Roth IRA when tax rates are lower, such as when you are in business school or on maternity leave.</li>
<li>Roth 401(k)s may be a better option for high savers because they can enjoy greater total tax deferral benefits. The author illustrates this with the example of Sally and Sam.</li>
<li>Using a retirement savings account to invest can avoid capital gains taxes, which can lead to significant long-term gains. The author uses simulated data to compare the returns of three approaches: tax-free accounts, accounts taxed once on capital gains, and accounts taxed annually on capital gains. The author also explains the impact of compounding on investment returns.</li>
<li>Maximizing your 401(k) may not be the best option because 401(k) plan fees may offset the tax benefits. The author suggests that you should at least increase your personal contributions to the point where you can receive the maximum employer match. For any contributions beyond that, you need to take into account the 401(k)&rsquo;s expense ratio and your own need for liquidity.</li>
<li>When allocating assets, it is advisable to place high-growth assets (e.g. stocks) in tax-advantaged accounts and low-growth assets (e.g. bonds) in taxable accounts.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chapter 20. Why Will You Never Feel Rich? 
    <div id="chapter-20-why-will-you-never-feel-rich" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chapter-20-why-will-you-never-feel-rich" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>You might already be rich, so why not?</p>
<ul>
<li>People can always find someone richer than themselves, so it&rsquo;s hard to feel content. The author illustrates people&rsquo;s sense of relative wealth by telling the story of Powerball lottery winner Jack Whittaker, and the story of his friend John.</li>
<li>If you compare yourself to people around the world, you may find that you are much richer than you think. For example, if your net worth is over $4,210, you are wealthier than half the world; if your net worth is over $93,170, you are in the top 10% of the world&rsquo;s wealth.</li>
<li>Don&rsquo;t let feelings of relative wealth affect your happiness and appreciate the wealth you have.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chapter 21. The Most Important Asset 
    <div id="chapter-21-the-most-important-asset" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chapter-21-the-most-important-asset" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>Why you can never get more of this asset.</p>
<ul>
<li>Time is your most important asset, and how you use your time will have a huge impact on your future life. The author tells the story of Dashrath Manjhi, an Indian villager who carved a road through a mountain, to illustrate the power of time.</li>
<li>In your younger years, you should prioritize career development because that&rsquo;s when your income grows the fastest. The author uses his own experience to illustrate the importance of making the right career choices early on.</li>
<li>Don&rsquo;t sacrifice your time in pursuit of money, because you can never buy more time with money.</li>
<li>People&rsquo;s happiness tends to follow a U-shaped curve as they age, overestimating their future happiness in their youth, being more pessimistic in middle age, and feeling pleasantly surprised in old age.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Conclusion. The Just Keep Buying Rules 
    <div id="conclusion-the-just-keep-buying-rules" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#conclusion-the-just-keep-buying-rules" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>How to win the time traveler&rsquo;s game?</p>
<ul>
<li>The author summarizes 21 financial guidelines to help you succeed on your financial journey, these guidelines are called the &ldquo;Just Keep Buying Rules&rdquo;:
<ol>
<li>The poor should focus on saving, and the rich should focus on investing.</li>
<li>Save what you can save.</li>
<li>Focus on income, not expenses.</li>
<li>Use the &ldquo;2x rule&rdquo; to eliminate spending guilt.</li>
<li>Save at least 50% of your future raises and bonuses.</li>
<li>Debt is not necessarily a good thing or a bad thing, it depends on how you use it.</li>
<li>Only buy a house when the timing is right.</li>
<li>Use cash when saving for large purchases.</li>
<li>There&rsquo;s more to retirement than just money.</li>
<li>Invest to accumulate financial capital to replace your diminishing human capital.</li>
<li>Think like an owner and buy income-producing assets.</li>
<li>Don&rsquo;t buy individual stocks.</li>
<li>Buy fast, sell slow.</li>
<li>Invest as early and as often as possible.</li>
<li>Investing is not just about the cards you have, it&rsquo;s also about how you play them.</li>
<li>Don&rsquo;t be afraid when volatility inevitably comes.</li>
<li>Market crashes are usually opportunities to buy.</li>
<li>Use your money for the life you need before risking it for the life you want.</li>
<li>Think twice before maximizing your 401(k).</li>
<li>You&rsquo;ll never feel rich, and that&rsquo;s okay.</li>
<li>Time is your most important asset.</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">III. Quotes 
    <div id="iii-quotes" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii-quotes" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>The surest way to get rich is to increase your income and invest in income-producing assets.</p></blockquote>
<p>Analysis: Instead of blindly pursuing saving, it is better to focus your energy on increasing your income and investing in assets that can generate income; this is a more reliable path to financial freedom.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The only right way to spend money is the way that works for you.</p></blockquote>
<p>Analysis: Everyone&rsquo;s values, life goals, and preferences are different, so their financial management style should also be personalized. Don&rsquo;t blindly follow the crowd; find a spending pattern that suits you in order to achieve true happiness.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Time is your most important asset.</p></blockquote>
<p>Analysis: Time is a non-renewable resource. We should cherish time and spend it on the most valuable things. Investing early is not only about accumulating wealth, but also about buying back more time and freedom.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">IV. Guiding Significance 
    <div id="iv-guiding-significance" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv-guiding-significance" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<ul>
<li><strong>Establishing the right financial mindset:</strong> This book helps us understand the essence of personal finance and how to develop a sound savings and investment plan, avoiding common financial pitfalls.</li>
<li><strong>Enhancing personal competitiveness:</strong> The book emphasizes the importance of increasing income and encourages us to continuously learn and improve our personal skills to gain greater career development space.</li>
<li><strong>Balancing life and wealth:</strong> The author reminds us that wealth is not the only goal in life. We should focus on the quality of life and the realization of personal values while pursuing wealth.</li>
<li><strong>Viewing investment rationally:</strong> This book emphasizes the importance of long-term investing and warns investors not to blindly chase short-term gains or be intimidated by market volatility. Only rationality and patience can ultimately lead to success.</li>
</ul>

  



<div
  
    class="flex px-4 py-3 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900"
  >

  <span
    
      class="text-primary-400 ltr:pr-3 rtl:pl-3 flex items-center"
    >

    

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 640 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M172.5 131.1C228.1 75.51 320.5 75.51 376.1 131.1C426.1 181.1 433.5 260.8 392.4 318.3L391.3 319.9C381 334.2 361 337.6 346.7 327.3C332.3 317 328.9 297 339.2 282.7L340.3 281.1C363.2 249 359.6 205.1 331.7 177.2C300.3 145.8 249.2 145.8 217.7 177.2L105.5 289.5C73.99 320.1 73.99 372 105.5 403.5C133.3 431.4 177.3 435 209.3 412.1L210.9 410.1C225.3 400.7 245.3 404 255.5 418.4C265.8 432.8 262.5 452.8 248.1 463.1L246.5 464.2C188.1 505.3 110.2 498.7 60.21 448.8C3.741 392.3 3.741 300.7 60.21 244.3L172.5 131.1zM467.5 380C411 436.5 319.5 436.5 263 380C213 330 206.5 251.2 247.6 193.7L248.7 192.1C258.1 177.8 278.1 174.4 293.3 184.7C307.7 194.1 311.1 214.1 300.8 229.3L299.7 230.9C276.8 262.1 280.4 306.9 308.3 334.8C339.7 366.2 390.8 366.2 422.3 334.8L534.5 222.5C566 191 566 139.1 534.5 108.5C506.7 80.63 462.7 76.99 430.7 99.9L429.1 101C414.7 111.3 394.7 107.1 384.5 93.58C374.2 79.2 377.5 59.21 391.9 48.94L393.5 47.82C451 6.731 529.8 13.25 579.8 63.24C636.3 119.7 636.3 211.3 579.8 267.7L467.5 380z"/></svg>

  </span>


  </span>

  <span
    
      class="dark:text-neutral-300"
    ><strong>Further Reading</strong>: Check out the author, <strong>Nick Maggiulli</strong>&rsquo;s blog: <a href="https://ofdollarsanddata.com/" target="_blank"><strong>Of Dollars And Data</strong></a></span>
</div>

<hr>

<section class="space-y-10 w-full">
    
    
        
            






















  <a class="flex flex-wrap article " href="/en/posts/1728295490690-book-list/">
    
        
        <div class="w-full md:w-auto h-full thumbnail nozoom thumbnailshadow md:mr-7" style="background-image:url(/posts/1728295490690-book-list/featured_hu_a14921d8ab66af4e.jpg);"></div>
        
      <div class=" mt-3 md:mt-0">
      <div class="items-center text-left text-xl font-semibold">
        
        <div class="font-bold text-xl text-neutral-800 decoration-primary-500 hover:underline hover:underline-offset-2 dark:text-neutral"
          href="/en/posts/1728295490690-book-list/">Recommended Reading List</div>
        
        
        
      </div>
      <div class="text-sm text-neutral-500 dark:text-neutral-400">
        











  



















<div class="flex flex-row flex-wrap items-center">
  
  
  <time datetime="2024-10-01T00:00:00&#43;00:00">1 October 2024</time>
  

  
  
</div>





<div class="flex flex-row flex-wrap items-center">
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  <span style="margin-top:0.5rem" class="mr-2" onclick="window.open(&#34;/en/tags/recommended/&#34;,'_self');">
    <span class="flex" style="cursor: pointer;">
  <span class="rounded-md border border-primary-400 px-1 py-[1px] text-xs font-normal text-primary-700 dark:border-primary-600 dark:text-primary-400">
    Recommended
  </span>
</span>
  </span>
  
  <span style="margin-top:0.5rem" class="mr-2" onclick="window.open(&#34;/en/tags/book/&#34;,'_self');">
    <span class="flex" style="cursor: pointer;">
  <span class="rounded-md border border-primary-400 px-1 py-[1px] text-xs font-normal text-primary-700 dark:border-primary-600 dark:text-primary-400">
    Book
  </span>
</span>
  </span>
  
  
  
  
</div>




      </div>
      
    </div>
  </a>

        
    
</section>
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Early Retirement Extreme: Book Notes</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1728390192272/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1728390192272/</guid><description>This book offers an unconventional philosophical and practical guide to financial independence and early retirement, encouraging readers to break free from the traditional &amp;#39;work-consume&amp;#39; cycle. By cultivating diverse skills, reducing consumption, and investing wisely, readers can achieve financial independence within a few years and live a more free and balanced life. The book also delves into how &amp;#39;the system&amp;#39; influences individual decisions and how to escape its constraints.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[

<h2 class="relative group">I. Summary 
    <div id="i-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This book&rsquo;s core is to guide readers in constructing a mindset of financial independence and encourage them to challenge and break free from the constraints of societal &ldquo;systems.&rdquo; The author argues that modern society, through education, careers, consumerism, and other means, &ldquo;locks&rdquo; people into a preset track, making them work and consume continuously to maintain the system&rsquo;s operation. This book encourages readers to break this cycle by cultivating diverse skills, reducing dependence on a single income and material possessions, and ultimately achieving financial independence and early retirement to pursue a more meaningful life.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">II. Chapter Summaries 
    <div id="ii-chapter-summaries" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii-chapter-summaries" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<ul>
<li><strong>About the Book:</strong> Explains the purpose and core ideas, emphasizing that it&rsquo;s a philosophical book about strategy, aiming to help readers build a framework for financial independence.</li>
<li><strong>A Different Thinking Framework:</strong> Challenges the traditional &ldquo;work-consume&rdquo; model and society&rsquo;s pursuit of material possessions, status, and happiness. It encourages readers to think like a &ldquo;Renaissance person&rdquo; by developing diverse skills and points out the challenges of implementing change.</li>
<li><strong>Locked In:</strong> Delves into how modern people are &ldquo;locked in&rdquo; by consumerism, social norms, and &ldquo;the system.&rdquo; It analyzes how &ldquo;the system,&rdquo; through education, careers, advertising, media, etc., influences individual decisions, limits choices, and creates dependencies.  The book encourages readers to break free from the limitations of &ldquo;the system&rdquo; and re-examine their lifestyles and values. (Example: The allegory of Plato&rsquo;s Cave, illustrating how people are trapped in limited cognition and experience, mistaking shadows for reality).</li>
<li><strong>Degrees of Economic Freedom:</strong> Introduces four economic states: Salaryman, Wage Earner, Businessman, and Renaissance Person. It analyzes their financial characteristics, strengths, weaknesses, and interactions with &ldquo;the system.&rdquo;  The concepts of financial coupling and job dependence are emphasized.</li>
<li><strong>The Renaissance Ideal:</strong> Explains the versatility and independence of the &ldquo;Renaissance person&rdquo; and contrasts it with the modern &ldquo;system&rsquo;s&rdquo; emphasis on specialization.
<ul>
<li><strong>Human Capital and Necessary Personal Assets:</strong> Details the specific meanings and goals of seven areas of competence, emphasizing how these competencies help individuals break free from dependence on &ldquo;the system.&rdquo;</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Strategies, Tactics, and Guiding Principles:</strong> Provides strategic and tactical guidance for achieving financial independence.</li>
<li><strong>Tactical Principles:</strong> Offers more specific action guidelines, such as how to identify needs and wants, how to build a modular lifestyle, and how to maximize the use of existing resources.</li>
<li><strong>Economic and Financial Foundations:</strong> Explains the cash flow cycle and how to make money work for you instead of working for money through saving and investing.</li>
<li><strong>Financial Independence and Investing:</strong> Discusses important financial ratios and investment strategies, emphasizing the importance of understanding investment principles and risk management.  (Formulas: N=log[(1)/(1- (Po)/(p)(i)/(1+i))]/log(1+i) and P = (1+0.03/12)/(0.03/12) p = 401 р)</li>
<li><strong>The Renaissance Lifestyle:</strong>  Explores how to implement the Renaissance ideal in aspects such as food, clothing, shelter, transportation, health, relationships, etc., contrasting it with the modern consumerist lifestyle. Emphasizes how reducing dependence on products and services provided by &ldquo;the system&rdquo; can lower living costs and improve quality of life. (Examples: how to replace car ownership with walking, cycling, or other methods, how to repair and maintain items oneself, and how to reduce expenses through socializing and sharing resources).</li>
<li><strong>Conclusion:</strong>  Summarizes the core ideas and encourages readers to break free from the constraints of &ldquo;the system&rdquo; to live more free and autonomous lives.</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">III. Key Quotes 
    <div id="iii-key-quotes" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii-key-quotes" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>Independence is not something you have; it&rsquo;s something you are.</p></blockquote>
<p>Insight:  Independence is a way of thinking and behaving, not a state of being.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>You cannot solve a problem with the same mindset that created it.</p></blockquote>
<p>Insight: Achieving financial independence requires a shift from a consumerist mindset to a creative problem-solving approach.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Be the change that you wish to see in the world.</p></blockquote>
<p>Insight: Instead of complaining about the system, change yourself and your actions, and influence others by example.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The best prison has invisible bars.</p></blockquote>
<p>Insight: Modern society subtly confines us through social norms, consumerism, and the education system, making us unconsciously comply.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">IV.  Guidance 
    <div id="iv--guidance" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv--guidance" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This book provides a perspective that goes beyond traditional financial advice, helping readers re-examine their lifestyles, values, and relationship with societal &ldquo;systems.&rdquo; It encourages readers to achieve financial independence and early retirement through:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Critical thinking:</strong> Question social norms and consumerism to avoid being manipulated by &ldquo;the system.&rdquo;</li>
<li><strong>Developing diverse skills:</strong> Increase self-worth and competitiveness, and reduce dependence on a single income source.</li>
<li><strong>Smart consumption:</strong> Avoid unnecessary expenses and allocate resources to more valuable areas.</li>
<li><strong>Long-term planning and investing:</strong> Prepare for the future and make money work for you.</li>
<li><strong>Building a resilient lifestyle:</strong> Reduce dependence on the external environment and &ldquo;the system&rdquo; and increase the ability to adapt to change.</li>
<li><strong>Pursuing personal growth and self-realization:</strong> Live a more meaningful, autonomous, and free life.</li>
</ul>
<p>In conclusion, this book encourages readers to undertake a profound self-reflection and lifestyle transformation to ultimately break free from the constraints of &ldquo;the system&rdquo; and achieve financial independence and true freedom.
<br/>

  



<div
  
    class="flex px-4 py-3 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900"
  >

  <span
    
      class="text-primary-400 ltr:pr-3 rtl:pl-3 flex items-center"
    >

    

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512">
<path fill="currentColor" d="M288 32c0-17.7-14.3-32-32-32s-32 14.3-32 32V274.7l-73.4-73.4c-12.5-12.5-32.8-12.5-45.3 0s-12.5 32.8 0 45.3l128 128c12.5 12.5 32.8 12.5 45.3 0l128-128c12.5-12.5 12.5-32.8 0-45.3s-32.8-12.5-45.3 0L288 274.7V32zM64 352c-35.3 0-64 28.7-64 64v32c0 35.3 28.7 64 64 64H448c35.3 0 64-28.7 64-64V416c0-35.3-28.7-64-64-64H346.5l-45.3 45.3c-25 25-65.5 25-90.5 0L165.5 352H64zM432 456c-13.3 0-24-10.7-24-24s10.7-24 24-24s24 10.7 24 24s-10.7 24-24 24z"/></svg>
  </span>


  </span>

  <span
    
      class="dark:text-neutral-300"
    ><strong>Download:</strong> <a href="https://github.com/TianmingLi/early_retirement_extreme_cn/blob/main/src/earlyretirementextreme.pdf" target="_blank">Early Retirement Extreme</a></span>
</div>

<br/>
<a id="github-ca5909c42993317bda43c57784488179" target="_blank" href="https://github.com/TianmingLi/early_retirement_extreme_cn" class="cursor-pointer">
  <div
    class="w-full md:w-auto pt-3 p-5 border border-neutral-200 dark:border-neutral-700 border rounded-md shadow-2xl">

    <div class="flex items-center">
      <span class="text-2xl text-neutral-800 dark:text-neutral" style="margin-right:10px;">
        

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 496 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M165.9 397.4c0 2-2.3 3.6-5.2 3.6-3.3.3-5.6-1.3-5.6-3.6 0-2 2.3-3.6 5.2-3.6 3-.3 5.6 1.3 5.6 3.6zm-31.1-4.5c-.7 2 1.3 4.3 4.3 4.9 2.6 1 5.6 0 6.2-2s-1.3-4.3-4.3-5.2c-2.6-.7-5.5.3-6.2 2.3zm44.2-1.7c-2.9.7-4.9 2.6-4.6 4.9.3 2 2.9 3.3 5.9 2.6 2.9-.7 4.9-2.6 4.6-4.6-.3-1.9-3-3.2-5.9-2.9zM244.8 8C106.1 8 0 113.3 0 252c0 110.9 69.8 205.8 169.5 239.2 12.8 2.3 17.3-5.6 17.3-12.1 0-6.2-.3-40.4-.3-61.4 0 0-70 15-84.7-29.8 0 0-11.4-29.1-27.8-36.6 0 0-22.9-15.7 1.6-15.4 0 0 24.9 2 38.6 25.8 21.9 38.6 58.6 27.5 72.9 20.9 2.3-16 8.8-27.1 16-33.7-55.9-6.2-112.3-14.3-112.3-110.5 0-27.5 7.6-41.3 23.6-58.9-2.6-6.5-11.1-33.3 2.6-67.9 20.9-6.5 69 27 69 27 20-5.6 41.5-8.5 62.8-8.5s42.8 2.9 62.8 8.5c0 0 48.1-33.6 69-27 13.7 34.7 5.2 61.4 2.6 67.9 16 17.7 25.8 31.5 25.8 58.9 0 96.5-58.9 104.2-114.8 110.5 9.2 7.9 17 22.9 17 46.4 0 33.7-.3 75.4-.3 83.6 0 6.5 4.6 14.4 17.3 12.1C428.2 457.8 496 362.9 496 252 496 113.3 383.5 8 244.8 8zM97.2 352.9c-1.3 1-1 3.3.7 5.2 1.6 1.6 3.9 2.3 5.2 1 1.3-1 1-3.3-.7-5.2-1.6-1.6-3.9-2.3-5.2-1zm-10.8-8.1c-.7 1.3.3 2.9 2.3 3.9 1.6 1 3.6.7 4.3-.7.7-1.3-.3-2.9-2.3-3.9-2-.6-3.6-.3-4.3.7zm32.4 35.6c-1.6 1.3-1 4.3 1.3 6.2 2.3 2.3 5.2 2.6 6.5 1 1.3-1.3.7-4.3-1.3-6.2-2.2-2.3-5.2-2.6-6.5-1zm-11.4-14.7c-1.6 1-1.6 3.6 0 5.9 1.6 2.3 4.3 3.3 5.6 2.3 1.6-1.3 1.6-3.9 0-6.2-1.4-2.3-4-3.3-5.6-2z"/></svg>

  </span>


      </span>
      <div
        id="github-ca5909c42993317bda43c57784488179-full_name"
        class="m-0 font-bold text-xl text-neutral-800 decoration-primary-500 hover:underline hover:underline-offset-2 dark:text-neutral">
        TianmingLi/early_retirement_extreme_cn
      </div>
    </div>

    <p id="github-ca5909c42993317bda43c57784488179-description" class="m-0 mt-2 text-md text-neutral-800 dark:text-neutral">
      Early Retirement Extreme 中文翻译 Renaissance &amp; Liberty
    </p>

    <div class="m-0 mt-2 flex items-center">

      <span class="mr-1 inline-block h-3 w-3 rounded-full"
        style="background-color: #e34c26"></span>
      <div class="m-0 mr-5 text-md text-neutral-800 dark:text-neutral">
         HTML 
      </div>

      <span class="text-md mr-1 text-neutral-800 dark:text-neutral">
        

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 576 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M287.9 0C297.1 0 305.5 5.25 309.5 13.52L378.1 154.8L531.4 177.5C540.4 178.8 547.8 185.1 550.7 193.7C553.5 202.4 551.2 211.9 544.8 218.2L433.6 328.4L459.9 483.9C461.4 492.9 457.7 502.1 450.2 507.4C442.8 512.7 432.1 513.4 424.9 509.1L287.9 435.9L150.1 509.1C142.9 513.4 133.1 512.7 125.6 507.4C118.2 502.1 114.5 492.9 115.1 483.9L142.2 328.4L31.11 218.2C24.65 211.9 22.36 202.4 25.2 193.7C28.03 185.1 35.5 178.8 44.49 177.5L197.7 154.8L266.3 13.52C270.4 5.249 278.7 0 287.9 0L287.9 0zM287.9 78.95L235.4 187.2C231.9 194.3 225.1 199.3 217.3 200.5L98.98 217.9L184.9 303C190.4 308.5 192.9 316.4 191.6 324.1L171.4 443.7L276.6 387.5C283.7 383.7 292.2 383.7 299.2 387.5L404.4 443.7L384.2 324.1C382.9 316.4 385.5 308.5 391 303L476.9 217.9L358.6 200.5C350.7 199.3 343.9 194.3 340.5 187.2L287.9 78.95z"/></svg>
  </span>


      </span>
      <div id="github-ca5909c42993317bda43c57784488179-stargazers" class="m-0 mr-5 text-md text-neutral-800 dark:text-neutral">
        185
      </div>

      <span class="text-md mr-1 text-neutral-800 dark:text-neutral">
        

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 448 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M80 104c13.3 0 24-10.7 24-24s-10.7-24-24-24S56 66.7 56 80s10.7 24 24 24zm80-24c0 32.8-19.7 61-48 73.3V192c0 17.7 14.3 32 32 32H304c17.7 0 32-14.3 32-32V153.3C307.7 141 288 112.8 288 80c0-44.2 35.8-80 80-80s80 35.8 80 80c0 32.8-19.7 61-48 73.3V192c0 53-43 96-96 96H256v70.7c28.3 12.3 48 40.5 48 73.3c0 44.2-35.8 80-80 80s-80-35.8-80-80c0-32.8 19.7-61 48-73.3V288H144c-53 0-96-43-96-96V153.3C19.7 141 0 112.8 0 80C0 35.8 35.8 0 80 0s80 35.8 80 80zm208 24c13.3 0 24-10.7 24-24s-10.7-24-24-24s-24 10.7-24 24s10.7 24 24 24zM248 432c0-13.3-10.7-24-24-24s-24 10.7-24 24s10.7 24 24 24s24-10.7 24-24z"/></svg>
  </span>


      </span>
      <div id="github-ca5909c42993317bda43c57784488179-forks" class="m-0 mr-5 text-md text-neutral-800 dark:text-neutral">
        41
      </div>

    </div>

  </div>
  <script>
    fetch("https://api.github.com/repos/TianmingLi/early_retirement_extreme_cn", {
      headers: new Headers({
        'User-agent': 'Mozilla/4.0 Custom User Agent'
      })
    })
      .then(response => response.json())
      .then(data => {
        document.getElementById('github-ca5909c42993317bda43c57784488179-full_name').innerHTML = data.full_name;
        document.getElementById('github-ca5909c42993317bda43c57784488179-description').innerHTML = data.description;
        document.getElementById('github-ca5909c42993317bda43c57784488179-stargazers').innerHTML = data.stargazers_count;
        document.getElementById('github-ca5909c42993317bda43c57784488179-forks').innerHTML = data.forks;
      })
      .catch(error => console.error(error))
  </script>
</a></p>
<hr>

<section class="space-y-10 w-full">
    
    
        
            






















  <a class="flex flex-wrap article " href="/en/posts/1728295490690-book-list/">
    
        
        <div class="w-full md:w-auto h-full thumbnail nozoom thumbnailshadow md:mr-7" style="background-image:url(/posts/1728295490690-book-list/featured_hu_a14921d8ab66af4e.jpg);"></div>
        
      <div class=" mt-3 md:mt-0">
      <div class="items-center text-left text-xl font-semibold">
        
        <div class="font-bold text-xl text-neutral-800 decoration-primary-500 hover:underline hover:underline-offset-2 dark:text-neutral"
          href="/en/posts/1728295490690-book-list/">Recommended Reading List</div>
        
        
        
      </div>
      <div class="text-sm text-neutral-500 dark:text-neutral-400">
        











  



















<div class="flex flex-row flex-wrap items-center">
  
  
  <time datetime="2024-10-01T00:00:00&#43;00:00">1 October 2024</time>
  

  
  
</div>





<div class="flex flex-row flex-wrap items-center">
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  <span style="margin-top:0.5rem" class="mr-2" onclick="window.open(&#34;/en/tags/recommended/&#34;,'_self');">
    <span class="flex" style="cursor: pointer;">
  <span class="rounded-md border border-primary-400 px-1 py-[1px] text-xs font-normal text-primary-700 dark:border-primary-600 dark:text-primary-400">
    Recommended
  </span>
</span>
  </span>
  
  <span style="margin-top:0.5rem" class="mr-2" onclick="window.open(&#34;/en/tags/book/&#34;,'_self');">
    <span class="flex" style="cursor: pointer;">
  <span class="rounded-md border border-primary-400 px-1 py-[1px] text-xs font-normal text-primary-700 dark:border-primary-600 dark:text-primary-400">
    Book
  </span>
</span>
  </span>
  
  
  
  
</div>




      </div>
      
    </div>
  </a>

        
    
</section>
]]></content:encoded></item></channel></rss>