<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Leverage on QQQ Investor</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/tags/leverage/</link><description>Recent content in Leverage on QQQ Investor</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jomonylw.github.io/en/tags/leverage/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>00530 Believers Believe, Non-Believers Lose! Still Dreaming of Getting Rich with VT?</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1757255899816/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1757255899816/</guid><description>This session&amp;#39;s core sharing focuses on shifting from a labor mindset to a rich mindset, learning how to leverage financial operations to consume with hundreds of times more assets than one&amp;#39;s own small capital, achieving continuous asset growth without selling. Teacher James elaborates on the importance of focusing on investing in the Nasdaq 100 index and refutes the drawbacks of other investment methods and financial products. The Q&amp;amp;A session delves into practical operational issues such as asset allocation, stock-backed loans, insurance, and cross-border asset management.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<lite-youtube videoid="msB-AwYaU7A" playlabel="msB-AwYaU7A" params=""></lite-youtube>



<h2 class="relative group">I. Current Topic 
    <div id="i-current-topic" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-current-topic" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>The core theme of this session is to <strong>break free from a labor mindset and establish a rich mindset</strong>. Traditional wisdom suggests that one needs to work hard, save money, and invest to get rich, while the core of a rich mindset is understanding how to utilize financial leverage. Teacher James illustrates with specific examples how a small principal (e.g., $30,000) can be used to spend far more than the principal (e.g., $1,000,000) through long-term low-interest borrowing (such as stock-backed loans), while the principal itself compounds in the market over the long term, with its future value sufficient to cover all debts. This financial operation of &ldquo;borrowing to spend, never selling assets&rdquo; is where the real big money is, far superior to the &ldquo;peanuts&rdquo; earned from stock picking and short-term trading.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">II. Briefing Content 
    <div id="ii-briefing-content" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii-briefing-content" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Core Principles and Mindset of Investing 
    <div id="core-principles-and-mindset-of-investing" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#core-principles-and-mindset-of-investing" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Focus on one, eliminate distractions</strong>: The only investment target is the Nasdaq 100 index fund (e.g., QQQ). Ignore market fluctuations, financial news, analyst opinions, financial reports, and any other recommended ETFs (such as VT, SPY, VTI, and various 0098x and other &ldquo;demonic&rdquo; codes in Taiwan). The teacher guarantees with 40+ years of investment experience that if there were a better target, he would have recommended it long ago.</li>
<li><strong>Trust in predecessors&rsquo; experience, avoid self-trial and error</strong>: Beginners should first accept the warning &ldquo;don&rsquo;t touch fire,&rdquo; meaning don&rsquo;t touch investment targets not recommended by the teacher. Asking questions won&rsquo;t teach you anything; you should calmly watch hundreds of videos first, and then the questions you have will be genuine. Learning from the wisdom and experience of predecessors (e.g., reading classics like &ldquo;Tao Te Ching,&rdquo; &ldquo;The Bible&rdquo;) can help avoid detours, which is the cheapest way to learn in life.</li>
<li><strong>Be highly vigilant of the financial system</strong>: You&rsquo;re alert when you receive a scam call, but you completely trust what financial advisors and insurance agents tell you, and that&rsquo;s the scariest scam. View the <strong>financial industry, insurance industry, and government</strong> as a united potential &ldquo;scam group,&rdquo; and be vigilant about any products they recommend.</li>
<li><strong>Advice for newcomers</strong>: New friends can start by watching video <strong>00451</strong> on our YouTube channel to build a basic understanding.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Asset Allocation and Account Management 
    <div id="asset-allocation-and-account-management" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#asset-allocation-and-account-management" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Asset Consolidation</strong>: All funds and individual stocks should be converted into an asset allocation based on QQQ.</li>
<li><strong>Account Configuration Recommendations for US Investors</strong>:
<ul>
<li><strong>Leveraged Funds (QLD, TQQQ)</strong>: Should be 99.99% placed in tax-advantaged retirement accounts (e.g., Roth IRA).</li>
<li><strong>Cash</strong>: Can be placed in any account, but for different purposes.
<ul>
<li><strong>Cash in Roth accounts</strong>: Used for &ldquo;smart rebalancing.&rdquo;</li>
<li><strong>Cash in Stock-Backed Loan Accounts (Pledge Account)</strong>: Used to reduce account volatility and prevent margin calls.</li>
<li><strong>Cash in Taxable Accounts or Traditional IRA</strong>: Used to slow down the appreciation rate of that account, which helps with tax planning.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Warning for Non-US Residents</strong>:
<ul>
<li><strong>Do not open accounts with US brokers</strong>: Non-US tax residents will face up to 40% estate tax on assets in the US, and accounts may be frozen at any time. The process for descendants to handle inheritance is extremely cumbersome and complex, and lawyer fees may deplete most of the assets.</li>
<li><strong>Keep money close</strong>: Assets should remain in your country of residence. If you live in Taiwan, keep your money in Taiwan; if you live in Hong Kong, keep your money in Hong Kong.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Importance of Financial Education</strong>: Educating children about finance is more important than academic performance. Children can have poor grades, they can be lazy, but they cannot be ignorant of financial management. In a capitalist society, knowing how to grow assets is more crucial than having a high degree but being a &ldquo;pauper.&rdquo; Cultivate independent thinking and judgment.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Breaking Free from a Labor Mindset, Establishing a Rich Mindset 
    <div id="breaking-free-from-a-labor-mindset-establishing-a-rich-mindset" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#breaking-free-from-a-labor-mindset-establishing-a-rich-mindset" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Misconceptions of traditional labor mindset</strong>: Believing that one must work hard, save diligently, and invest diligently to have money to spend. This is a passive and inefficient mindset that prevents an easy life.</li>
<li><strong>Core of Rich Mindset – Financial Operations</strong>:
<ul>
<li><strong>The Art of Borrowing</strong>: The core of borrowing is not to consider the interest rate first, but that the <strong>loan term should be as long as possible</strong>. If a loan can be repaid principal and interest in 40 years, even if the interest rate is as high as 8%, it&rsquo;s worth borrowing because inflation and asset appreciation will far exceed the interest cost.</li>
<li><strong>Leveraging Small Capital for Large Assets</strong>:
<ul>
<li><strong>Example</strong>: You currently have $30,000. At an annualized return of 15%, it will grow to nearly $7,000,000 in 40 years. Based on this enormous future asset, you now have the ability to borrow $1,000,000 to spend, as long as this loan is long-term, or even never requires principal repayment (like a stock-backed loan). Your asset growth rate will exceed your debt growth rate.</li>
<li><strong>Conclusion</strong>: Don&rsquo;t spend your $30,000; let it snowball. The money you spend is borrowed. This is the essence of financial operations, which involves tens of millions or hundreds of millions of dollars.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Stop Focusing on Small Money</strong>: Don&rsquo;t dwell on stock picking, short-term trading, and other behaviors aimed at earning price differences. These are insignificant like sesame seeds compared to the grand scope of financial operations.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">III. Q&amp;A Session 
    <div id="iii-qa-session" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii-qa-session" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Washington 
    <div id="washington" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#washington" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question 1: Regarding workplace salary, I asked my boss for a $20,000 raise and a $50,000 bonus. My boss agreed to the raise but refused the bonus, which I accepted. I felt that the long-term nature of salary was more important than a one-time bonus. I&rsquo;d like to ask for Teacher James&rsquo;s opinion.
<ul>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo;s Reply: Your decision was absolutely correct. Supervisors are usually willing to give raises because the money belongs to the company, not them personally. A fixed salary increase is permanent, while a bonus is one-time and can be canceled by the company at any time. This aligns with our philosophy of long-term investing, which seeks stable and continuous growth (15% annually) rather than short-term spikes (a single day&rsquo;s surge). You&rsquo;ve grasped the key point.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Li 
    <div id="li" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#li" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Share 1: I only discovered the teacher&rsquo;s channel in late August and felt like I&rsquo;d struck gold. Within a week, I invested all my funds into the market and plan to invest the money from cashing out my endowment insurance.
<ul>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo;s Comment: Excellent.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Share 2: I shared the teacher&rsquo;s philosophy with a beauty industry group I founded, hoping my peers could also benefit, as many in our industry receive advance payments from clients, which serves as excellent interest-free cash flow for investment. However, some people left the group as soon as they heard about investing, which made me feel frustrated and regretful.
<ul>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo;s Comment: This is a very typical reaction. Topics like investing and politics should not be shared casually in non-homogeneous groups. Every group has its inherent attributes, and abruptly introducing unrelated topics, like discussing politics in a group, will inevitably cause a &ldquo;commotion.&rdquo; You must anticipate such a reaction. Also, a reminder: for advance payments received by businesses, you need to reserve sufficient working capital for operations and not over-invest.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 1: A client of mine, almost 50 years old, thinks this investment method is too slow and that one doesn&rsquo;t have many 40-year periods in life. I&rsquo;d like to hear the teacher&rsquo;s insights. Also, should the funds from my surrendered endowment insurance all be invested in 00865B (Taiwanese short-term government bond ETF) as cash, or do I need to keep some in a savings account at the bank?
<ul>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo;s Reply: Regarding your client&rsquo;s question, this is a difference in mindset. For fund allocation, cash does not need to be kept in the bank. 00865B has excellent liquidity; if you sell today, the money arrives the day after tomorrow, so it can be used entirely as cash. For daily expenses, try to use credit cards, and then sell 00865B once to repay the bill. Your subsequent income can be vaguely and randomly invested into 00662, 00670L, and 00865B, no need to be overly precise, for example, rotating among the three every four months.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Lilian 
    <div id="lilian" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#lilian" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question 1: I&rsquo;m 53. Due to government housing policies, I&rsquo;m considering selling my self-occupied home in Taoyuan at a low price and renting instead, which would give me about 5 million in cash. Should I use this money to pay off my car loan and personal loan first, and then invest the remaining money using a 70/30 or 60/13/30 strategy? Also, I pay a lot for insurance every month, and some policies are nearing their maturity. What should I do?
<ul>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo;s Reply: You can sell the house and invest the money. But <strong>absolutely do not use the money from selling the house to pay off any loans</strong>. Borrowed money is &ldquo;someone else&rsquo;s chicken&rdquo;; let it lay eggs. Your own money is &ldquo;your own chicken&rdquo;; let it lay eggs too. Use your future salary from re-entering the workforce to make monthly installment payments. For insurance, <strong>immediately, right now, surrender all of it</strong>; take back whatever you can. As long as you stop paying, you win, and you&rsquo;ll have tens of millions more in the future.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Tina 
    <div id="tina" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#tina" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question 1: Regarding the order of placing leveraged funds in accounts, why would Traditional IRA/401k be prioritized over a Brokerage Account? This seems to contradict the idea of &ldquo;putting cash in a Traditional account to slow appreciation.&rdquo; Moreover, future withdrawals from Traditional accounts are taxed at Income Tax rates, which are higher than Brokerage&rsquo;s Capital Gain Tax rates.
<ul>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo;s Reply: This question is more complex. The core reasons are: 1) Leveraged funds cannot be used for stock-backed loans. Placing leveraged funds in a Brokerage account would &ldquo;pollute&rdquo; this account, which might be used for pledging in the future. 2) Leveraged funds have high volatility and will inevitably require rebalancing, which would incur taxes if done in a Brokerage account. Although the future tax rate in a Traditional account is higher, it provides a &ldquo;tax deferral&rdquo; effect, allowing you to operate freely internally without tax worries. More importantly, you don&rsquo;t need to allocate leverage in every account. <strong>The core is to maintain the overall investment portfolio&rsquo;s Beta value at 1.0.</strong> You can achieve Beta 1.0 through leveraged funds in Roth accounts and cash or QQQ in Traditional/Brokerage accounts. This results in the same return but with a superior tax structure and risk control.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Jenny 
    <div id="jenny" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#jenny" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Share 1: After listening to the teacher&rsquo;s class, I decided to cancel a life insurance policy I had paid for 7 years, at CAD 20,000 per year. Although I lost CAD 100,000, I felt relieved. My husband also agreed because I calculated for him that even if we only got back a portion of this money, its value in 40 years would far exceed the CAD 1,000,000 insured amount. I don&rsquo;t regret my past decisions because they were made with the knowledge I had at the time, but now my understanding has upgraded.
<ul>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo;s Comment: Excellent sharing and decision. Having tens of millions in assets while alive is far more meaningful than receiving a million in insurance after death.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 1: I&rsquo;m 50 and plan to sell an investment property, expecting CAD 900,000 in cash. How should I allocate this large sum into my planned configuration of 40% QQQ, 15% QLD, 10% TQQQ, and 35% cash?
<ul>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo;s Reply: For someone nearing retirement, safety is paramount. First, calculate how many years of living expenses you&rsquo;ll need after retirement and prepare <strong>at least 10-15 years of cash</strong>. For example, if you spend 60,000 a year, you&rsquo;ll need 600,000 in cash for 10 years. Set this money aside first, and then allocate the remaining funds according to your asset allocation ratio.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Peter 
    <div id="peter" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#peter" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Share 1: I spent two weeks manually typing the 120,000 words of Mr. Huang Pei-Yuan&rsquo;s book &ldquo;The Bible of Financial Management,&rdquo; published in 1996, into an electronic version because its content is highly consistent with the CLEC philosophy. I want to share it with everyone, but I have concerns about copyright.
<ul>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo;s Reply: Thank you very much for your effort. Sharing it internally within our closed study group is fine; it&rsquo;s not public dissemination and doesn&rsquo;t involve profit. You can post it, noting &ldquo;Please inform us if there is any infringement, and it will be immediately deleted.&rdquo;</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Damon 
    <div id="damon" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#damon" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Share 1: My short-term trading for the past 10 years ultimately amounted to nothing, but in the past two years, I switched to long-term QQQ investing, yielding substantial returns.</li>
<li>Question 1: I leveraged an additional NT$15 million from real estate in Taiwan, with an interest rate of 2.88%, renewed annually, with no principal repayment required. Is it feasible to invest this money and then use a portion of the investment profits to pay the interest, continuing this operation? Also, I am currently in the US, with most of my assets in Taiwan. Is this long-term plan suitable?
<ul>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo;s Reply: Short-term operations are feasible. But in the long run, if you and your children will eventually settle in the US, assets should ultimately be transferred to the US. This is primarily to simplify estate planning and avoid Taiwan&rsquo;s relatively high estate tax on large cash assets. The US estate tax exemption is much higher than Taiwan&rsquo;s. You need to be aware of the potential risks and penalties of not declaring overseas assets to the IRS and plan accordingly.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Jun 
    <div id="jun" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#jun" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question 1: I&rsquo;m new to the teacher&rsquo;s philosophy and plan to transfer all my funds. Should a large sum (e.g., $1 million) be invested all at once, or in batches?
<ul>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo;s Reply: <strong>Immediately, right now, buy all at once</strong>. Investing in batches leads to poorer performance and is a tormenting process. You can adopt a 70/30 strategy, meaning 70% of the funds are bought immediately, and the remaining 30% is held as cash (invested in a money market fund). Don&rsquo;t be afraid of buying at a high point; looking back a few years from now, any current price will seem low.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Dian 
    <div id="dian" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#dian" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question 1: After putting all my cash into the market, should my future living expenses be paid by taking out a 2% stock-backed loan?
<ul>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo;s Reply: Yes, that&rsquo;s the correct approach.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2: US stocks might enable 24-hour on-chain trading in the future. How does this affect us long-term investors?
<ul>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo;s Reply: No impact. This is just technological progress, like moving from phone orders to online orders. It doesn&rsquo;t change the long-term investment strategy itself.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Xi 
    <div id="xi" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#xi" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question 1: In the US, for investment purposes, would forming one&rsquo;s own company (e.g., LLC) be better than individual investment? For example, one could establish a Solo 401K, etc., to put more tax-free funds.
<ul>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo;s Reply: <strong>Absolutely not</strong>. This is an unnecessary complication that will only bring endless trouble, such as accounting, tax filing, company maintenance, etc. For long-term investors who don&rsquo;t sell, a personal Brokerage account is already very tax-optimized, so there&rsquo;s no need to complicate things for a little extra Roth space. The benefits are minimal, and the drawbacks are numerous.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Curiosity 
    <div id="curiosity" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#curiosity" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question 1: In the teacher&rsquo;s simulation, the final asset multiple of the 433 configuration without pledging (5.8x) was higher than that with pledging (4.somethingx). So why should we still choose stock-backed loans?
<ul>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo;s Reply: The simulation results depend on the historical market path. Our simulated period (starting from the 2000 high) was a &ldquo;volatile market&rdquo; with a sharp ten-year decline followed by a slow recovery. In such a market, &ldquo;mindless rebalancing&rdquo; (without pledging) performs better because it dares to buy heavily during downturns. However, in a long-term bull market (e.g., 1980-2000), &ldquo;smart rebalancing&rdquo; (with pledging) would outperform. The most important reason we choose pledging is not to pursue the highest return, but to <strong>ensure survival in extreme markets and avoid liquidation.</strong></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2: When actually taking out a stock-backed loan, where does the monthly interest come from? Is it reserved from the $200,000 borrowed?
<ul>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo;s Reply: No. The interest should also be borrowed. Your total loan limit is very high (e.g., $6 million on $10 million in assets), and you only borrowed $200,000. The monthly interest, a few hundred dollars, can be directly borrowed from your available credit limit. This way, your debt will increase slowly, but your assets will grow at a faster rate.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Share 1: A supplementary piece of information: In the US, if underage children have earned income, Roth IRA accounts can be opened for them, starting compounding early.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Nhu 
    <div id="nhu" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#nhu" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question 1: Regarding car loan interest at 8%, life insurance, and the Canadian ETF HXS.TO.
<ul>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo;s Reply: Car loan interest at 8% is too expensive. Don&rsquo;t take out a loan at a car dealership; consider buying a Tesla, their interest rates are much lower. Life insurance is for dead people; living people don&rsquo;t need it, it&rsquo;s meaningless. Canadian investors can buy HXS.TO.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Vincent 
    <div id="vincent" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#vincent" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question 1: Can I exclude cash from my 662 asset allocation?
<ul>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo;s Reply: No, you must have 30% cash. This is a very important part of asset allocation, used to stabilize the portfolio and hedge against risk.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Other 
    <div id="other" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#other" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question 1: Can pension and Social Security be counted as part of the cash component in asset allocation?
<ul>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo;s Reply: No. They are your <strong>cash flow</strong>, not your <strong>cash assets</strong>. They can reduce the amount you need to withdraw from your investment portfolio annually, but they cannot replace the cash position that acts as a stabilizer in asset allocation.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">IV. Key Insights 
    <div id="iv-key-insights" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv-key-insights" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>You currently have 300 dollars, you should be able to spend 10,000 dollars.
&ndash; Teacher James</p></blockquote>
<p>This insight concisely explains the power of financial leverage. Your purchasing power should not be determined by your current cash, but by the potential future value of your assets.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Hard work has no future&hellip; Making money work hard is what truly matters.
&ndash; Teacher James</p></blockquote>
<p>This insight overturns traditional values, emphasizing the importance of passive income and asset appreciation. The core is to make capital work for you, not the other way around.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>You&rsquo;re even vigilant when you receive a scam call, but you completely trust what your financial advisor tells you, and that&rsquo;s what&rsquo;s truly terrifying.
&ndash; Teacher James</p></blockquote>
<p>This insight uses a strong contrast to warn investors that they must maintain independent judgment and critical thinking towards all financial institutions&rsquo; advice, not blindly trusting them.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The financial industry, the insurance industry, and the government, combined, are a scam group.
&ndash; Teacher James</p></blockquote>
<p>This insight, in an extreme way, reminds investors to be highly wary of complex products recommended by all financial institutions, as their goal is usually to earn your fees and commissions, not to serve your best interests.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The Beta is the same, the volatility is the same, the return rate is the same.
&ndash; Teacher James</p></blockquote>
<p>This insight is the scientific core of asset allocation. The return of an investment portfolio is determined by its overall market risk exposure (Beta), not by how many &ldquo;magical&rdquo; leveraged products it contains.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>I actually didn&rsquo;t feel much pain, discomfort, or regret&hellip; because that was the decision I made based on my understanding at the time, but now I&rsquo;m different.
&ndash; Jenny</p></blockquote>
<p>Jenny&rsquo;s reflection when sharing her decision to surrender a loss-making insurance policy embodies the process of an investor&rsquo;s mental maturation: not being trapped by past sunk costs, but bravely making the right decision based on a higher level of understanding now.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>If it&rsquo;s not a truth you&rsquo;ve realized yourself, there&rsquo;s no extra profit in it for you, because it belongs to others.
&ndash; Teacher James</p></blockquote>
<p>Emphasizes the importance of independent thinking and truly understanding investment philosophy. Following the crowd or using strategies one doesn&rsquo;t understand, even if profitable in the short term, cannot be sustained in the long run because it doesn&rsquo;t fall within one&rsquo;s own circle of competence.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">V. Summary 
    <div id="v-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#v-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This gathering was a profound course in reshaping financial intelligence. Teacher James fundamentally challenged the traditional notion of &ldquo;work hard, save money to get rich,&rdquo; clearly advocating a rich mindset centered on &ldquo;financial operations.&rdquo; Through the strategy of &ldquo;borrowing to consume, never selling assets,&rdquo; investors can break free from dependence on active income, allowing assets to calmly compound in the market over the long term. The Q&amp;A session served as a rich case study, applying this core concept to diverse real-world scenarios such as salary negotiations, insurance decisions, large-sum asset deployment, and cross-border asset management, providing listeners with extremely valuable practical guidance and mindset building. The entire sharing was not just about &ldquo;technique&rdquo; (how to invest), but more about &ldquo;philosophy&rdquo; (how to think about wealth).</p>

  



<div
  
    class="flex px-4 py-3 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900"
  >

  <span
    
      class="text-primary-400 ltr:pr-3 rtl:pl-3 flex items-center"
    >

    

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M506.3 417l-213.3-364c-16.33-28-57.54-28-73.98 0l-213.2 364C-10.59 444.9 9.849 480 42.74 480h426.6C502.1 480 522.6 445 506.3 417zM232 168c0-13.25 10.75-24 24-24S280 154.8 280 168v128c0 13.25-10.75 24-23.1 24S232 309.3 232 296V168zM256 416c-17.36 0-31.44-14.08-31.44-31.44c0-17.36 14.07-31.44 31.44-31.44s31.44 14.08 31.44 31.44C287.4 401.9 273.4 416 256 416z"/></svg>

  </span>


  </span>

  <span
    
      class="dark:text-neutral-300"
    ><strong>Disclaimer:</strong> This article is solely for personal study notes and does not constitute any investment advice.</span>
</div>

]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>00509 Don't Let Greed and Fear Ruin Your Investment Life: Investing Isn't About Being the Fastest, But About Who Laughs Last</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1743323578617/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1743323578617/</guid><description>In this episode, James discusses the normalcy of market fluctuations, emphasizes the importance of long-term holding of index funds, analyzes the actual situation of U.S. Treasury bonds, and shares insights on asset allocation, leverage use, investment psychology, real estate, children&amp;#39;s education, and consumption concepts.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<lite-youtube videoid="p6vRBnH2VqA" playlabel="p6vRBnH2VqA" params=""></lite-youtube>



<h2 class="relative group">I. Current Theme 
    <div id="i-current-theme" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-current-theme" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>The market is always fluctuating; this is normal. Investors should have a long-term perspective, ignoring short-term volatility and market noise (such as international situations, economic analysis, financial reports, etc.). The core strategy is to hold high-quality index funds (such as QQQ) for the long term, and to make reasonable asset allocation (including cash reserves) based on individual risk tolerance, while overcoming the greed and fear of human nature. Learning and building a firm belief are essential.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">II. Briefing Content 
    <div id="ii-briefing-content" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii-briefing-content" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Market Volatility and Long-Term Investing 
    <div id="market-volatility-and-long-term-investing" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#market-volatility-and-long-term-investing" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Market volatility is normal</strong>: A 10% market drop is normal, 20% happens about every two or three years, and 50% may happen every five to ten years. This is like the tides, wind, rain, and earthquakes in nature; it&rsquo;s an inevitable natural phenomenon. Don&rsquo;t think &ldquo;this year is different&rdquo;; every year is the same.</li>
<li><strong>Importance of a long-term perspective</strong>: As long as you stay in the market long enough, you will understand that there is nothing new in the market. The core laws of the market are &ldquo;always rising&rdquo; and &ldquo;always fluctuating.&rdquo;</li>
<li><strong>Ignore the noise</strong>: Market fluctuations, international situations, market analysis, financial reports, and economic situations are all irrelevant to the decisions of long-term investors.</li>
<li><strong>Recommended strategy</strong>: Hold the Nasdaq 100 index fund (QQQ) for the long term; it can be bought worldwide. This is the simplest and most effective strategy.</li>
<li><strong>Interactive request</strong>: Hope everyone likes, leaves comments, and most importantly, subscribes on various platforms (Podcast, Bilibili, YouTube).</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Learning and Mindset 
    <div id="learning-and-mindset" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#learning-and-mindset" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Learning to build belief</strong>: Investing is simple (buy index funds), but there are many external distractions (monsters and ghosts). You need to build firm belief and willpower through learning, so that you will not be easily swayed by other people&rsquo;s opinions.</li>
<li><strong>Overcoming human weaknesses</strong>: Greed and fear are the biggest enemies of investment.
<ul>
<li><strong>Manifestations of greed</strong>: Chasing high when the market rises, thinking that the opportunity to &ldquo;buy the dip&rdquo; has come when the market falls, and using up all cash too early (e.g., constantly adding positions when the market has just fallen 5%-13%).</li>
<li><strong>Manifestations of fear</strong>: Not daring to buy when the market rises, only FOMOing (fear of missing out) All-in when it has risen too much; panicking when the market falls and selling at a loss at the bottom.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Importance of cash</strong>: Ample cash is a magic weapon to overcome human nature (especially fear), as important as air. It makes you feel comfortable and secure when the market falls. Don&rsquo;t exhaust your cash when the market just starts to fall.</li>
<li><strong>Living in the present</strong>: Don&rsquo;t dwell on past mistakes (such as losses in real estate investment), don&rsquo;t worry too much about future uncertainties, focus on the present, and do your current investment and learning well.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Asset Allocation and Leverage 
    <div id="asset-allocation-and-leverage" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#asset-allocation-and-leverage" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Finding the comfort zone</strong>: Everyone has a different risk tolerance. You need to find your comfortable asset allocation ratio through market fluctuations (such as 442, 433, 523, 514, 505, etc.), and the cash ratio is very important. If you feel uncomfortable when the market falls, you should adjust to a configuration that you can hold with peace of mind during rebounds.</li>
<li><strong>Leverage risk</strong>: Few people can withstand fluctuations of more than 1.2 times Beta. When the market falls, many people will not be able to stand it and reduce leverage. Don&rsquo;t be overconfident in adding leverage when the market is good.
<ul>
<li><strong>Example</strong>: Some people went from 442 to 0.9x leverage or even lower.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Rebalancing</strong>: It is recommended to do rebalancing once a year. Only use a small amount of cash (e.g., 2% per year) to buy if the market is down at the end of the year. Don&rsquo;t operate frequently or exhaust your cash due to monthly or short-term declines.</li>
<li><strong>About full-position leverage</strong>: It is not recommended for young people to use &ldquo;full-position two-times leverage,&rdquo; because there will always be a big bubble in life. High leverage may lead to a significant asset drawdown (e.g., falling to 0.1), which is difficult to recover, and you may reach your goal later than with a stable investment.</li>
<li><strong>Tortoise and hare</strong>: A stable configuration (tortoise) will outperform an aggressive high-leverage strategy (hare) in the long run. Even if the Beta is lower than 1, it doesn&rsquo;t matter.</li>
<li><strong>Purpose of secured borrowing</strong>: The purpose of secured borrowing is not to pursue extreme returns, but to meet living needs or make better configurations while holding high-quality assets for the long term. The risk lies in the ability to repay the principal, not the interest burden.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">U.S. Treasury Bonds and the Economy 
    <div id="us-treasury-bonds-and-the-economy" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#us-treasury-bonds-and-the-economy" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>US Debt Clock Update</strong>: The website has been updated, adding data such as DoJ Waste Recovery of federal wasted funds and U.S. Hidden Wealth Assets (including gold, minerals, real estate, land, stocks, Recaptured Assets, etc.).</li>
<li><strong>U.S. Balance Sheet</strong> (as of March 27, 2025, approximate numbers):
<ul>
<li>Total Assets: Approximately 168 Trillion (T)</li>
<li>Federal Government Debt (in bond form): Approximately 36 T</li>
<li>Total Liabilities (including credit represented by cash M1/M2, etc.): Approximately 102 T</li>
<li>Annual Income (GDP): Approximately 28 T</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Interpretation</strong>: It&rsquo;s like a person having 1.68 million in assets (and the assets are growing at a rate of about 10%), 1.02 million in debt (of which 360,000 is core debt), and an annual salary of 280,000 (which is also growing). The debt is controllable, and the risk of bankruptcy is very low. U.S. dollar cash itself is also a liability, but it will depreciate with inflation, reducing the actual repayment pressure.</li>
<li><strong>Interest problem</strong>: Federal debt interest expenditure is about 1T, which is controllable relative to federal tax revenue (about 4.9T + state tax) and GDP (28T). There is no need to worry too much about the so-called interest exceeding defense spending (about 0.9T), as this comparison is not meaningful.</li>
<li><strong>Clarification of Musk&rsquo;s views</strong>: Musk mainly criticized the <strong>inefficiency and waste</strong> of the U.S. government&rsquo;s spending, rather than the debt itself being unsustainable.</li>
<li><strong>Impact of tariffs</strong>: Raising tariffs essentially shifts costs to consumers, leading to rising prices, which is equivalent to a disguised tax. This is just a different form from directly collecting federal taxes (paying in installments in daily consumption vs. paying once a year). The impact on the overall economy is complex, but for individuals, it may just be &ldquo;shifting from the left pocket to the right pocket.&rdquo;</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Other Sharing 
    <div id="other-sharing" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#other-sharing" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>HSBC Hong Kong Account Opening Experience (Student Sharing)</strong>:
<ul>
<li>Threshold: May require assets equivalent to HK$1 million to avoid monthly fees (approximately HK$380).</li>
<li>Transaction fee: Relatively high, but has little impact on long-term holders.</li>
<li>Stock pledge interest rate: HIBOR + 1.2%, currently about 4.92%, which is acceptable.</li>
<li>Suggestion: It is more convenient to sell stocks in other brokerages for cash and transfer them in than to perform complex cross-system transfers. Don&rsquo;t delay important matters for small fees.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Canadian Real Estate Investment Issues (Student Sharing)</strong>:
<ul>
<li>Non-tax residents face high withholding tax on selling property (35% of the selling price, not the profit), and transaction costs are high (brokerage fees, prepayment penalties, lawyer and accounting fees).</li>
<li>Conclusion: Houses are &ldquo;invisible cages&rdquo; and tools for governments, the financial industry, and capitalism to bind labor. Don&rsquo;t hesitate to sell the house; past investments are sunk costs. James also shared his experience of losing money selling a house in Longtan, Taiwan.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Retirement Planning Case (Student Question)</strong>:
<ul>
<li>NT$15 million in funds + NT$5 million in financial-type mortgage.</li>
<li>Suggestion: For the part that needs cash flow, consider buying ETFs such as 0050/0056 that provide dividends, but be aware that their dividends may include principal (selling component stocks).</li>
<li>Investment of NT$15 million: If you don&rsquo;t need to withdraw money from it, you can consider leveraged allocation (such as 433); if you need to withdraw money, you cannot use leverage. Choose the allocation based on the withdrawal rate (the amount needed after deducting Social Security benefits) (e.g., 2% withdrawal with 80/20 QQQ/cash; 3% withdrawal with SPY). The withdrawal rate is key, not the traditional 4% rule.</li>
<li>Core: Any configuration must consider whether you can withstand a 50% market drop.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Tesla FSD Experience (Student and Teacher Sharing)</strong>:
<ul>
<li>FSD V12 is amazing, close to fully autonomous driving, able to handle complex road conditions (such as San Francisco), and significantly reduces driving stress and fatigue.</li>
<li>FSD has a certain &ldquo;perception&rdquo; ability and can judge the intentions of other vehicles/pedestrians and make intelligent reactions.</li>
<li>Value: The teacher believes that FSD is worth the money (willing to spend $100,000 to buy it), improves safety (saves lives), improves the driving experience (reduces family quarrels), and may even reduce insurance premiums (using Tesla Insurance). Strongly recommends buying a Tesla car with FSD (the new Model Y comes standard). Use the teacher&rsquo;s referral code for discounts.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Consumption Concepts and Family (Student Question)</strong>:
<ul>
<li>Problem: Family members (such as spouses, parents) continue to demand new car replacements and other consumption due to &ldquo;laborer thinking&rdquo; or material needs, which conflicts with their own goals of accumulating wealth, and they feel annoyed.</li>
<li>Teacher&rsquo;s suggestion:
<ul>
<li>Understand the needs and feelings of family members (love what they love).</li>
<li>Learn to &ldquo;consume smartly,&rdquo; using financial tools (such as secured loans, adjusting allocation ratios) to meet some reasonable needs without excessively affecting the growth of core investments. For example, sell 100,000 QQQ, exchange it for 50,000 QLD (keeping some exposure) + 50,000 cash to buy a car.</li>
<li>The goal of capitalists is to make money generate money and ultimately use it to improve the quality of life, not just to save money. Find a balance between accumulation and consumption.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Technology Product Consumption</strong>: The teacher shared that buying high-quality displays (Nano-texture display) and AirPods Pro 2 (with hearing aid function, about $249) is to protect health and improve the quality of life. These investments are worthwhile, and financial operations (such as secured loans, credit card rebates reinvestment) can be used to make them feel like &ldquo;no money is spent.&rdquo;</li>
<li><strong>Defining Purchasing Power</strong>: True purchasing power means that when the purchased items (such as houses and cars) are accidentally damaged, you have the ability to easily buy another one without feeling financial pressure or heartache. Otherwise, you are exceeding your consumption capacity.</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">III. Q&amp;A Session 
    <div id="iii-qa-session" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii-qa-session" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">K 
    <div id="k" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#k" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Often explains to friends that market fluctuations are normal and not to panic. Also dissuaded friends from borrowing too much to invest just because their income could afford the interest.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s comment: Agreed. The main risk of secured borrowing is not the ability to pay interest, but the ability to repay the principal (Margin Call) when the market falls. Adjusting leverage to a comfortable level during market rebounds is important.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">C 
    <div id="c" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#c" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Thanks for the teacher&rsquo;s inspiration, sharing that he and a friend were deeply touched and started taking action, but also lamented that many people would rather eat, drink, and have fun than squeeze out a small amount of money to invest each month. Cognition determines wealth.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s comment: Glad to see students agree and execute, eventually becoming wealthy. Shared the example of an early student (2006) who persisted and has achieved financial freedom. Becoming a capitalist requires cognition and persistence, and it is indeed a minority of people.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Tommy 
    <div id="tommy" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#tommy" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Reviewed his 16-year investment journey: early purchases of 0050/0056 -&gt; chasing biotech stocks (heavy losses) -&gt; starting to invest in U.S. stocks (VOO/VTI/bonds, diversified) after the pandemic -&gt; epiphany after listening to the course, and is now concentrating assets into QQQ. Realized that dividends (0056) are not as good as total return (0050), paying off the mortgage too early was a wrong decision, and the cost of time is terrible.</li>
<li>Question 1: Should asset allocation (such as 442/433) be achieved on all accounts (Taiwan, US Brokerage, IRA, Roth 401k, etc.) as a whole, or should each account follow?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s reply: All accounts should be regarded as a whole for allocation. Leveraged funds (such as QLD) can only be placed in tax-free growth Roth accounts. Cash can be placed in Brokerage or Traditional IRA/401k (doing so can slow down the growth of pre-tax accounts, which is beneficial for future taxes). The final Beta value will be limited by the size of the Roth account. Even if the Beta is lower than 1, it doesn&rsquo;t matter. Stability (tortoise) may outperform aggression (hare).</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2: There are historical contributions in Traditional 401k (mutual funds have been converted to QQQ), and now it is a mix of Roth and Traditional. Should the Traditional portion be converted to Roth?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s reply: Whether to convert depends on the amount and current tax rate. If the amount is not large, you can convert it all at once. If the amount is large (e.g., 500,000), in order to avoid high tax burdens, it should be converted over many years. You can use the Investment Calculator to calculate how much amount to convert each year to reduce the Traditional balance to zero within a set period (e.g., 10 years) while controlling the annual tax burden. Fidelity clearly distinguishes the shares of Roth and Traditional internally.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">MMA 
    <div id="mma" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#mma" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Experienced Tesla FSD V12 and felt it was very good. 99% of the journey can be driven automatically, including handling cut-ins, traffic jams, and complex slopes in San Francisco, which greatly improves driving efficiency and comfort. Admired Tesla&rsquo;s technology and efficiency (the AI ​​department has few people but significant results).
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s comment: Very much agree. FSD is not just mechanical execution, but can also &ldquo;feel&rdquo; the intentions of other vehicles and pedestrians and make intelligent judgments. FSD greatly reduces driving pressure and improves safety (saves lives). Using FSD also helps reduce the insurance premium for Tesla Insurance. Strongly recommends buying a Tesla with FSD, and stocks can be held through QQQ.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Iam 
    <div id="iam" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iam" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Encountered a brokerage that promoted an IPO and realized that it was an interference from &ldquo;monsters and ghosts.&rdquo;</li>
<li>Question: How to deal with close people (parents, spouses, children) who continue to hold &ldquo;laborer thinking&rdquo; and constantly demand material consumption (such as changing to a new car), which conflicts with their own wealth accumulation philosophy and feels annoyed and pressured? Is there a good way to deal with it?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s reply:
<ol>
<li><strong>Understanding and love</strong>: Understand the needs of family members and love them (love what they love). Meeting reasonable needs is part of maintaining family harmony.</li>
<li><strong>Smart consumption</strong>: Capitalists don&rsquo;t not consume, but consume smartly. Use financial tools (secured loans, adjusting investment portfolios such as selling QQQ for QLD + cash) to meet consumption needs as much as possible without affecting the compound growth of core assets.</li>
<li><strong>Balance</strong>: Find a balance between wealth accumulation and enjoyment of life. It is not necessary to meet all requirements, but it is not possible to completely reject them. It is necessary to meet one or two needs that family members value every year or every few years.</li>
<li><strong>No need to explain too much</strong>: Actions speak louder than words. Express love through practical actions (such as buying a car), but there is no need to argue too much about concepts.</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Ling 
    <div id="ling" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ling" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Describes a complex arbitrage strategy: Using secured borrowing (leverage may exceed 1.5 times), puts some funds into a digital account in Taiwan (about 2% interest), and buys 00864B (USD money market fund) to try to cover the 2.8% borrowing cost. Also shared how to use credit card payments to get 0% interest installments and then use the money to buy 00864B for arbitrage.</li>
<li>Question: Is this operation feasible? Does it conform to the 442 configuration idea?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s reply:
<ol>
<li><strong>Not 442</strong>: What you described is an arbitrage strategy, not the 442 asset allocation based on long-term growth that we discussed.</li>
<li><strong>Arbitrage efficiency</strong>: Putting borrowed money (cost 2.8%) into a NTD account with 2% interest is losing money. All of it should be put into 00864B with higher returns (about 4.5%) and matching currencies (USD) for arbitrage. Exchange rate fluctuations are not important.</li>
<li><strong>Credit card arbitrage</strong>: It is feasible to use 0% interest installments for arbitrage, but it is a &ldquo;sesame green bean&rdquo; small trick and should not be distracted too much.</li>
<li><strong>Risk</strong>: As long as the target (00864B) itself does not fall, this pure arbitrage strategy has low risk and will not be margin called.</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Sandy 
    <div id="sandy" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#sandy" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Experienced the 2008 financial crisis, assets were halved, and since then has attached importance to cash, maintaining 30-40% cash all year round. Dared to buy in when the market fell sharply in 2022 and made a profit at the end of the year.</li>
<li>Question 1: Made considerable profits last year and early this year and wanted to sell some at a high level to avoid a callback, but her husband prevented it because of concerns about high taxes (believing that it would push the tax bracket to 50%). How to deal with it?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s reply: Her husband&rsquo;s understanding of tax law is wrong. Long-term Capital Gain Tax is calculated separately from ordinary income tax. Its tax rate is tiered (usually 0%, 15%, 20%), and the highest is 20% (plus a possible 3.8% NIIT). Selling capital gains will not push ordinary income to an extremely high tax bracket (such as 50%). The tax rate for selling a lot of LTCG is basically fixed (it is 20% after reaching a certain amount). However, it is not recommended to time the market to sell. If you really want to operate, you should prioritize doing so in retirement accounts (such as IRA/401k). Selling has no immediate tax impact, and you can even buy reverse ETFs (such as SQQQ) for hedging in retirement accounts (advanced operation, not recommended).</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2: Is it better to buy dividend-paying stocks or other things with the cash (Money Market) held? Worried about the tax on dividend-paying stocks.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s reply: Don&rsquo;t use dividend-paying stocks to hold cash, the tax efficiency is low. You should use money market funds. If you want to avoid both federal and state taxes, you can consider municipal bond funds (Muni Bond Fund, such as Vanguard&rsquo;s VOOX). If you only consider federal tax, you can use U.S. Treasury money market funds (such as SGOV, BIL). There is a capital gains tax problem only when selling.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 3: I want to anonymously sponsor a talented child (a friend&rsquo;s child, with decent family conditions), but I don&rsquo;t want the other party to know now, how to operate? Worried about tax issues.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s reply: Anonymous operation is difficult, especially involving opening an account. And the other party&rsquo;s family may not need sponsorship. A safer way is to write this child (providing name, address, and other information) into your own trust file as a beneficiary of future inheritance. This operation is simple and usually tax-free.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">CL 
    <div id="cl" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#cl" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question 1: In the United States, in addition to mortgage loans and stock pledges, what other similar low-cost sources of funds can be used like &ldquo;Han Xin counting soldiers&rdquo;?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s reply: The U.S. financial market is highly efficient and has a lot of &ldquo;smart money,&rdquo; so the interest rate on unsecured personal loans is usually higher (such as 8% +). Unlike Taiwan, which has a large amount of low-cost funds (due to export-oriented currency abundance), there are indeed not many other low-cost, flexible sources of funds besides stock pledges (Pledge Loan). If you have channels in Taiwan to borrow low-interest NTD funds, you can consider it.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2: Regarding children&rsquo;s college tuition fees, is it better for them to apply for student loans themselves (and we will use the pledged money to pay them back after graduation), or to pay directly with the pledged money? Which is better?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s reply: There is no absolute right or wrong, it depends on the child&rsquo;s personality and feelings. If the child feels stressed about debt, pay directly. If the child understands financial leverage and the student loan conditions are favorable (such as interest only after graduation), you can let them take out the loan and the parents will pay it back later. The key is to communicate well with the child. The teacher shared his experience of paying his daughter&rsquo;s tuition fees directly.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Sharing: Fortunate to have followed the teacher&rsquo;s advice to sell the expensive house in Los Angeles and exchange it for a cheaper one and use a pledge loan. Now I feel relaxed, unlike some friends who are trapped in expensive houses and facing difficulties under the wave of layoffs.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s comment: Yes, real estate has poor liquidity, especially when bought at a high price, which easily limits life choices and financial flexibility. Young people should be especially cautious.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Hao Qing (浩清) 
    <div id="hao-qing-%E6%B5%A9%E6%B8%85" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#hao-qing-%E6%B5%A9%E6%B8%85" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Told about his difficult experiences in the United States in the early stages of immigration: meager salary (less than 30,000 USD/year), relying on friends to introduce jobs, being questioned by the boss for his ability, saving money, working long hours and studying every day to support his family. Shared the process and feelings of raising three children: Children are motivation and will find their own way out. Responded to the teacher&rsquo;s video case about hesitating whether to have a third child, encouraged having children, and believed that children have their own future.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s comment: Shared his own experience of being poor when he first came to the United States (borrowing money to come to the United States, living in Motel 6, cooking by himself). Emphasized that the hardship of life is a process and also a valuable wealth and memory. Encouraged everyone to face life challenges bravely. Marriage and childbirth are not that terrible, love is the key, and money is usually not the biggest problem.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Terry 
    <div id="terry" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#terry" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question 1: Concerns about U.S. Treasury bonds (such as the debt-to-GDP ratio, interest burden), is it possible that the world will stop buying U.S. bonds?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s reply: U.S. assets (168T) far exceed debt (federal debt 36T). The interest burden is controllable relative to fiscal revenue and GDP. Countries around the world hold a large amount of USD reserves and must purchase USD assets (government bonds, treasury bills, money market funds, etc.) to store them. There are no other large-scale options to replace them. Therefore, the world will not stop buying U.S. bonds. A strong U.S. dollar is in the best interest of the United States.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2: The price of SGOV (short-term treasury bond ETF) is rising slightly every day, while the price of TLT (long-term treasury bond ETF) has been falling recently, why?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s reply: SGOV tracks short-term interest rates. Its mechanism is to accrue interest accumulation daily and the net value returns after dividends, showing a step-like slight oscillation. TLT represents long-term treasury bonds, and its price (yield) mainly reflects the market&rsquo;s <strong>expectations for future long-term inflation</strong>. If the market expects inflation to rise in the future (for example, worrying about tariffs leading to inflation), the yield on long-term treasury bonds will rise and the price of TLT will fall. This has little to do with the Fed&rsquo;s current short-term interest rate policy.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">IV. Highlighted Quotes 
    <div id="iv-highlighted-quotes" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv-highlighted-quotes" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>The market is always fluctuating&hellip; There is nothing new in the market, that is, as long as you stay in the market long enough.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>(Emphasizes the normalcy of market volatility and the importance of a long-term perspective)</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Cash is a magic weapon to overcome human nature.
&ndash; James (Cookie student also mentioned &ldquo;Cash is King&rdquo;)</p></blockquote>
<p>(Emphasizes the key role of cash in dealing with market fluctuations and psychological biases)</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Even if you are a god, you have many magic weapons. If you run out of magic weapons, you are not a god.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>(Uses metaphor to illustrate the importance of cash reserves, which cannot be easily exhausted)</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The purpose of capitalists is to spend money. Money is a tool, so what do we earn so much money for? It&rsquo;s to spend&hellip; We need to know how to spend money without reducing assets, killing other people&rsquo;s chickens, and our own chickens are still full of pits. This is our capitalist&rsquo;s philosophy, not saving money.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>(Explains a capitalist mindset that uses financial tools to achieve &ldquo;smart consumption&rdquo; and balance wealth growth and quality of life)</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Good individual stocks don&rsquo;t mean you can&rsquo;t get rich, they mean you can&rsquo;t get rich.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>(Explains the difficulty of holding a single stock with huge fluctuations, it&rsquo;s better to invest in index funds)</p>
<blockquote>
<p>When you can afford to buy two houses, you go buy one&hellip; You can buy something that, if it breaks, you&rsquo;re not sad at all, and you&rsquo;re even happy that you can buy a new one. That means you have the ability to consume.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>(Defines true &ldquo;purchasing power&rdquo; as the ability to afford losses without affecting life, advising young people to be cautious about buying houses)</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Long-term (capital gains) has nothing to do with income&hellip; Long-term capital gain is a fixed tax rate, it&rsquo;s either 15% or 20% and that&rsquo;s it, it won&rsquo;t be higher than 20%&hellip; You sell 10 million and it&rsquo;s still 20%.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>(Clarifies the calculation of U.S. long-term capital gains tax, it is not mixed with ordinary income and progressively increases)</p>
<blockquote>
<p>A strong dollar is in the best interest of the United States.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>(Points out the core interest orientation of the United States in monetary policy)</p>
<blockquote>
<p>TLT&hellip; Its interest is linked to inflation, linked to inflation expectations. So it has nothing to do with the central bank&rsquo;s interest rate.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>(Explains the core drivers of long-term treasury bond yields)</p>


<h2 class="relative group">V. Summary 
    <div id="v-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#v-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>In this CLEC investment and financial management sharing session, James reiterated the core philosophy of long-term investment: embrace market volatility, adhere to holding index funds represented by QQQ, and build firm belief through continuous learning. The teacher analyzed the real situation of U.S. Treasury bonds in detail, believing that there is no need to worry too much, and clarified the misunderstanding about its interest burden and Musk&rsquo;s criticism. At the same time, it discussed the rational use of leverage, the importance of cash reserves (like air and magic weapons), and how to overcome psychological biases in investment. The Q&amp;A session involved asset allocation across accounts, Roth conversion, real estate processing (including Canadian non-resident tax issues and personal experience), children&rsquo;s education funding planning, the excellent value and experience of Tesla FSD, consumption concept balance (smart consumption vs. laborer thinking), the limited sources of low-cost funds in the United States, the driving factor differences between long-term and short-term treasury bond ETFs, and the correct understanding of U.S. long-term capital gains tax and other practical issues, providing specific operational suggestions and thinking frameworks. The core message is to maintain a long-term perspective, make rational decisions, use financial tools to achieve a balance between wealth growth and quality of life, while understanding and respecting the needs of the people around you.</p>

  



<div
  
    class="flex px-4 py-3 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900"
  >

  <span
    
      class="text-primary-400 ltr:pr-3 rtl:pl-3 flex items-center"
    >

    

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M506.3 417l-213.3-364c-16.33-28-57.54-28-73.98 0l-213.2 364C-10.59 444.9 9.849 480 42.74 480h426.6C502.1 480 522.6 445 506.3 417zM232 168c0-13.25 10.75-24 24-24S280 154.8 280 168v128c0 13.25-10.75 24-23.1 24S232 309.3 232 296V168zM256 416c-17.36 0-31.44-14.08-31.44-31.44c0-17.36 14.07-31.44 31.44-31.44s31.44 14.08 31.44 31.44C287.4 401.9 273.4 416 256 416z"/></svg>

  </span>


  </span>

  <span
    
      class="dark:text-neutral-300"
    ><strong>Disclaimer:</strong> This article is for personal study notes only and does not constitute any investment advice.</span>
</div>

]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>00496 Global Markets and the Tech Wave: How to Seize Opportunities for Wealth Growth Amidst Volatility. The Philosophy of Financial Freedom: From Personalized Investing to Exploring Life's Values</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1735482278058/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1735482278058/</guid><description>At the end of 2024, with market fluctuations, Teacher James shared his insights on the current economic situation, financial markets, and investment strategies. In addition, several students asked questions online, covering asset allocation, business operations, health and wellness, tax planning, stock leveraging, and other areas.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Part One
<lite-youtube videoid="9F1rAWjCGX8" playlabel="9F1rAWjCGX8" params=""></lite-youtube>
</p>
<p>Part Two
<lite-youtube videoid="oPb4m81Nv24" playlabel="oPb4m81Nv24" params=""></lite-youtube>
</p>


<h2 class="relative group">I. Main Topic of the Session 
    <div id="i-main-topic-of-the-session" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-main-topic-of-the-session" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>Investment mindset and strategy adjustments amidst year-end market volatility, along with comprehensive reflections on personal life and financial health.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">II. Presentation Content 
    <div id="ii-presentation-content" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii-presentation-content" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Market Volatility and Investment Mindset 
    <div id="market-volatility-and-investment-mindset" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#market-volatility-and-investment-mindset" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>The only constant in the market is volatility. Investors should ignore market fluctuations, international situations, market analysis, financial reports, and economic situations, and focus on long-term investment.</li>
<li>Disclaimer: The content of the COC investment and financial management channel is for educational purposes only and does not constitute investment advice. Investment involves high risks, and proper asset allocation is necessary.</li>
<li>Newcomers should watch the YouTube episode 00451 &ldquo;Investment Lecture Worth 100 Million&rdquo; and also find related content on Bilibili and podcasts.</li>
<li>Investing requires independent thinking. Do not blindly follow advice or join any groups to avoid being deceived.</li>
<li>The Nasdaq 100 index fund is recommended as the only focused fund, with others being supplementary.</li>
<li>The handout includes information on Nasdaq 100 index funds worldwide, including leveraged funds, and information on retirement accounts in various regions, with content continuously updated.</li>
<li>The &ldquo;Investment Lecture Worth 100 Million&rdquo; video is the most important. Investors should always be extremely optimistic; the market will eventually rise and reach new highs.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">UK and European Financial Information 
    <div id="uk-and-european-financial-information" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#uk-and-european-financial-information" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Showcasing information provided by a UK friend regarding UK investments, loans, retirement accounts, ETFs, and insurance companies, particularly information on 2x leveraged funds on the PEA website.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">US-China Trade War and Globalization 
    <div id="us-china-trade-war-and-globalization" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#us-china-trade-war-and-globalization" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Issues like the US-China trade war and tariffs do not affect technological advancements and the innovation of American companies, thus having little impact on index investing.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Risks and Returns of Leveraged Funds 
    <div id="risks-and-returns-of-leveraged-funds" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#risks-and-returns-of-leveraged-funds" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>The risk of a 2x leveraged fund is not simply double, and the return is not twice the annualized rate of return, but approximately 1.4 times.</li>
<li>The annualized return of QQQ over 20 years is 14%, while QLD&rsquo;s is 19.6%. QLD&rsquo;s total return over 20 years is 2.6 times that of QQQ, far exceeding double.</li>
<li>Combining leveraged funds with cash can reduce risk and increase returns.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Investment Wisdom and Market Essence 
    <div id="investment-wisdom-and-market-essence" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#investment-wisdom-and-market-essence" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>The market is always smarter than individual investors. Stock picking and timing the market are futile.</li>
<li>In a bull market, many &ldquo;gurus&rdquo; emerge, but they disappear when the market falls; this is a market norm.</li>
<li>Controlling the major stocks on Wall Street means controlling the world.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Investment Sharing and Personal Insights 
    <div id="investment-sharing-and-personal-insights" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#investment-sharing-and-personal-insights" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Investment sharers need to provide clear, diverse, and universally applicable investment methods and benefit from them.</li>
<li>Buffett&rsquo;s investment philosophy emphasizes long-term investment, perfecting the investment system.</li>
<li>Understanding the essence of finance, economics, accounting, and logic helps resist external interference and adhere to index investing.</li>
<li>Asset allocation is simplified into two types: 433 (conservative) and 442 (aggressive), pursuing safety rather than high returns, with cash being a safe asset.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Finance and Monetary Theory 
    <div id="finance-and-monetary-theory" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#finance-and-monetary-theory" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>The foundation of capitalism is currency. Understanding monetary theory is crucial to understanding finance, investment, and the economy.</li>
<li>The status of the US dollar as the world&rsquo;s reserve currency determines the subordinate status of other countries, especially those holding large amounts of US dollar foreign exchange reserves.</li>
<li>China and other emerging countries are trying to break away from their dependence on the US dollar to escape US control.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Life&rsquo;s Meaning and Happiness 
    <div id="lifes-meaning-and-happiness" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#lifes-meaning-and-happiness" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>The happiest thing in life is giving. Happiness is a human right. Sharing and giving energy on a spiritual level can bring more happiness than material things.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Extremes of Capitalism and Social Issues 
    <div id="extremes-of-capitalism-and-social-issues" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#extremes-of-capitalism-and-social-issues" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Capitalism will lead to an expansion of the wealth gap. The development of robots will make spiritual education even more important.</li>
<li>Systemic discrimination exists in society, leading to a vicious cycle of poverty. Our goal is to help eliminate poverty as much as possible.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">US Accounting System and Social Phenomena 
    <div id="us-accounting-system-and-social-phenomena" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#us-accounting-system-and-social-phenomena" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>The US accounting system is very complete. Phenomena like &ldquo;zero-dollar shopping&rdquo; are the result of accounting costs and leftist thinking, and there is no need to over-interpret them.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Wealth and Government Relations 
    <div id="wealth-and-government-relations" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#wealth-and-government-relations" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Wealthy individuals escape government control by paying taxes, while the poor are trapped.</li>
<li>Legitimate tax avoidance is an important topic.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Personalization of Diet and Asset Allocation 
    <div id="personalization-of-diet-and-asset-allocation" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#personalization-of-diet-and-asset-allocation" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Both diet and asset allocation should be customized according to individual circumstances and cannot be generalized.</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">III. Q&amp;A Session 
    <div id="iii-qa-session" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii-qa-session" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Zhang Yong 
    <div id="zhang-yong" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#zhang-yong" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing</strong>: The chaos in the domestic insurance industry, where banks lure customers into buying insurance with high commissions, is even linked to the performance evaluations of customer managers. Many customers do not understand investments and choose low-yield or even risky insurance products to preserve their capital. He also shared a case of a friend who was defrauded of over 1.7 million in a romance scam, illustrating the complexity of the domestic financial environment.
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s comment</strong>: The US financial system strictly separates life insurance from other financial businesses, and there is no such thing as banks selling insurance. The financial supervision in China and Taiwan is problematic. Banks should focus on deposit and loan business and should not be involved in insurance and investment. This chaos will ultimately harm the interests of emerging countries.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question</strong>: Does Teacher James share content each week based on reflections on the same theme, or does he summarize viewpoints from reading many books?
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s reply</strong>: In addition to reading a lot of books, more importantly, independent thinking and critical thinking are involved. The formation of monetary theory stems from thinking about the nature of capitalism, and the content of the handouts mostly comes from students&rsquo; questions and his own reflections. This information is endless. To be an excellent sharer, one needs to have basic knowledge, thinking ability, and originality.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Xiao Cai 
    <div id="xiao-cai" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#xiao-cai" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing 1</strong>: Took over the family food business ten years ago when the company&rsquo;s assets and liabilities were zero. After ten years of operation, the company turned a profit, and its current value (including real estate) is about 300 million NTD. Over the past decade, he distributed about 200 million NTD of revenue to his family, retaining 100 million NTD for loan purposes. Currently, he has invested 80 million in 00662 (a 2x leveraged Nasdaq 100 index ETF) and 20 million in 00631L (Taiwan&rsquo;s 50 Positive 2 ETF).
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s comment</strong>: None</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question 1</strong>: The bank will allocate a loan of 60 million NTD on January 1st. Should this fund be used to buy 00662 all at once, or should he wait for a 20% market drop before buying? Also, if the market crashes and 00662 and 00631L go to zero, how will he deal with it?
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s reply</strong>: If the market goes to zero, the company can still make loan payments. The worst-case scenario is that the land is auctioned off, and he can still get tens of millions. Since the worst has been considered, how to buy the 60 million is not important. If it were me, I would buy it all on Monday. If you choose to wait for a 20% drop before buying, you can follow your plan and inform everyone when you buy.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question 2</strong>: How to maintain good health?
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s reply</strong>: Regular comprehensive physical examinations are necessary. I have been doing annual check-ups since my thirties. Wellness, like asset allocation, needs to be personalized. The advice I can give everyone now is to eat well, sleep well, and don&rsquo;t worry. What to eat specifically, what exercises to do, etc., need to be decided according to personal circumstances and cannot be given a unified recommendation.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question 3</strong>: What are your views on Taiwan&rsquo;s politics and how to support political parties?
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s reply</strong>: Regarding politics and religious beliefs, everyone has different positions and viewpoints. Discussing these issues in the classroom is meaningless and fruitless. It is recommended that students do not discuss these topics in the classroom and keep their opinions to themselves.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question 4</strong>: How to preserve assets in response to potential cross-strait issues? He currently has about 200 million NTD in assets in Taiwan and a house worth 8 million in Vietnam. How should he allocate his assets?
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s reply</strong>: If you can&rsquo;t sleep due to worries about cross-strait issues, it&rsquo;s recommended to immigrate as soon as possible. If you choose to stay in Taiwan, you need to make some decisions, such as whether to close the company. If the 40 employees are causing you distress, consider closing the company and compensating them. Life decisions should be decisive, not prolonged. Be responsible for your own happiness.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Additional question</strong>: How to get rid of the shackles of the family business?
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s reply</strong>: You have managed the company very well. The choice is your life. Do whatever makes you happy. If the family business makes you unhappy, shut it down and give the employees a good severance package. Consider your own life, not your father&rsquo;s. If your father&rsquo;s business is no longer your concern, and it&rsquo;s not bringing you happiness, then let it go.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Repeated emphasis</strong>: Believes that apart from investment and financial management, health is the most important asset in life, and cited the example of &ldquo;Yu (Yuan) Lingqi&rdquo; to emphasize the importance of regular health check-ups, hoping the channel will pay more attention to health issues.
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s reply</strong>: Health is very important. Everyone&rsquo;s health condition is different, and it is impossible to provide a unified recommendation. Everyone needs to pay attention to and manage their health according to their own situation.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Lare 
    <div id="lare" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#lare" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Question</strong>: Based in Canada, unable to leverage stocks. If income decreases in a certain year, and the tax rate drops from 32% to 24%, is it worth selling some stocks to increase income to the 32% tax bracket to improve the future cost basis?
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s reply</strong>: It is not recommended to sell stocks because selling incurs taxes. Canada&rsquo;s tax system is very unfavorable for stock investments. When immigrating, consider future generations and choose countries with development prospects. In Canada, you can consider using an IB account for loans, but this will face inheritance tax issues, possibly up to 40%. Therefore, when planning estates, minimize assets in IB accounts. In the long run, trusts can be used to avoid taxes. It is currently not recommended to sell stocks for short-term tax benefits. Consider selling after retirement when income is lower.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Additional explanation</strong>: IB accounts have a low financing ratio for Canadian stocks, only up to 50%.
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s addition</strong>: You can borrow 40% first, and add more if needed. But ultimately, there will still be inheritance tax issues.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Terry 
    <div id="terry" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#terry" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Question 1</strong>: How to transfer taxable accounts or retirement accounts to tax-free accounts, such as Roth IRA? What are the specific steps?
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s reply</strong>: If it&rsquo;s within the same brokerage, such as Charles Schwab, you can fill out a form online directly. If it&rsquo;s at different brokerages, you need to contact the brokerage to obtain and fill out a form. For specific steps, you can refer to the previously released video &ldquo;Investment and Financial Management Tips 26: How to Transfer from a Traditional Taxable Account to a Roth IRA Online at 722.&rdquo;</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question 2</strong>: What is your view on Crypto, and will QQQ include Crypto companies in the future?
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s reply</strong>: I don&rsquo;t know much about Crypto and am not sure if it will exist forever, so I won&rsquo;t answer.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">IM 
    <div id="im" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#im" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing</strong>: Through learning, I realized that my investment was too risky, and emergency funds should not all be invested in QQQ. Now I have withdrawn 36 months of emergency funds back to the Money Market Fund. When starting with small funds, one should focus on their main job and increase income sources. After investing in index funds, my mindset changed, and I began to focus on the importance of timing. Therefore, I started to focus on diet, fitness, and learning from the experiences of long-lived people around me. In addition, I learned from investing to avoid risks, such as giving up dangerous activities like diving.
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s comment</strong>: It is wise to learn from the experiences of others. Being overly aggressive is human nature, but it is important to realize and correct it in time. It is wrong to increase positions when the market is rising and to be fearful when it is falling. It should be the other way around. Emergency funds should not be added to.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question</strong>: How to judge whether you are being too adventurous? For example, increasing the leverage ratio of asset allocation from 1.0 to 1.8 when stocks are rising.
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s reply</strong>: This is also a necessary evil. Now that you realize it&rsquo;s not right, you can start to retreat, or when it rises, you buy in, and when it falls, you get scared. Oh, what to do? Then start to retreat. Once you have learned, don&rsquo;t do it again. So, as Buffett said, when others are greedy, you should be fearful, and when others are fearful, you should be greedy. That&rsquo;s the right pace. So, when you want to increase your position in the future, it should be when others are fearful. That&rsquo;s how I do it. This emergency fund should not be increased. Regardless of whether the market is rising or falling, you should not add to this cervical spine disease. How could you add to it? This is not allowed. Then, if you use our asset allocation, when the market falls, you automatically buy in for one year, and when the market rises, you automatically withdraw from the leveraged fund. This is passive, and this has already achieved the practice of being greedy when others are fearful and being fearful when others are greedy.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Patty 
    <div id="patty" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#patty" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Question</strong>: The relationship between the asset-backed ratio and cash reserves. If asset-backed financing is carried out, how to ensure that the cash on hand is greater than the pledged amount? For example, with assets of 1 million, allocated according to the 721 ratio, 200,000 is pledged, but 100,000 in cash cannot be moved. Is it necessary to balance for one or two years to accumulate 200,000 in cash before making a pledge?
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s reply</strong>: You cannot borrow 200,000 all at once; you can only borrow 2% per year. When conducting asset-backed financing, the asset allocation should be 433, not 721. Borrow 2% each year and conduct &ldquo;smart rebalancing.&rdquo; Even if the market falls, you will not be forced to liquidate. The cash ratio may be lower than the loan ratio in extreme cases (such as a continuous 10-year decline), but since the total asset value is still greater than the debt, there will be no problem.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Mike 
    <div id="mike" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#mike" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing</strong>: A friend&rsquo;s experience. The friend took over his father&rsquo;s family business and eventually had health problems due to overwork. He later sold the company for over 600 million and invested the funds in QQQ. He is now very happy.
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s comment</strong>: None</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question 1</strong>: Regarding 401k and RMD. Previously, company stock was placed in a 401k, and now it has a high value, facing the RMD issue. After Trump takes office, is it possible to abolish RMD and change it to a 15% capital gains tax?
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s reply</strong>: This possibility is extremely slim. The government is unlikely to give up the tax revenue brought by RMD.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question 2</strong>: Regarding the Debt to Equity Ratio of companies. It is found that there are large differences in the debt-to-equity ratios of Buffett and many technology companies. Is this related to the nature of the industry? For example, the debt-to-equity ratio of software companies is usually low, while that of hardware companies like Apple is high. So, for individuals, is it a healthy level to control the debt-to-equity ratio at 0.2?
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s reply</strong>: The higher the debt-to-equity ratio, the higher the ROE usually is, but this needs to be based on healthy debt. Healthy debt refers to debt that can be repaid through its own operating activities, such as credit, stock-backed loans (under safe circumstances), and mortgages (that can be repaid). Apple&rsquo;s debt-to-equity ratio is high because it borrows a lot of money to pay dividends and places assets overseas. In addition, it has a large amount of accounts payable. Therefore, it cannot be simply considered that a high debt-to-equity ratio is bad. It is necessary to analyze the nature and safety of the debt specifically.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question 3</strong>: What are your thoughts on the Jetson Orin product launched by Nvidia? This product is mainly for the personal AI market, is cheap, can use ChatGPT to generate code, and runs locally, thereby creating your own AI database.
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s reply</strong>: I don&rsquo;t know much about this product. Our AI is mainly trained using ChatGPT as a personal assistant. Currently, I don&rsquo;t use other devices for personal AI.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">IV. Highlighted Quotes 
    <div id="iv-highlighted-quotes" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv-highlighted-quotes" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>The only constant in the market is volatility.
&ndash; Teacher James</p></blockquote>
<p>This viewpoint emphasizes the normality of market fluctuations. Investors should be mentally prepared and not be affected by short-term market fluctuations.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Investing requires independent thinking. Do not blindly follow advice or join any groups to avoid being deceived.
&ndash; Teacher James</p></blockquote>
<p>This viewpoint emphasizes the importance of independent thinking in investing. Investors should make investment decisions based on their own judgment rather than blindly following others&rsquo; opinions or joining unreliable investment groups.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The happiest thing in life is giving. Happiness is a human right. Sharing and giving energy on a spiritual level can bring more happiness than material things.
&ndash; Teacher James</p></blockquote>
<p>This viewpoint emphasizes that spiritual pursuits are more important than material ones. Giving and sharing can bring greater happiness.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>If you, as a commercial bank, do lending well, then focus on lending. Deposits are 2%. Then your lending is 3.5%, 4%. You just make that 2% difference. This is what a commercial bank should do. Commerce should not touch insurance.
&ndash; Teacher James</p></blockquote>
<p>This viewpoint points out that commercial banks should focus on deposit and loan business instead of being involved in areas like insurance, which not only violates financial regulations but also harms the interests of customers.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Happiness is a human right. If you are alive, you should be happy. If you live so miserably, why bother?
&ndash; Teacher James</p></blockquote>
<p>This viewpoint reminds everyone to pursue happiness and not sacrifice their happiness for money or other goals.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Impotence is also a kind of strength because accepting one&rsquo;s own impotence and acknowledging one&rsquo;s own impotence is also a kind of strength.
&ndash; Teacher James</p></blockquote>
<p>This viewpoint expresses a broad-minded attitude towards life. Acknowledging one&rsquo;s limitations is not a bad thing; instead, it can make one more relaxed.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The truly wealthy are those who foresee a future eternally disconnected from government oversight, swiftly settling their dues to escape the clutches of authority.
&ndash; Teacher James</p></blockquote>
<p>This perspective highlights how affluent individuals utilize legitimate tax avoidance strategies to minimize governmental control over their wealth.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Learning from the experiences of others is a wise approach.
&ndash; IM</p></blockquote>
<p>This viewpoint emphasizes the importance of learning and drawing lessons from others&rsquo; experiences, which can help us avoid making the same mistakes.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>When others are greedy, you should be fearful; when others are fearful, you should be greedy.
&ndash; Teacher James, quoting Buffett</p></blockquote>
<p>This is a very important principle in investing, namely, contrarian thinking, staying calm when the market is frenzied and looking for opportunities when the market is panicking.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Just be happy. There&rsquo;s nothing to it, nothing to fight for, no particular meaning, nothing that grand or great.
&ndash; Teacher James</p></blockquote>
<p>This viewpoint expresses a detached attitude towards life. Don&rsquo;t put too much pressure on yourself; learn to enjoy life.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Don&rsquo;t wait until it&rsquo;s too late, leaving no time for regrets.
&ndash; Teacher James</p></blockquote>
<p>Drawing on investment principles, this perspective underscores the importance of early health screenings, urging not to wait until problems arise before regretting, echoing Xiao Cai&rsquo;s shared viewpoint.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>We investors are always extremely optimistic. Market fluctuations should be ignored. The market will eventually rise and always reach new highs.
&ndash; Teacher James</p></blockquote>
<p>This viewpoint emphasizes the optimistic attitude towards the long-term trend of the market and the neglect of short-term fluctuations, demonstrating the proper mindset for long-term investors.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">V. Summary 
    <div id="v-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#v-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>The content of this episode of the investment and financial management channel is rich. Teacher James not only shared his views on the current market and investment strategies but also answered the practical questions of many students, involving asset allocation, business operations, health and wellness, tax planning, and other aspects. In addition, he also emphasized the importance of happiness and health, as well as investment concepts such as independent thinking, long-term investment, and reasonable tax avoidance. In summary, the content of this episode provides valuable guidance and inspiration for investors, helping everyone make wise decisions in a complex market environment and have a healthier and happier life.</p>

  



<div
  
    class="flex px-4 py-3 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900"
  >

  <span
    
      class="text-primary-400 ltr:pr-3 rtl:pl-3 flex items-center"
    >

    

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M506.3 417l-213.3-364c-16.33-28-57.54-28-73.98 0l-213.2 364C-10.59 444.9 9.849 480 42.74 480h426.6C502.1 480 522.6 445 506.3 417zM232 168c0-13.25 10.75-24 24-24S280 154.8 280 168v128c0 13.25-10.75 24-23.1 24S232 309.3 232 296V168zM256 416c-17.36 0-31.44-14.08-31.44-31.44c0-17.36 14.07-31.44 31.44-31.44s31.44 14.08 31.44 31.44C287.4 401.9 273.4 416 256 416z"/></svg>

  </span>


  </span>

  <span
    
      class="dark:text-neutral-300"
    ><strong>Disclaimer:</strong> This article is only a personal study note and does not constitute any investment advice.</span>
</div>

]]></content:encoded></item></channel></rss>