<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Market Timing on QQQ Investor</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/tags/market-timing/</link><description>Recent content in Market Timing on QQQ Investor</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 05 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jomonylw.github.io/en/tags/market-timing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>00510 Facing the Unpredictability of Short-Term Market Fluctuations; The True Purpose of Investing: Getting Rich While Staying Alive</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1744120117914/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1744120117914/</guid><description>In this lecture, James emphasizes that long-term investors need not pay excessive attention to short-term market volatility, international affairs, financial statements, or economic conditions. The core strategy is to buy and hold high-quality index funds (such as the Nasdaq 100) and maintain a long-term holding period (10-20 years or more), aiming for returns of several times the initial investment. The lecture focuses on the importance of risk management, including holding sufficient cash, understanding and accepting the possibility of significant market declines (such as 50% or more), and avoiding leverage or market timing. It also addresses questions from students regarding asset allocation (433, 442), annual rebalancing, investing new funds, the Canadian ETF (HXQ), managing mindset during market downturns, handling differing investment views among family members, and opinions on current market events (such as tariffs).</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<lite-youtube videoid="5JE-0-2fYVc" playlabel="5JE-0-2fYVc" params=""></lite-youtube>



<h2 class="relative group">I. Current Theme 
    <div id="i-current-theme" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-current-theme" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>The core theme of this lecture is <strong>the mindset and strategies of long-term investors</strong>: adhering to a long-term hold of index funds in the face of market volatility and uncertainty, ignoring short-term fluctuations, and emphasizing the importance of risk management and maintaining sufficient cash.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">II. Briefing Content 
    <div id="ii-briefing-content" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii-briefing-content" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Core Concept: Ignore Short-Term Volatility 
    <div id="core-concept-ignore-short-term-volatility" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#core-concept-ignore-short-term-volatility" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Market Volatility Irrelevance:</strong> For investors preparing to hold assets for 5 years, 10 years, 20 years, or even longer (such as for retirement), short-term market price fluctuations (&ldquo;market price&rdquo;) are irrelevant because they are not selling at this moment. The focus should be on long-term (10-20 years later) multiple (4x, 5x, 10x) growth.</li>
<li><strong>Information Noise Filtering:</strong> Short-term information such as market analysis, financial statements, economic conditions, and international affairs are all noise for long-term investors who are not selling, and should be ignored. Don&rsquo;t listen, don&rsquo;t watch, don&rsquo;t pay attention, and short-term problems will not exist.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Risk Management and Mindset 
    <div id="risk-management-and-mindset" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#risk-management-and-mindset" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>&ldquo;Staying Alive&rdquo; is Paramount:</strong> The primary principle of investing is being able to withstand extreme market declines (such as a 50% drop or even more) and &ldquo;stay alive.&rdquo; Those who cannot tolerate volatility are not suitable for investing and should stay away from the market.</li>
<li><strong>Risk is Ubiquitous:</strong> Risk can happen at any time (an earthquake next second, a company going bankrupt, etc.). Recognize, understand, and control risk. Be prepared to deal with the worst-case scenarios (such as the market going to zero, unemployment), ensuring basic living necessities are met.</li>
<li><strong>Importance of Cash:</strong> Allocating sufficient cash (such as 20% or more) is key to risk control, ensuring the ability to maintain living standards during a market crash.</li>
<li><strong>Investor Optimism:</strong> Investing is like starting a business, requiring extreme optimism and belief that the market will eventually rise (&ldquo;always towards the sunlight&rdquo;).</li>
<li><strong>Avoid Greed and Fear:</strong> Do not try to &ldquo;buy the dip&rdquo; (&ldquo;touching the bottom might lead to touching a great white shark&rdquo;), &ldquo;the more greedy, the poorer.&rdquo; The market has no bottom, only lower. Maintain a peaceful mindset, not panicking due to declines.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Investment Targets and Strategies 
    <div id="investment-targets-and-strategies" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#investment-targets-and-strategies" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Focus on Index Funds:</strong> Primarily invest in the Nasdaq 100 index fund (QQQ and its local versions, such as Taiwan 00662, Canada HXQ). Investing in individual stocks is not recommended because the risk of individual stocks far exceeds that of indexes (greater volatility, risk of disappearing).</li>
<li><strong>&ldquo;Never Sell&rdquo; Only Applies to Indexes:</strong> The strategy of &ldquo;buy and hold, never sell&rdquo; applies to index funds because they have a self-elimination and update mechanism. Individual stocks cannot guarantee long-term existence (such as Kodak, BlackBerry), requiring timing the sale or switching stocks. Buffett&rsquo;s holding of Coca-Cola is also not absolutely eternal.</li>
<li><strong>Asset Allocation and Rebalancing:</strong>
<ul>
<li><strong>Allocation Ratio:</strong> Mentioned allocation methods such as 433 (40% original + 30% leverage + 30% cash) and 442 (40% original + 40% leverage + 20% cash).</li>
<li><strong>Investing New Funds:</strong> Invest according to the allocation ratio. For example, under the 433 allocation, a monthly salary can be invested with 6 months in the original, 3 months in leverage, and 3 months in cash. For 442, invest with 4 months in the original, 4 months in leverage, and 4 months in cash (or 5/5/2 or other approximately correct methods).</li>
<li><strong>Annual Rebalancing:</strong> Rebalance once a year at the end of the year. No need to be too precise with monthly investments. Frequent rebalancing (such as based on price points) is incorrect.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Canadian ETF HXQ:</strong> Specifically mentioned Canada&rsquo;s HXQ, because it does not pay dividends, avoiding withholding tax, making it an alternative to QC.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Learning and Community 
    <div id="learning-and-community" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#learning-and-community" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Independent Learning:</strong> Emphasized the importance of independent learning and thinking, recommending watching specific series of videos (e.g., newcomers watch 451, then start from 398 and watch in order to the latest).</li>
<li><strong>Community Selection:</strong> Be wary of noisy investment groups lacking effective answers, or even containing &ldquo;deviant&rdquo; viewpoints. It&rsquo;s better to ask James directly. Mentioned that a certain mainland group has become frivolous and started charging fees, discouraging participation.</li>
<li><strong>Understand the Spirit, Not the Letter:</strong> When taking advice (such as &ldquo;never sell&rdquo;), understand its core spirit (long-term holding philosophy), rather than nitpicking (such as questioning whether rebalancing counts as selling).</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Market Behavior and Risk Awareness 
    <div id="market-behavior-and-risk-awareness" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#market-behavior-and-risk-awareness" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Don&rsquo;t Predict the Market:</strong> It&rsquo;s impossible to predict market highs and lows. Don&rsquo;t try to buy the dip or sell high and buy low. Most people can&rsquo;t do it. CC&rsquo;s example illustrates the consequences of failed selling high and buying low.</li>
<li><strong>Leverage Risk:</strong> <strong>Absolutely prohibit</strong> using funds from stock pledging or margin to reinvest and increase positions. Market declines can far exceed expectations (halving again after halving). Leverage will amplify risk, leading to liquidation (&ldquo;being carried out&rdquo;). Even top investors like Buffett and Howard Marks cannot predict the absolute bottom.
<ul>
<li><strong>Distinguish Safe Leverage:</strong> 理财型 mortgage (such as in Taiwan) used for investment is feasible if the interest can be afforded. Its risk nature is different from stock pledging.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Bottom Signals:</strong> True market bottoms are usually accompanied by extreme panic, with no one daring to buy and bulls in despair. When people still want to buy the dip and add leverage, it&rsquo;s usually not the real bottom.</li>
<li><strong>Different Perspectives:</strong> Understand that the views of different people (e.g., Musk vs. Buffett) stem from their different positions and experiences. No need to argue about right or wrong, the focus is on understanding their logic.</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">III. Q&amp;A Session 
    <div id="iii-qa-session" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii-qa-session" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Kate 
    <div id="kate" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#kate" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing 1: The market is fluctuating, and friends are reacting strongly, but the teacher and myself remain calm. Shared a &ldquo;psychological stability card&rdquo; made by a friend, available on their social media.</li>
<li>Sharing 2: Narrated the story of a friend who trusted her teacher in 2018, when the US-China trade war caused a sharp 20% market drop, and insisted on selling stocks because they couldn&rsquo;t handle the pressure. Emphasized the importance of mental state, and that &ldquo;leaving the market&rdquo; is a greater risk than market declines, like jumping off a speeding train.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Comment: Leaving the market is indeed a greater risk than the market decline itself, and it is difficult to recover.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">LY 
    <div id="ly" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ly" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question 1: Which videos should beginners watch? (Didn&rsquo;t remember the series the teacher mentioned earlier)
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Response: Look at the links in the handout. Beginners should first watch <strong>00451</strong>, then start from <strong>00398</strong> and watch in order to the latest (about 100).</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2: How exactly do you do rebalancing once a year?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Response: Watch the videos to learn (e.g., 00451 and subsequent series).</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 3: Are index funds passively managed and will automatically change their constituent stocks?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Response: Yes, for example, QQQ will automatically adjust, maintaining the top 100 Nasdaq companies by market capitalization.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 4: After experiencing market volatility, should I sell one-third after the stock price rises by 30% to lock in profits, and then buy back when there is a correction?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Response: The idea is good, but in practice, almost no one can do it. If you could do it, you wouldn&rsquo;t need to come to learn. Market timing is very difficult and not recommended. Suggested that she could try it and then come back to share the results. Historically, if this method worked, many people would be richer than Buffett.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Linda 
    <div id="linda" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#linda" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question 1: As a new member attending for the first time, how should I start learning? Should I start with the earliest videos, or are there specific recommendations?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Response: First watch the <strong>00451</strong> video. After watching, you can start investing a portion of your funds (beginners are advised to invest up to 50% at first). Then start from <strong>00398</strong> and watch in order to the latest (about 100). When investing, be sure to keep at least 20% cash. The remaining funds can be invested gradually over 3-6 months.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">CC 
    <div id="cc" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#cc" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing 1: Shared personal experience: Came into contact with the teacher&rsquo;s philosophy in 2020, established a position at the high point in 2021 (cost about 340), and did not sell when it fell to 259. When it returned to breakeven in August 2023, she was worried about another decline and sold, wanting to buy back at a lower position. As a result, the market did not fall below and went all the way up, eventually chasing back at a higher position (cost 409). Realized the difficulty of market timing and the importance of holding faith. Now has a peaceful mindset in the face of declines.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Comment: Ordinary investors have no valuation ability and cannot judge highs and lows, so they should not time the market. Accepting the long-term return of the index (annualized 10-12%) is a realistic and effective strategy.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Huang 
    <div id="huang" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#huang" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing 1: Learned about the teacher&rsquo;s method through his aunt and cut off individual stocks, switching to QQQ/00662.</li>
<li>Question 1: Previously, borrowed NT$2 million when QQQ was about 500 and invested it all at once (believing in not guessing highs and lows). Now the market is falling, and there is no extra cash. Can I continue to increase positions through stock pledge loans?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Response: <strong>Absolutely not!</strong> The market may fall even deeper (halving again after halving). Pledging and reinvesting carries the risk of being forcibly liquidated to zero (&ldquo;being carried out&rdquo;). Risk is unpredictable (such as a major earthquake destroying a technology park). Don&rsquo;t do anything that could lead to &ldquo;death&rdquo; (the end of your investment career), even if the probability is small. Being stuck won&rsquo;t kill you, but adding leverage might.</li>
<li>Kate&rsquo;s Comment: The market often reverses after washing out leveraged investors, and borrowing money to buy the dip is very dangerous.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Liao 
    <div id="liao" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#liao" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question 1: Should I invest in batches now that I have money? The teacher said not to buy the dip, so should I invest now?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Response: &ldquo;Depends.&rdquo; It depends on the individual&rsquo;s existing investment size, cash ratio, and risk tolerance. Relative to an existing large investment portfolio, a small amount of new funds (such as salary surplus) can be invested all at once. If the new funds account for a relatively large proportion, or the investor&rsquo;s mindset is tense, then it should be invested in batches, or adopt right-side trading (wait for the market to confirm the rise before buying). The key is to let yourself &ldquo;eat well and sleep well.&rdquo;</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Yao 
    <div id="yao" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#yao" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing 1: The current market situation is similar to the trade war period during Trump&rsquo;s first term. The teacher&rsquo;s previous teachings (cash is the best medicine against human nature, human nature oscillates between greed and fear, annual rebalancing, not buying the dip) provide the answers. Now is a good time to review and learn.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Comment: Agreed. Investing does not need to pursue exorbitant profits. An annualized return of 10-12% is enough to get rich. The key is to survive. Quoting Munger(?): &ldquo;Newbies die on the mountaintop, experts die halfway up the mountain, and veterans die at the bottom of the valley (being scared away).&rdquo; We need a safe and sustainable method, not luck.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Yin 
    <div id="yin" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#yin" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing 1: Recommends new students to watch video <strong>00451</strong> (investment lecture worth 100 million), emphasizing the importance of watching videos to understand the background of the strategy. It is difficult to grasp the essence based solely on Q&amp;A.</li>
<li>Sharing 2: Shared personal lessons: After the pandemic, I did not believe the teacher. During the big drop in 2022, I liquidated my stocks and switched to US dollar fixed deposits with 5% interest, and missed the sharp rebound in 2023. The return was far less than holding the index. Now fully follows the teacher&rsquo;s strategy, and my mindset is calm.</li>
<li>Sharing 3: Plans to use the 理财型 mortgage (home equity line of credit) on the house to increase investment when the market falls.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Comment: A <strong>理财型 mortgage</strong> (if the interest can be afforded) is different from <strong>stock pledging</strong>. The former has controllable risk, while the latter has extremely high risk. Yin&rsquo;s approach is wise (Smart).</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Mike 
    <div id="mike" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#mike" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing 1: Reviewed six years of learning history, once took detours (such as playing TQQQ), but stopped after Munger&rsquo;s warning about leverage. Realized the subtlety of the teacher&rsquo;s method and wealth growth (2% of living expenses has doubled). Admitted that he did not fully follow the annual rebalancing principle (once operated according to price points) and realized the mistake.</li>
<li>Question 1: The USADCOK website shows that the total value of the US stock market is still 50T after the market decline, and has not decreased. What is the reason?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Response: I don&rsquo;t know the specific calculation method of the website, and it may not fully reflect the change in market value in real time. Further research is needed.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2: How do you view Musk&rsquo;s criticism of Buffett-style investing (unearned income)?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Response: Understand Musk&rsquo;s perspective (creating value through real industry). But Buffett also has his contributions (effectively allocating funds and supporting the development of enterprises). The two represent different perspectives, with no absolute right or wrong. The important thing is to understand why they say so.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 3: Regarding the risk comparison between Taiwan 0050 (Taiwan Top 50) and 00662 (Fubon Nasdaq) (due to concerns about the risk of the top seven technology stocks).
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Response: (Mentioned in the subsequent chat records) QQQ (similar to 00662) is already sufficiently diversified, and the return is usually the highest. Global markets are highly correlated, and diversification into other markets is not very meaningful.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Sharing 2: Quoted Shaw&rsquo;s words about the tragedy of life (utter despair vs. contentment), reminding us to remain humble and learn.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Sandy 
    <div id="sandy" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#sandy" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question 1: I invested the proceeds from selling my house at the end of last year into 00662 all at once, at a relatively high point, and now I regret not investing in batches. Currently, I have a 433 configuration, but not much cash. Can I adjust to 442 and transfer some money market funds into the leveraged fund (00670L) to buy the dip?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Response: <strong>It is not recommended</strong> to reduce the cash ratio (from 30% to 20%) when the market is falling and you feel uneasy. Maintain the existing configuration and wait until the end of the year to re-evaluate. Holding 30% cash safely is more stable than taking the risk of increasing positions. Suggest deleting the APP, out of sight, out of mind, and focus on the cash held.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2: How do you view the potential impact of Trump&rsquo;s possible global tariffs on the future?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Response: Believes it is a short-term disruption, with a smaller impact than the trade freeze during the pandemic. The market and businessmen are highly adaptable and will quickly find a balance, eventually &ldquo;passing water leaves no trace.&rdquo; No need to worry too much.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">IM 
    <div id="im" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#im" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing 1: Gleaned a philosophy of life from the teacher&rsquo;s investment philosophy (observing, listening, and understanding from multiple perspectives).</li>
<li>Sharing 2: Difficulty in trying to teach investing to friends around me: friends don&rsquo;t understand indexes and prefer low-priced stocks; have low expectations for returns (3-5%); have weak savings ability. Discovered that the key problem is the habit of saving rather than the investment return itself.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Comment: It is difficult to teach others, because people only accept what they want to accept. Knowledge requires practice. Listening without practice is like the blind touching an elephant. Encourage taking action (such as going to the bank in person to handle pledging to understand the process) rather than asking endless questions.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Yi Sheng (Doctor) 
    <div id="yi-sheng-doctor" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#yi-sheng-doctor" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing 1: Explained and apologized for the potential noise, poor management, and fee-charging group issues in the mainland WeChat group he manages. Explained the challenges of WeChat group restrictions, complex member backgrounds, and network restrictions. The fee-charging group is for discussing sensitive strategies under domestic policies in a smaller range (such as using financing to achieve a pledge effect), which is voluntary and refundable. Emphasized that he answers questions from group members privately seriously.</li>
<li>Sharing 2: Shared personal lessons: When using stock financing to achieve a pledge effect, it is easy to &ldquo;get carried away&rdquo; beyond the predetermined proportion (such as 10%), and failed to promptly convert the obtained funds into cash, but continued to invest, amplifying the risk. Warned about the human challenge of leverage operations.</li>
<li>Sharing 3: Reminded domestic investors that although transferring funds to Hong Kong to purchase US dollar money market funds has higher returns, the difficulty of returning funds under foreign exchange control must be considered.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Comment: Understands that managing groups is not easy, and users can judge the value of charging fees. Thanks him for frankly sharing the risks and lessons of leverage operations.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">T 
    <div id="t" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#t" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question 1: If you have 1 million in cash (regardless of the source), how would James invest in the current &ldquo;bear market&rdquo; atmosphere?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Response: Emphasized again &ldquo;Depends.&rdquo; It depends on the existing asset size, cash ratio, and risk tolerance. Small funds relative to a large portfolio can be invested all at once. Large funds or beginners/people with unstable mindsets should invest in batches, or wait for the market to recover (right-side trading). The key is to find a way that makes you comfortable.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2: Another approach is to wait for the stock price to return to the buying point (such as 500) before buying. What kind of people is this suitable for?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Response: Suitable for people who cannot tolerate book losses, and losses will seriously affect their mentality and even lead to selling at the bottom. This approach sacrifices some potential returns, but preserves the mindset and the possibility of continued investment.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 3: QQQ has risen from a high point of 408 at the end of 2021 to about 423 in April 2025. The return has not been high in the past four years (about 15/3.5 years?). How do you view this?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Response: Three or four years is still short-term. Citing historical data (S&amp;P 500), investing for 5 years may still result in losses (annualized -2.58% is the historical worst). The focus is on the long term. There is a high probability of profit for <strong>15 years or more</strong>. Even in the worst 15-year period in history, the annualized return is about 4.21%. It is calculated that even if you buy at the highest point of 408 in 2021, after 15 years (2036), the stock price should reach about 742 even under the worst-case scenario. Looking back from 2036, today&rsquo;s 422 is an enviable low point.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Any 
    <div id="any" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#any" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question 1: My nephew (24-year-old soldier) borrowed NT$2 million at a high point (QQQ around 500) and invested it all at once. Previously had a dollar-cost averaging foundation. Now faces enormous pressure from a strong mother (who only believes in real estate) who demands that he sell the stocks. The nephew himself is also under pressure, and even asked whether he could finance to increase positions. How to help the nephew cope with the pressure and persuade/appease the elders?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Response: Unable to change the elders&rsquo; views, it is recommended to <strong>&ldquo;pay lip service&rdquo;</strong> to the mother (tell her that you have sold and stop sharing information) to protect the nephew from interference. Encourage the nephew to persist in long-term investment (hoping to be financially free after 15 years), emphasizing that he is very young and time is his greatest advantage. Any&rsquo;s support as an aunt is very important and can provide spiritual and necessary emergency financial support (although the nephew said he doesn&rsquo;t need it).</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">James (Answering questions in the chat area) 
    <div id="james-answering-questions-in-the-chat-area" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#james-answering-questions-in-the-chat-area" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Handouts/Email:</strong> Look for them at the top of the Cloudhouse message board or at the end of the YouTube video.</li>
<li><strong>HXQ.TO:</strong> Limited to Canadian investors only.</li>
<li><strong>Singapore Brokers:</strong> Opening an account with a local Singapore broker (not a US broker) to buy US stocks generally does not involve US estate tax.</li>
<li><strong>Doctor Community/Fees:</strong> Users judge the value themselves, it is not a scam.</li>
<li><strong>Tech Stock Risk/Tariffs:</strong> Tech giants are highly adaptable, tariffs are a short-term issue and will be digested by the market.</li>
<li><strong>VTI Rebalancing:</strong> You need to have cash to operate.</li>
<li><strong>Why is Beta 1.2 difficult to bear:</strong> Stems from loss aversion (the pain of a decline is 3 times greater than the joy of an increase) and leverage loss. Even if the market is flat and volatile, the psychological feeling of holders is biased towards negativity, and leverage has an actual loss.</li>
<li><strong>Buffett Paying Taxes:</strong> Confirmed that Buffett paid huge taxes.</li>
<li><strong>Trump Policies:</strong> Not related to the long-term direction of the market.</li>
<li><strong>Unemployment Risk:</strong> You need to plan in advance for survival scenarios under the worst conditions (unemployment + market crash).</li>
<li><strong>Is QQQ the Best:</strong> Yes, it is sufficiently diversified and has historically had the best returns. Global markets are linked, and over-diversification is not very meaningful. Volatility does not equal return.</li>
<li><strong>Roth Conversion:</strong> For people with large amounts of money in Traditional IRAs/401ks, it is <strong>necessary</strong> to do the conversion, and paying taxes is necessary.</li>
<li><strong>QRD Holding Account:</strong> Should be placed in a Roth IRA, not a Traditional IRA. Cash is preferred for Traditional IRAs and Brokerage accounts.</li>
<li><strong>Switching Individual Stocks to Indexes:</strong> Do it <strong>at any time</strong>, no need to time the market. Selling individual stocks at a high point to buy an index is also a high point, and the same is true at a low point.</li>
<li><strong>TQQQ:</strong> Cannot be held with a full position, it will go to zero.</li>
<li><strong>Leveraged Fund Rebalancing:</strong> For people holding leveraged funds, it is <strong>necessary</strong> to do annual rebalancing (buying low with cash), otherwise the leverage effect will be difficult to exert, and may even result in losses.</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">IV. Brilliant Ideas 
    <div id="iv-brilliant-ideas" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv-brilliant-ideas" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>Market fluctuations have nothing to do with us&hellip; short-term fluctuations should be ignored&hellip; just wait 10 years, 15 years, 20 years, we&rsquo;re talking about four times, five times, ten times.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>Background: Explains why long-term investors do not need to pay attention to short-term market fluctuations.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The investment market will still decline in the short term. Lose more than 50% of your assets, so you must be able to survive. No matter how the market falls, you must survive. Survival is the key.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>Background: Emphasizes that risk awareness and survival ability are the top priorities of investing.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Buying and holding and never selling can only be done by people who invest in indexes&hellip; individual stock friends can&rsquo;t do it&hellip; who can guarantee that Moutai will still exist in 100 years&hellip; only index funds can&hellip; be sold at any time.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>Background: Distinguishes the differences in holding strategies between index funds and individual stocks.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Don&rsquo;t keep buying and buying and buying while the market is falling, the more greedy you are, the more&hellip; the market has no bottom, only lower&hellip; In the end, investing should be about survival. Who can survive?
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>Background: Warns about the risk of blindly increasing positions and buying the dip in a falling market.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Anything can happen with any risk&hellip; Absolutely do not do anything that will kill you, even if it&rsquo;s a one in a million thing&hellip; If you reinvest with financing or pledge and reinvest, you may die, so why would you go that way?
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>Background: Strongly opposes using leverage (financing, pledging) for investment, emphasizing its potential destructive risk.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Leaving the market is a very risky behavior&hellip; When the train is running, if you leave the market, how can you chase the train&hellip; You want to jump around in it&hellip; impossible.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>Background: Illustrates the extreme difficulty of seizing opportunities after exiting the market.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>What I want to tell everyone is that there must be a formal and safe way. This is what I have learned in 40 years&hellip; Don&rsquo;t rely on luck in the market. You won&rsquo;t be able to survive.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>Background: Summarizes forty years of investment experience, emphasizing the importance of safe and compliant methods, rather than relying on luck.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Newbies die on the mountaintop, experts die halfway up the mountain, and veterans die at the bottom of the valley.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>Background: Describes the common causes of failure for investors of different experience levels, emphasizing the ruthlessness of the market.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Funds are not effective, so we must effectively allocate funds like Buffett to promote the development of these small and medium-sized enterprises. This is his contribution&hellip; It&rsquo;s just that Elon (Musk) can&rsquo;t see it from his perspective, because they are on different mountain tops.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>Background: Explains the social value of Buffett&rsquo;s investment model (effective allocation of capital), responding to Musk&rsquo;s criticism and pointing out the existence of different perspectives.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>You have to look at it from a long-term perspective&hellip; After 15 years, it should be&hellip; a minimum of 742&hellip; People in 2036 will look back and be very envious that we can have a stock price of 422 to buy.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>Background: Using the worst historical 15-year return to predict the lowest point in the future, emphasizing the attractiveness of the current price from a long-term perspective.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">V. Summary 
    <div id="v-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#v-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This lecture, against the backdrop of market volatility, once again reaffirmed the core concept of long-term investment. James repeatedly emphasized that for investors with a cycle of more than ten years, ignoring short-term noise and adhering to holding high-quality index funds such as the Nasdaq 100 is key. Of particular importance is risk management, including maintaining sufficient cash, deeply understanding and accepting the possibility of significant market fluctuations, and <strong>absolutely prohibiting</strong> the use of leverage or stock pledges for reinvestment. The Q&amp;A session explored asset allocation, handling new funds, specific ETFs, mindset adjustments to cope with market downturns, handling different investment views among family members, and how to view poor short-term returns from a long-term perspective, among other practical issues, in depth. The core message is: maintain discipline, manage risk, believe in the long term, and you can &ldquo;stay alive&rdquo; on the road to investment and ultimately achieve your wealth goals.</p>

  



<div
  
    class="flex px-4 py-3 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900"
  >

  <span
    
      class="text-primary-400 ltr:pr-3 rtl:pl-3 flex items-center"
    >

    

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M506.3 417l-213.3-364c-16.33-28-57.54-28-73.98 0l-213.2 364C-10.59 444.9 9.849 480 42.74 480h426.6C502.1 480 522.6 445 506.3 417zM232 168c0-13.25 10.75-24 24-24S280 154.8 280 168v128c0 13.25-10.75 24-23.1 24S232 309.3 232 296V168zM256 416c-17.36 0-31.44-14.08-31.44-31.44c0-17.36 14.07-31.44 31.44-31.44s31.44 14.08 31.44 31.44C287.4 401.9 273.4 416 256 416z"/></svg>

  </span>


  </span>

  <span
    
      class="dark:text-neutral-300"
    ><strong>Disclaimer:</strong> This article is only a personal study note and does not constitute any investment advice.</span>
</div>

]]></content:encoded></item></channel></rss>