<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Annuity on QQQ Investor</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/en/tags/annuity/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Annuity on QQQ Investor</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 17 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/en/tags/annuity/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>00480 part 1 Is investing in Index Fund guaranteed to be profitable? How can one consistently make profits in the market?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/posts/1728203545381/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/posts/1728203545381/</guid>
      <description>This lecture primarily discusses the relationship between economic recession and central bank policy, the risks of investing in Chinese stocks, asset allocation strategies, insurance choices, retirement account investments, currency value and credit, and the concept of leveraged investing. James addresses questions from students regarding Starlink, dollar-cost averaging into leveraged funds, Roth IRA investments, timing investments in Chinese stocks, real estate investment, and annuities, using real-life examples to explain these concepts clearly.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<lite-youtube videoid="ztdWeAncmqY" playlabel="ztdWeAncmqY" params=""></lite-youtube>



<h2 class="relative group">I. Main Topic 
    <div id="i-main-topic" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-main-topic" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This lecture focuses on how to make sound asset allocation and investment decisions amidst economic fluctuations and market uncertainty.  The core message is to prioritize long-term, value-based investing, avoid chasing market highs and lows, and develop a rational investment strategy based on individual circumstances and risk tolerance.  Avoid blindly following trends and emotional market reactions.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">II.  Lecture Summary 
    <div id="ii--lecture-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii--lecture-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<ul>
<li><strong>Central Bank Policy and the Economy:</strong> Central banks primarily focus on inflation and unemployment. Economic recessions are typically accompanied by rising unemployment, prompting central banks to implement policies like quantitative easing to stimulate the economy and reduce unemployment.  For instance, quantitative easing during the subprime mortgage crisis and the pandemic aimed to address rising unemployment.</li>
<li><strong>Risks of Chinese Stocks:</strong> James reiterates his advice against investing in Chinese stocks, using his personal experience of recommending selling off Chinese stocks at the beginning of the US-China trade war as evidence of their risk.  He mentions Nio&rsquo;s price surge from $16 to $30-$40, followed by a significant drop, illustrating the high volatility and risk associated with Chinese stocks.</li>
<li><strong>Asset Allocation Strategy:</strong>  James emphasizes that asset allocation and the amount of capital available for investment are two distinct concepts.  The correct buying strategy is &ldquo;buy when you have money,&rdquo; not dollar-cost averaging. This is similar to the 401k or retirement account investment strategy, where early investment is encouraged to maximize the benefits of compounding.</li>
<li><strong>Insurance Choices:</strong>  He advises against purchasing commercial insurance, particularly investment-linked insurance products, arguing that they offer low returns and poor liquidity. He recommends Term Life Insurance and Medical Care insurance for managing unforeseen risks.  For example, a Term Life policy might cost only a few hundred dollars a year for $1 million in coverage. He discourages purchasing other commercial insurance products like long-term care insurance and universal life insurance, viewing them as a waste of money that could be better used for investments.</li>
<li><strong>The Concept of Leveraged Investing:</strong>  James introduces the concept of leveraged investing, suggesting that borrowing at low interest rates to invest in high-return assets can be a sound strategy. For example, with loan interest rates at 2%-7% and potential asset appreciation of 10%-12%, leveraged investing can be more profitable in the long run. He illustrates this with a hypothetical example: If you have $1 million and spend $100,000 annually, your assets will remain at $1 million after ten years. However, if you borrow money to invest that $1 million, even after deducting annual expenses and 7% interest, your assets could grow to $30 million in 30 years, resulting in a net profit of over $20 million.</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">III. Q&amp;A Session 
    <div id="iii-qa-session" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii-qa-session" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p><strong>Mike:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Question: You use T-Mobile; why don&rsquo;t you have Starlink as a backup?</li>
<li>Answer: My apartment building doesn&rsquo;t allow Starlink installation, and the T-Mobile signal is generally good. Network interruptions are rare and usually resolved by restarting the router.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Mike:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Comment: Some YouTubers claim that the central bank ignores economic recessions.</li>
<li>Question: Is this true?</li>
<li>Answer: The central bank focuses on the unemployment rate, which is highly correlated with economic recessions.  Therefore, the central bank doesn&rsquo;t ignore recessions, but rather focuses on a different indicator.  Many YouTubers are not professional financial advisors; don&rsquo;t be misled.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Jason:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Question: Can I dollar-cost average into leveraged funds in my retirement account without rebalancing?</li>
<li>Answer: Your question indicates a misunderstanding of asset allocation.  Asset allocation and dollar-cost averaging are different concepts.  The correct buying strategy is &ldquo;buy when you have money.&rdquo; Leveraged funds are volatile and are better purchased in a lump sum.  The same applies to QQQ.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>PC:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Comment: A friend surrendered their investment-linked insurance policy and invested the proceeds in 00670L (2x leveraged ETF), recovering their losses within two weeks.</li>
<li>Summary: Don&rsquo;t be trapped by sunk costs. Cut your losses promptly and reallocate your assets effectively.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Wolf:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Question: I&rsquo;m ten years from retirement with limited retirement savings. Can I take advantage of market downturns to buy QLD in my Roth IRA and convert my 401k to cash?</li>
<li>Answer:  With limited Roth IRA funds, you should invest entirely in leveraged funds.  Hold an equivalent amount of cash in your 401k. For example, if you buy $100,000 of QLD, hold $100,000 in cash in your 401k. If your Roth IRA only has $30,000, invest it all in TQQQ and hold $60,000 cash in your 401k. This strategy aims for higher returns due to the Roth IRA&rsquo;s lower contribution limits.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>IAM:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Comment: The devaluation of the Malaysian currency brings to mind the impact of migration on currency, such as wealthy individuals from Hong Kong migrating. How does the US avoid currency devaluation, and do US companies benefit from the US dollar?</li>
<li>Answer: A country&rsquo;s currency value depends on its creditworthiness, which is backed by its industries and national strength.  The US has four pillars: government, finance, corporations, and national defense.  Whether US companies benefit from the dollar is uncertain, but they are undoubtedly protected by the US government.  James uses a hypothetical &ldquo;James currency&rdquo; (10 point) example:  The value of a currency depends on the issuer&rsquo;s services and creditworthiness.  For example, 10 points could be exchanged for a meal. If others recognize the value of the James currency, it can circulate.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>T:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Question: Do you still consider market cycles in your investing approach?</li>
<li>Answer: I will continue to discuss cycles, but cycle-based trades will be anticipated, potentially three months, six months, or even a year in advance, and may be incorrect. I will no longer advocate for all-in/all-out strategies, but rather adjusting Beta. This is because managing a large volume of funds from many individuals makes rapid market entry and exit difficult and prone to market impact.  It&rsquo;s better to invest the annual $7,000 contribution as a lump sum rather than in installments; long-term performance will likely be better.  Lump-sum investing in the US market has historically outperformed dollar-cost averaging or periodic investments.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>YJ:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Question: Why allocate to 00864B?  Why is 00757 no longer recommended?  What advice do you have for Taiwanese investors?</li>
<li>Answer: Asset allocation strategies are generally universal. 00864B is similar to a US dollar time deposit but carries exchange rate risk. Refer to the 2021-2022 videos for information on 00757. The main difference between investing in Taiwan and the US lies in pledging.  Maintain a loan-to-value ratio above 167%, avoid pledging all assets, and diversify pledges across multiple financial institutions to mitigate the risk of credit lines being reduced. For instance, if you have $50 million in assets, don&rsquo;t pledge all of it; start by pledging 1/3, enough to cover your needs, and seek other financial institutions for additional pledging needs. Taiwanese financial institutions have fluctuating credit lines, so be cautious.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Little John:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Question: Why borrow against assets instead of selling stocks?</li>
<li>Answer:  Pledging assets offers lower interest rates (2%-7%) compared to the potential for higher asset appreciation (10%-12%).  Using loans for investment is more cost-effective and avoids capital gains taxes from selling stocks.  Example: If you have $1 million and spend $100,000 annually, you&rsquo;ll still have $1 million after ten years. But if you borrow and invest, even after 30 years of expenses and interest payments, your assets could grow to $30 million, resulting in a net profit of over $20 million after paying off the loan.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Cristina:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Question: Questions about annuities and what to do with funds after selling a house.</li>
<li>Answer: Avoid annuities; surrender them if you have any.  Proceeds from a house sale cannot be put into an IRA or Roth IRA; they should be placed in a brokerage account.</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">IV. Key Takeaways 
    <div id="iv-key-takeaways" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv-key-takeaways" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>The central bank&rsquo;s primary focus is the unemployment rate; economic recession and unemployment are closely related.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>In response to Mike&rsquo;s question about the central bank&rsquo;s focus.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Asset allocation strategy and the amount of capital are distinct; the buying strategy is &ldquo;buy when you have the money.&rdquo;
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Addressing Jason&rsquo;s question about dollar-cost averaging into leveraged funds.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Don&rsquo;t be trapped by sunk costs; cut your losses promptly.
&ndash; PC</p>
</blockquote>
<p>PC shared an anecdote about a friend who cut losses on an investment and quickly recovered by investing in a leveraged ETF.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Timing the Market is always wrong.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>James repeatedly emphasized this point when students asked about market timing.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Hesitation is the worst thing in investing.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>James&rsquo;s response to Cristina&rsquo;s question about handling real estate sales.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">V. Conclusion 
    <div id="v-conclusion" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#v-conclusion" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This lecture reinforces James&rsquo;s consistent investment philosophy, emphasizing the importance of long-term, value-based investing and risk management. He uses clear language and relatable examples to answer students&rsquo; questions about asset allocation, insurance choices, retirement account investments, currency value, and real estate investments, tailoring his advice to the specific context of Taiwanese investors. He encourages the audience to ask questions, think critically, and develop personalized investment strategies based on their circumstances.</p>

  



<div
  
    class="flex px-4 py-3 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900"
  >

  <span
    
      class="text-primary-400 ltr:pr-3 rtl:pl-3 flex items-center"
    >

    

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M506.3 417l-213.3-364c-16.33-28-57.54-28-73.98 0l-213.2 364C-10.59 444.9 9.849 480 42.74 480h426.6C502.1 480 522.6 445 506.3 417zM232 168c0-13.25 10.75-24 24-24S280 154.8 280 168v128c0 13.25-10.75 24-23.1 24S232 309.3 232 296V168zM256 416c-17.36 0-31.44-14.08-31.44-31.44c0-17.36 14.07-31.44 31.44-31.44s31.44 14.08 31.44 31.44C287.4 401.9 273.4 416 256 416z"/></svg>

  </span>


  </span>

  <span
    
      class="dark:text-neutral-300"
    ><strong>Disclaimer:</strong> This article represents personal notes and should not be considered financial advice.</span>
</div>

]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
