<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Compound Interest on QQQ Investor</title>
    <link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/tags/compound-interest/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Compound Interest on QQQ Investor</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jomonylw.github.io/en/tags/compound-interest/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Personal Investment Bible: Investment Iron Law I</title>
      <link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1731056005960/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1731056005960/</guid>
      <description>This article criticizes the traditional financial concept of “saving money in the bank”.  It points out that under inflation, low bank deposit interest rates struggle to withstand erosion from inflation, effectively resulting in “the more you save, the less you have”. This viewpoint is supported by examples from biblical stories, savings rate data, and the Nobel Prize Foundation&amp;#39;s case, encouraging readers to invest their funds in long-term, high-return investment tools like stocks and real estate to achieve wealth appreciation.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[

<h2 class="relative group">Investment Iron Law I: Don&rsquo;t Keep Your Money in the Bank 
    <div id="investment-iron-law-i-dont-keep-your-money-in-the-bank" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#investment-iron-law-i-dont-keep-your-money-in-the-bank" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>The vast majority of people who fail at financial management don&rsquo;t do so because they don&rsquo;t earn enough,
but because they put their assets in the wrong place.
Have you ever heard of anyone getting rich from bank savings?</p>
</blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">Saving Equals Wasting Resources 
    <div id="saving-equals-wasting-resources" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#saving-equals-wasting-resources" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>There&rsquo;s a parable in the Bible about financial stewardship. A landowner entrusted his property to three servants. He gave the first servant five units of money, the second two, and the third one. He told them to cherish and manage their wealth wisely, and he would return in a year to see how they had fared.</p>
<p><strong>Wasting Time and Money</strong></p>
<p>The first servant invested his money; the second bought raw materials and produced goods to sell; the third, for safety, buried his money under a tree. A year later, the landowner returned.  The first two servants had doubled their wealth, pleasing the landowner.  Only the third servant&rsquo;s money remained unchanged. He explained, &ldquo;Fearing loss through mismanagement, I kept the money safe. Today, I return it untouched.&rdquo;</p>
<p>The landowner was furious.  &ldquo;You lazy servant!&rdquo; he scolded. &ldquo;You didn&rsquo;t even try to utilize your wealth!&rdquo;  Wealth not utilized is wasted money and wasted potential. The third servant was rebuked not for misusing the money, nor for losing it through failed investments, but for keeping it &ldquo;safe&rdquo; and unproductive.</p>
<p>Keeping money in the bank is the most common approach to personal finance today, and also the biggest mistake people make.  Therefore, the first and most important financial rule this book offers is: <em>Don&rsquo;t keep your money in the bank.</em>  &ldquo;Bank&rdquo; here refers to post offices, commercial banks, and any other financial institution where money can be deposited.</p>
<p>Many believe that earning interest in a bank, benefiting from compound interest, constitutes sound financial planning. In reality, with inflation, the real rate of return is close to zero, meaning no real financial gain. Therefore, leaving money in the bank is equivalent to no financial management at all.</p>
<p>It&rsquo;s impossible to predict how much wealth each person will accumulate through financial management. The only certainty is that getting rich solely through bank savings is incredibly difficult.  Ask yourself, &ldquo;Have you ever heard of anyone getting rich purely from bank deposits?&rdquo;  Those who keep all their savings in the bank often find themselves not only failing to become wealthy in their old age but also struggling to maintain financial independence. Such stories are common.  Those who choose bank deposits as their primary financial management method do so primarily for safety. However, readers must understand:  <strong>&ldquo;Money in the bank is safest in the short term, but the most dangerous form of financial management in the long term.&rdquo;</strong></p>
<p><strong>Blind Spots in Personal Finance</strong></p>
<p><em>Most people manage their finances by keeping their money in the bank, so most people are not wealthy.</em></p>
<p>If accumulating immense wealth were as easy as the examples suggest, then most people over 65 today would be millionaires. However, this is far from reality.  Millionaires over 65 are few and far between, with many senior citizens facing financial hardship, relying on continued work or support from their children to make ends meet.</p>
<p>Surveys on the elderly in Taiwan reveal increasingly serious financial challenges for senior citizens.  Among approximately 1.48 million people aged 65 and above, about 13% rely on financial assistance from family and friends or social welfare.  This demonstrates a serious problem with most people&rsquo;s financial concepts and investment methods. How else could they reach old age not only without wealth but without even basic financial independence?</p>
<p>Taiwan&rsquo;s savings rate has historically been above 30%, currently hovering between 20% and 30%, consistently ranking among the highest globally. This indicates excellent performance in saving and budgeting. Consequently, we can deduce that flawed financial management is the primary reason for the lack of financial independence among ordinary people. To understand where they go wrong, we must first observe how they handle their assets. In various lectures, I often ask the audience, &ldquo;How are your assets stored?&rdquo;  The majority answer: &ldquo;In the bank.&rdquo;</p>
<p><strong>Prioritizing Security over Investment</strong></p>
<p>Surveys on Taiwanese household investment preferences reveal that the top three investment choices are demand deposits (72%), rotating savings and credit associations (53%), and time deposits (36%). Clearly, most people lean towards traditional financial methods.  Furthermore, when asked, &ldquo;If you had 10 million Taiwan dollars in savings, how would you use it?&rdquo;, about 41% of surveyed households said they would deposit it in a financial institution to earn interest. This illustrates the widespread preference for bank savings.</p>
<p>Indeed, people have high savings rates and a strong preference for depositing money in financial institutions to earn interest.  In early 1996, total deposits in Taiwanese financial institutions reached 12.6 trillion Taiwan dollars.  With a population of 21 million, this translates to an average deposit of 600,000 Taiwan dollars per person, regardless of age.  For an average family of four, this amounts to 2.4 million Taiwan dollars.  This demonstrates a strong inclination towards bank savings. However, this traditional and conservative approach is the primary reason why most people fail to achieve wealth through investment.</p>
<p>This phenomenon reveals an over-reliance on traditional bank deposits for financial management. People prioritize safety and convenience over the rate of return. However, focusing solely on earning and saving money, then depositing it in a bank, is often the first step towards financial mismanagement.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Keeping money in the bank is like having no financial plan at all.</p>
</blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">Deposit Interest Rates Lack True Compound Interest Benefits 
    <div id="deposit-interest-rates-lack-true-compound-interest-benefits" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#deposit-interest-rates-lack-true-compound-interest-benefits" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>What&rsquo;s wrong with bank deposits? The problem lies in the low interest rates (return on investment), making them unsuitable for long-term investment tools.</p>
<p>How much interest can bank deposits earn?  The salaries of average office workers are usually directly deposited into demand deposit accounts (current interest rates around 2%-4%). A portion serves as temporary funds or covers daily expenses, while the remainder is transferred to time deposits (current interest rates around 5%-8%) for investment purposes. Thus, the average interest rate earned on bank deposits is about 5%.</p>
<p><strong>5% Interest is Hardly a Path to Wealth</strong></p>
<p>Most people have a basic understanding of compound interest, believing that interest earned on bank deposits, accumulating over time, can create substantial wealth. This misconception arises from a superficial understanding of compounding.  The vast differences in final returns resulting from different rates of return on the same principal over the same period often come as a surprise.</p>
<p>Let&rsquo;s illustrate with an example. Suppose someone saves 14,000 Taiwan dollars annually at the end of each year for 40 years, depositing everything into a bank account with an average interest rate of 5%. How much will they accumulate after 40 years? Before answering, recall the similar example from the previous section, but with the money in a bank instead of invested in stocks or real estate with an average annual return of 20%.</p>
<p>You might guess 25 million, 10 million, or even a conservative 5 million Taiwan dollars.  The correct answer, however, is only 1.69 million.  This can be calculated using the future value of an annuity formula:</p>
<p><math xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" display="block"><mtable displaystyle="true" columnalign="right center left" columnspacing="0 thickmathspace" rowspacing="3pt"><mtr><mtd><mn>14,000</mn><mo>×</mo><mfrac><mrow><msup><mrow><mo stretchy="false">(</mo><mn>1</mn><mo>+</mo><mn>0.05</mn><mo stretchy="false">)</mo></mrow><mrow><mn>40</mn></mrow></msup><mo>−</mo><mn>1</mn></mrow><mn>0.05</mn></mfrac></mtd><mtd><mi></mi><mo>=</mo></mtd><mtd><mn>1,690,000</mn></mtd></mtr><mtr><mtd><mn>14,000</mn><mo>×</mo><mfrac><mrow><msup><mrow><mo stretchy="false">(</mo><mn>1</mn><mo>+</mo><mn>0.20</mn><mo stretchy="false">)</mo></mrow><mrow><mn>40</mn></mrow></msup><mo>−</mo><mn>1</mn></mrow><mn>0.20</mn></mfrac></mtd><mtd><mi></mi><mo>=</mo></mtd><mtd><mn>102,810,000</mn></mtd></mtr></mtable></math></p>
<p>Let&rsquo;s compare this with the 20% return scenario.  The only difference between the two formulas is the rate of return (5% vs. 20%). A 20% return over 40 years yields 102.81 million Taiwan dollars, while a 5% return over the same period yields only 1.69 million, less than a fraction of the former. The difference is over 60 times! This illustrates the power of compound interest.  Many assume they benefit from compound interest in a bank, but at a 5% return, even with compounding over a long period, the wealth creation effect is very limited.</p>
<p>This example demonstrates that one of the keys to successful financial management is the rate of return. The key is not just whether your assets are invested, but <em>where</em> they are invested and what the rate of return is.</p>
<ul>
<li>
<ol>
<li>The key to financial management lies in how your assets are allocated. The rate of return has a decisive impact on your future wealth.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol start="2">
<li>While bank savings provide interest income and the benefit of compounding,  you&rsquo;ll find that as you age, bank deposits contribute little to overall wealth growth.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol start="3">
<li>The first step towards building wealth through investment is to allocate assets to investments with high long-term rates of return.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol start="4">
<li>&ldquo;Financial Management&rdquo; is a significant factor contributing to wealth disparity in society.</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>Inflation makes money worth less and less.</p>
</blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">The Invisible Killer of Currency Value: Inflation 
    <div id="the-invisible-killer-of-currency-value-inflation" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#the-invisible-killer-of-currency-value-inflation" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>Forty years ago, a millionaire was truly wealthy.  Today, a millionaire might struggle to afford a house. Why?  Inflation.  Every investor must consider the impact of inflation.</p>
<p><em>Inflation reduces the purchasing power of money and lowers the real rate of return, diminishing the effect of wealth accumulation.</em></p>
<p>Over the past 30 years, the average annual inflation rate in Taiwan has been around 5%. What about the future?  Inflation and economic growth are closely linked. As Taiwan&rsquo;s economy continues to grow, inflation is expected to remain around 5% annually.</p>
<p>Inflation means continuously rising prices, which translates to decreasing purchasing power.  If you keep your money in a demand deposit account earning 4% interest with a 5% inflation rate, what happens?  Your purchasing power decreases.  The longer your money sits in a savings account, the less it&rsquo;s worth.  What used to cost 10 Taiwan dollars for a newspaper now costs 15. Your 10 dollars can now only buy two-thirds of a newspaper. With inflation, money in the bank shrinks like wool submerged in water.</p>
<p><strong>Saving Alone Won&rsquo;t Make You Rich, Not Even in Two Lifetimes</strong></p>
<p>With 5% inflation and a nominal interest rate of around 5% on bank deposits, your real rate of return is zero. In this scenario, the effect of compound interest is nullified.  Wealth accumulation relies solely on painstaking saving. Imagine someone saves 500,000 Taiwan dollars a year. How long would it take to become a billionaire?  200 years!</p>
<p>Saving 500,000 Taiwan dollars a year is difficult; living for 200 years is even harder!  Therefore, even with diligent saving and budgeting, if all the money is kept in the bank, this person won&rsquo;t become wealthy in this lifetime, and worse, not even in the next! The average lifespan is around 75 years, meaning two lifetimes total only 150 years.  It would take a third lifetime for someone relying solely on bank savings to potentially reach billionaire status.  If a family maintains the financial strategy of &ldquo;frugality and bank savings,&rdquo; it would take at least 200 years, or about seven generations, for them to potentially become wealthy.  Conversely, with proper financial management, wealth can be achieved in 40 years (half a lifetime).</p>
<p><strong>Money in the Bank Should Be Spent Sooner Rather Than Later</strong></p>
<p>I remember 30 years ago, when I was in second or third grade, a popsicle cost 20 cents, and a red bean ice cream cost 50 cents.  My parents gave me 50 cents each day for allowance, which I invariably spent on red bean ice cream after school. My parents constantly encouraged me to save, so my father opened a bank account for me. If I had been obedient and developed good saving habits from a young age, saving those 50 cents daily and earning 8% interest, it would have grown tenfold over 30 years, to 5 Taiwan dollars.  However, a red bean ice cream now costs 15 Taiwan dollars. Those 5 dollars can only buy one-third of a red bean ice cream. More importantly, for a小学生 30 years ago, a red bean ice cream was precious.  Even a dozen red bean ice creams today couldn&rsquo;t compare to the value of one back then. Had I followed my parents&rsquo; financial advice and kept my money in the bank, I would regret it now.</p>
<p>Therefore, if you&rsquo;re going to keep money in the bank, my sincere advice is: &ldquo;Spend it sooner rather than later!&rdquo; This might sound shocking, but there&rsquo;s logic to it.  From an economic perspective, money has more value and higher utility when used sooner. We save money in the bank, delaying gratification for the sake of greater enjoyment in the future.  However, with inflation, money left in the bank often leads to <em>less</em> enjoyment.</p>
<p><strong>The Value of Money Decreases with Age</strong></p>
<p>My wife and her friends developed a financial philosophy: &ldquo;Money is most valuable when spent while young.&rdquo; This makes economic sense.  Their reasoning: &ldquo;When you&rsquo;re old, delicacies might harm your health, traveling becomes difficult, and most importantly, wearing beautiful clothes attracts unwanted attention and ridicule.&rdquo;</p>
<p>Thus, everyone managing their finances must be mindful of the dual pressures of inflation and the diminishing value of money with age. Bank deposit interest rates cannot compensate for these losses. In other words, <strong>money in the bank, while nominally increasing, actually decreases in value.</strong></p>
<p>Of course, I&rsquo;m not encouraging you to spend all your savings immediately.  Rather, I&rsquo;m highlighting that if you keep money in the bank, you must consider the declining purchasing power due to inflation and the reduced economic benefit as you age.  The fundamental solution is to withdraw your money from the bank and invest it in instruments with higher returns than bank deposit rates. <strong>Therefore, the best way to combat inflation is: Don&rsquo;t keep your money in the bank. Invest in long-term, high-return assets like stocks and real estate.</strong></p>
<p>Because inflation decreases real returns and hinders wealth accumulation, even saving 14,000 Taiwan dollars annually and investing in stocks or real estate for 40 years to become a billionaire won&rsquo;t carry the same weight as being a billionaire today.  Therefore, under inflation, consider using the <em>real</em> rate of return. If the return on investment is 20% and inflation is 5%, the real return is 15%.  So how much should you save annually, investing in stocks or real estate with a nominal return of around 20% (real return of 15%), to become a billionaire in 40 years?  The answer is 57,000 Taiwan dollars per year.</p>
<p><math xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" display="block"><mn>57,000</mn><mo>×</mo><mfrac><mrow><msup><mrow><mo stretchy="false">(</mo><mn>1</mn><mo>+</mo><mn>0.15</mn><mo stretchy="false">)</mo></mrow><mrow><mn>40</mn></mrow></msup><mo>−</mo><mn>1</mn></mrow><mn>0.15</mn></mfrac><mo>=</mo><mn>101,410,000</mn><mspace linebreak="newline"></mspace></math></p>
<blockquote>
<p>A small step today makes a world of difference tomorrow.</p>
</blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">The Path to Wealth of Chang Pin-san, Former Chairman of Chang Hwa Bank 
    <div id="the-path-to-wealth-of-chang-pin-san-former-chairman-of-chang-hwa-bank" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#the-path-to-wealth-of-chang-pin-san-former-chairman-of-chang-hwa-bank" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>Chang Po-hsin, the current standing director of Chang Hwa Bank, with assets exceeding tens of billions, inherited and expanded upon the fortune of his father, Chang Pin-san, the former chairman of Chang Hwa Bank, earning him a place among Taiwan&rsquo;s wealthiest individuals.</p>
<p><strong>Trading Bank Deposits for Stock Dividends</strong></p>
<p>Forty years ago, both Chang Pin-san and my father were from Nantun District, Taichung City.  They were not only fellow townsmen but also colleagues. Back then, Chang Pin-san was just a junior manager at Chang Hwa Bank, without much wealth.  However, he borrowed money to buy Chang Hwa Bank shares from colleagues who wanted to sell them. At the time, stock dividends were far lower than bank interest. Despite this, Chang Pin-san persisted in borrowing money to acquire shares, holding onto them for the long term.  Other colleagues deposited the proceeds from their stock sales into banks. Years later, Chang Pin-san, owning the most shares, became the largest shareholder and eventually the chairman of Chang Hwa Bank, laying the foundation for his immense wealth.</p>
<p>Chang Pin-san was also friends with Lien Chen-tung, father of Lien Chan, and encouraged him to buy Chang Hwa Bank shares. The Lien family&rsquo;s fortune also originated from those hundreds of Chang Hwa Bank shares.</p>
<p>It&rsquo;s hard to believe that the path to wealth could be so simple: borrow money to buy a few Chang Hwa Bank shares, invest in some real estate, hold them long-term, and essentially forget about them.  Decades later, great wealth is attained. Those who sold their shares and deposited the money in banks are still wondering how others became rich. Some might attribute this to luck, but financial management is not about luck.  It&rsquo;s about the method chosen and the investment tools selected.  Therefore, if you don&rsquo;t want to be poor, don&rsquo;t keep your money in the bank.</p>
<p><strong>Bank Savings Shouldn&rsquo;t Exceed Living Expenses</strong></p>
<p>Someone once jokingly asked me, &ldquo;You&rsquo;re telling us not to keep money in the bank.  Are we supposed to pay with stocks or real estate certificates at the supermarket or restaurant?&rdquo; Of course not!  Advising against keeping money in the bank doesn&rsquo;t mean you can&rsquo;t have any money in the bank at all. Bank deposits offer advantages: security and convenience. They are ideal for storing funds needed for daily expenses. However, you can&rsquo;t have your cake and eat it too.  Convenience comes at the cost of high returns.</p>
<p>The wise approach is to clearly divide funds into two categories: daily expenses and investments.  Keep enough for daily needs in the bank, enjoying the security and convenience it offers. Invest the rest in higher-return assets like stocks and real estate.</p>
<p>In my opinion, keeping the equivalent of two months&rsquo; living expenses in the bank is sufficient for an individual or family. Most individuals and families receive regular income, which is deposited into their bank accounts. Therefore, one month&rsquo;s expenses for immediate use and another month&rsquo;s worth as a safety net should be ample.  The remaining funds should be invested in higher-return assets like stocks and real estate.  In other words, if your monthly expenses average 50,000 Taiwan dollars, and your bank balance consistently exceeds 100,000, you are not managing your finances effectively.  Actively seek suitable investment opportunities to make your surplus funds work for you.</p>
<p><strong>The &ldquo;Two Big, One Small&rdquo; Approach to Flexible Fund Management</strong></p>
<p>Some believe in maintaining substantial emergency funds. However, even if unforeseen circumstances drain your bank savings, there&rsquo;s no need to panic. The high-return investments mentioned earlier—stocks and real estate—are not as illiquid as some might think.  Listed stocks in Taiwan&rsquo;s active stock market can be sold almost any day of the year (excluding holidays), providing quick access to cash within a few days.  Reluctant to sell? Stocks can also be used as collateral for loans.</p>
<p>Real estate is less liquid than stocks, but many Taiwanese banks now offer &ldquo;revolving mortgage loans,&rdquo; allowing property owners to convert fixed assets into liquid assets. These loans involve mortgaging a property to secure a credit line of up to 70%-75% of the property&rsquo;s value. Borrowers can draw and repay funds as needed, with interest accruing only on the outstanding balance. For example, a 10 million Taiwan dollar property could secure a 7.5 million credit line.  Borrowing 5 million leaves 2.5 million available without interest charges, with interest accruing only on the 5 million borrowed.  Any surplus funds can be used to repay the loan, reducing interest costs.</p>
<p>Many financial experts recommend a &ldquo;three-part&rdquo; approach, dividing assets equally among bank savings, real estate, and more speculative investments. I propose a &ldquo;two big, one small&rdquo; approach: allocate most of your assets to stocks and real estate, keeping a small portion in a bank for daily expenses.  This isn&rsquo;t my invention. In fact, this is the portfolio strategy employed by many who have achieved wealth through investments.</p>
<ul>
<li>
<ol>
<li>Keeping money in the bank is the riskiest form of financial management.  Inflation erodes returns, leaving real interest rates near zero.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol start="2">
<li>Banks offer convenience, not high returns.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol start="3">
<li>Keep only two months&rsquo; worth of living expenses in the bank.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol start="4">
<li>Trying to get rich with money in the bank is like trying to win a baseball game without swinging the bat.</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ul>
<p>If all this hasn&rsquo;t convinced you to reconsider keeping most of your money in a financial institution, perhaps the story of the Nobel Prize Foundation&rsquo;s success might change your mind.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Change your asset management perspective, change your financial destiny.</p>
</blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">Lessons from the Nobel Prize Foundation 
    <div id="lessons-from-the-nobel-prize-foundation" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#lessons-from-the-nobel-prize-foundation" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>Every October, the Nobel Committee announces the Nobel laureates. The Nobel Prize attracts global attention not only for representing the highest academic honor but also because each laureate receives a substantial prize of 1 million US dollars.</p>
<p><strong>The Folly of Depleting Capital</strong></p>
<p>The Nobel Foundation awards several prizes annually, disbursing millions of dollars. This raises the question: How large is the Nobel fund to sustain such substantial payouts? The Nobel Foundation&rsquo;s success, besides the substantial initial donation by Alfred Nobel over a century ago, is largely attributed to its shrewd financial management.</p>
<p>Established in 1896 with a 9.8 million US dollar donation from Nobel, the foundation&rsquo;s purpose is to fund the prizes.  Flawless fund management was paramount.  Initially, its charter stipulated that investments be restricted to safe, fixed-income instruments like bank deposits and government bonds, explicitly excluding stocks and real estate to avoid market risks.</p>
<p>This capital preservation approach, prioritizing safety over returns, seemed prudent, preventing losses. However, sacrificing returns had consequences.  After 50 years of prize payouts and operating expenses, low returns depleted two-thirds of the Nobel fund, leaving only a little over 3 million US dollars by 1953.</p>
<p><strong>From 3 Million to 270 Million: The Secret</strong></p>
<p>Facing depletion, the Nobel Foundation&rsquo;s board recognized the importance of investment returns. In 1953, they made a groundbreaking change, amending the charter to shift from bank deposits and bonds to primarily stocks and real estate.  This shift in investment philosophy transformed the foundation&rsquo;s fate. Over the next 40 years, despite continued prize payouts and operating costs, the foundation not only recovered all previous losses but also grew its assets to 270 million US dollars by 1993.</p>
<p><em>Nobel Prize Foundation Asset Growth and Decline</em></p>
<table>
  <thead>
      <tr>
          <th style="text-align: left">Year</th>
          <th style="text-align: left">Total Assets (Million USD)</th>
          <th style="text-align: left">Remarks</th>
      </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
      <tr>
          <td style="text-align: left">1896</td>
          <td style="text-align: left">9.8</td>
          <td style="text-align: left">Foundation Established</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td style="text-align: left">1953</td>
          <td style="text-align: left">3.3</td>
          <td style="text-align: left">Investment Charter Amended</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td style="text-align: left">1993</td>
          <td style="text-align: left">270</td>
          <td style="text-align: left"></td>
      </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>
<p>Had the Nobel Foundation not changed its approach 40 years ago, clinging to bank savings, it would have vanished, unable to fund the prizes.  Perhaps other wealthy individuals would have established new foundations with larger prizes, replacing the Nobel Prize.</p>
<p>The Nobel Foundation&rsquo;s history underscores the importance of financial management.  Even a substantial initial fund, if mismanaged, can be depleted. Conversely, even with significant spending, skillful management can generate rapid growth.</p>
<p>I once heard of a Taiwanese hometown association that established a foundation with 100,000 Taiwan dollars 40 years ago to provide scholarships for children from their hometown.  Forty years later, the fund remains at 100,000 Taiwan dollars. While a significant sum back then, today it barely covers administrative costs, threatening the foundation&rsquo;s existence.  The problem? Neglecting financial management.</p>
<p>Learning from the Nobel Foundation, many US foundations, pension funds, university endowments, and even personal trusts have shifted from bank deposits and bonds to primarily stocks and real estate. In contrast, few Taiwanese foundations grasp this concept, and university endowments rarely address financial management seriously.  The fate of these foundations, if they don&rsquo;t adapt, is clear.</p>
<p>I often participate in corporate training programs, where I habitually ask companies about the size and investment strategy of their employee welfare funds.  The answers are usually similar: small funds, mostly in bank deposits, rarely exceeding a few hundred thousand or a million Taiwan dollars. However, in 1990, during my time at China Development Corporation, the employee welfare fund exceeded 200 million Taiwan dollars. Why?  Because it was primarily invested in China Development Corporation&rsquo;s own stock.</p>
<ul>
<li>
<ol>
<li>The Nobel Foundation&rsquo;s course correction 40 years ago secured its status today.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol start="2">
<li>Prioritizing security above all else leads to asset depletion.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol start="3">
<li>The growth and decline of wealth for individuals, families, businesses, or other entities depends on their investment strategy.</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ul>
<p>Will your hard-earned wealth shrink like the early Nobel fund, or grow like the later one? The key lies in <em>how</em> you invest. If, like many, you keep most of your money in the bank, it&rsquo;s not too late to change. The Nobel Foundation&rsquo;s story shows how a change in investment philosophy can transform everything.  Should you reconsider your financial habits and prioritize investments in stocks and real estate? Let the Nobel Foundation inspire your financial thinking. A single change in mindset can lead to immense wealth decades from now!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Personal Investment Bible: The Correct Concept of Financial Management</title>
      <link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1731056005959/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1731056005959/</guid>
      <description>This article explores the correct concept of financial management, pointing out that investment is the key to wealth, rather than simply relying on increasing income and reducing expenditure.  Using the wealth comparison between Koo Chen-fu and Koo Li-hsiung, the financial management methods of the Lien Chan family, and an example of becoming a billionaire by investing $1,200 monthly for 40 years, the article illustrates the importance of investment and emphasizes the power of compound interest.  Furthermore, it analyzes the impact of financial habits on the wealth gap and how to educate the next generation to establish a correct concept of financial management, suggesting incorporating “Don&amp;#39;t keep money in the bank” into family precepts to cultivate investment awareness from an early age.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[

<h2 class="relative group">The Correct Concept of Financial Management 
    <div id="the-correct-concept-of-financial-management" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#the-correct-concept-of-financial-management" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>The key to winning the wealth race lies not in the starting point, but in choosing the right track.</p>
</blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">Investment Leads to Wealth 
    <div id="investment-leads-to-wealth" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#investment-leads-to-wealth" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>The Chinatrust Financial Holding Co., one of the top five conglomerates in Taiwan, was led by Koo Chen-fu, chairman of the Koo&rsquo;s Group, and Jeffrey Koo, chairman of Chinatrust Commercial Bank. The Koo&rsquo;s Group encompassed seven major business segments: finance, manufacturing, construction, hotels, media, services, and overseas operations, with over 50 affiliated companies and total assets exceeding NT$460 billion. Many wondered how this uncle-nephew duo achieved both political and business success, and who was wealthier.</p>
<p><strong>The Wealth Race Between Koo Chen-fu and Jeffrey Koo</strong></p>
<p>Wealth often correlates with personality. Koo Chen-fu was a slow and steady type, while Jeffrey Koo was more of a go-getter.  Due to their vastly different personalities, their investment approaches also differed significantly.  Koo Chen-fu&rsquo;s eldest son, Eugene Koo, the general manager of China Life Insurance in Taiwan, understood them well. He once said, &ldquo;Money put in Koo Chen-fu&rsquo;s pocket would never come out, but money put in Jeffrey Koo&rsquo;s pocket would disappear.&rdquo;  This was because Jeffrey Koo continuously reinvested his money, leading to greater wealth accumulation than his uncle. Jeffrey Koo&rsquo;s personal assets were spread across the US and Japan, invested in real estate, funds, hotels, golf courses, and banks.  Koo Chen-fu, in his 80s, was quite conservative. Regarding his financial management philosophy, he said, &ldquo;I neglect financial management and don&rsquo;t want to worry about money.&rdquo;  His personal income was deposited in the bank by his secretary, and aside from necessary expenses, the rest was converted into fixed-term deposits.</p>
<p>Over the years, Koo Chen-fu naturally had more cash on hand, as his money remained in the bank. However, in terms of wealth creation, Jeffrey Koo far surpassed him. Despite a 17-year age difference, with proper investment, one could still come out ahead.</p>
<p><strong>Investing $1,200 Monthly Can Make You a Billionaire in 40 Years</strong></p>
<p><em>It&rsquo;s not what you don&rsquo;t know that gets you into trouble. It&rsquo;s what you know for sure that just ain&rsquo;t so.</em></p>
<p>The first concept to understand about investment is: <strong>Investment not only improves financial situations but also allows anyone to achieve wealth.</strong></p>
<p>Let&rsquo;s illustrate with a simple example:</p>
<p>Suppose a young person with no savings starts saving NT$14,000 annually for 40 years.  If this money is invested in stocks or real estate with an average annual return of 20%, how much wealth will they accumulate after 40 years?</p>
<p>The author often asks this question in lectures. Most guesses range from NT$2 million to NT$8 million, with a maximum of NT$10 million. The correct answer, however, is a surprising NT$102.81 million!  For a 25-year-old, saving NT$14,000 annually (equivalent to $1,200 monthly) for 40 years, with a total investment of NT$560,000, could result in becoming a billionaire by age 65, assuming a 20% annual return in stocks or real estate.</p>
<p>This figure is calculated using the future value of an annuity formula in finance and investment. The calculation is as follows:</p>
<p><math xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" display="block"><mn>1.4</mn><mo>×</mo><mfrac><mrow><msup><mrow><mo stretchy="false">(</mo><mn>1</mn><mo>+</mo><mn>0.20</mn><mo stretchy="false">)</mo></mrow><mrow><mn>40</mn></mrow></msup><mo>−</mo><mn>1</mn></mrow><mn>0.20</mn></mfrac><mo>=</mo><mn>10281</mn><mspace linebreak="newline"></mspace></math>
(Units are in NT$10,000)</p>
<p>This formula illustrates how small amounts of money can grow significantly through investment.  Understanding the formula isn&rsquo;t crucial; most people who become billionaires through investment don&rsquo;t know it, and knowing it doesn&rsquo;t guarantee success.</p>
<p>Therefore, with youth, ambition, investment knowledge, and three key factors—saving NT$14,000 annually, investing in stocks or real estate, and patiently waiting for 40 years—anyone can achieve wealth through investment, regardless of their current economic situation.  These three factors are attainable for everyone:</p>
<ol>
<li>
<p>Saving NT$14,000 annually (NT$1,200 monthly) should be manageable for most. (If you can&rsquo;t save this much, focus on saving before investing. This book may not be as helpful yet, as you need some capital to start investing.)</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Historically, the long-term average return on stocks and real estate has been above 20%.  Consistently investing in these assets and holding them long-term can yield a 20% average return. These investment tools are accessible to everyone. (Data shows that the Taiwan stock market has averaged around 20% annual returns over the past 20 years; studies show similar returns for Taiwan real estate over the past 40 years.)</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>40 years seems long, but it&rsquo;s a timeframe most people have.  Starting work between 20 and 25 and retiring at 65 provides a 40-year investment window.  While some are born rich and others poor, most have a fair chance at accumulating wealth over 40 years.</p>
</li>
</ol>
<p>This example shows that investment not only improves finances but also provides a path to wealth.  With the right concepts and practices, anyone can achieve wealth through investment.</p>
<p><strong>Smart Investing Can Shorten the Journey by 10 Years</strong></p>
<p>While the initial example uses 40 years to demonstrate the power of investing, most readers are likely in a better position. They may already have savings and can save more than NT$14,000 annually, shortening their path to wealth.</p>
<p>The table below illustrates the wealth accumulation over 10-year intervals using the previous example (investing NT$14,000 annually with a 20% return):</p>
<p>If you have NT$360,000, congratulations! You&rsquo;ve saved 10 years of effort. By continuing to invest in stocks or real estate, you could become a billionaire in 30 years. With NT$2.61 million, you&rsquo;ve saved 20 years. With NT$16.55 million, you&rsquo;re even closer, needing only 10 more years.</p>
<table>
  <thead>
      <tr>
          <th style="text-align: left">Investment Years</th>
          <th style="text-align: left">Accumulated Amount (NT$10,000)</th>
          <th style="text-align: left">Amount Accumulated in the Last Decade (NT$10,000)</th>
      </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
      <tr>
          <td style="text-align: left">10</td>
          <td style="text-align: left">36</td>
          <td style="text-align: left">36</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td style="text-align: left">20</td>
          <td style="text-align: left">261</td>
          <td style="text-align: left">225</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td style="text-align: left">30</td>
          <td style="text-align: left">1655</td>
          <td style="text-align: left">1394</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td style="text-align: left">40</td>
          <td style="text-align: left">10281</td>
          <td style="text-align: left">8626</td>
      </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>
<p>Most readers likely have some savings, allowing them to achieve significant wealth in 20-30 years.</p>
<p><strong>Investing Doesn&rsquo;t Require Advanced Knowledge</strong></p>
<p><em>The trouble with the world is not that people know too little, but that they know so many things that just aren&rsquo;t so.</em></p>
<p>Many believe investing requires perfect timing and extensive financial knowledge.  This isn&rsquo;t entirely true.  After years of studying investment, and witnessing ordinary people achieve wealth through it, I can confidently say that investment success doesn&rsquo;t depend on academic qualifications, intelligence, technical skills, or predictive abilities.  It depends on doing the right things. Successful investors aren&rsquo;t necessarily highly educated or technically skilled; they can be ordinary people who understand fundamental principles.</p>
<p>By doing the right things, anyone can achieve wealth through investment, regardless of their background or effort. Investing doesn&rsquo;t require genius or specialized knowledge; common sense and consistent action are key. Investors don&rsquo;t need to rely on experts; with the right mindset, you can outperform them.</p>
<p>Investing isn&rsquo;t about complex techniques; it&rsquo;s about having the right mindset.  Successful investors simply cultivate habits that most people find uncomfortable or difficult to maintain. Do you understand that investing can create wealth? If so, are you actively pursuing it?</p>
<p>From another perspective, investing can be challenging. The difficulty lies not in needing advanced knowledge, but in going against ingrained habits. This is difficult for most people.</p>
<p>This book presents seemingly simple investment concepts, but wealth is built through consistent, correct habits. Start your investment journey by building the right habits!</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The amount of money you accumulate in your lifetime depends not on how much you earn, but on how you manage it.</p>
</blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">Saving Alone Is Not Enough 
    <div id="saving-alone-is-not-enough" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#saving-alone-is-not-enough" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>A Taiwanese proverb says, &ldquo;People have two legs, money has four.&rdquo; Money chases money faster than people chase money.</p>
<p>Traditional wisdom dictates that &ldquo;the path to wealth lies in diligence and frugality.&rdquo;  This held true in times of economic stagnation, but in today&rsquo;s rapidly changing economy, this mindset requires adjustment.</p>
<p>A century ago, before modern economics became widespread, during periods of economic stagnation and frequent wars, saving was indeed crucial for wealth accumulation. Today, however, with global economic growth and soaring stock and real estate prices, the focus should shift from saving to leveraging the power of compound interest for exponential growth.</p>
<p><strong>How Did Lien Chan Become Wealthy?</strong></p>
<p><em>With so many assets, it&rsquo;s impossible to monitor everything closely. During the period of entrusted management, the principle was to hold existing investments and not trade stocks or dispose of real estate.</em></p>
<p>Lien Chan, with an estimated net worth of nearly NT$6 billion, was one of Taiwan&rsquo;s wealthiest officials. His wealth wasn&rsquo;t accumulated through decades of frugal living on a government salary or through earning a doctoral degree.  It stemmed from his mother&rsquo;s shift in investment strategy over 40 years prior.</p>
<p>Around 1951, Chang Pin-san, former chairman of Chang Hwa Bank, advised Lien Chan&rsquo;s father, Lien Chen-tung, to invest in shares of the &ldquo;Big Three&rdquo; commercial banks.  Following this advice, Lien Chan&rsquo;s mother, Chao Lan-kun, invested her savings in hundreds of shares of Chang Hwa Bank, holding them long-term and letting their value appreciate naturally. This laid the foundation for the Lien family&rsquo;s fortune. Chao Lan-kun had a keen financial mind. Unlike other women who participated in rotating savings and credit associations or simply deposited money in banks, she actively invested.  She sold ancestral farmland in Miaoli and co-developed a property on Nanjing West Road with Huang Lie-huo, founder of Wei Chuan Foods Corporation, splitting the profits. This prime real estate became a significant source of wealth for the Lien family.</p>
<p>Stocks, real estate, and land were the Lien family&rsquo;s wealth-generating tools. Over the years, Lien Chan accumulated holdings in 19 different stocks, including Chang Hwa Bank, Taipei Business Bank, Hua Nan Bank, and Cathay Life Insurance.  His real estate holdings were located in prime areas like the Da&rsquo;an, Shilin, and Zhongshan districts, including 11 plots of land and 26 properties.</p>
<p>Lien Chan once described his family&rsquo;s investment approach as &ldquo;Wu Wei Er Zhi&rdquo; (doing nothing and achieving everything), meaning buying and holding long-term.  By investing in stocks and real estate 40 years ago and patiently holding them, with minimal trading and benefiting from annual returns exceeding 20%, they amassed a fortune nearing NT$10 billion.</p>
<p>You might argue that the Lien family was already wealthy 40 years ago. This might be true, but the point is that while they were prominent, many families in Taiwan were wealthier back then. Today, very few families surpass the Liens in wealth.  This is attributed to their early adoption of the correct investment strategy – focusing on stocks and real estate.</p>
<p><strong>The Key to Wealth Lies in Financial Management, Not Just Saving</strong></p>
<p><em>The ability to earn money is less important than having a mind for financial management, understanding how to make money work for you.</em></p>
<p>Chinese culture values diligence and frugality.  Older generations often teach younger ones that the path to wealth lies in these principles and careful budgeting.  The saying &ldquo;Great wealth comes from heaven, small wealth from frugality&rdquo; encourages thriftiness, as it&rsquo;s seen as the key to wealth.  This emphasis on saving is reflected in Taiwan&rsquo;s high savings rate.  However, I want to convey a crucial message: while saving is important, financial management is even more so.</p>
<p>In the previous example, how much of the NT$100+ million fortune came from diligence and frugality? The answer is NT$560,000, accumulated by saving NT$14,000 annually for 40 years.  This represents only 0.5% of the total.  The remaining 99.5% came from investment, specifically the power of compound interest at a 20% annual return over 40 years.  Which is more important, saving or investing? <strong>Therefore, lifetime wealth accumulation depends not on how much you earn, but on how you manage your money.</strong></p>
<p>If a worker realizes in old age that their wealth primarily comes from a lifetime of hard work and saving, it&rsquo;s almost certain they won&rsquo;t be very wealthy.  The key to wealth through investment isn&rsquo;t the ability to &ldquo;earn and save,&rdquo; but the ability to leverage the &ldquo;compounding power of money.&rdquo;  For most, improving their financial situation requires focusing on investment, not just saving.</p>
<p>Consider this: saving NT$1 million annually without investing would take 100 years to reach NT$100 million. In contrast, investing NT$14,000 annually could make you a billionaire in 40 years. If Chao Lan-kun had only focused on saving and not investing, would the Lien family be as wealthy as they are today?</p>
<p>I&rsquo;m not dismissing the importance of saving, but I want to emphasize that it shouldn&rsquo;t overshadow investment. Investment plays a crucial role in wealth accumulation.  For successful investors, wealth comes primarily from &ldquo;making money work for you,&rdquo; not from earning or saving. Therefore, in addition to being diligent and frugal, learn how to invest.</p>
<p>To improve your financial situation, remember: earning is important, but managing your money is more so. <strong>A correct investment mindset and wise investment choices have a greater impact on your future financial status than your current wealth or future income.</strong> For most, the first step towards improving their finances is not to increase saving, but to understand the correct investment concepts and take action.</p>
<p><em>1. For those who achieve wealth through investment, their fortune comes primarily from making money work for them, not from earning or saving.</em></p>
<p><em>2.  Less than 1% of a NT$100 million fortune comes directly from earned income.</em></p>
<p><em>3.  Investment is not a technique, but a mindset.</em></p>
<p><em>4. The key to financial management is having money to manage, not the amount of money.</em></p>
<blockquote>
<p>Those who learn to invest are like having a money-printing machine.</p>
</blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">How Investment Strategies Create the Wealth Gap 
    <div id="how-investment-strategies-create-the-wealth-gap" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#how-investment-strategies-create-the-wealth-gap" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>A study indicates that in recent years, the public has perceived a serious wealth gap in Taiwan, with a trend towards wealth polarization. Over 47% of respondents believe that &ldquo;speculation in stocks or real estate&rdquo; is the main cause of this widening gap, followed by &ldquo;personal work ability and effort&rdquo; (14%) and &ldquo;family background&rdquo; (11%).  This suggests a common belief that the wealth gap isn&rsquo;t solely due to individual effort, but also to systemic issues, luck, and unequal opportunities.</p>
<p>Indeed, &ldquo;stocks and real estate&rdquo; are major contributors to the wealth gap, while &ldquo;personal work ability and effort&rdquo; and &ldquo;family background&rdquo; have less impact. <strong>People often attribute their poverty to external factors like systemic issues, luck, or lack of opportunity, or use negative terms like &ldquo;speculation&rdquo; to explain their lack of action.</strong> Wealthy individuals often accumulate their wealth through real estate or stock investments, not primarily through &ldquo;speculation,&rdquo; but through &ldquo;holding appropriate investment assets.&rdquo;</p>
<p>Looking ahead, the wealth gap will likely continue to widen. Some will benefit, while others will suffer, depending on their ability to navigate the changing landscape. External factors alone don&rsquo;t determine our financial situation; our investment abilities play a crucial role.</p>
<p><em>1. Financial habits create the difference between the rich and the poor.</em></p>
<p><em>2. The prerequisite for building wealth through investment is allocating assets to high-return investments like stocks or real estate.</em></p>
<p><em>3. One way for the government to address the widening wealth gap is to educate the public about proper financial management.</em></p>
<p><strong>Greater Investment, Greater Returns</strong></p>
<p><em>&ldquo;Thoughts change actions, actions change habits, habits change character, and character changes destiny.&rdquo;</em></p>
<p>Imagine two classmates who join the same company after graduation, holding similar positions with the same salary.  Both are equally frugal, saving NT$14,000 annually for investment. The difference lies in their approach: one keeps their savings in the bank, while the other invests in stocks. Both largely leave their money untouched after depositing or investing it.</p>
<p>After 40 years, the stock investor becomes a billionaire, while the bank saver becomes a &ldquo;millionaire.&rdquo;  While a billion represents significant wealth, &ldquo;millionaire&rdquo; now evokes laughter, being synonymous with &ldquo;homeless&rdquo; in Taiwan&rsquo;s expensive housing market.</p>
<p>The &ldquo;millionaire&rdquo; classmate, seeing their former colleague with the same starting conditions become a billionaire, might assume foul play or lottery winnings. How could their wealth differ so drastically, with one rich and the other struggling?</p>
<p>Those with less wealth often attribute the success of the wealthy to luck or illicit activities. A more positive view might be that they worked harder or were more frugal.  However, they often overlook the critical factor: financial habits. The rich and poor manage their money differently: the rich hold assets like real estate and stocks, while the poor keep their money in the bank.</p>
<p>To become wealthy through investment, one must break free from conventional thinking. An adult who couldn&rsquo;t ride a bicycle saw a child doing so and complained, &ldquo;Only agile children can ride bikes.&rdquo; The child responded, &ldquo;Agility isn&rsquo;t necessary,&rdquo; and taught the adult to ride.  The adult quickly learned but, upon parting ways, instinctively pushed the bicycle home instead of riding it.  This illustrates the difficulty of breaking free from ingrained habits.</p>
<p>If financial management is the primary cause of the wealth gap, the solution lies in improving financial literacy and encouraging people to learn more about investing.</p>
<p><strong>Focusing Solely on Saving is Outdated</strong></p>
<p><em>If one adheres to the principles of investment, it&rsquo;s hard not to become wealthy. If one doesn&rsquo;t, it&rsquo;s hard to become wealthy.</em></p>
<p>I often wonder why, after over 200 years since their ancestors arrived in Taiwan with nothing, most Taiwanese families aren&rsquo;t significantly wealthy. Perhaps the problem lies in outdated family precepts that hinder wealth accumulation.</p>
<p>Family precepts are the guiding principles passed down through generations.  Most families emphasize diligence, frugality, and academic excellence, believing these are the keys to success and wealth.</p>
<p>Many families diligently follow these precepts, raising children who are both frugal and well-educated.  However, few families achieve significant wealth through these alone.  These precepts focus on earning money, not on managing it.  To build generational wealth, families need to update their guiding principles.  While &ldquo;diligence and frugality&rdquo; and &ldquo;academic excellence&rdquo; remain valuable, add another: &ldquo;Don&rsquo;t keep money in the bank.&rdquo;</p>
<p>Why retain &ldquo;diligence and frugality&rdquo;? While saving alone won&rsquo;t lead to great wealth, it&rsquo;s a virtue and a necessary foundation for investment.</p>
<p><strong>Educating the Next Generation Requires a Balanced Approach</strong></p>
<p>Why keep &ldquo;academic excellence&rdquo;?  Studies show a weak correlation between education and wealth.  Academic success doesn&rsquo;t guarantee financial success.  Based on this, I once stopped emphasizing academics with my children, resulting in declining grades.  Their teacher, puzzled, asked, &ldquo;You and your wife are both highly educated, why don&rsquo;t your children share this trait?&rdquo; I was ashamed.</p>
<p>I immediately reinstated the emphasis on academics. I realized it was partly for our own pride, but also because education can enhance social standing and job security. So, for both parents and children, academic pursuits remain important.</p>
<p>However, for future generations to prosper, add another precept: &ldquo;Don&rsquo;t keep money in the bank!&rdquo;  Encourage children to invest in assets like stocks and real estate, rather than leaving money in low-interest bank accounts.  Otherwise, building significant wealth might take generations.</p>
<p>Every Lunar New Year, I buy stocks for my children instead of giving cash. My second-grader is already learning the importance of investing over saving. This concept should be ingrained early as part of family values, fostering a healthy financial mindset from a young age.</p>
<p>In conclusion, most family precepts are outdated.  Building wealth for future generations requires new concepts and practices.  By updating family values and changing how we accumulate wealth, families can achieve lasting prosperity.</p>
<p><em>1. Diligence, frugality, and academic excellence alone are not enough for building lasting wealth.</em></p>
<p><em>2. Teach children not to keep money in the bank, cultivating a proper investment mindset from a young age.</em></p>
<p><em>3.  Leaving money to children might sustain them for a few years; teaching them how to manage it can provide for a lifetime and for generations to come.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Millionaire Teacher：Book Notes</title>
      <link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1728295541698/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1728295541698/</guid>
      <description>Andrew Hallam, the author of this book, started investing at the age of 19 and achieved millionaire status within 17 years on a teacher&amp;#39;s salary. He shares nine financial principles that anyone can learn, yet few are taught in school. Through real-life stories and personal experiences, he guides readers on how to avoid common investment pitfalls and achieve financial freedom using the simplest, safest, and most effective methods.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[

<h2 class="relative group">I. Summary 
    <div id="i-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This book reveals a financial secret that everyone can learn but is rarely taught in school: <strong>You don&rsquo;t have to be a finance expert or a high-income earner to achieve financial freedom; prudent spending and rational investing are all it takes, even on a modest income.</strong></p>
<p>The author, Andrew Hallam, is a high school English teacher who started investing at age 19 and became a millionaire by age 38. He distilled his years of investment experience and wisdom he garnered from numerous financial wizards into nine simple and actionable principles. Supported by factual cases and personal anecdotes, he guides readers step-by-step towards financial freedom.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">II. Chapter Summaries 
    <div id="ii-chapter-summaries" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii-chapter-summaries" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Lesson One: Spend Like You Want to Grow Rich 
    <div id="lesson-one-spend-like-you-want-to-grow-rich" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#lesson-one-spend-like-you-want-to-grow-rich" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Distinguish between &ldquo;wants&rdquo; and &ldquo;needs&rdquo;</strong>: Spend rationally, control unnecessary expenses, and avoid over-reliance on credit cards. Invest the money you save.
<ul>
<li>Example: In his youth, the author lived an extremely frugal life to pay off his student loans as quickly as possible, succeeding within a year and subsequently investing all his income.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>How to buy a car for less</strong>: Opt for low-mileage, easy-to-resell used cars instead of blindly pursuing luxury vehicles.
<ul>
<li>Example: The author purchased low-mileage used Japanese cars in his youth and sold them for the same or even higher price after a few years, turning a small profit.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Buying a house: It&rsquo;s not about the down payment, but the interest rate</strong>:  Consider whether you can still afford the mortgage if the interest rate doubles to prevent financial strain due to rising rates.</li>
<li><strong>Start strong, don&rsquo;t rely on a &ldquo;rich dad&rdquo;</strong>:  Excessive financial support from parents can hinder a child&rsquo;s ability to create wealth independently. Teach them financial knowledge and skills, letting them learn how to earn, save, and invest on their own.
<ul>
<li>Example: Studies show that accountants who received financial assistance from their parents had 43% less average wealth than their self-made counterparts.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>You don&rsquo;t have to live like a pauper, but spend like a millionaire</strong>: Frugality does not equate to a lower quality of life. It&rsquo;s about investing the money you save, allowing it to work for you instead of the other way around.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Lesson Two: Use the Greatest Investment Ally You Have 
    <div id="lesson-two-use-the-greatest-investment-ally-you-have" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#lesson-two-use-the-greatest-investment-ally-you-have" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Leverage compound interest to accelerate wealth accumulation</strong>: The earlier you start investing, the longer the time horizon for compound interest to work its magic, leading to faster wealth growth.
<ul>
<li>Example: Investing $45 per month for 40 years yields significantly higher returns than investing $800 per month for only 25 years.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Buffett&rsquo;s &ldquo;Noah&rsquo;s Ark Principle&rdquo;</strong>: Invest early, just like Noah built the ark, don&rsquo;t wait for the &ldquo;flood&rdquo; to arrive before taking action.</li>
<li><strong>What to do when you get paid</strong>:  Keep track of your monthly expenses, calculate the amount available for investment, and transfer that money to your investment account on payday to avoid running out of funds at the end of the month.
<ul>
<li>Example: A couple the author knew, both teachers, realized their wasteful spending habits after tracking their expenses for three months. They subsequently allocated more money to investment, tripling their investment amount within two years.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>The stock market doesn&rsquo;t believe in tears, but it believes in time</strong>:  In the long run, the stock market rises with corporate earnings growth. Therefore, be patient and don&rsquo;t be intimidated by short-term market fluctuations. The author&rsquo;s stock market investments from 1990 had increased tenfold by 2016.
<ul>
<li>Example: Using Willy Wonka&rsquo;s chocolate factory as an analogy, the author explains the fundamentals of stocks, share prices, dividends, and the stock market in a simple and engaging way, highlighting the substantial returns from long-term investment.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Lesson Three: Small Fees Pack Big Punches 
    <div id="lesson-three-small-fees-pack-big-punches" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#lesson-three-small-fees-pack-big-punches" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Index funds: the secret to effortless wealth generation</strong>: Index funds track a specific market index, holding all or most of the stocks in that index to achieve the same return as the market. Their advantages lie in low costs, risk diversification, and stable returns.</li>
<li><strong>&ldquo;The Oracle of Omaha&rdquo; buys index funds</strong>:  Investment gurus like Warren Buffett, Paul Samuelson, and Daniel Kahneman all recommend index funds because they provide market-average returns at the lowest cost, outperforming the vast majority of actively managed funds over the long term.
<ul>
<li>Example: Buffett suggests putting 90% of one&rsquo;s funds into an ultra-low-cost S&amp;P 500 index fund.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>78% of active fund returns go to the advisors&rsquo; pockets</strong>:  The high fees (management fees, transaction costs, commissions, etc.) of actively managed funds will eat up most of the investors&rsquo; gains. Generally, their returns underperform index funds over the long run.
<ul>
<li>Example: The author&rsquo;s wife could have earned an extra $20,000 if she had invested in index funds instead of actively managed funds, as recommended by her financial advisor, over the past five years.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Don&rsquo;t bother picking &ldquo;top actively managed funds&rdquo;</strong>: There is no reliable method to consistently pick actively managed funds that will outperform index funds. Even if a fund has a history of exceptional performance, it doesn&rsquo;t guarantee future success. Their returns tend to revert to the average or lower in the long run.
<ul>
<li>Example: Investors in Morningstar&rsquo;s five-star-rated funds often experience lower long-term returns compared to index fund investors.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>&ldquo;International citizens&rdquo; should opt for index funds</strong>:  Actively managed funds are significantly more expensive outside of the US. Therefore, &ldquo;international citizens&rdquo; should choose index funds to lower their investment costs.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Lesson Four: Conquer the Enemy in the Mirror 
    <div id="lesson-four-conquer-the-enemy-in-the-mirror" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#lesson-four-conquer-the-enemy-in-the-mirror" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Stay rational, earn 10% returns even in a bear market</strong>: Don&rsquo;t let fear and greed dictate your investment decisions. Don&rsquo;t panic sell in a falling market or chase rising prices in a bull market. Stick to regular investment and buy more cheap stocks in a bear market to achieve higher returns in the long run.
<ul>
<li>Example: During the 2008-2009 financial crisis, investors who steadily invested in index funds at the lows ultimately reaped higher returns.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Don&rsquo;t try to time the market</strong>:  No one can accurately predict short-term market trends; don&rsquo;t try to beat the market by timing it. Market timing often causes you to miss the best investment opportunities, leading to lower investment returns.</li>
<li><strong>Earning 150%? Be wary of tech stocks</strong>:  Don&rsquo;t be fooled by high-growth, high-valuation stocks. Stock prices eventually revert to the level justified by corporate earnings. Blindly chasing hot stocks can easily lead to losing your entire investment.
<ul>
<li>Example: The dot-com bubble burst in 1999, causing countless investors to suffer heavy losses. The author himself lost nearly half of his money due to investing in Nortel Networks stock.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Falling stocks: a buying opportunity</strong>:  A bear market is the best time to invest. Seize the opportunity to buy more cheap stocks when prices are low. In the long run, stocks rise with corporate earnings growth.</li>
<li><strong>Young people should be excited when stocks rebound</strong>: Young investors have more time to allow compound interest to work its magic. They should actually hope for market declines to buy more low-priced stocks. Over the long term, stocks bought at a discount offer higher returns.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Lesson Five: Build Mountains of Money with a Responsible Portfolio 
    <div id="lesson-five-build-mountains-of-money-with-a-responsible-portfolio" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#lesson-five-build-mountains-of-money-with-a-responsible-portfolio" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Buy bonds as insurance for your stocks</strong>:  Bonds offer lower returns than stocks but have lower volatility, reducing the overall risk of your portfolio. They act as a buffer when the stock market falls.
<ul>
<li><strong>Short-term bonds: a safe haven for your money</strong>:  Short-term bonds are less sensitive to interest rate fluctuations and are more suitable as a &ldquo;safety cushion&rdquo; for your portfolio.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Adjusting your portfolio to profit from market crashes</strong>:  Determine the appropriate mix of stocks and bonds based on your age and risk tolerance. Rebalance your portfolio regularly (e.g., review it annually), selling bonds to buy stocks in a down market and selling stocks to buy bonds in a bull market.
<ul>
<li>Example: Before the 2008 financial crisis, the author created a portfolio with a 35% bond allocation. During the downturn, he consistently increased his stock holdings. Consequently, he achieved higher returns when the market rebounded.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>&ldquo;Globalize&rdquo; your investment</strong>: Don&rsquo;t limit yourself to the domestic market. Diversify your investments across the globe to further reduce risk and access a wider range of opportunities.</li>
<li><strong>&ldquo;Lazy portfolio&rdquo;: adjust once a year for annual returns</strong>:  Allocate your portfolio equally between stocks and bonds, rebalance once a year. This simple strategy delivers impressive long-term returns without demanding excessive time or effort.
<ul>
<li>Example: Following the &ldquo;Lazy Portfolio&rdquo; strategy allowed investors to achieve positive returns even during the 2008 financial crisis.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Lesson Six: Sample a &ldquo;Round-the-World&rdquo; Ticket to Indexing 
    <div id="lesson-six-sample-a-round-the-world-ticket-to-indexing" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#lesson-six-sample-a-round-the-world-ticket-to-indexing" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>ETFs: Access Global Markets with One Account</strong>:  Exchange-traded funds (ETFs) offer a convenient way to invest in index funds. They are traded on stock exchanges like individual stocks and cover a wide array of global markets.
<ul>
<li><strong>How to buy ETFs?:</strong> The author details the steps involved in buying ETFs: opening a brokerage account, finding the ETF ticker symbol, determining the price per share, and setting the investment amount, etc.</li>
<li><strong>Limit orders vs. market orders:</strong> The author explains these two common ETF order types and recommends using limit orders to avoid losses due to price fluctuations.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>US Indexes: Strategic Allocation for Optimal Returns</strong>:  For US investors, a portfolio split equally between a US stock market index, a global stock market index, and a US bond market index, with annual rebalancing, is recommended for stable long-term returns.
<ul>
<li>Example: The author&rsquo;s friend, Chris, following this approach, grew his portfolio by 73.09% in 10 years despite experiencing the 2008-2009 financial crisis.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Canadian Indexes: Minimize Costs for Maximum Returns</strong>:  Canadians can build a low-cost, diversified global portfolio using TD Bank&rsquo;s &ldquo;e-Series&rdquo; index funds or ETFs.
<ul>
<li>The author uses personal anecdotes to illustrate that Canadian financial advisors are more inclined to recommend actively managed funds while overlooking low-cost index funds.</li>
<li>He uses the example of Air Force Technician, Felix, to demonstrate how investors can build a low-cost, diversified portfolio through TD&rsquo;s &ldquo;e-Series&rdquo; index funds.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>UK Indexes: Avoid High Fees, Optimize your Portfolio</strong>:  UK investors should be wary of high-fee index funds. Building a diversified portfolio using low-cost index funds or ETFs provided by Vanguard or iShares is recommended.
<ul>
<li>The author cites Virgin Money as an example to demonstrate how high fees and tracking errors can significantly affect index fund returns.</li>
<li>He then uses the case of software engineer, Paul, to illustrate how investors can utilize iShares and Vanguard ETFs to build a low-cost, diversified portfolio.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Australian Indexes: Multi-Asset Portfolios, Lower Fees with Higher Investments</strong>:  Australians can opt for Vanguard&rsquo;s multi-asset LifeStrategy funds or utilize platforms like Stockspot and Ignition Wealth to build ETF portfolios.
<ul>
<li>The author shares the story of Andy, a software developer, who uses the Nabtrade brokerage platform to buy ETFs and create a diversified index fund portfolio.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Singapore indexes: Low cost, smart allocation</strong>:  Singaporean investors should also be cautious of high-fee index funds. Building a diversified portfolio using low-cost ETFs offered by Vanguard is recommended, but it&rsquo;s important to avoid ETFs traded on US exchanges to avert US estate taxes.
<ul>
<li>The author utilizes the example of &ldquo;Fundsupermart&rsquo;s&rdquo; &ldquo;S&amp;P 500 index&rdquo; fund to illustrate how high fees significantly impact long-term investment returns.</li>
<li>He further uses the case of a professor couple to show how investors can construct a diversified portfolio using ETFs traded on Singaporean and Canadian exchanges, thus avoiding US estate taxes.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Lesson Seven: No, You Don&rsquo;t Have to Invest on Your Own 
    <div id="lesson-seven-no-you-dont-have-to-invest-on-your-own" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#lesson-seven-no-you-dont-have-to-invest-on-your-own" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Why do index investors lag behind the index?:</strong> Many investors fall prey to their emotions, making irrational decisions during market fluctuations, or are swayed by investment predictions, ultimately hindering their returns.
<ul>
<li>Example: Some investors panic sell during market downturns and chase rising prices in a bull market, resulting in returns far lower than the index itself.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>US Robo-Advisors: Let the Smart Investors &ldquo;Win&rdquo; Effortlessly</strong>: Robo-advisor platforms can help investors create and manage low-cost index fund portfolios, rebalancing them regularly, and preventing investors from damaging their accounts.
<ul>
<li>Example: Vanguard&rsquo;s Target Retirement Funds offer a one-stop solution at a very low cost, suitable for those who prefer a hands-off approach to investment.
<ul>
<li>The author uses his wife as an example to highlight the advantages of Vanguard Target Retirement Funds: achieving positive returns even without investment knowledge.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Vanguard&rsquo;s Comprehensive Financial Advisory Services:</strong> Vanguard provides comprehensive financial planning services at a low cost, making it a good option for investors seeking professional advice.</li>
<li><strong>Investment Guidance Training Services:</strong> Mark Zoril of PlanVision offers training services that guide investors to open low-cost brokerage accounts and build their own index fund portfolios.</li>
<li><strong>Investment Enhancement Services:</strong> Scott Burns of AssetBuilder provides investment enhancement services, using Dimensional Fund Advisors (DFA) index funds to help investors build a &ldquo;Lazy Portfolio&rdquo;.
<ul>
<li>The author elaborates on DFA&rsquo;s investment philosophy: pursuing excess returns through small-cap and value stocks.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Betterment, Rebalance IRA, SigFig, and Wealthfront:</strong> These companies also offer robo-advisory services, building and managing portfolios consisting of index funds or ETFs for investors.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Canadian Robo-Advisors: Lower Cost and More Targeted:</strong> Robo-advisor platforms in Canada, such as WealthBar and Wealthsimple, offer lower-cost, personalized services, tailoring portfolios to suit client risk tolerance and investment goals.
<ul>
<li>The author uses personal experiences to demonstrate that Canadian bank advisors still favor actively managed funds over low-cost index funds.</li>
<li><strong>Tangerine:</strong> Tangerine bank provides Canadian investors with a financial product that encompasses a diversified index fund portfolio. Low cost makes it suitable for those who prefer to invest small sums regularly.
<ul>
<li>The author uses 19-year-old Katie as an example to show how young people can leverage Tangerine&rsquo;s investment products for regular investing.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>WealthBar:</strong> WealthBar offers Canadian investors five portfolio management solutions and provides comprehensive financial planning based on their risk tolerance.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>UK Robo-Advisors: Diversified Index Fund Baskets</strong>: UK robo-advisor platforms, like Nutmeg, construct diverse index fund portfolios for investors, rebalancing regularly, although their fees are comparatively higher.</li>
<li><strong>Australian Robo-Advisors: Increasing Competition and Falling Fees</strong>: The Australian robo-advisor market is highly competitive with decreasing fees. Platforms like Stockspot and Ignition Wealth offer low-cost, personalized ETF portfolio management services.</li>
<li><strong>Singapore Robo-Advisors: Avoid &ldquo;Suicidal&rdquo; Asset Allocation:</strong>  Singapore&rsquo;s robo-advisory market is nascent. Investors should opt for companies that don&rsquo;t utilize ETFs traded on US exchanges to avoid US estate tax liabilities.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Lesson Eight: Peek Inside A Pilferer’s Playbook 
    <div id="lesson-eight-peek-inside-a-pilferers-playbook" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#lesson-eight-peek-inside-a-pilferers-playbook" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Identifying Financial Advisors&rsquo; Tricks:</strong> Financial advisors use various tactics to persuade investors to buy actively managed funds, such as claiming that &ldquo;index funds are more dangerous during downturns&rdquo; or that &ldquo;index funds can only achieve average returns,&rdquo; both of which are misleading.
<ul>
<li>Examples:  When the author and his friend sought advice from financial advisors, they were aggressively steered towards actively managed funds without mention of their high fees or lower returns. One advisor even claimed index funds were riskier and that actively managed funds were better suited for navigating bear markets.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Index Fund Returns Outshine &ldquo;Financial Elites&rdquo;</strong>: Even seasoned investment professionals like pension fund managers struggle to beat index fund returns. Many pension funds have started shifting towards indexed investments, allocating a significant portion of their funds to index funds.
<ul>
<li>Example: A study by US consulting firm FutureMetrics revealed that less than 30% of large corporate pension funds outperformed a diversified portfolio holding 60% S&amp;P 500 index and 40% corporate bond index.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Don&rsquo;t Accidentally Become a &ldquo;Second-Rate Investor&rdquo;</strong>:  Don&rsquo;t be fooled by financial advisors&rsquo; sales pitches. Trust the data and facts - index funds are the most reliable way to profit in the stock market. Advisors&rsquo; interests are often at odds with those of their clients; they prioritize commission income over investor returns.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Lesson Nine: Avoid Seduction 
    <div id="lesson-nine-avoid-seduction" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#lesson-nine-avoid-seduction" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Stock Picking Scams: Do their stock recommendations really work?:</strong>  Investment newsletter predictions are often inaccurate, and their recommended stocks are likely to lead to financial ruin. Their primary goal is to attract subscribers, not to help investors make money.
<ul>
<li>Example: The author invested in stocks recommended by &ldquo;The Gilder Technology Report&rdquo; and suffered significant losses.  The author of that report continues to publish similar reports, using the lure of high past returns to attract investors.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Investing in Emerging Markets: Don&rsquo;t be fooled by GDP</strong>: High economic growth does not necessarily translate into high stock market returns. Be cautious when investing in emerging markets. They are more volatile and risky, and their long-term returns may not surpass developed markets.
<ul>
<li>Example: While China&rsquo;s GDP grew rapidly from 2008 to 2016, its stock market performance was lackluster, with investors in a large-cap Chinese stock ETF experiencing a 30% loss.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>&ldquo;Gold speculation&rdquo;: It&rsquo;s not investing</strong>: Gold has a low long-term return rate with high price volatility, making it unsuitable for long-term investment. &ldquo;Gold speculators&rdquo; attempt to profit from price differences by buying low and selling high, a risky strategy that cannot guarantee stable long-term returns.
<ul>
<li>Example: $1 worth of gold purchased in 1801 would only be worth $73 in 2016, whereas a $1 investment in the US stock market during the same period would turn into $16.24 million.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Investment Magazines: The Untold Truth</strong>:  Investment magazines rely heavily on advertising revenue, leading them to cater to their advertisers rather than prioritize investors&rsquo; needs. They often recommend high-fee actively managed funds while neglecting low-cost index funds.
<ul>
<li>Example: In April 2009, &ldquo;SmartMoney&rdquo; magazine recommended bond funds and gold, ignoring the investment opportunity presented by low-priced stocks amidst the financial crisis.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Hedge Funds: Picking the Pockets of the Rich</strong>: Hedge funds charge exorbitant fees and carry significant risks, with long-term returns that are often no better, and sometimes even worse, than index funds. Their reported performance is often skewed by &ldquo;survivorship bias&rdquo; and &ldquo;backfill bias.&rdquo;
<ul>
<li>Example: Hedge funds struggle to achieve an average annual compounded return of even 1%.  Only one out of the top 20 largest hedge funds has outperformed the S&amp;P 500 index.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Don&rsquo;t buy currency-hedged ETFs</strong>: Currency-hedged ETFs  aim to eliminate the impact of exchange rate fluctuations on investment returns. However, the hedging mechanism itself incurs costs, decreasing a portfolio&rsquo;s returns.
<ul>
<li>Example: Research indicates that non-currency-hedged ETFs generally outperform their currency-hedged counterparts over the long term.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Don&rsquo;t fall for smart beta funds</strong>: These hybrid funds fall somewhere between active and index funds, attempting to achieve excess returns with specific strategies. Their effectiveness is debated, and their fees are generally higher.
<ul>
<li>Example:  Studies show that the market capitalization growth of smart beta funds has been primarily due to valuation increases, not corporate earnings growth, suggesting potential decreases in future returns.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Don&rsquo;t blindly buy into small-cap stocks</strong>:  Small-cap stocks, those of smaller companies, offer high growth potential, but also carry higher risk. Investing in them requires careful consideration and risk tolerance; avoid chasing high returns blindly.</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">III. Key Quotes 
    <div id="iii-key-quotes" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii-key-quotes" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>You don&rsquo;t have to be a financial expert; even with a moderate income, you can achieve financial freedom through prudent spending and rational investing.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This encapsulates the core message of the book:  financial management and investment are not exclusive to the wealthy; ordinary people can also achieve financial freedom through learning and practical application.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Time is money.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This emphasizes that time is our most valuable asset. The earlier you start investing, the longer the time horizon for compound interest to work its magic, leading to faster wealth accumulation.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>A successful investor should follow two principles: the first is to never lose money and the second is to never forget the first principle.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This quote highlights the importance of risk management and capital preservation in investing.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The investor&rsquo;s task is to focus on the horse, not the jockey.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This means that investors should prioritize a company&rsquo;s intrinsic value over the fund manager&rsquo;s individual ability. Over the long run, a company&rsquo;s profitability is the most important factor determining its stock price.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>If you plan to live off hamburgers for the rest of your life, but you don&rsquo;t own any cattle, would you want beef prices to go up or down?</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Buffett used this analogy to illustrate that stocks represent ownership in a company. When share prices fall, long-term investors should view it as an opportunity to buy more shares.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The most insidious devil is the high cost associated with holding certain actively managed funds.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This quote emphasizes that investment costs are one of the most important factors affecting investment returns. Choosing low-cost index funds maximizes gains.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>How much you can accumulate in your lifetime depends not on how much you can earn, but on how you invest. Money finds people more effectively than people find money. Let your money work for you, not the other way around.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Buffett stresses the importance of investment and financial management, pointing out that wealth accumulation relies not only on income but also on how you manage and invest your money.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Too much money can harm investment returns.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This seemingly paradoxical statement highlights a critical principle: avoid over-diversification and the blind pursuit of high returns. Concentrating your investments in a few high-quality assets and holding them for the long term often yields better results.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>In stock investing, luck inevitably plays a role, but in the long run, good luck and bad luck offset each other. For sustained success, skills and sound principles are essential.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This emphasizes that the key to successful investing lies in mastering the correct investment philosophy and principles and adhering to them in the long term, rather than relying on luck.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Let time and money work for you; you just need to sit back and wait for the results.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This emphasizes the power of long-term investment and compound interest. By choosing the right investment method and being patient, significant returns will follow.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">IV. Practical Implications 
    <div id="iv-practical-implications" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv-practical-implications" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This book&rsquo;s key takeaways include:</p>
<ol>
<li><strong>Developing a sound financial mindset</strong>: Understand the importance of thrift, control unnecessary spending, and invest your savings.</li>
<li><strong>Mastering simple and effective investment methods</strong>: Learn to leverage compound interest, start investing early, choose low-cost index funds, and commit to long-term investments. Avoid being swayed by short-term market volatility.</li>
<li><strong>Avoiding common investment pitfalls</strong>:  Be wary of financial advisors&rsquo; sales tactics, don&rsquo;t blindly trust investment predictions or stock recommendations, and avoid being lured by the promise of high returns.</li>
<li><strong>Developing financial independence</strong>: Learn basic financial knowledge and skills, don&rsquo;t rely solely on financial advisors, and learn to make investment decisions independently.</li>
</ol>
<hr>

<section class="space-y-10 w-full">
    
    
        
            






















  <a class="flex flex-wrap article " href="/en/posts/1728295490690-book-list/">
    
        
        <div class="w-full md:w-auto h-full thumbnail nozoom thumbnailshadow md:mr-7" style="background-image:url(/posts/1728295490690-book-list/featured_hu4424409690304057825.jpg);"></div>
        
      <div class=" mt-3 md:mt-0">
      <div class="items-center text-left text-xl font-semibold">
        
        <div class="font-bold text-xl text-neutral-800 decoration-primary-500 hover:underline hover:underline-offset-2 dark:text-neutral"
          href="/en/posts/1728295490690-book-list/">Recommended Reading List</div>
        
        
        
      </div>
      <div class="text-sm text-neutral-500 dark:text-neutral-400">
        











  









  



  









<div class="flex flex-row flex-wrap items-center">
  
  
  <time datetime="2024-10-01T00:00:00&#43;00:00">1 October 2024</time><span class="px-2 text-primary-500">&middot;</span><span>
  
  
    
    
      
      
        
        
      
        
        
      
      
    
  
  <span id="views_posts/1728295490690-book-list/index.md" class="animate-pulse inline-block text-transparent max-h-3 rounded-full mt-[-2px] align-middle bg-neutral-300 dark:bg-neutral-400" title="views">loading</span>
  <span class="inline-block align-text-bottom">

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 576 512">
<path fill="currentColor" d="M288 32c-80.8 0-145.5 36.8-192.6 80.6C48.6 156 17.3 208 2.5 243.7c-3.3 7.9-3.3 16.7 0 24.6C17.3 304 48.6 356 95.4 399.4C142.5 443.2 207.2 480 288 480s145.5-36.8 192.6-80.6c46.8-43.5 78.1-95.4 93-131.1c3.3-7.9 3.3-16.7 0-24.6c-14.9-35.7-46.2-87.7-93-131.1C433.5 68.8 368.8 32 288 32zM432 256c0 79.5-64.5 144-144 144s-144-64.5-144-144s64.5-144 144-144s144 64.5 144 144zM288 192c0 35.3-28.7 64-64 64c-11.5 0-22.3-3-31.6-8.4c-.2 2.8-.4 5.5-.4 8.4c0 53 43 96 96 96s96-43 96-96s-43-96-96-96c-2.8 0-5.6 .1-8.4 .4c5.3 9.3 8.4 20.1 8.4 31.6z"/></svg>
  </span>

</span>
</span><span class="px-2 text-primary-500">&middot;</span><span>
  
  
    
    
      
      
        
        
      
        
        
      
      
    
  
  <span id="likes_posts/1728295490690-book-list/index.md"
    class="animate-pulse inline-block text-transparent max-h-3 rounded-full mt-[-2px] align-middle bg-neutral-300 dark:bg-neutral-400"
    title="likes">loading</span>
  <span class="inline-block align-text-bottom">

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512">
<path fill="currentColor" d="M47.6 300.4L228.3 469.1c7.5 7 17.4 10.9 27.7 10.9s20.2-3.9 27.7-10.9L464.4 300.4c30.4-28.3 47.6-68 47.6-109.5v-5.8c0-69.9-50.5-129.5-119.4-141C347 36.5 300.6 51.4 268 84L256 96 244 84c-32.6-32.6-79-47.5-124.6-39.9C50.5 55.6 0 115.2 0 185.1v5.8c0 41.5 17.2 81.2 47.6 109.5z"/></svg>
  </span>

</span>
</span>
  

  
  
</div>





<div class="flex flex-row flex-wrap items-center">
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  <span style="margin-top:0.5rem" class="mr-2" onclick="window.open(&#34;/en/tags/recommended/&#34;,'_self');">
    <span class="flex" style="cursor: pointer;">
  <span class="rounded-md border border-primary-400 px-1 py-[1px] text-xs font-normal text-primary-700 dark:border-primary-600 dark:text-primary-400">
    Recommended
  </span>
</span>
  </span>
  
  <span style="margin-top:0.5rem" class="mr-2" onclick="window.open(&#34;/en/tags/book/&#34;,'_self');">
    <span class="flex" style="cursor: pointer;">
  <span class="rounded-md border border-primary-400 px-1 py-[1px] text-xs font-normal text-primary-700 dark:border-primary-600 dark:text-primary-400">
    Book
  </span>
</span>
  </span>
  
  
  
  
</div>




      </div>
      
    </div>
  </a>

        
    
</section>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
