<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Personal Investment Bible on QQQ Investor</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/series/personal-investment-bible/</link><description>Recent content in Personal Investment Bible on QQQ Investor</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jomonylw.github.io/en/series/personal-investment-bible/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Personal Investment Bible: Investment Iron Law IV</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1731056005963/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1731056005963/</guid><description>This article explores the financial strategy of &amp;#34;making money with other people&amp;#39;s money,&amp;#34; also known as leveraged investing. It analyzes the principle of financial leverage, emphasizing that the return on investment must be higher than the loan interest rate to be profitable. Case studies of entrepreneurs like Chen Youhao and Weng Damming illustrate the advantages and risks of leveraged investing. The article further discusses borrowing principles, how to build credit, how to avoid improper borrowing, and how to determine an appropriate level of debt. Finally, it points out that banks are a source of borrowing rather than a place to save money, and emphasizes the importance of prudent borrowing.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[

<h2 class="relative group">Investment Iron Law 4: Making Money with Other People&rsquo;s Money 
    <div id="investment-iron-law-4-making-money-with-other-peoples-money" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#investment-iron-law-4-making-money-with-other-peoples-money" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>By applying the principle of financial leverage, an investment of 500 million can double your business.</p>
</blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">Utilizing Leveraged Investing 
    <div id="utilizing-leveraged-investing" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#utilizing-leveraged-investing" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>The path to wealth through investment relies on &ldquo;making money with money.&rdquo;  Therefore, the prerequisite for investment is having capital.  A common dilemma faced by individuals when investing is, &ldquo;What if I don&rsquo;t have enough money?&rdquo; This can lead to missed opportunities. This book proposes a solution: &ldquo;If you don&rsquo;t have enough money, but someone else does and is willing to lend it to you, then borrow it.&rdquo; This is the highest realm of investment management—leveraged investing.</p>
<p><strong>Chen Youhao, President of the Tuntex Group: The Money-Making Method of Borrowing and Rolling</strong></p>
<p>Starting in the textile industry, Chen Youhao used financial leverage to rapidly expand the Tuntex Group into chemical fibers, construction, cement, hotels, petrochemicals, and other fields. With over 30 affiliated companies, it became one of the top 15 largest corporate groups in Taiwan. He also planned to invest nearly 7 billion USD in Taiwan and Thailand to expand chemical fiber plants.</p>
<p>Tuntex&rsquo;s growth never stopped, and its debt continued to rise. In 1995, Tuntex Group&rsquo;s core business, Tonwin Construction, had total assets of 59.6 billion TWD, revenue of 15.7 billion TWD, and net profit after tax of 2.6 billion TWD, but its debt ratio was still as high as 60.99%.</p>
<p>A graduate of the Department of Economics at National Taiwan University, Chen Youhao always prided himself on his sophisticated money-making method of borrowing and rolling. He had full confidence in Tuntex&rsquo;s financial management. His financial principles were: 1/3 self-owned capital, the rest borrowed from financial institutions; current assets must be greater than current liabilities, with a current ratio greater than 100%; and the ratio of self-owned capital to debt must not exceed 1/2.</p>
<p>Chen Youhao emphasized that whenever the company&rsquo;s debt ratio approached its limit, he would strictly control it, so the company&rsquo;s financial situation remained normal. However, whenever the construction industry was in a downturn, Tuntex would be plagued by rumors of financial difficulties. In June 1995, due to capital needs, Chen Youhao pledged 46.5 million shares of Tonwin, setting a record for the highest number of shares pledged by directors and supervisors that month. Chen Youhao repeatedly assured the public that Tuntex&rsquo;s finances were absolutely sound.</p>
<p>Despite the rumors damaging the company&rsquo;s image, Chen Youhao firmly believed that reasonable borrowing could enable the company to earn more profits. He was also confident that businesses funded by loans would be profitable because the return on investment was higher than the interest rate on loans.</p>
<p><strong>Is Borrowing to Invest Wrong?</strong></p>
<p>Is borrowing money for investment appropriate? Shakespeare wrote in Hamlet, &ldquo;Neither a borrower nor a lender be.&rdquo; This was once considered a golden rule. Our elders often warned their children not to borrow money from others or lend money to others; borrowing was not considered respectable and should be avoided unless absolutely necessary.</p>
<p>Indeed, most stories of financial ruin are caused by debt, such as the cases of Tsai Chen-chou of the Tenth Credit Cooperative and the stock market tycoon Lei Borong. Countless examples of bankruptcy caused by debt make people fear and avoid it.</p>
<p>However, among the famous wealthy individuals we know, such as Wang Yongqing, Kao Ching-yuan, Chang Yung-fa, and Wu Ho-Su, who didn&rsquo;t rely on borrowing to invest in their journey from rags to riches? The answer is &ldquo;none.&rdquo; Moreover, the more successful people are at making money, the more they tend to borrow. Looking at the financial statements of listed companies, are there any renowned high-performing enterprises in Taiwan, such as Formosa Plastics, Uni-President, and Evergreen, that have zero debt?  The message is clear: successful tycoons, like successful businesses, rarely achieve their wealth without using other people&rsquo;s money. In business management, appropriate borrowing is not only necessary but also reasonable.</p>
<p>If Shakespeare were alive in the 21st century and understood how capitalism works and how people become wealthy, he might change his words to: &ldquo;If you have no money, but others do and are willing to lend it to you, then borrow.&rdquo;</p>
<p>After reviewing these characteristics of success, reflect on your own financial situation. What percentage of your investment funds comes from borrowing? If, like most people, 100% of your investments are made with your own funds, you are overlooking an important tool for building wealth: borrowing.</p>
<p><strong>Borrowing is a Crucial Tool for Wealth Creation</strong></p>
<p>American investment consultant Robert Allen repeatedly emphasizes in his bestselling book <em>Creating Wealth</em>: &ldquo;You cannot become rich by investing without borrowing.&rdquo; I disagree with this argument. The examples in Chapter 1 of this book clearly demonstrate that with proper financial management, one can become a billionaire without relying on borrowed investments.  The American investment master Warren Buffett does not advocate leveraged investing.  Without debt, he is a prime example of building wealth solely through his own funds. However, there is a prerequisite for accumulating wealth using only your own funds: long-term patient waiting. Warren Buffett only rose to prominence after three to four decades of investing.</p>
<p>Although Robert Allen&rsquo;s argument that &ldquo;you cannot become rich without borrowing&rdquo; is incorrect, I must admit that the &ldquo;leveraged investing&rdquo; he advocates is an important means of building wealth, especially for those who want to accelerate the speed of wealth creation.  Leveraged investing is a tool that should not be ignored.</p>
<p>In conclusion, whether you want to accelerate wealth accumulation or can tolerate the pressure of leveraged investing, you must understand the nature and impact of leveraged investing before deciding if this tool is right for you.</p>
<ul>
<li>
<ol>
<li>Leveraged investing is a powerful tool, but it must be used wisely.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol start="2">
<li>It is possible to build wealth without borrowing.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol start="3">
<li>Leveraged investing, when used correctly, can accelerate wealth accumulation.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol start="4">
<li>Don&rsquo;t be afraid of leveraged investing, but be very careful.</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>Aim high with your business goals,
Once decided, go for it and never back down.
The key to success in business lies in courage and strategy.</p>
</blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">Weng Damming&rsquo;s Revival of the Family Business 
    <div id="weng-dammings-revival-of-the-family-business" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#weng-dammings-revival-of-the-family-business" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>In Taiwan, there are quite a few entrepreneurs skilled in financial leverage. Besides Chen Youhao, the president of the Tuntex Group, Weng Damming, the head of the Hualon Group, is also a master of this art.</p>
<p>Weng Damming, the head of the Hualon Group, became a highly controversial figure due to his unconventional style. After the death of his father, Weng Mingchang, Weng Damming shouldered the heavy responsibility of reviving the family business.  Starting in textiles, the Hualon Group owned Hualon Textile, Hualon Microelectronics, Yixin Trading, Jiashin Livestock, and Kuo Hua Life Insurance, among other affiliated companies.</p>
<p>Weng Damming adopted a high-leverage approach to business management. In 1994, the Hualon Group had total assets of 130 billion TWD and debts as high as over 50 billion TWD, of which over 30 billion TWD were short-term debts.  He used the stocks or real estate of affiliated companies as collateral for bank loans, with a pledge ratio of nearly 60%. Therefore, during the stock market crash and the real estate downturn, Weng Damming was troubled by rumors of financial difficulties.  Due to the sluggish stock and real estate markets, the collateral value of the Hualon Group was insufficient, requiring him to supplement the collateral or face the pressure of being &ldquo;liquidated.&rdquo; However, the seasoned Weng Damming, with his flexible financial management, once again demonstrated that the financial crisis was just a false alarm.</p>
<p>As Hualon Textile, the parent company of the Hualon Group, enjoyed stable profits and increased earnings with the gradual recovery of the textile industry, Weng Damming was able to borrow money fearlessly and aggressively expand into new businesses.  With a gambler&rsquo;s mentality, Weng Damming can be said to have maximized the principle of financial leverage. The story of this legendary figure shows us both the rewards and risks of leveraged investing.</p>
<p><strong>The Principle of Financial Leverage</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Act within your means; don&rsquo;t over-leverage, or you risk being shaken out.</li>
</ul>
<p>In finance, borrowing is known as &ldquo;financial leverage.&rdquo; Simply put, leverage is the principle of using a small force to achieve a large effect. Humans discovered the power of leverage early on and used it to move or lift heavy objects. The ancients used the principle of leverage to create magnificent engineering marvels such as the Great Wall and the pyramids. Modern wealthy individuals use the principle of financial leverage to create immense fortunes. Archimedes once said, &ldquo;Give me a place to stand, and I shall move the earth.&rdquo;  In investment management, financial leverage implies: &ldquo;Lend me enough money, and I can make any large investment.&rdquo;</p>
<p>Leveraged investing involves borrowing other people&rsquo;s money to make larger investments, thus utilizing the leverage effect.  Proper use of leverage can turn small amounts of money into large profits. Conversely, improper use can also lead to significant losses with small amounts of money. Here&rsquo;s an example to help readers understand how financial leverage works. Suppose you buy a house with 10 million in cash. A year later, you are fortunate enough to sell it for 13 million, making a 30% profit (R1). If you only paid 3 million in cash for the house and borrowed the remaining 7 million from the bank at a 10% interest rate, and then sold it for 13 million a year later, your profit margin would increase to 77% (R2).  Conversely, if the house price unfortunately drops by 30% after a year, and you sell it for 7 million, the person who bought it entirely in cash would lose 30% (R3). The investor who borrowed 7 million would see their loss expand to 123% (R4), meaning not only is the original investment lost, but they are also in debt. The calculation of the above rates of return is as follows:</p>
<p><math xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" display="block"><mtable displaystyle="true" columnalign="right center left" columnspacing="0 thickmathspace" rowspacing="3pt"><mtr><mtd><mi>R</mi><mn>1</mn></mtd><mtd><mi></mi><mo>=</mo></mtd><mtd><mi></mi><mo stretchy="false">(</mo><mn>1300</mn><mo>−</mo><mn>1000</mn><mo stretchy="false">)</mo><mrow><mo>/</mo></mrow><mn>1000</mn></mtd><mtd><mi></mi><mo>=</mo></mtd><mtd><mn>30</mn><mi mathvariant="normal">%</mi></mtd></mtr><mtr><mtd></mtd></mtr><mtr><mtd><mi>R</mi><mn>2</mn></mtd><mtd><mi></mi><mo>=</mo></mtd><mtd><mi></mi><mo stretchy="false">(</mo><mn>1300</mn><mo>−</mo><mn>1000</mn><mo>−</mo><mn>700</mn><mo>×</mo><mn>10</mn><mi mathvariant="normal">%</mi><mo stretchy="false">)</mo><mrow><mo>/</mo></mrow><mn>300</mn></mtd><mtd><mi></mi><mo>=</mo></mtd><mtd><mn>77</mn><mi mathvariant="normal">%</mi></mtd></mtr><mtr><mtd></mtd></mtr><mtr><mtd><mi>R</mi><mn>3</mn></mtd><mtd><mi></mi><mo>=</mo></mtd><mtd><mi></mi><mo stretchy="false">(</mo><mn>700</mn><mo>−</mo><mn>1000</mn><mo stretchy="false">)</mo><mrow><mo>/</mo></mrow><mn>1000</mn></mtd><mtd><mi></mi><mo>=</mo></mtd><mtd><mi></mi><mo>−</mo><mn>30</mn><mi mathvariant="normal">%</mi></mtd></mtr><mtr><mtd></mtd></mtr><mtr><mtd><mi>R</mi><mn>4</mn></mtd><mtd><mi></mi><mo>=</mo></mtd><mtd><mi></mi><mo stretchy="false">(</mo><mn>700</mn><mo>−</mo><mn>1000</mn><mo>−</mo><mn>700</mn><mo>×</mo><mn>10</mn><mi mathvariant="normal">%</mi><mo stretchy="false">)</mo><mrow><mo>/</mo></mrow><mn>300</mn></mtd><mtd><mi></mi><mo>=</mo></mtd><mtd><mi></mi><mo>−</mo><mn>123</mn><mi mathvariant="normal">%</mi></mtd></mtr><mtr><mtd></mtd></mtr><mtr><mtd><mo stretchy="false">(</mo><mo>Calculations in units of 10,000</mo><mo stretchy="false">)</mo></mtd></mtr></mtable></math></p>
<p>From the above example, we can clearly see how debt leverage exerts the power of &ldquo;using a small force to achieve a large effect.&rdquo; <strong>When the return on investment is higher than the interest rate on the loan, leveraged investing will increase the return on investment. When the return on investment is lower than the interest rate on the loan, the return on investment will decrease due to the borrowing.</strong></p>
<p>The main reason for the leverage effect is that loan interest is a cost that must be paid under any circumstances. Regardless of the investment return, the interest cost of borrowing remains fixed. Therefore, when the investment return is greater than the loan cost, the excess profit belongs to the borrower, creating a positive leverage effect and naturally increasing the return on investment of the principal. However, when the investment return is less than the loan interest cost, the borrower must bear the difference, resulting in a negative leverage effect, which reduces the return on the principal. This is especially true when the investment incurs a loss, as the borrowing cost will magnify the loss.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Financial leverage is like a seesaw,
It can lift you very high,
It can also cause you to fall hard.</p>
</blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">Two Major Principles of Borrowing 
    <div id="two-major-principles-of-borrowing" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#two-major-principles-of-borrowing" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>Financial leverage is like a seesaw: it can lift you very high or cause you to fall hard, depending on whether the leverage effect is positive or negative.  The key factor determining the direction of the leverage effect is which is higher: the return on investment or the interest rate on the loan. If the return on investment is greater than the interest rate, the leverage effect is positive. Conversely, if the return on investment is lower than the interest rate, the leverage effect becomes detrimental.</p>
<p><strong>Return on Investment Must Be Higher Than the Interest Rate</strong></p>
<p>Therefore, when deciding whether to use leveraged investing, the first things to consider are: What is the purpose of the loan? What is the expected return on investment for the target investment? Is it higher than the loan interest rate? If the return on investment of the targeted investment is significantly lower than the borrowing rate, the idea of leveraged investing should be dismissed early on. Otherwise, the result will certainly be detrimental rather than beneficial. If you can&rsquo;t understand what the expected return on investment is or whether the return is higher than the interest rate, then I advise you to understand these issues before borrowing!</p>
<p>Debt is synonymous with risk. Increasing debt increases risk and the possibility of personal or family bankruptcy. There are two major principles of leveraged investing:</p>
<ul>
<li>
<ol>
<li>The expected return on investment must be greater than the interest rate on the loan. For example, if the loan interest rate is 11%, it&rsquo;s only worthwhile if the after-tax return on investment is above 11%.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol start="2">
<li>In the worst-case scenario, your cash income must be sufficient to cover the principal and interest payments. For instance, if the investment price falls instead of rises after a few years, you must have enough cash income to repay the principal and interest on time.</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ul>
<p>Furthermore, investors must keep in mind that leveraged investing should not be based on the expectation that the price of the investment target will definitely rise, but rather on the preparation for a price drop.  Therefore, you should only engage in leveraged investing if you can still afford the interest payments even if the price continues to fall. You must also be able to withstand the psychological pressure that comes with leveraged investing.</p>
<p><strong>Avoiding Improper Borrowing</strong></p>
<p>Some readers may feel smug after reading this section because they are already engaged in what they consider leveraged investing. Upon further inquiry, however, it turns out they are borrowing money to buy lottery tickets, futures, or other speculative products, or even taking out loans to purchase consumer goods.  I must emphasize that these actions do not constitute proper &ldquo;leveraged investing.&rdquo;</p>
<p>Futures markets, margin trading (such as foreign exchange and bonds), or any gambling activities like lotteries and horse racing all have negative expected returns.  Long-term participation will inevitably lead to financial ruin.  Coupled with the deadly effect of borrowing, the result will undoubtedly be rapid bankruptcy.  Therefore, no matter how alluring these games are, remember:  It&rsquo;s okay to indulge occasionally for recreational purposes, but never borrow money to participate, or you will accelerate your path to bankruptcy with dire consequences.</p>
<p>Another point to remind readers of is to avoid borrowing money to purchase consumer goods. Borrowing to consume is like using future money to create &ldquo;false wealth.&rdquo; Unless absolutely necessary, the concept of borrowing for consumption should be avoided. Otherwise, the family&rsquo;s financial situation will be burdened.</p>
<p>For banks, consumer loans are extremely risky and require high interest rates.  Generally, consumer loan interest rates are above 10%.  Readers should understand that high-return investments have an amazing compounding effect.  Similarly, high-interest loans also have a dramatic compounding effect.  Take car loans, for example.  Assuming a 20% loan interest rate, after three and a half years, you will have to repay double the amount. This means that if you borrow money to buy a car now, three and a half years later, not only will the original car have depreciated significantly, but you will effectively have to pay for two new cars of the same model.  My advice on car loans is: don&rsquo;t take them. Wait until you can afford to pay in cash. Car loan interest rates are usually very high, often exceeding 15%, although there are occasional promotional periods with lower rates.  Fundamentally, except for commercial vehicles, cars are consumer goods with no investment return.  From an investment perspective, borrowing for car purchases is highly inadvisable.</p>
<p><strong>Uncontrolled Consumer Lending Easily Leads to Bankruptcy</strong></p>
<p>Credit cards, now a ubiquitous form of plastic currency worldwide, are also a typical example of consumer loans.  Since the popularization of credit cards, consumer behavior has undergone significant changes. While credit cards offer great convenience, their widespread use has led to a surge in bankruptcy cases among American families, with outstanding credit card debt exceeding 700 billion USD.  Some may wonder: how can credit cards lead to bankruptcy if you only spend what you have?  In fact, from a borrowing perspective, credit cards have an irresistible allure.</p>
<p>The greatest temptation of credit card borrowing lies in its simplicity.  With just a signature, you can make purchases in advance and even borrow cash from the bank, subtly inflating your spending power.  Remember: when using credit cards, never spend more than you can afford to repay each month.  Credit card interest rates are often above 20%, so you should always pay off your credit card balance promptly.  My advice is: &ldquo;If you can&rsquo;t control your spending urges, it&rsquo;s best not to apply for a credit card. If you apply for one for convenience, never use it for the sake of credit.  Use it only when it truly offers convenience.&rdquo;</p>
<p>While using credit cards for borrowing is convenient, those who entertain this idea should first understand the destructive power of a 20% interest rate. As mentioned earlier, if you save 14,000 per year and invest it in an investment tool with a 20% annual return, after 40 years, the 560,000 invested will grow to 102.81 million due to the power of compounding. Similarly, if someone borrows 14,000 per year on a credit card for 40 years, totaling 560,000, with a 20% interest rate, they will have to repay the bank 102.81 million after 40 years. This explains why the prevalence of credit card debt in the United States has historically led to numerous bankruptcies.</p>
<p>Another common type of loan is a mortgage.  Generally, mortgages are a sound form of leveraged investing because, in the long run, the average return on real estate is above 20%, while typical mortgage interest rates are around 10%, which meets the first principle of leveraged investing: the expected return on investment is higher than the interest rate on the loan. Whether it meets the second principle depends on the purchase conditions. In recent years, with the real estate market downturn and oversupply, some pre-sale housing promotions offer &ldquo;70% financing,&rdquo; allowing you to own a 10 million house with only a 3 million down payment. This is quite appealing, but investors often overlook the fact that while borrowing 7 million sounds great, they must be able to afford the monthly principal and interest payments of over 70,000. Without considering this, there is a risk of foreclosure and being forced to sell at a low price within months of purchase, suffering losses before enjoying any benefits of leveraged investing. Therefore, when purchasing real estate with borrowed funds, careful calculations must be made beforehand to choose a suitable house price that does not jeopardize the family&rsquo;s normal living expenses.</p>
<p>Although the initial burden of a mortgage is heavy, it becomes lighter over time as work experience and salary increase.  If you wait until you have saved enough money to buy a house, you might miss the opportunity entirely due to the rapid appreciation of house prices. Therefore, <strong>young people without real estate should consider buying a house as an investment. It not only forces them to save but also effectively combats inflation. Moreover, they can utilize the principle of financial leverage, using the bank&rsquo;s money to expand their credit and accumulate wealth.</strong></p>
<p><strong>How Much Debt Should You Take On?</strong></p>
<p>If you decide to use leveraged investing, the next question is: how much debt should you take on? This is a crucial question. Too much debt carries high risks, while too little debt fails to fully utilize the potential of making money with other people&rsquo;s money.</p>
<p>How much debt should a family take on?  Like &ldquo;how much debt should a company have,&rdquo; this is a question without a precise answer. In practice, it depends on the specific circumstances of each family. However, one thing is certain: if a family has the capacity to borrow but chooses not to, it is being too conservative and not managing its finances optimally. Conversely, excessive borrowing is too dangerous.  Before taking on debt, each family should consider its actual situation and make a wise judgment about its debt level.  As for how much to borrow, I recommend considering the following factors:</p>
<ul>
<li>
<ol>
<li>Income Stability:  Loan interest must be paid on time regardless of investment performance. If your income source is unstable, you may not be able to make regular interest payments, making high-leverage investments unsuitable. Similar to companies with stable income, they have a greater capacity to utilize more debt.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol start="2">
<li>Personal Assets: Borrowing from financial institutions requires tangible assets as collateral. Therefore, owning more assets suitable as collateral allows for larger leveraged investments.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol start="3">
<li>Return on Investment: Other things being equal, the higher the return on investment, the greater the benefits of financial leverage.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol start="4">
<li>Inflation Rate: Borrowing is more advantageous during periods of high inflation, as inflation allows you to repay debt with less valuable money.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol start="5">
<li>Risk Tolerance: Everyone has a different risk tolerance, related to personality and individual circumstances. Those with low risk tolerance should not over-leverage, even if it could lead to large profits, as the stress could take a toll.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol start="6">
<li>Market Interest Rate Levels: Generally, when market interest rates fall and bank funds are ample, not only is it easier for investors to borrow money, but the benefits of financial leverage are also greater. Therefore, falling interest rates present an opportune time for investors to consider leveraged investing.</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>Keeping money in the bank makes a person poor.</p>
</blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">The Bank is Not a Place for Saving Money 
    <div id="the-bank-is-not-a-place-for-saving-money" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#the-bank-is-not-a-place-for-saving-money" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>What is the function of a bank to you? Many people believe banks are for saving money. However, for those who truly understand investment management, banks are not a place to save money, but a source of borrowing.</p>
<p><strong>The function of a bank is to provide a place for those who are not good at managing money to save, so that those who are good at it can use that money to invest and make profits.</strong> Suppose someone deposits 14,000 per year into a bank at a 5% interest rate. After 40 years, the bank will owe this depositor 1.69 million. On the other hand, if an investor borrows 14,000 per year from the same bank at the same 5% interest rate and invests that money in stocks or real estate, achieving an average annual return of 20%, after 40 years, their investment would grow to 102.81 million, while they only need to repay the bank 1.69 million. In other words, the 101.12 million gained was made by utilizing the money of bank depositors.</p>
<p><strong>How to Build Credit</strong></p>
<p>In today&rsquo;s highly developed financial markets, there are numerous financing channels for businesses. However, for individuals, banks remain the primary source of borrowing.  Maintaining a close relationship with the bank and earning their trust is crucial for building personal credit.</p>
<p>Credit is the ability to borrow.  A person with high credit not only demonstrates a strong ability to repay loans but also indicates wealth. How do you build credit?  As the saying goes, &ldquo;Loan and repay, and borrowing again is easy.&rdquo; The first rule of building credit is to borrow money and repay it on time. Some people, to establish their creditworthiness (the ability to borrow), even borrow small sums of money for seemingly frivolous reasons, just to build a good borrowing record so they can borrow larger amounts in the future.</p>
<p>Discard the outdated notion that &ldquo;borrowing is not respectable.&rdquo; In the past, only those in dire financial straits would borrow money. Nowadays, such individuals can at most borrow small amounts from relatives and friends.  They would likely be unable to borrow a cent from a bank.  Today, those who can borrow from banks are typically wealthy individuals.</p>
<p>Based on current bank loan approval standards, without sufficient assets as collateral or evidence of stable future income and repayment ability, can anyone borrow money? Therefore, when I hear about someone heavily in debt, my first question is whether the source of the debt is banks or private loans.  If the source is entirely from banks, my immediate thought is: &ldquo;This person must be wealthy.&rdquo;</p>
<p><strong>Borrowing: A Double-Edged Sword</strong></p>
<p>Those who don&rsquo;t borrow cannot go bankrupt; similarly, those who don&rsquo;t borrow can hardly become immensely wealthy in a short period.  &ldquo;Debt&rdquo; appears in the lives of both the most successful and the most unsuccessful. While many wealthy individuals utilize debt to become rich, many poor people are ruined by misusing debt. Borrowing is a double-edged sword. Used correctly, it is a significant aid to investment and wealth creation. Used improperly, its destructive power can lead to complete ruin.  Prudence is essential when using it. It&rsquo;s like a double-edged sword that can save or harm, depending on how it&rsquo;s wielded.</p>
<p>I advise against rushing into leveraged investing before fully understanding its principles.  First, understand the nature of leveraged investing and carefully consider whether to use borrowing for investment.  Before borrowing, thoroughly understand how leveraged investing works. Only then can you truly achieve the goal of making money with other people&rsquo;s money without harming yourself.</p>
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Personal Investment Bible: Investment Iron Law V</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1731056005964/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1731056005964/</guid><description>This article explores the relationship between risk and return in investment and financial management, emphasizing the importance of risk management. It points out that all high-return investments come with high risks, and while risk aversion is human nature, excessive risk aversion can lead to missed opportunities. Using Forbes&amp;#39; philosophy on risk as an example, the author illustrates how to assess risks and rewards, advocating for calculated risks with adequate preparation. The article also cautions readers against being seduced by high-risk, low-return speculative activities, encouraging them to start with small investments to gain experience, gradually overcome their fear of risk, and ultimately master risk to achieve wealth growth.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[

<h2 class="relative group">Investment Iron Law V: Mitigating Investment Risk 
    <div id="investment-iron-law-v-mitigating-investment-risk" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#investment-iron-law-v-mitigating-investment-risk" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>Investment and financial management should never prioritize returns while neglecting risks.</p>
</blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">Analyzing Risk, Minimizing Damage 
    <div id="analyzing-risk-minimizing-damage" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#analyzing-risk-minimizing-damage" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>In 1987, while working at Merrill Lynch in the United States, I met a seasoned investment veteran with decades of Wall Street experience. He once said, &ldquo;I can teach you how to pick stocks in an hour, but it would take me more than five years to teach you how to manage investment risk.&rdquo;</p>
<p><strong>Risk is Unavoidable</strong></p>
<p>In the ever-changing and unpredictable world of investment, uncertainties abound. We call these uncertainties risks. How you face these risks when they materialize is a question every investor must confront. <strong>Risk is called risk precisely because future outcomes are uncertain and unavoidable.</strong> Therefore, investment and financial management should never solely focus on returns while ignoring risks. In fact, managing risk is even more crucial. <strong>The purpose of risk management is not to eliminate risk entirely, but to acknowledge its inherent existence and impossibility of complete eradication.  It&rsquo;s about analyzing risk and subsequently mitigating it.</strong></p>
<p>While engaging in risk management, investors must understand that &ldquo;you can never be fully prepared for every risk.&rdquo;  You can strive to reduce risk, but don&rsquo;t attempt to eliminate it completely. Many try to avoid risk through predictions or expert advice.  However, no matter how accurate your forecasting techniques or how insightful the expert predictions, risk can never be fully avoided. <strong>The greatest danger of predictions is not their frequent inaccuracy, but the tendency for investors to blindly trust them, losing their risk awareness. They focus solely on whether the prediction comes true, neglecting the potential magnitude of the underlying risks.</strong>  Relying solely on predictions without thorough risk analysis is extremely dangerous. Any sound investment decision inherently involves unknowns, uncertainties, and risks.  Furthermore, investments without uncertainties and a degree of risk are unlikely to be good investments.</p>
<p><strong>All High-Return Investments Carry High Risks</strong></p>
<p>The key to successful investment and financial management lies in learning to grasp high returns while effectively managing the accompanying risks.</p>
<p>The investment environment is constantly changing and unpredictable. The only constant is change. Some external factors (such as interest rates, exchange rates, economic conditions, and inflation rates) are bound to change, although the nature of these changes remains unknown.  Additionally, unforeseen events (such as wars, political events, and natural disasters) are uncontrollable variables.  To succeed in this volatile investment world, the most important thing is not to lament change but to accept it as inevitable. <strong>Prepare for various changes and even anticipate them, because only through change can wealth be redistributed.</strong> Change is both a threat and an opportunity, depending on how you respond.  Skilled investors often find profitable opportunities amidst change.</p>
<p>People often assume investors love risk.  This is not true.  Successful investors possess a unique ability to manage risk. They don&rsquo;t see &ldquo;risk-taking&rdquo; as a source of amusement, nor do they find the act of taking risks thrilling or exciting. They take risks solely for the potential of high investment returns.  Since all high-return investments inherently carry high risks, risk-taking is an unavoidable part of the journey to financial success.</p>
<p>Many perceive stock investment as extremely risky, believing stock investors to be risk-seekers. In reality, investing in stocks is not about loving the risk associated with stocks. It&rsquo;s about understanding that all high-return investments carry high risks. To build wealth, you must take the risk of investing in high-return assets and bear the associated risks.  Savvy investors understand how to take calculated risks and mitigate them.  In fact, if risk mitigation measures are implemented effectively, the actual risks of investment and financial management are relatively small.</p>
<p><strong>Stocks and real estate offer high returns precisely because of their inherent volatility and risk.</strong> Because most people are risk-averse and avoid investing in risky assets like stocks and real estate, those who can tolerate risk are better positioned to reap higher returns.</p>
<p>Many shy away from stocks and real estate primarily because they fear losses, are intimidated by future uncertainties, or can&rsquo;t handle price fluctuations. <strong>In fact, short-term price fluctuations are perfectly normal and highlight the high-risk nature of high-return investments.</strong> Therefore, to achieve high returns, one must possess a spirit of adventure and be able to withstand significant volatility.</p>
<p><em>1. Unpredictable risks allow risk-takers to earn a risk premium.</em></p>
<p><em>2. We miss opportunities because we are afraid to take risks, not because the world doesn&rsquo;t offer them.</em></p>
<p><em>3. To achieve financial success through investment, you must take risks, because high returns always come with high risks.</em></p>
<blockquote>
<p>I dislike taking unnecessary risks, so before every activity, I do my best to take necessary precautions to mitigate risk.</p>
</blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">The Forbes Philosophy on Risk 
    <div id="the-forbes-philosophy-on-risk" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#the-forbes-philosophy-on-risk" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>Malcolm Forbes was a legendary figure in the American business world.  He amassed a fortune by founding Forbes magazine, possessed a priceless collection, and was listed among the 400 wealthiest Americans. He not only ran a high-risk magazine business but was also a renowned hot air balloonist and motorcycle enthusiast.  He once rode a motorcycle across Eurasia from Paris to Beijing.  He traveled the world, flying hot air balloons across the United States, and even ventured to Turkey and China, setting multiple world records and attracting widespread media attention, making him a household name.</p>
<p><strong>Averting Danger Before it Happens, Ensuring Safety</strong></p>
<p>Some labeled him an &ldquo;adventurer.&rdquo;  He offered an insightful explanation of this label, saying, &ldquo;Many people think I&rsquo;m a risk-lover.  I&rsquo;m not. Like most people, I strongly dislike risk. The reason I take risks today, despite my aversion to them, is simple: all good things in life come with risks. I take risks purely to live a rich and fulfilling life.”  &ldquo;Riding in a hot air balloon or on a motorcycle across different lands broadens one&rsquo;s horizons and exposes one to the world&rsquo;s beauty, enriching life. However, many people, despite yearning for these experiences, hesitate to engage in them because they perceive them as high-risk activities. But, once you actually try them, you&rsquo;ll find that if you take adequate precautions beforehand, the risks involved are quite small.” &ldquo;I dislike taking unnecessary risks, so before every activity, I strive to take the necessary preventative measures to mitigate risk.&rdquo;</p>
<p>Malcolm Forbes was risk-averse, but he took risks to experience the good things in life, and after taking those risks, he sought ways to mitigate them.</p>
<p><strong>Assess the Rewards and Risks, If It&rsquo;s Worth It – Take the Risk</strong></p>
<p>Are you afraid of taking risks? If so, you are not alone.  Most people are afraid of taking risks; very few are natural risk-takers.  But why are some people so composed in the face of risk, and even achieve success through it?  It&rsquo;s because they understand the principles of &ldquo;nothing ventured, nothing gained&rdquo; and &ldquo;no high risk, no high return.&rdquo;  Indeed, the correct perspective on risk should be: take risks worth taking, and then find ways to mitigate them.</p>
<p>Successful investors are driven by the pursuit of &ldquo;wealth.&rdquo; Although they must be prepared to withstand the pressure of price fluctuations, as long as the expected return is high and there&rsquo;s a risk premium, risk-taking will ultimately lead to success.</p>
<p>Before every investment, it&rsquo;s essential to understand the potential risks and develop contingency plans for every possible scenario. Analyze the degree of blind risk-taking, estimate the probability of success, and continuously re-evaluate throughout the process. I recommend investors create a risk-reward assessment table before making any investment, weighing all factors.  Ask yourself, &ldquo;Can I bear the consequences if the worst-case scenario unfolds?&rdquo; and &ldquo;Is the potential return of this investment attractive enough?&rdquo;</p>
<p>Always plan for the worst and prepare for the best. This is especially true for investment and financial management.  <strong>Before making any investment, no matter how confident you are, you should ask yourself, &ldquo;What is the worst possible outcome?&rdquo; Then ask, &ldquo;Can I bear the consequences if the worst happens?&rdquo; If the answer to both questions is yes, and the expected return is high enough, then you should invest. If the worst-case scenario is unbearable, then no matter how alluring the potential reward, you should categorically refuse to invest.</strong></p>
<p><strong>Don&rsquo;t Take Unnecessary Risks</strong></p>
<p>If you ever visit Las Vegas or Atlantic City, observe the lavishly decorated casinos carefully. You&rsquo;ll notice the absence of clocks and windows, and the ever-present bright lights.  &ldquo;There&rsquo;s no time in the mountains, and no time in casinos.&rdquo; Why are there no clocks or windows in casinos?  It&rsquo;s because casinos leverage the law of large numbers to win your money.  The lack of clocks and windows is designed to blur the lines between day and night, encouraging gamblers to play endlessly until they lose track of time. The longer you play, the more times you play, the higher the probability of the casino winning.  As the number of games increases, the expected value gradually reveals itself.  Gambling inevitably leads to losses because its expected value is negative.  This might not be apparent in a few instances, but over time, the expected value becomes increasingly evident. Therefore, prolonged gambling inevitably leads to losses.  This explains the saying &ldquo;nine out of ten gamblers lose&rdquo; and &ldquo;long-term gambling leads to certain loss,&rdquo; which aligns perfectly with the principle of the law of large numbers. The law of large numbers states that the more times a game is played, the closer the return gets to the expected value of that game.</p>
<p>I had a classmate in the doctoral program at UC Berkeley who excelled in mathematics and frequented Las Vegas casinos on weekends.  Curious, I asked him, &ldquo;You&rsquo;re so smart and you know that gambling is designed against the players. Are you trying to win money?&rdquo;  He replied, &ldquo;I never go there to win money. I gamble to relieve stress.&rdquo;  He explained that after a heartbreak in college, he tried various methods to cope, such as drinking, speeding, and traveling, but none were effective.  He eventually found that only gambling could allow him to truly escape. Gambling can be a form of entertainment, but it&rsquo;s certainly not a way to make money. Its expected average return is lower than bank deposits, making it impossible to build wealth through such activities.</p>
<p>Many people hold the misconception that &ldquo;high risk always equates to high return.&rdquo; This misunderstanding stems from a misinterpretation of the definition of &ldquo;return.&rdquo; High risk might indeed offer high potential returns, but this represents the maximum possible return, which has a very low probability.  However, in the context of &ldquo;high risk, high return,&rdquo; the &ldquo;return&rdquo; refers to the expected return (long-term average return), not the maximum possible return.  Indeed, gambling boasts incredibly high maximum potential returns, but its average, or expected, return is negative. Taking such risks is not only unprofitable but also detrimental.</p>
<p><strong>There are No High-Return, Zero-Risk Investments</strong></p>
<p>Success requires risk-taking, but risk-taking doesn&rsquo;t guarantee success.  One must take calculated risks. A calculated risk is one that, on average, offers high returns over the long term.</p>
<p>Some people&rsquo;s problem isn&rsquo;t a lack of risk-taking spirit but a tendency to take unnecessary risks. They don&rsquo;t know what risks to take to achieve financial success. As detailed in previous chapters, the cornerstone of investment success is the power of compounding, which only works effectively with high returns.  Over the long term, stocks and real estate are asset classes that offer high expected returns.  Therefore, taking calculated risks means investing in assets with high expected returns and bravely bearing the associated risks.</p>
<p>Consider a game where participants must pay $100. There&rsquo;s a 99.9% chance of losing $100 and a 0.1% chance of winning $95,000. Would you play?  In a survey I conducted with hundreds of students, over 65% chose to play this high-risk game.  Their reasoning was simple: while the risk was high, the potential loss was capped at $100, while the potential gain was a whopping $95,000.  However, the expected return of this game is negative.  Even if you get lucky and win once, in the long run, you&rsquo;re bound to lose.  This is a classic example of a risk not worth taking.</p>
<p>Avoid risks that don&rsquo;t offer high returns. Activities like futures trading, margin trading in foreign exchange and bonds, lotteries, and short-term stock trading all carry high risks and often have negative returns.  In other words, these are high-risk, negative-return activities.  You can engage in these activities for entertainment, but never delude yourself into believing they will bring you wealth.</p>
<p><strong>There are no high-return, zero-risk investment opportunities.</strong> In a society filled with intelligent individuals, such opportunities are impossible. If someone offers you a high-return, risk-free investment opportunity, they are undoubtedly trying to scam you.</p>
<p>I remind readers again: don&rsquo;t blindly chase high returns and jump into risky ventures.  Speculative activities like those mentioned above are not truly high-return investment tools, but they are definitely high-risk endeavors.  These risks are not worth taking.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Absolute safety is a myth. The real danger is not taking any risks. In a volatile environment, the biggest risk is not taking any risks.</p>
</blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">Don&rsquo;t Shy Away from Risk Entirely 
    <div id="dont-shy-away-from-risk-entirely" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#dont-shy-away-from-risk-entirely" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>The future world is changing rapidly.  Changes will accelerate across all aspects of business, economics, finance, politics, and society, creating a more complex financial landscape.  <strong>It&rsquo;s foreseeable that wealth redistribution will also accelerate.</strong> Risk aversion is human nature.  In the past, you could live a stable life without taking risks.  However, <strong>in the face of the volatile investment environment of the future, not taking risks becomes the biggest risk of all.</strong></p>
<p><strong>Fear of Falling Will Keep You from Running Fast</strong></p>
<p>Fear of risk prevents many from investing, causing them to miss out on the opportunity to build wealth.  Keeping money in a bank seems safe and risk-free. However, as previously analyzed, inflation severely erodes the real value of money.  From a financial management perspective, keeping money in a bank carries the greatest risk.  Decades later, when those around you who invested wisely become millionaires, those who kept their money in banks may face financial hardship.  My point is: don&rsquo;t shy away from risk entirely. Risk isn&rsquo;t as terrifying as it seems.  Taking calculated risks with high potential returns is absolutely worthwhile.</p>
<p>I&rsquo;m often asked, &ldquo;Teacher, will the stock market fall again?&rdquo; My answer is, &ldquo;I don&rsquo;t know.&rdquo;  Then they ask, &ldquo;When will it start rising?&rdquo; My answer remains, &ldquo;I don&rsquo;t know.&rdquo;  They further inquire, &ldquo;Which stock should I buy?  Can you give me a hot tip?&rdquo; My answer is still, &ldquo;I don&rsquo;t know.&rdquo;  Then they question skeptically, &ldquo;How can you invest when you don&rsquo;t know anything? Isn&rsquo;t that too risky?&rdquo; My response is, &ldquo;You must invest and manage your finances without knowing the answers to these questions to succeed.&rdquo;</p>
<p>Why invest when the answers are unknown and the future is uncertain? The reason is simple: While the future is full of risks, one thing is certain: as long as the economy continues to grow and corporate profitability rises, the long-term return on investment in the stock market will inevitably surpass bank deposits, and by a significant margin.  Repeatedly avoiding worthwhile risks will prevent you from building wealth.</p>
<p><strong>How to Cultivate a Risk-Taking Spirit</strong></p>
<p><em>A courageous risk-taker is not someone without fear, but someone with the power to overcome it.</em></p>
<p>The spirit of adventure isn&rsquo;t innate; it&rsquo;s developed through practice, through taking risks, failing, taking risks again, failing again… step by step.</p>
<p>Everyone is capable of taking risks, and everyone has had the experience of taking bold risks.  As toddlers, we dared to stand and learn to walk, falling and getting back up countless times.  Learning to ride a bicycle involved numerous falls, followed by getting back up, falling again, and getting back up again, until we finally mastered it. Most life skills, such as swimming, skating, driving, public speaking, and so on, are not innate instincts.  Learning these skills requires going through a phase of risk-taking, embracing the spirit of perseverance, and trying repeatedly.  Learning investment and financial management is no exception; it requires this standard process of risk-taking.  To become a successful investor, you must first discard the habit of risk aversion, rediscover your lost instinct for adventure, and cultivate a healthy risk-taking spirit.</p>
<p>Does investing have to be extremely risky?  In reality, the risks involved in investment and financial management are no greater than the examples mentioned above.  It&rsquo;s just that as we reach an age where we believe we are qualified to manage finances, our risk-taking spirit has diminished significantly. As children, almost everyone learns to walk.  A little older, most learn to ride a bicycle.  But as we grow older, the number of people who learn more adventurous activities like swimming and skating decreases considerably.  In adulthood, the number of people comfortable with public speaking dwindles even further.</p>
<p><strong>Our risk-taking spirit seems to fade with age.  This is partly because experiencing failures and mistakes naturally leads to frustration and discouragement. Without sufficient motivation, we tend to avoid taking risks to minimize the blow of failure.  Another contributing factor is traditional education.  Out of a desire to protect children, adults often reprimand them for any risky behavior, instilling a habit of prioritizing safety and avoiding mistakes.  Children then strive to be &ldquo;good kids&rdquo; who never do anything wrong.  As we age, this risk aversion becomes ingrained. While avoiding risk isn&rsquo;t inherently bad, excessive risk aversion becomes a significant obstacle to successful investment and financial management.</strong></p>
<p><strong>The First Priority of Financial Management: Overcoming Fear</strong></p>
<p>When individuals can control their fear, they can control their thoughts and actions.  Self-control enables them to remain calm in chaotic environments, make necessary decisions without being paralyzed by the uncertainty of the outcomes, and be prepared to bear the consequences of failure when things don&rsquo;t go as planned. This courage and risk-taking spirit in the face of danger are essential qualities for investors.</p>
<p><strong>Courageous risk-takers are not fearless; they simply recognize risk and overcome their fear of it.</strong> Courage stems from controlling fear, and cultivating a risk-taking spirit begins with understanding risk.</p>
<p>To become a successful investor, you must first discard the habit of avoiding risk.  Admittedly, changing long-held risk-averse habits is no easy feat.  However, since risk-taking is an indispensable element of successful financial management, the first priority in learning to manage your finances is to overcome fear and force yourself to take risks.  Cultivate a healthy risk-taking spirit, invest bravely in assets with high expected returns, and bear the associated risks.</p>
<p><strong>Top performers in any field achieve success by bravely facing their fears and taking calculated risks.</strong> Those who achieve financial success and fulfill their dreams through investment share this same spirit of adventure. <strong>Remember: excessive caution hinders success.  Without a spirit of adventure, dreams will forever remain dreams.</strong></p>
<blockquote>
<p>Mastering risk is the foundation of successful financial management.</p>
</blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">Overcoming Risk – Start Small 
    <div id="overcoming-risk--start-small" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#overcoming-risk--start-small" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>Skilled risk-takers never test the depth of the water by stepping in with both feet. They extend one foot first, and if the situation seems unfavorable, they quickly withdraw.  An African proverb states, &ldquo;Only a fool tests the depth of the water with both feet.&rdquo;  Similarly, only a fool would go all-in without any investment experience.</p>
<p><strong>Gain Experience with Small Amounts of Money</strong></p>
<p>When faced with unfamiliar investment opportunities, don&rsquo;t put all your eggs in one basket. Start small.  Skilled generals don&rsquo;t expose their main forces to unnecessary danger.  To gather intelligence and gain an advantage, they deploy small reconnaissance units deep into enemy territory to identify low-risk, high-impact attack strategies.</p>
<p>The same principle applies to investment risk-taking strategies.  When dealing with unfamiliar investments, unclear situations, or a lack of confidence, avoid going all-in.  Start small, using small amounts of money to gain experience and familiarize yourself with the situation. Once you have sufficient experience and confidence, then you can invest larger sums.</p>
<p>As the saying goes, &ldquo;All things are difficult before they are easy.&rdquo; The best way to overcome fear is to confront what you fear head-on.  Since risk-taking is an essential part of building wealth through investment, don&rsquo;t shy away from it.  Start with small investments to build your risk tolerance.  With experience, the feeling of fear will gradually dissipate.  By progressively overcoming small fears, you can then face larger risks. You&rsquo;ll soon discover that the experience gained through risk-taking is helping you steadily approach your dreams.</p>
<p><strong>Once You&rsquo;re Used to Risk, You&rsquo;ll Find It&rsquo;s Not So Scary</strong></p>
<p>Risk aversion is human nature, but don&rsquo;t let a single investment failure shatter your confidence and prevent you from investing again, turning you into a perpetual loser.  Conversely, don&rsquo;t let a stroke of good luck make you forget the existence of risk, leading you to borrow heavily and invest recklessly, resulting in irreparable losses.  Successful and unsuccessful investors alike fear risk; they simply react to it differently.</p>
<p>Dear readers, if you haven&rsquo;t tried investing yet, take the plunge for the sake of building wealth!  If you take appropriate risk mitigation measures after investing, I can assure you from experience: &ldquo;The risks of investing are actually quite small, even smaller than the risk of riding a bicycle.  After 10 or 20 years of investing, when you see your wealth growing rapidly, the feeling will be hundreds of times better than riding a bicycle.&rdquo;</p>
<p><strong>The first element of investing is a strong adventurous spirit, seeking to generate substantial risk premiums between risk and safety.</strong> No matter what investment you choose, as long as it offers high expected returns, risk is inevitable. Investors should embrace calculated risks and accumulate financial knowledge and experience along the way. Risk naturally decreases with accumulated knowledge, and wealth grows at an increasing pace.</p>
<p>This book dedicates significant space to discussing risk because the biggest challenge people face in financial management is their inability to confront risk directly.  They don&rsquo;t know how to face or manage risk, and some are even afraid to take any risks.  They don&rsquo;t realize that the biggest obstacle to successful investment and financial management is the fear of risk. This mindset is understandable, as most investment and financial management decisions are made amidst uncertainty and change. In short, to achieve financial success through investment, you must be willing to take calculated risks. Currently, many people suffer significant losses due to blind risk-taking and involvement in high-risk speculative activities.</p>
<p>If you are unwilling to take risks and prefer a conservative approach, be prepared for a life of mediocrity, as this is unavoidable. Of course, there&rsquo;s nothing wrong with a conservative and mediocre life if it brings you happiness. The choice is yours. <strong>People usually regret the things they didn&rsquo;t do, not the things they tried.</strong> Therefore, my advice is: <strong>Take risks, but be cautious and learn how to manage them.</strong></p>
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Personal Investment Bible: Investment Iron Law II</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1731056005961/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1731056005961/</guid><description>This article explains that the key to wealth accumulation through personal finance is patience. Using Li Ka-shing&amp;#39;s wealth accumulation as an example, it explains the power of compound interest and emphasizes the importance of long-term investment and time. At the same time, the article also points out the pitfalls of getting rich quickly and advises readers to choose entrepreneurship rather than speculation.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[

<h2 class="relative group">Investment Iron Law II: Patience is Key to Wealth Accumulation 
    <div id="investment-iron-law-ii-patience-is-key-to-wealth-accumulation" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#investment-iron-law-ii-patience-is-key-to-wealth-accumulation" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>Working hard is not about making more money,<br>
but about maintaining a state of mind<br>
— challenge, goals, struggle, and success.</p>
</blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">How Did Li Ka-shing Accumulate His Wealth? 
    <div id="how-did-li-ka-shing-accumulate-his-wealth" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#how-did-li-ka-shing-accumulate-his-wealth" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>Li Ka-shing, ranked among the top ten wealthiest Chinese in the world with a fortune of nearly $7 billion, is the chairman of Cheung Kong Holdings and Hutchison Whampoa Limited in Hong Kong. His legendary journey to wealth and his influence in Hong Kong&rsquo;s political and business circles have earned him another nickname — &ldquo;Superman Li.&rdquo;</p>
<p><strong>Capitalizing on the Plunging Property Market</strong></p>
<p>In 1939, 12-year-old Li Ka-shing moved to Hong Kong from his hometown of Chao&rsquo;an, Guangdong, with his father. After two years of schooling, Hong Kong fell due to the Pacific War. The following year, his father died of a serious illness, forcing Li Ka-shing, the eldest son, to drop out of school and support his family. After Hong Kong&rsquo;s liberation in 1945, he ended his odd-job career and became a salesman at a plastics factory, working over 16 hours a day. Three years later, at the age of 20, he was promoted to general manager. Two years after that, he used all his savings of HK$7,000 to start his own small plastics factory, &ldquo;Cheung Kong Industries,&rdquo; the predecessor of today&rsquo;s largest conglomerate in Hong Kong, Cheung Kong Holdings.</p>
<p>How did Li Ka-shing, without even a primary school diploma, take his first step toward becoming the richest man by producing plastic flowers? In 1958, due to a rent increase by the landlord of his factory, Li Ka-shing bought a piece of land in North Point and built his own factory. In the early 1960s, the plastic flower industry declined, and in 1967, Hong Kong property prices plummeted. Li Ka-shing seized the opportunity to acquire land at low prices. In 1972, the Hong Kong stock market soared, and Cheung Kong Industries went public, taking advantage of the opportunity to raise capital from the public to purchase more land. In the 10 years following the completion of his first factory in 1958, his real estate holdings increased 50-fold. Cheung Kong now holds approximately 1.48 million square meters of floor space. Li Ka-shing has been investing in real estate for over 40 years, and long-term investment has accumulated his enormous wealth.</p>
<p>Having strived for 50 years and achieved success in wealth accumulation, Li Ka-shing has unique insights into success. He said: &ldquo;Before the age of 20, 100% of career success comes from hard work; between 20 and 30, when a career has some foundation, 10% of success depends on good luck, and 90% still comes from diligence; after 30, the proportion of opportunity gradually increases; now, luck accounts for about 30% to 40%.&rdquo;</p>
<p>The same applies to wealth accumulation. Before 20, all money comes from hard work; between 20 and 30 is the time to work hard to earn and save money; after 30, the importance of investment and financial management gradually increases. By middle age, the money earned is less important, and how to manage money becomes more critical. Li Ka-shing has been fighting for his wealth all his life. To become rich, one must have enough patience.</p>
<p><strong>The Power of Compound Interest Takes Time</strong></p>
<p>Many people who have heard my lectures often ask the same questions: &ldquo;Saving 14,000 yuan a year to become a billionaire is indeed impressive, but according to your method, it takes 40 years, which is really discouraging!&rdquo; &ldquo;It takes 40 years to become a billionaire. By then, I might be dead. What&rsquo;s the point of having billions then?&rdquo; &ldquo;Can you teach some secrets to getting rich quickly?&rdquo;</p>
<p>Even I feel that 40 years is too long. At the repeated requests of the audience, I did spend some time studying this issue in depth. The result of the research is: <strong>Financial management requires a long time, and the effect is not visible in the short term.  It is impossible to get rich quickly through financial management.</strong></p>
<p>If someone starts now and saves 14,000 yuan at the end of each year, and if the money saved each year can be invested in stocks or real estate with an average annual return of 20%, we know that the wealth will grow to 102.81 million yuan after 40 years. Now, let&rsquo;s ask: How much wealth can he accumulate after 10 years? Most people think that with such a high return, even with a shorter time, after 10 years of compounding, it should be at least 5 million yuan, some even guess 10 million, and the most conservative guess is 1 million.  Similarly, this is a surprising answer: 360,000 yuan! The following calculation formula should be familiar to readers, but they will be surprised that the amount is so small.</p>
<p><math xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" display="block"><mtable displaystyle="true" columnalign="right center left" columnspacing="0 thickmathspace" rowspacing="3pt"><mtr><mtd><mn>14,000</mn><mo>×</mo><mfrac><mrow><msup><mrow><mo stretchy="false">(</mo><mn>1</mn><mo>+</mo><mn>0.20</mn><mo stretchy="false">)</mo></mrow><mrow><mn>10</mn></mrow></msup><mo>−</mo><mn>1</mn></mrow><mn>0.20</mn></mfrac></mtd><mtd><mi></mi><mo>=</mo></mtd><mtd><mn>360,000</mn></mtd></mtr><mtr><mtd><mn>14,000</mn><mo>×</mo><mfrac><mrow><msup><mrow><mo stretchy="false">(</mo><mn>1</mn><mo>+</mo><mn>0.20</mn><mo stretchy="false">)</mo></mrow><mrow><mn>40</mn></mrow></msup><mo>−</mo><mn>1</mn></mrow><mn>0.20</mn></mfrac></mtd><mtd><mi></mi><mo>=</mo></mtd><mtd><mn>102,810,000</mn></mtd></mtr></mtable></math></p>
<p>With the same 20% return, 14,000 yuan per year results in 102.81 million yuan after 40 years of financial management, but only 360,000 yuan after 10 years, which is unbelievable! The difference is more than 300 times! Fortunately, this concept is presented to readers in a timely manner. Otherwise, if readers use the methods mentioned in this book, save 14,000 yuan every year, and invest all of it in stocks, thinking that they can become billionaires, they would be shocked to find that after ten years of hard work, with an average annual return of 20%, they have only accumulated 360,000 yuan! They might feel cheated.  After struggling for 10 years, they can&rsquo;t even afford a car, let alone become billionaires!</p>
<p>What is 10 years? Ten years is a long time. After 10 years of struggle, there&rsquo;s only a little over 300,000 yuan. How discouraging! This is the frustration one inevitably encounters in the process of accumulating wealth through investment and financial management.  Investors must understand that financial management is a &ldquo;marathon&rdquo; rather than a &ldquo;sprint.&rdquo; It&rsquo;s about endurance, not explosive power.</p>
<p>The prerequisite for getting rich through investment and financial management is time, and a long time. You must go through a very long waiting period before you can see the results. If the invested capital is small, no results will be seen after 10 years.</p>
<p><strong>Earning Your Second 10 Million is Easier Than the First 1 Million</strong></p>
<p>Saving 14,000 yuan at the end of each year with an average investment return of 20%, even after 20 years, the assets will only accumulate to 2.61 million yuan.  At this point, one is still far from being a billionaire. It takes 30 years to accumulate 16.55 million yuan, barely reaching the millionaire level.  Only after 40 years of continuous struggle can one become a billionaire with 102.81 million yuan.</p>
<p><em>Annual Investment of 14,000 Yuan, Wealth Accumulation (20% Return, Unit/10,000 Yuan)</em></p>
<table>
  <thead>
      <tr>
          <th>Year</th>
          <th>Accumulated Amount at Year End</th>
          <th>Amount Increased in the Last Five Years</th>
      </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
      <tr>
          <td>5</td>
          <td>10</td>
          <td>10</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>10</td>
          <td>36</td>
          <td>26</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>15</td>
          <td>101</td>
          <td>65</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>20</td>
          <td>261</td>
          <td>160</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>25</td>
          <td>661</td>
          <td>400</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>30</td>
          <td>1655</td>
          <td>994</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>35</td>
          <td>4128</td>
          <td>2473</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>40</td>
          <td>10281</td>
          <td>6153</td>
      </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>
<p>From the table above, we can see: by saving 14,000 yuan annually with a 20% investment return, the wealth increased by 360,000 yuan in the first decade, 2.25 million yuan in the second decade, 13.94 million yuan in the third decade, and 86.26 million yuan in the fourth decade. This is the characteristic of geometric progression, and it is also the principle that people engaged in investment and financial management should understand.  Therefore, three important characteristics of investment and financial management can be summarized here:</p>
<ul>
<li>
<ol>
<li>Most wealth is created in the later stages. From the above example, we can see that only 41.28 million yuan was accumulated in the first 35 years, while 61.53 million yuan was created in the last 5 years.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol start="2">
<li>In terms of amount, your ability to make money through financial management increases over time. From the table above, it can be seen that doing the same thing, the amount of money earned increases, the only thing needed is patience.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol start="3">
<li>Earning the second 10 million yuan is often easier than the first 1 million yuan.</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>Wealth accumulation doesn&rsquo;t happen overnight.</p>
</blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">Patience Pays Off 
    <div id="patience-pays-off" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#patience-pays-off" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>A self-made man who got rich by investing in stocks once told me: &ldquo;Now that I&rsquo;ve made it, a stock price increase can easily bring in millions of yuan. Making money has suddenly become so easy, it&rsquo;s unstoppable. Thinking back to the days when I first entered the stock market 30 years ago, it took a lot of hard work to earn tens of thousands of yuan. I really don&rsquo;t know where the money went back then.&rdquo;</p>
<p>This experience is not unfamiliar to many who have struggled to build their fortunes from scratch.  Everything is difficult at the beginning.  During the initial struggle, money is hard to earn.  It takes a lot of effort to earn just tens of thousands of yuan. It&rsquo;s puzzling why money is so hard to earn.  Until success is achieved, and money comes rolling in, one wonders why making money has become so easy.</p>
<p><strong>Time is the Stepping Stone to Wealth Accumulation</strong></p>
<p>Everyone desires the ability to effortlessly earn their second million or ten million, reaching a state of abundant wealth.  The problem is, before earning the second million, you need to have the first million. But how can you earn the first million?  If you want to accumulate 1 million through investment and financial management, you need &ldquo;time.&rdquo; You have to go through a long period of hardship. If you can endure the difficult period of earning the first million, you can naturally enjoy the ease of earning the second million.</p>
<p>From the compound interest formula, we can see that time is an indispensable factor for compound interest to take effect.  Patient waiting is a prerequisite for investment and financial management.  Especially for wealth accumulation through financial management, the required patience is not a few months or years, but at least two or three decades, or even four or five decades.</p>
<p>The vast majority of wealthy people accumulate their huge fortunes gradually from small amounts of money over a long period. In the beginning, most people have very little capital, even negligible. However, success is woven from a series of small achievements. Great wealth is the accumulation of small wealth, coupled with the effect of compound interest.</p>
<p>The importance of time in investment and financial management is evident. Patience is essential for financial management. The more patient you are in enduring the long waiting period, the greater the power of wealth creation will be. This is the characteristic of &ldquo;compound interest.&rdquo; However, today we live in a &ldquo;fast food&rdquo; culture where everything emphasizes speed and efficiency: fast food restaurants for meals, express delivery for mail, highways for driving, one-hour photo processing, and crash courses for learning. People have become increasingly impatient and short-sighted, lacking patience.  In investment and financial management, they are also impatient and lack patience, wanting to see results immediately.  It may be more efficient to pursue speed in other matters, but investment and financial management cannot be rushed. Time is a necessary condition for financial management. The more you rush, the less you achieve.  Based on my observations, a common mistake among investors is giving up halfway. They get easily discouraged during bear markets and simply sell their stocks and real estate, completely leaving the stock and property markets, not knowing that lack of patience and perseverance makes it difficult to achieve anything.</p>
<ul>
<li>
<ol>
<li>Time is an indispensable factor in achieving wealth through financial management.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol start="2">
<li>The patience required for wealth accumulation is not a few months or years, but at least two or three decades.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol start="3">
<li>Patient waiting allows compound interest to take effect.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol start="4">
<li>How can investors achieve a state of abundant and unstoppable wealth? Long-term holding and patient waiting.</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>The Real Estate Investment Experience of Madam Chang Yao-Hung-Ying, Chairperson of Grand Pacific Construction</strong></p>
<p><em>&ldquo;Land I bought for hundreds of thousands in the past is now worth hundreds of millions.&rdquo;</em></p>
<p>Madam Chang Yao-Hung-Ying, chairperson of Grand Pacific Construction, pointed out: In the 1930s, a mainlander investing in land in Taiwan was often ridiculed. But it was with this small capital and perseverance that Madam Chang Yao-Hung-Ying, who left Shanghai for Taiwan in 1947, when her husband became disillusioned with his business, saw the development potential of Taiwan. She picked up their real estate business skills from Shanghai and started buying land.</p>
<p>After more than 40 years, her long-term investment in real estate finally paid off.  Her family&rsquo;s business is growing bigger and bigger, and they now own two listed companies: ASE Technology Holding and Grand Pacific Construction. ASE Technology Holding is now the second largest packaging factory in the world. As for Grand Pacific Construction, it launched the Earl&rsquo;s Court project in Xizhi in 1987, which boosted the real estate market in Xizhi and rapidly accumulated their family&rsquo;s wealth, making them one of the richest families in Taiwan.</p>
<p>Madam Chang Yao-Hung-Ying has now passed the baton to her son, Jason Chang. Jason Chang, chairman of ASE Technology Holding, seems to have inherited his mother&rsquo;s investment acumen. He&rsquo;s the kind of person who buys land wherever he goes, whether it&rsquo;s in Taiwan, Hong Kong, mainland China, or the United States. Perhaps in another two or three decades, Jason Chang will also say: &ldquo;I didn&rsquo;t expect that the land I bought for a few million back then would now be worth tens of billions.&rdquo;  However, Jason Chang&rsquo;s wealth accumulation speed will be much faster than his mother&rsquo;s because he has already laid a good foundation.  All he needs to do is go with the flow, and his wealth will increase geometrically, with money rolling in, unstoppable.</p>
<p><strong>Withstanding the Test of Time is the True Measure</strong></p>
<p><em>It&rsquo;s not your judgment that makes you a lot of money, but your patience.</em></p>
<p>A crucial factor in financial management is time. Without a correct understanding of it, impatience will naturally arise.  Impatience leads to taking significant risks, turning potential success into failure.</p>
<p>Whether it&rsquo;s the accumulation of wealth or experience, it&rsquo;s not something that can be accomplished overnight. It takes time. Fortunately, God is very fair in this regard. Regardless of whether one is born rich or poor, noble or humble, everyone has only 24 hours a day and an average lifespan of about 75 years. Time is the greatest wealth in life, and a person&rsquo;s honor, status, wealth, and happiness all depend on how they use this wealth.</p>
<p>To accumulate wealth through investment and financial management, time is an indispensable factor. It cannot be rushed.  Investment and financial management can lead to slow and steady wealth accumulation, but investing small amounts of money and wanting to earn billions of wealth in a short period is, I can say with certainty, &ldquo;impossible!&rdquo; Just imagine, can a mother give birth without going through ten months of pregnancy? Can a farmer shorten the growth period of rice seedlings?</p>
<p>The growth of wealth is like the growth of life.  It&rsquo;s formed bit by bit, day by day, month by month, year by year, under the effect of compound interest.  It cannot be achieved overnight. This is the law of nature, and God never changes his natural laws.</p>
<p><strong>Luck is Not a Long-Term Strategy</strong></p>
<p>Many investors make a fortune overnight and go bankrupt overnight. Their success is due to luck, and their failure is because &ldquo;you may be lucky for a while, but you cannot always be lucky.&rdquo; <strong>Any investment opportunity that promises overnight riches must hide a greater risk of overnight poverty.</strong> This is why most of those who fantasize about getting rich quickly through financial management end up losing everything.</p>
<p>As long as you are patient and invest your assets in the right investment vehicles, you don&rsquo;t need to actively manage or worry. Compound interest will naturally lead to wealth growth, and becoming a billionaire over time is almost a certainty. In investment and financial management, haste makes waste. &ldquo;Fast&rdquo; is definitely not good!</p>
<p>If you really want to get rich quickly, I suggest you try entrepreneurship instead of investment and financial management. If any of the readers want to get rich quickly, what should they do?  My sincere suggestion is to choose the path of entrepreneurship. I have studied the wealth accumulation process of many rich people throughout history and found that there are many examples of getting rich quickly through entrepreneurship. Bill Gates, the richest man in the United States, dropped out of college in his freshman year to found Microsoft and became the richest man in the United States in just 20 years.</p>
<p>However, the probability of success in getting rich through entrepreneurship is extremely low.  According to statistics from the Taiwan Entrepreneurship Association, the success rate of a person&rsquo;s first business venture is only about 7%, and entrepreneurial success does not necessarily mean getting rich. In other words, for every successful entrepreneur we see, there are at least dozens of unknown failures behind them.  Moreover, the entrepreneurial process is very arduous. Working more than ten hours a day seems to be a prerequisite for successful entrepreneurs.</p>
<p>On the contrary, as long as the method is correct, investing money in the stock market and property market, and waiting patiently for decades, the probability of getting rich through investment and financial management is very high. It&rsquo;s hard not to get rich, and the process is relatively easy and enjoyable!  Which method you choose to get rich is up to you. I must emphasize again that there is a possibility of getting rich quickly through entrepreneurship, but it is absolutely impossible to get rich quickly through financial management.</p>
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Personal Investment Bible: Investment Iron Law III</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1731056005962/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1731056005962/</guid><description>This article explores the importance of investing and managing finances, emphasizing the principle of &amp;#39;the sooner, the better.&amp;#39; It points out that procrastination is the primary cause of financial failure and encourages young people to start managing their finances early, rather than waiting until middle or old age. The article uses the success stories of Warren Buffett and Jeffrey Koo Jr. to illustrate the power of long-term investment and compound interest. It also emphasizes that even with limited funds, one should start managing their finances and learn how to utilize high-return investment tools to grow their wealth.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[

<h2 class="relative group">Investment Iron Law 3: Invest Sooner Rather Than Later 
    <div id="investment-iron-law-3-invest-sooner-rather-than-later" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#investment-iron-law-3-invest-sooner-rather-than-later" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>Invest first, then wait for the opportunity,<br>
rather than waiting for the opportunity to invest.</p>
</blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">Procrastination: The Primary Cause of Financial Failure 
    <div id="procrastination-the-primary-cause-of-financial-failure" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#procrastination-the-primary-cause-of-financial-failure" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>The mentality of &ldquo;things will work out&rdquo; and a passive approach to financial management is the most common obstacle to personal finance. It&rsquo;s also the main reason why many people struggle to achieve financial independence by retirement.  Many individuals adopt a passive attitude towards financial planning, believing that things will naturally fall into place. As they age and witness the rapid growth of others&rsquo; wealth, they finally realize the importance of financial management.  However, by then, time is often limited, the power of compound interest cannot be fully utilized, and it becomes too late, even if they understand the principles of financial management.</p>
<p><strong>Financial Management Is Not Just for the Middle-Aged</strong></p>
<p>Many young people believe that financial management is something for middle-aged or wealthy individuals, and that it&rsquo;s not too late to worry about it in old age.  Here, I want to remind readers that the ability to build wealth through financial management has little correlation with the amount of money one possesses, but a significant correlation with the length of time invested.  People often reach middle age, facing retirement with some savings, and only then start thinking about preparing for their financial future. However, at this point, it&rsquo;s often too late. The reason is insufficient time to allow compound interest to work its magic.  Turning small amounts of money into substantial wealth requires at least two to three decades.  Recall the previous example: 10 years is not enough time to see significant growth.  A much longer period is needed for remarkable results.</p>
<p>Since we know that building wealth through investment requires investing in high-return assets and leveraging the long-term effects of compound interest, our approach, besides enriching our investment knowledge and skills, should involve immediate action.  Financial planning should start as early as possible, cultivating patience and a long-term perspective.</p>
<p>The reason for many financial failures today is the lack of knowledge about how to utilize funds effectively to achieve the goal of making money work for you and building wealth through investment. This is a flaw in our education system. Schools dedicate significant time to teaching students how to earn a living but fail to teach them how to manage their earnings.  College students exploring financial management through stock investment are often viewed as engaging in speculative and greedy behavior. In a future dominated by finance, the lack of proper financial knowledge not only erodes the dream of wealth accumulation but also harms the financial operations of businesses and the overall prosperity of society.</p>
<p>Don&rsquo;t delay your financial plan using the excuse of uncertain future price trends.  Who can predict when real estate or stock prices will rise?  Past price surges always lead to regret for those who missed out. There are no clear signs before prices start to rise, and no one will announce it with fanfare. <strong>For investments that are unpredictable in the short term but offer high expected returns in the long term, the safest strategy is to invest first and then wait for the opportunity, not the other way around.</strong></p>
<p><strong>Warren Buffett Started Investing at Age 11</strong></p>
<p><em>I believe every business school graduate should sign a contract pledging to make no more than 20 major decisions in their lifetime. If your career spans 40 years, that&rsquo;s one decision every two years.</em></p>
<p>Warren Buffett, ranked the second richest man in America by Forbes magazine in 1996, is widely regarded as the god of stock investment. He claims that more than half of his net worth is attributed to about ten investment decisions. He believes the key to investment is to buy stocks of good companies at good prices and hold them for the long term. As long as these companies continue to perform well, don&rsquo;t sell their stocks.</p>
<p>Buffett, with a net worth of $9 billion, amassed his fortune entirely from the stock market.  At 68, he held an MBA from Columbia University and was the son of a stockbroker-turned-congressman.  Buffett made his first investment at the age of 11, putting his and his sister&rsquo;s small savings into the stock market. Initially, he lost money, and his sister criticized him, but he insisted that it would take three to four years to see profits. His sister sold her shares, while he held on, ultimately proving his point.</p>
<p>At 20, while studying at Columbia University, Buffett immersed himself in finance books and insurance industry statistics while his peers focused on leisure activities.  Lacking capital and disliking borrowing, he often sold stocks prematurely to reinvest in others. Despite the limitations of his funds, his wealth continued to grow.</p>
<p>In 1954, he joined Professor Graham&rsquo;s investment firm. Two years later, he raised $100,000 from family and friends and established his own firm. After its assets increased thirtyfold, he dissolved the company in 1969, returned the partners&rsquo; money, and focused on his own investments.</p>
<p>He is a true stock market tycoon and has been America&rsquo;s richest man for years. Other wealthy Americans, like Bill Gates and Henry Lea Hillman, built their fortunes through businesses, while Buffett focused on stock investment. As long as the US economy continues to grow, his wealth will continue to increase.</p>
<p>Buffett&rsquo;s immense wealth, accumulated through nearly 60 years of investing, is a testament to the power of compound interest.  His early experiences with trial and error played a crucial role in honing his investment acumen.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Financial management is like farming.<br>
A bountiful harvest in the future depends on diligent sowing and watering today.</p>
</blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">Start Investing Today 
    <div id="start-investing-today" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#start-investing-today" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>If time is an indispensable element of financial management, the best strategy is to act now. Start managing your finances today!</p>
<p><strong>Don&rsquo;t Wait Until Your Hair Turns White</strong></p>
<p>The earlier you start investing, the sooner you&rsquo;ll achieve your financial goals and enjoy the fruits of your labor with your family. Furthermore, starting early maximizes the time for compound interest to work, requiring smaller initial investments and making financial management easier and more enjoyable.</p>
<p>Starting later requires significantly higher monthly investments to reach the same goals. The following table is based on these assumptions: an annual return of 15%, a target amount of 100 million yuan, and a retirement age of 65. It calculates the required monthly investment for different starting ages.</p>
<p><em>Monthly Investment Required to Become a Millionaire, by Starting Age</em></p>
<table>
  <thead>
      <tr>
          <th>Starting Age</th>
          <th>Monthly Investment (Yuan)</th>
      </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
      <tr>
          <td>20</td>
          <td>2324</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>25</td>
          <td>4684</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>30</td>
          <td>9458</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>35</td>
          <td>19863</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>40</td>
          <td>39163</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>45</td>
          <td>81348</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>50</td>
          <td>175143</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>55</td>
          <td>410428</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>60</td>
          <td>1235959</td>
      </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>
<p>The table clearly demonstrates that youth is a valuable asset in wealth accumulation. The younger you are, the better positioned you are to achieve the dream of building wealth from small investments.  Starting financial planning in old age requires monthly investments that are beyond the reach of most people. In short, start saving for retirement early. Don&rsquo;t wait until your hair turns white; time waits for no one.</p>
<p>Your future financial well-being depends on your actions today. Don&rsquo;t let hesitation hold you back. Follow the principles outlined in this book, invest your funds in the stock market, real estate, or other high-return investment vehicles, and over time, you too can become wealthy.</p>
<p><em>1. The earlier you start investing, the longer the time for compound interest to work, and the sooner you&rsquo;ll achieve your wealth goals.</em></p>
<p><em>2. Only young people can dream of building wealth from small investments.</em></p>
<p><em>3. The best time to start managing your finances is as early as possible.</em></p>
<p><strong>Jeffrey Koo Jr.&rsquo;s Path to Wealth</strong></p>
<p>Jeffrey Koo Jr., the eldest son of Jeffrey Koo Sr., chairman of Chinatrust Commercial Bank in Taiwan, and current Vice President of Chinatrust, is actively uniting the third generation of Taiwanese entrepreneurs. He organized a luncheon club primarily for the third generation of prominent Taiwanese business families to network and exchange information. To expand its influence, Koo Jr. has also strengthened the luncheon club&rsquo;s connections with Southeast Asian politicians and the second and third generations of overseas Chinese business families.</p>
<p>Koo Jr. is a representative figure among Taiwan&rsquo;s third-generation entrepreneurs and the heir apparent to his father. Many assume his wealthy background afforded him a comfortable financial situation. However, Koo Sr. instilled frugal habits in his children and didn&rsquo;t provide excessive allowances.  Koo Jr. had to find his own ways to become financially independent.</p>
<p>Sent to Japan for his education by his father, Koo Jr. returned to Taiwan for university after graduating high school with only his accumulated New Year&rsquo;s money, around NT$100,000, in his bank account. In early 1987, as the weighted stock price index climbed from 1,000 points, many people invested in the stock market. Koo Jr., then a junior in college, followed suit, investing all his savings.  His grandmother&rsquo;s daily routine of asking him to recite the stock market index further influenced him.  His frequent interactions with entrepreneurs from various industries provided him with business opportunities, enabling him to grow his NT$100,000 capital to NT$10 million during the bull market.</p>
<p>When the stock market crashed from over 10,000 points in 1990, he was already pursuing his Master&rsquo;s degree at the Wharton School of Business in the US. His father, hoping for him to join the family business sooner, disapproved of his overseas studies and threatened to withhold financial support. Koo Jr. confidently assured his father that he could support himself financially. He successfully completed his studies in the US and even bought his dream car, a Porsche, with his own money.  Koo Jr.&rsquo;s knack for investment and financial management from a young age made his dreams a reality. If you aspire to be wealthy, start now!</p>
<p><strong>Youth Is the Greatest Asset for Financial Success</strong></p>
<p>Successful people have a habit: they delay, but don&rsquo;t give up, the enjoyment of the fruits of their labor.</p>
<p>In Louis Cha&rsquo;s novel <em>The Book and the Sword</em>, the Qianlong Emperor tells his sworn brother, &ldquo;I don&rsquo;t envy anything about you except your youth.&rdquo; Even the emperor envied youth.</p>
<p>Similarly, from a financial perspective, youth is the most important asset. I often tell college students, &ldquo;Young people, your name is wealth!&rdquo;  The compound interest formula clearly shows that time is money, and youth is wealth.</p>
<p>The compound interest chart provides a clear roadmap for financial planning: focus on increasing income and saving during your youth and start investing early. Money saved during youth contributes significantly to wealth in old age.  NT$10,000 saved in your youth can grow to over NT$2.3 million in 30 years.  The same amount saved in old age will only grow to NT$60,000 in 10 years. Whether the statement &ldquo;Young people, your name is wealth&rdquo; becomes a reality depends on whether young people manage their finances wisely. Poor financial management, even with the advantage of youth, will not bring wealth.</p>
<p>The prevalent notion among young people today is that it&rsquo;s fine to indulge in enjoyment while young and worry about financial planning later. This is a misguided perspective. Many young people believe retirement is far off and their funds are limited, so there&rsquo;s no need to consider investment. They often miss the opportunity to start early.</p>
<p>In reality, starting financial planning in old age, even with some savings, is often too late due to limited time. The correct approach is: <strong>investing and managing finances is the job of young people, while managing wealth is the job of old age.</strong>  However, many young people prioritize immediate gratification, spending their money on sports cars, high-end audio systems, or travel, believing they can enjoy life now and worry about finances later.</p>
<p>If you understand the role of time in financial management, it&rsquo;s easy to see why such individuals are destined for mediocrity.  Countless examples in society demonstrate how prioritizing enjoyment in youth leads to poverty in old age. The key is their neglect of the importance of early financial planning. By the time they realize it, it&rsquo;s often too late.</p>
<p>As Taiwan&rsquo;s population ages and smaller family structures become the norm, future generations will rely on their own financial resources for living expenses. Therefore, the concept of starting financial planning in youth becomes increasingly critical.</p>
<p><strong>Youth Is the Best Time for Taking Risks</strong></p>
<p>Young people possess the most valuable asset in financial management - time. Youth is also the best time to take risks because family responsibilities are generally lighter. Young people should embrace a risk-taking mindset because the cost of failure is lower.  You can recover from setbacks more easily. Moreover, with limited funds, potential losses are smaller, providing valuable learning experiences.  Most importantly, young people have ample time for compound interest to work its magic.</p>
<p>Before 50, one shouldn&rsquo;t adopt an overly conservative approach to investment and financial management. The best time to learn about financial management is as early as possible. Sound financial judgment comes from experience, and experience comes from mistakes. Since developing good judgment requires making some mistakes along the way, why not gain this experience while you&rsquo;re young and the stakes are lower?  By the time you have more capital, you can apply your honed financial judgment effectively.</p>
<p>Young people should not just spend money but also understand the importance of saving. Start saving, and once you have a few thousand or tens of thousands of yuan, consider long-term, high-return investments, even if they carry some risk.</p>
<p>Some may feel they are no longer young and their current income is low, leaving no surplus for investment. Indeed, older individuals have less time to benefit from compound interest. However, don&rsquo;t be discouraged. Money can buy time, and you might still have opportunities to catch up.  By following sound financial principles, you can achieve unexpected gains. If you are past 50, help your children by sharing these fundamental wealth-building concepts so they don&rsquo;t miss out on the opportunity to build wealth early in their lives.  Instead of giving your next generation money, teach them the knowledge of making money work for them.</p>
<p><em>1. Youth is the greatest asset for building wealth through financial management. 2. Young people should embrace risk-taking because the cost of failure is lower.</em> <em>3. Invest when you&rsquo;re young to maximize the benefits of compound interest over time.</em></p>
<blockquote>
<p>Playing a good hand well is nothing special; playing a bad hand well is what deserves admiration.</p>
</blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">Don&rsquo;t Neglect Financial Management Due to Limited Funds 
    <div id="dont-neglect-financial-management-due-to-limited-funds" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#dont-neglect-financial-management-due-to-limited-funds" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>Some believe that financial management is exclusive to the wealthy and high-income families, requiring substantial capital to even consider it.  Indeed, financial management is about making money work for you. It&rsquo;s not about turning stone into gold or creating something from nothing, so you need some initial capital. However, what many don&rsquo;t realize is that the most influential factors on future wealth, according to the compound interest formula, are the rate of return and the length of the investment period, not the current amount of capital or future contributions.</p>
<p><strong>Small Beginnings Can Lead to Great Fortunes</strong></p>
<p>With the right approach, even a small amount of money can generate significant wealth over time, as illustrated in previous examples.  Even someone with no initial capital, by investing 14,000 yuan annually, can become a millionaire in 40 years.  <strong>The principle of investment and financial management is this: understanding how to utilize high-return tools and the long-term effects of compound interest is more important than the amount of money invested.</strong></p>
<p>A common misconception is that financial planning is only necessary after accumulating a large sum of money. In reality, the key factors influencing future wealth are the rate of return and the length of investment period, not the amount of capital.  The key to successful financial management lies in maximizing returns and holding investments for the long term.  While having more capital can accelerate wealth accumulation, it&rsquo;s not the decisive factor.</p>
<p>Perhaps you&rsquo;ve considered investing but dismissed the idea due to limited funds. By doing so, you&rsquo;ve missed a valuable opportunity to enhance your investment skills.  The focus of investment should not be on &ldquo;how much money is earned&rdquo; but on &ldquo;the rate of return&rdquo; at which money is earned.  For example, earning 5,000 yuan on a principal of 100,000 yuan represents a 5% return, which is a poor investment. Earning 2,000 yuan on a principal of 10,000 yuan represents a 20% return, which is a good investment.  Over time, the latter will significantly outperform the former.  Therefore, the earlier you learn financial management, the better. It allows limited funds to leverage the power of compound interest and create substantial wealth.</p>
<p><strong>Those with Less Should Strive Harder</strong></p>
<p>Some may question how to invest with only a few thousand or tens of thousands of yuan. In today&rsquo;s developed financial markets, investment units are highly divisible. Around 10,000 yuan can buy a lower-priced stock, and a few thousand yuan can be invested in mutual funds.  Real estate is also moving towards securitization. In short, there will be more investment options for smaller amounts in the future.  Therefore, any idle funds not needed in the short term, even a few thousand yuan, should be invested.</p>
<p>Are people truly too poor to manage small amounts of money?  During the Chang Hwa Credit Cooperative bank run, many ordinary people withdrew hundreds of thousands of yuan.  Statistics also show that the average bank deposit is 600,000 yuan, which is more than enough for investment purposes.</p>
<p>Even those with no current savings or expecting limited future income shouldn&rsquo;t underestimate themselves and give up on financial planning. While wealthy or high-income individuals have a head start, those with fewer assets or lower incomes should understand the principles of financial management and leverage it to compensate for their financial disadvantages, ultimately improving their lifetime financial situation.</p>
<p>Moreover, individuals from humble beginnings and with modest incomes can achieve a greater sense of accomplishment by building wealth through diligent financial management.  As the saying goes, &ldquo;<strong>There&rsquo;s nothing remarkable about playing a good hand well; it&rsquo;s playing a bad hand well that deserves admiration.</strong>&rdquo; If you truly have no money, find ways to increase income and reduce expenses, save some money, and then start managing your finances. Remember, even a small amount of money is enough to begin. While the path to wealth may be longer and more challenging with limited initial funds, the goal is still achievable, and the journey itself is valuable.</p>
<p><em>1. Investment and financial management are not exclusive to the wealthy or high-income earners.</em></p>
<p><em>2. Those with limited assets or low incomes should leverage financial management to catch up.</em></p>
<p><em>3. The amount of money you have when you start doesn&rsquo;t matter. Less money might even be better, allowing you to experiment with smaller investments initially and gradually increase your investment as you become more comfortable with risk.</em></p>
<p><em>4. Leverage other people&rsquo;s money to accelerate wealth building.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Personal Investment Bible: Investment Iron Law I</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1731056005960/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1731056005960/</guid><description>This article criticizes the traditional financial concept of “saving money in the bank”. It points out that under inflation, low bank deposit interest rates struggle to withstand erosion from inflation, effectively resulting in “the more you save, the less you have”. This viewpoint is supported by examples from biblical stories, savings rate data, and the Nobel Prize Foundation&amp;#39;s case, encouraging readers to invest their funds in long-term, high-return investment tools like stocks and real estate to achieve wealth appreciation.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[

<h2 class="relative group">Investment Iron Law I: Don&rsquo;t Keep Your Money in the Bank 
    <div id="investment-iron-law-i-dont-keep-your-money-in-the-bank" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#investment-iron-law-i-dont-keep-your-money-in-the-bank" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>The vast majority of people who fail at financial management don&rsquo;t do so because they don&rsquo;t earn enough,
but because they put their assets in the wrong place.
Have you ever heard of anyone getting rich from bank savings?</p>
</blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">Saving Equals Wasting Resources 
    <div id="saving-equals-wasting-resources" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#saving-equals-wasting-resources" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>There&rsquo;s a parable in the Bible about financial stewardship. A landowner entrusted his property to three servants. He gave the first servant five units of money, the second two, and the third one. He told them to cherish and manage their wealth wisely, and he would return in a year to see how they had fared.</p>
<p><strong>Wasting Time and Money</strong></p>
<p>The first servant invested his money; the second bought raw materials and produced goods to sell; the third, for safety, buried his money under a tree. A year later, the landowner returned.  The first two servants had doubled their wealth, pleasing the landowner.  Only the third servant&rsquo;s money remained unchanged. He explained, &ldquo;Fearing loss through mismanagement, I kept the money safe. Today, I return it untouched.&rdquo;</p>
<p>The landowner was furious.  &ldquo;You lazy servant!&rdquo; he scolded. &ldquo;You didn&rsquo;t even try to utilize your wealth!&rdquo;  Wealth not utilized is wasted money and wasted potential. The third servant was rebuked not for misusing the money, nor for losing it through failed investments, but for keeping it &ldquo;safe&rdquo; and unproductive.</p>
<p>Keeping money in the bank is the most common approach to personal finance today, and also the biggest mistake people make.  Therefore, the first and most important financial rule this book offers is: <em>Don&rsquo;t keep your money in the bank.</em>  &ldquo;Bank&rdquo; here refers to post offices, commercial banks, and any other financial institution where money can be deposited.</p>
<p>Many believe that earning interest in a bank, benefiting from compound interest, constitutes sound financial planning. In reality, with inflation, the real rate of return is close to zero, meaning no real financial gain. Therefore, leaving money in the bank is equivalent to no financial management at all.</p>
<p>It&rsquo;s impossible to predict how much wealth each person will accumulate through financial management. The only certainty is that getting rich solely through bank savings is incredibly difficult.  Ask yourself, &ldquo;Have you ever heard of anyone getting rich purely from bank deposits?&rdquo;  Those who keep all their savings in the bank often find themselves not only failing to become wealthy in their old age but also struggling to maintain financial independence. Such stories are common.  Those who choose bank deposits as their primary financial management method do so primarily for safety. However, readers must understand:  <strong>&ldquo;Money in the bank is safest in the short term, but the most dangerous form of financial management in the long term.&rdquo;</strong></p>
<p><strong>Blind Spots in Personal Finance</strong></p>
<p><em>Most people manage their finances by keeping their money in the bank, so most people are not wealthy.</em></p>
<p>If accumulating immense wealth were as easy as the examples suggest, then most people over 65 today would be millionaires. However, this is far from reality.  Millionaires over 65 are few and far between, with many senior citizens facing financial hardship, relying on continued work or support from their children to make ends meet.</p>
<p>Surveys on the elderly in Taiwan reveal increasingly serious financial challenges for senior citizens.  Among approximately 1.48 million people aged 65 and above, about 13% rely on financial assistance from family and friends or social welfare.  This demonstrates a serious problem with most people&rsquo;s financial concepts and investment methods. How else could they reach old age not only without wealth but without even basic financial independence?</p>
<p>Taiwan&rsquo;s savings rate has historically been above 30%, currently hovering between 20% and 30%, consistently ranking among the highest globally. This indicates excellent performance in saving and budgeting. Consequently, we can deduce that flawed financial management is the primary reason for the lack of financial independence among ordinary people. To understand where they go wrong, we must first observe how they handle their assets. In various lectures, I often ask the audience, &ldquo;How are your assets stored?&rdquo;  The majority answer: &ldquo;In the bank.&rdquo;</p>
<p><strong>Prioritizing Security over Investment</strong></p>
<p>Surveys on Taiwanese household investment preferences reveal that the top three investment choices are demand deposits (72%), rotating savings and credit associations (53%), and time deposits (36%). Clearly, most people lean towards traditional financial methods.  Furthermore, when asked, &ldquo;If you had 10 million Taiwan dollars in savings, how would you use it?&rdquo;, about 41% of surveyed households said they would deposit it in a financial institution to earn interest. This illustrates the widespread preference for bank savings.</p>
<p>Indeed, people have high savings rates and a strong preference for depositing money in financial institutions to earn interest.  In early 1996, total deposits in Taiwanese financial institutions reached 12.6 trillion Taiwan dollars.  With a population of 21 million, this translates to an average deposit of 600,000 Taiwan dollars per person, regardless of age.  For an average family of four, this amounts to 2.4 million Taiwan dollars.  This demonstrates a strong inclination towards bank savings. However, this traditional and conservative approach is the primary reason why most people fail to achieve wealth through investment.</p>
<p>This phenomenon reveals an over-reliance on traditional bank deposits for financial management. People prioritize safety and convenience over the rate of return. However, focusing solely on earning and saving money, then depositing it in a bank, is often the first step towards financial mismanagement.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Keeping money in the bank is like having no financial plan at all.</p>
</blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">Deposit Interest Rates Lack True Compound Interest Benefits 
    <div id="deposit-interest-rates-lack-true-compound-interest-benefits" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#deposit-interest-rates-lack-true-compound-interest-benefits" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>What&rsquo;s wrong with bank deposits? The problem lies in the low interest rates (return on investment), making them unsuitable for long-term investment tools.</p>
<p>How much interest can bank deposits earn?  The salaries of average office workers are usually directly deposited into demand deposit accounts (current interest rates around 2%-4%). A portion serves as temporary funds or covers daily expenses, while the remainder is transferred to time deposits (current interest rates around 5%-8%) for investment purposes. Thus, the average interest rate earned on bank deposits is about 5%.</p>
<p><strong>5% Interest is Hardly a Path to Wealth</strong></p>
<p>Most people have a basic understanding of compound interest, believing that interest earned on bank deposits, accumulating over time, can create substantial wealth. This misconception arises from a superficial understanding of compounding.  The vast differences in final returns resulting from different rates of return on the same principal over the same period often come as a surprise.</p>
<p>Let&rsquo;s illustrate with an example. Suppose someone saves 14,000 Taiwan dollars annually at the end of each year for 40 years, depositing everything into a bank account with an average interest rate of 5%. How much will they accumulate after 40 years? Before answering, recall the similar example from the previous section, but with the money in a bank instead of invested in stocks or real estate with an average annual return of 20%.</p>
<p>You might guess 25 million, 10 million, or even a conservative 5 million Taiwan dollars.  The correct answer, however, is only 1.69 million.  This can be calculated using the future value of an annuity formula:</p>
<p><math xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" display="block"><mtable displaystyle="true" columnalign="right center left" columnspacing="0 thickmathspace" rowspacing="3pt"><mtr><mtd><mn>14,000</mn><mo>×</mo><mfrac><mrow><msup><mrow><mo stretchy="false">(</mo><mn>1</mn><mo>+</mo><mn>0.05</mn><mo stretchy="false">)</mo></mrow><mrow><mn>40</mn></mrow></msup><mo>−</mo><mn>1</mn></mrow><mn>0.05</mn></mfrac></mtd><mtd><mi></mi><mo>=</mo></mtd><mtd><mn>1,690,000</mn></mtd></mtr><mtr><mtd><mn>14,000</mn><mo>×</mo><mfrac><mrow><msup><mrow><mo stretchy="false">(</mo><mn>1</mn><mo>+</mo><mn>0.20</mn><mo stretchy="false">)</mo></mrow><mrow><mn>40</mn></mrow></msup><mo>−</mo><mn>1</mn></mrow><mn>0.20</mn></mfrac></mtd><mtd><mi></mi><mo>=</mo></mtd><mtd><mn>102,810,000</mn></mtd></mtr></mtable></math></p>
<p>Let&rsquo;s compare this with the 20% return scenario.  The only difference between the two formulas is the rate of return (5% vs. 20%). A 20% return over 40 years yields 102.81 million Taiwan dollars, while a 5% return over the same period yields only 1.69 million, less than a fraction of the former. The difference is over 60 times! This illustrates the power of compound interest.  Many assume they benefit from compound interest in a bank, but at a 5% return, even with compounding over a long period, the wealth creation effect is very limited.</p>
<p>This example demonstrates that one of the keys to successful financial management is the rate of return. The key is not just whether your assets are invested, but <em>where</em> they are invested and what the rate of return is.</p>
<ul>
<li>
<ol>
<li>The key to financial management lies in how your assets are allocated. The rate of return has a decisive impact on your future wealth.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol start="2">
<li>While bank savings provide interest income and the benefit of compounding,  you&rsquo;ll find that as you age, bank deposits contribute little to overall wealth growth.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol start="3">
<li>The first step towards building wealth through investment is to allocate assets to investments with high long-term rates of return.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol start="4">
<li>&ldquo;Financial Management&rdquo; is a significant factor contributing to wealth disparity in society.</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>Inflation makes money worth less and less.</p>
</blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">The Invisible Killer of Currency Value: Inflation 
    <div id="the-invisible-killer-of-currency-value-inflation" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#the-invisible-killer-of-currency-value-inflation" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>Forty years ago, a millionaire was truly wealthy.  Today, a millionaire might struggle to afford a house. Why?  Inflation.  Every investor must consider the impact of inflation.</p>
<p><em>Inflation reduces the purchasing power of money and lowers the real rate of return, diminishing the effect of wealth accumulation.</em></p>
<p>Over the past 30 years, the average annual inflation rate in Taiwan has been around 5%. What about the future?  Inflation and economic growth are closely linked. As Taiwan&rsquo;s economy continues to grow, inflation is expected to remain around 5% annually.</p>
<p>Inflation means continuously rising prices, which translates to decreasing purchasing power.  If you keep your money in a demand deposit account earning 4% interest with a 5% inflation rate, what happens?  Your purchasing power decreases.  The longer your money sits in a savings account, the less it&rsquo;s worth.  What used to cost 10 Taiwan dollars for a newspaper now costs 15. Your 10 dollars can now only buy two-thirds of a newspaper. With inflation, money in the bank shrinks like wool submerged in water.</p>
<p><strong>Saving Alone Won&rsquo;t Make You Rich, Not Even in Two Lifetimes</strong></p>
<p>With 5% inflation and a nominal interest rate of around 5% on bank deposits, your real rate of return is zero. In this scenario, the effect of compound interest is nullified.  Wealth accumulation relies solely on painstaking saving. Imagine someone saves 500,000 Taiwan dollars a year. How long would it take to become a billionaire?  200 years!</p>
<p>Saving 500,000 Taiwan dollars a year is difficult; living for 200 years is even harder!  Therefore, even with diligent saving and budgeting, if all the money is kept in the bank, this person won&rsquo;t become wealthy in this lifetime, and worse, not even in the next! The average lifespan is around 75 years, meaning two lifetimes total only 150 years.  It would take a third lifetime for someone relying solely on bank savings to potentially reach billionaire status.  If a family maintains the financial strategy of &ldquo;frugality and bank savings,&rdquo; it would take at least 200 years, or about seven generations, for them to potentially become wealthy.  Conversely, with proper financial management, wealth can be achieved in 40 years (half a lifetime).</p>
<p><strong>Money in the Bank Should Be Spent Sooner Rather Than Later</strong></p>
<p>I remember 30 years ago, when I was in second or third grade, a popsicle cost 20 cents, and a red bean ice cream cost 50 cents.  My parents gave me 50 cents each day for allowance, which I invariably spent on red bean ice cream after school. My parents constantly encouraged me to save, so my father opened a bank account for me. If I had been obedient and developed good saving habits from a young age, saving those 50 cents daily and earning 8% interest, it would have grown tenfold over 30 years, to 5 Taiwan dollars.  However, a red bean ice cream now costs 15 Taiwan dollars. Those 5 dollars can only buy one-third of a red bean ice cream. More importantly, for a小学生 30 years ago, a red bean ice cream was precious.  Even a dozen red bean ice creams today couldn&rsquo;t compare to the value of one back then. Had I followed my parents&rsquo; financial advice and kept my money in the bank, I would regret it now.</p>
<p>Therefore, if you&rsquo;re going to keep money in the bank, my sincere advice is: &ldquo;Spend it sooner rather than later!&rdquo; This might sound shocking, but there&rsquo;s logic to it.  From an economic perspective, money has more value and higher utility when used sooner. We save money in the bank, delaying gratification for the sake of greater enjoyment in the future.  However, with inflation, money left in the bank often leads to <em>less</em> enjoyment.</p>
<p><strong>The Value of Money Decreases with Age</strong></p>
<p>My wife and her friends developed a financial philosophy: &ldquo;Money is most valuable when spent while young.&rdquo; This makes economic sense.  Their reasoning: &ldquo;When you&rsquo;re old, delicacies might harm your health, traveling becomes difficult, and most importantly, wearing beautiful clothes attracts unwanted attention and ridicule.&rdquo;</p>
<p>Thus, everyone managing their finances must be mindful of the dual pressures of inflation and the diminishing value of money with age. Bank deposit interest rates cannot compensate for these losses. In other words, <strong>money in the bank, while nominally increasing, actually decreases in value.</strong></p>
<p>Of course, I&rsquo;m not encouraging you to spend all your savings immediately.  Rather, I&rsquo;m highlighting that if you keep money in the bank, you must consider the declining purchasing power due to inflation and the reduced economic benefit as you age.  The fundamental solution is to withdraw your money from the bank and invest it in instruments with higher returns than bank deposit rates. <strong>Therefore, the best way to combat inflation is: Don&rsquo;t keep your money in the bank. Invest in long-term, high-return assets like stocks and real estate.</strong></p>
<p>Because inflation decreases real returns and hinders wealth accumulation, even saving 14,000 Taiwan dollars annually and investing in stocks or real estate for 40 years to become a billionaire won&rsquo;t carry the same weight as being a billionaire today.  Therefore, under inflation, consider using the <em>real</em> rate of return. If the return on investment is 20% and inflation is 5%, the real return is 15%.  So how much should you save annually, investing in stocks or real estate with a nominal return of around 20% (real return of 15%), to become a billionaire in 40 years?  The answer is 57,000 Taiwan dollars per year.</p>
<p><math xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" display="block"><mn>57,000</mn><mo>×</mo><mfrac><mrow><msup><mrow><mo stretchy="false">(</mo><mn>1</mn><mo>+</mo><mn>0.15</mn><mo stretchy="false">)</mo></mrow><mrow><mn>40</mn></mrow></msup><mo>−</mo><mn>1</mn></mrow><mn>0.15</mn></mfrac><mo>=</mo><mn>101,410,000</mn><mspace linebreak="newline"></mspace></math></p>
<blockquote>
<p>A small step today makes a world of difference tomorrow.</p>
</blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">The Path to Wealth of Chang Pin-san, Former Chairman of Chang Hwa Bank 
    <div id="the-path-to-wealth-of-chang-pin-san-former-chairman-of-chang-hwa-bank" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#the-path-to-wealth-of-chang-pin-san-former-chairman-of-chang-hwa-bank" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>Chang Po-hsin, the current standing director of Chang Hwa Bank, with assets exceeding tens of billions, inherited and expanded upon the fortune of his father, Chang Pin-san, the former chairman of Chang Hwa Bank, earning him a place among Taiwan&rsquo;s wealthiest individuals.</p>
<p><strong>Trading Bank Deposits for Stock Dividends</strong></p>
<p>Forty years ago, both Chang Pin-san and my father were from Nantun District, Taichung City.  They were not only fellow townsmen but also colleagues. Back then, Chang Pin-san was just a junior manager at Chang Hwa Bank, without much wealth.  However, he borrowed money to buy Chang Hwa Bank shares from colleagues who wanted to sell them. At the time, stock dividends were far lower than bank interest. Despite this, Chang Pin-san persisted in borrowing money to acquire shares, holding onto them for the long term.  Other colleagues deposited the proceeds from their stock sales into banks. Years later, Chang Pin-san, owning the most shares, became the largest shareholder and eventually the chairman of Chang Hwa Bank, laying the foundation for his immense wealth.</p>
<p>Chang Pin-san was also friends with Lien Chen-tung, father of Lien Chan, and encouraged him to buy Chang Hwa Bank shares. The Lien family&rsquo;s fortune also originated from those hundreds of Chang Hwa Bank shares.</p>
<p>It&rsquo;s hard to believe that the path to wealth could be so simple: borrow money to buy a few Chang Hwa Bank shares, invest in some real estate, hold them long-term, and essentially forget about them.  Decades later, great wealth is attained. Those who sold their shares and deposited the money in banks are still wondering how others became rich. Some might attribute this to luck, but financial management is not about luck.  It&rsquo;s about the method chosen and the investment tools selected.  Therefore, if you don&rsquo;t want to be poor, don&rsquo;t keep your money in the bank.</p>
<p><strong>Bank Savings Shouldn&rsquo;t Exceed Living Expenses</strong></p>
<p>Someone once jokingly asked me, &ldquo;You&rsquo;re telling us not to keep money in the bank.  Are we supposed to pay with stocks or real estate certificates at the supermarket or restaurant?&rdquo; Of course not!  Advising against keeping money in the bank doesn&rsquo;t mean you can&rsquo;t have any money in the bank at all. Bank deposits offer advantages: security and convenience. They are ideal for storing funds needed for daily expenses. However, you can&rsquo;t have your cake and eat it too.  Convenience comes at the cost of high returns.</p>
<p>The wise approach is to clearly divide funds into two categories: daily expenses and investments.  Keep enough for daily needs in the bank, enjoying the security and convenience it offers. Invest the rest in higher-return assets like stocks and real estate.</p>
<p>In my opinion, keeping the equivalent of two months&rsquo; living expenses in the bank is sufficient for an individual or family. Most individuals and families receive regular income, which is deposited into their bank accounts. Therefore, one month&rsquo;s expenses for immediate use and another month&rsquo;s worth as a safety net should be ample.  The remaining funds should be invested in higher-return assets like stocks and real estate.  In other words, if your monthly expenses average 50,000 Taiwan dollars, and your bank balance consistently exceeds 100,000, you are not managing your finances effectively.  Actively seek suitable investment opportunities to make your surplus funds work for you.</p>
<p><strong>The &ldquo;Two Big, One Small&rdquo; Approach to Flexible Fund Management</strong></p>
<p>Some believe in maintaining substantial emergency funds. However, even if unforeseen circumstances drain your bank savings, there&rsquo;s no need to panic. The high-return investments mentioned earlier—stocks and real estate—are not as illiquid as some might think.  Listed stocks in Taiwan&rsquo;s active stock market can be sold almost any day of the year (excluding holidays), providing quick access to cash within a few days.  Reluctant to sell? Stocks can also be used as collateral for loans.</p>
<p>Real estate is less liquid than stocks, but many Taiwanese banks now offer &ldquo;revolving mortgage loans,&rdquo; allowing property owners to convert fixed assets into liquid assets. These loans involve mortgaging a property to secure a credit line of up to 70%-75% of the property&rsquo;s value. Borrowers can draw and repay funds as needed, with interest accruing only on the outstanding balance. For example, a 10 million Taiwan dollar property could secure a 7.5 million credit line.  Borrowing 5 million leaves 2.5 million available without interest charges, with interest accruing only on the 5 million borrowed.  Any surplus funds can be used to repay the loan, reducing interest costs.</p>
<p>Many financial experts recommend a &ldquo;three-part&rdquo; approach, dividing assets equally among bank savings, real estate, and more speculative investments. I propose a &ldquo;two big, one small&rdquo; approach: allocate most of your assets to stocks and real estate, keeping a small portion in a bank for daily expenses.  This isn&rsquo;t my invention. In fact, this is the portfolio strategy employed by many who have achieved wealth through investments.</p>
<ul>
<li>
<ol>
<li>Keeping money in the bank is the riskiest form of financial management.  Inflation erodes returns, leaving real interest rates near zero.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol start="2">
<li>Banks offer convenience, not high returns.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol start="3">
<li>Keep only two months&rsquo; worth of living expenses in the bank.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol start="4">
<li>Trying to get rich with money in the bank is like trying to win a baseball game without swinging the bat.</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ul>
<p>If all this hasn&rsquo;t convinced you to reconsider keeping most of your money in a financial institution, perhaps the story of the Nobel Prize Foundation&rsquo;s success might change your mind.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Change your asset management perspective, change your financial destiny.</p>
</blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">Lessons from the Nobel Prize Foundation 
    <div id="lessons-from-the-nobel-prize-foundation" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#lessons-from-the-nobel-prize-foundation" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>Every October, the Nobel Committee announces the Nobel laureates. The Nobel Prize attracts global attention not only for representing the highest academic honor but also because each laureate receives a substantial prize of 1 million US dollars.</p>
<p><strong>The Folly of Depleting Capital</strong></p>
<p>The Nobel Foundation awards several prizes annually, disbursing millions of dollars. This raises the question: How large is the Nobel fund to sustain such substantial payouts? The Nobel Foundation&rsquo;s success, besides the substantial initial donation by Alfred Nobel over a century ago, is largely attributed to its shrewd financial management.</p>
<p>Established in 1896 with a 9.8 million US dollar donation from Nobel, the foundation&rsquo;s purpose is to fund the prizes.  Flawless fund management was paramount.  Initially, its charter stipulated that investments be restricted to safe, fixed-income instruments like bank deposits and government bonds, explicitly excluding stocks and real estate to avoid market risks.</p>
<p>This capital preservation approach, prioritizing safety over returns, seemed prudent, preventing losses. However, sacrificing returns had consequences.  After 50 years of prize payouts and operating expenses, low returns depleted two-thirds of the Nobel fund, leaving only a little over 3 million US dollars by 1953.</p>
<p><strong>From 3 Million to 270 Million: The Secret</strong></p>
<p>Facing depletion, the Nobel Foundation&rsquo;s board recognized the importance of investment returns. In 1953, they made a groundbreaking change, amending the charter to shift from bank deposits and bonds to primarily stocks and real estate.  This shift in investment philosophy transformed the foundation&rsquo;s fate. Over the next 40 years, despite continued prize payouts and operating costs, the foundation not only recovered all previous losses but also grew its assets to 270 million US dollars by 1993.</p>
<p><em>Nobel Prize Foundation Asset Growth and Decline</em></p>
<table>
  <thead>
      <tr>
          <th>Year</th>
          <th>Total Assets (Million USD)</th>
          <th>Remarks</th>
      </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
      <tr>
          <td>1896</td>
          <td>9.8</td>
          <td>Foundation Established</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>1953</td>
          <td>3.3</td>
          <td>Investment Charter Amended</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>1993</td>
          <td>270</td>
          <td></td>
      </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>
<p>Had the Nobel Foundation not changed its approach 40 years ago, clinging to bank savings, it would have vanished, unable to fund the prizes.  Perhaps other wealthy individuals would have established new foundations with larger prizes, replacing the Nobel Prize.</p>
<p>The Nobel Foundation&rsquo;s history underscores the importance of financial management.  Even a substantial initial fund, if mismanaged, can be depleted. Conversely, even with significant spending, skillful management can generate rapid growth.</p>
<p>I once heard of a Taiwanese hometown association that established a foundation with 100,000 Taiwan dollars 40 years ago to provide scholarships for children from their hometown.  Forty years later, the fund remains at 100,000 Taiwan dollars. While a significant sum back then, today it barely covers administrative costs, threatening the foundation&rsquo;s existence.  The problem? Neglecting financial management.</p>
<p>Learning from the Nobel Foundation, many US foundations, pension funds, university endowments, and even personal trusts have shifted from bank deposits and bonds to primarily stocks and real estate. In contrast, few Taiwanese foundations grasp this concept, and university endowments rarely address financial management seriously.  The fate of these foundations, if they don&rsquo;t adapt, is clear.</p>
<p>I often participate in corporate training programs, where I habitually ask companies about the size and investment strategy of their employee welfare funds.  The answers are usually similar: small funds, mostly in bank deposits, rarely exceeding a few hundred thousand or a million Taiwan dollars. However, in 1990, during my time at China Development Corporation, the employee welfare fund exceeded 200 million Taiwan dollars. Why?  Because it was primarily invested in China Development Corporation&rsquo;s own stock.</p>
<ul>
<li>
<ol>
<li>The Nobel Foundation&rsquo;s course correction 40 years ago secured its status today.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol start="2">
<li>Prioritizing security above all else leads to asset depletion.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol start="3">
<li>The growth and decline of wealth for individuals, families, businesses, or other entities depends on their investment strategy.</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ul>
<p>Will your hard-earned wealth shrink like the early Nobel fund, or grow like the later one? The key lies in <em>how</em> you invest. If, like many, you keep most of your money in the bank, it&rsquo;s not too late to change. The Nobel Foundation&rsquo;s story shows how a change in investment philosophy can transform everything.  Should you reconsider your financial habits and prioritize investments in stocks and real estate? Let the Nobel Foundation inspire your financial thinking. A single change in mindset can lead to immense wealth decades from now!</p>
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Personal Investment Bible: Preface</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1731056005958/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1731056005958/</guid><description>This book aims to help readers establish a correct view of wealth management, learn financial knowledge, master easy wealth management techniques, and ultimately achieve financial freedom, even becoming millionaires. Author Huang Peiyuan uses the story of the Lien Chan family&amp;#39;s wealth management as an example, explaining the importance of wealth management in a simple and profound way, and combining his rich experience and academic research, proposes the key elements of wealth accumulation: regular savings, pursuing high returns, and long-term waiting. In addition, this book also emphasizes the inadequacy of financial education and the importance of continuous learning and adaptation in a rapidly changing investment environment.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[
  



<div
  
    class="flex px-4 py-3 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900"
  >

  <span
    
      class="text-primary-400 ltr:pr-3 rtl:pl-3 flex items-center"
    >

    

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M256 0C114.6 0 0 114.6 0 256s114.6 256 256 256s256-114.6 256-256S397.4 0 256 0zM256 128c17.67 0 32 14.33 32 32c0 17.67-14.33 32-32 32S224 177.7 224 160C224 142.3 238.3 128 256 128zM296 384h-80C202.8 384 192 373.3 192 360s10.75-24 24-24h16v-64H224c-13.25 0-24-10.75-24-24S210.8 224 224 224h32c13.25 0 24 10.75 24 24v88h16c13.25 0 24 10.75 24 24S309.3 384 296 384z"/></svg>

  </span>


  </span>

  <span
    
      class="dark:text-neutral-300"
    ><strong>Synopsis</strong><br>
Written by Mr. Huang Peiyuan from Taiwan, this book&rsquo;s greatest strength lies in its departure from traditional thinking. It uses clear and easy-to-understand language to teach correct wealth management methods. The book outlines thirteen ironclad rules for effortless wealth management, guiding readers on how to establish a correct view of financial management. Many people strive to make money but don&rsquo;t know how.  Many possess the conditions for wealth but miss opportunities due to a lack of financial literacy. Even worse, some lose everything due to investment mistakes. The author draws on practical experience and extensive academic research, exploring these thirteen ironclad rules to help you &ldquo;enjoy wealth management, achieve wealth with ease,&rdquo; and confidently join the ranks of millionaires.
<br>
<br>
<strong>About the Author</strong><br>
<strong>Huang Peiyuan</strong>, Ph.D. in Business Administration from the University of California, Berkeley, General Manager of Sancai Construction and Real Estate Co., Ltd. Former Director of the Institute of Business Administration, Tunghai University, Deputy Director of the Project Business Department, China Development Trust Company, Vice President of East-West Securities, USA, Investment Manager at Merrill Lynch, USA, and financial advisor to numerous companies.</span>
</div>



<h2 class="relative group">Learning Wealth Management from the Lien Chan Family 
    <div id="learning-wealth-management-from-the-lien-chan-family" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#learning-wealth-management-from-the-lien-chan-family" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>The people of Taiwan are not only surprised by the enormous wealth of the Lien Chan family, the former chairman of the Kuomintang, but also harbor doubts. How could two generations of civil servants, with their meager salaries, accumulate wealth comparable to that of tycoon families?</p>
<p>This suspicion is deeply ingrained, but the Lien family is a prominent political family in Taiwan, and no one wants to antagonize them by probing too deeply.</p>
<p>As a journalist, the Lien family&rsquo;s wealth has always been a puzzle to me. I even made a determined effort to uncover the truth, but to no avail.  Six months ago, Professor Huang Peiyuan, then director of the Institute of Business Administration at Tunghai University, spoke about his desire to combine theory and practice and publish a &ldquo;Personal Investment Bible.&rdquo; After reading Professor Huang&rsquo;s manuscript, the mystery of the Lien family&rsquo;s wealth became clear to me.  The Lien family is a perfect example of the principles in this &ldquo;Personal Investment Bible.&rdquo; Perhaps Lien Ya-tang, in his early years, wrote not only the renowned &ldquo;General History of Taiwan,&rdquo; but also a &ldquo;Wealth Management Manual&rdquo; passed down only within the family.</p>
<p>According to Professor Huang&rsquo;s (his title at the time; now he is in business) &ldquo;Personal Investment Bible,&rdquo; the first rule is &ldquo;Don&rsquo;t keep your money in the bank.&rdquo; The second is that if you want to get rich, invest in stocks and real estate.  This gives you the opportunity, with the income of an average office worker, to become a multimillionaire after 40 years of wealth management.</p>
<p>By this standard, the Lien family is indeed the most faithful follower of the &ldquo;Personal Investment Bible.&rdquo; When they had little wealth, Lien&rsquo;s mother (Lien Chan&rsquo;s mother) invested solely in stocks and real estate.  Over the past few decades, the Lien family remained steadfast, waiting for the appreciation of their stocks and real estate, which naturally led to the vast wealth that now arouses public suspicion.</p>
<p>Several decades ago, there were many business people who possessed similar wealth to the Lien family.  These individuals also worked hard to manage their businesses and accumulate more wealth.  However, compared to the Lien family now, most of them lament their inferiority in terms of wealth. The Lien family&rsquo;s role as pure investors fully demonstrates that &ldquo;as long as the concepts and methods are correct, wealth will naturally follow.&rdquo;</p>
<p>In fact, the theories and methods in the &ldquo;Personal Investment Bible&rdquo; have been discussed by countless scholars and experts in mature Western societies, but not many have truly adhered to them and become millionaires as a result.  The reason lies not in the inadequacy of the theories and methods, but in the lack of confidence and patience of those who apply them, leading them to give up halfway.</p>
<p>Therefore, I advise all readers of this book to truly believe in the theories presented, have long-term patience, and adhere to them unwaveringly in order to succeed.</p>
<p>We wish all readers the ability to enjoy a happy retirement with sufficient financial resources, which is perhaps the greatest contribution of the &ldquo;Personal Investment Bible&rdquo; to the public! (This article is written by the president of Business Weekly Taiwan)</p>


<h2 class="relative group">The Joy of Wealth Management, Achieving Wealth with Ease 
    <div id="the-joy-of-wealth-management-achieving-wealth-with-ease" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#the-joy-of-wealth-management-achieving-wealth-with-ease" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>When I was young, I thought that money was the most important thing in life; now that I am old, I know that it is.</p>
<p>— Oscar Wilde, British playwright</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This book is written for those who are determined to become wealthy and strive for financial independence. If you have tried every possible way to get rich and your home is filled with investment books, but you still can&rsquo;t figure out how to achieve wealth in your lifetime, congratulations! You have found the book you need. The investment and financial management concepts and methods described in this book are absolutely understandable and achievable for everyone. As long as you put them into practice, becoming a millionaire is not difficult.</p>
<p>I see many people working tirelessly to make money, hoping to improve their own and their families&rsquo; financial situation, but they can&rsquo;t find the right way. Many people clearly have the conditions to become rich through financial management, but they don&rsquo;t know how to manage their finances, resulting in missed opportunities.  Others know that investment and financial management can lead to wealth, but the problem is that what they know is not true, leading them astray and suffering from financial mismanagement.  The author sees these phenomena and often feels sorry for them.</p>
<p>The biggest problem in Taiwan at present is the serious lack of financial education. The public lacks a correct concept of financial management. They either don&rsquo;t know how to manage their finances and neglect it, or they use the wrong methods. As a result, some people not only fail to achieve wealth through financial management, but even fail to achieve basic financial independence.  Insufficient or incorrect financial concepts are harmful not only to one&rsquo;s own financial situation, but also to the public. This is the main motivation for the author to write this book, and what this book offers readers is the correct basic concept of investment and financial management.</p>
<p>As a scholar and a practitioner of financial management, I feel obligated to share my years of investment research results and practical experience in financial management with everyone, helping the public to easily manage their finances and achieve wealth through investment. The message this book wants to convey is: Financial management is actually very simple. Not only can everyone do it easily, but almost all young people have the conditions to achieve wealth through financial management.</p>
<p>This book is based on 20 years of practical financial management experience in the United States and Taiwan, 6 years of investment research at Tunghai University, and 15 years of experience as a financial advisor.  In fact, the concepts and practices in this book were developed 3 years ago.  For the past 3 years, the author has given lectures on this topic in various places and received tremendous feedback.  Many listeners have continuously requested that I compile these concepts and action guidelines into a book.  I personally also feel that these financial management concepts and action guidelines are indeed beneficial to the public and there is indeed a need to publish a book.</p>
<p>However, putting these concepts into words is a difficult task for me, so I have procrastinated for 3 years. Recently, thanks to the repeated urging of Mr. He, President of Business Weekly Cultural Enterprise, and Ms. Sun Meiqing, and the examples and suggestions provided by Ms. Shen Wenci, and especially the efforts of Mr. Yang Weikai, who spent several months helping me revise and proofread, this book has finally been completed. I express my sincere gratitude here.</p>
<p>If this book can be read by the general public, and if they can accept the concepts and financial management methods described in the book, then all the author&rsquo;s efforts will have been truly worthwhile. Good ideas should be shared with everyone. I hope everyone can benefit from them and easily become millionaires through financial management.</p>
<p>Finally, I dedicate this book to my parents, Mr. Huang Minting and Ms. Huang Juzhi, who raised and nurtured me.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">Preface 
    <div id="preface" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#preface" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>In recent years, Taiwan&rsquo;s economy has grown rapidly.  While continuous economic growth is certainly gratifying, the problem of uneven wealth distribution has become increasingly serious. Some blame inappropriate government policies, while others believe it&rsquo;s due to speculation, which has caused stock and housing prices to rise, widening the gap between rich and poor. The author believes that these factors are not the main cause. The real reason for the widening wealth gap is the significant disparity in financial literacy among the public.</p>
<p>Starting in 1986, Taiwan officially entered an era of abundant capital and a focus on wealth management.  The New Taiwan dollar slowly appreciated from 40 to 27 against the US dollar, and during this period, a large amount of foreign exchange flowed into Taiwan, creating a situation where &ldquo;money overflowed in Taiwan.&rdquo;</p>
<p>Due to the excess capital, people began to shift their money towards investing in stocks and real estate. The huge influx of funds into the stock and housing markets caused stock and housing prices to soar. Between 1986 and 1989, housing prices increased by an average of two to four times, and the weighted stock market index rose from over 700 points in early 1986 to 12,680 points in February 1990, an increase of 18 times.  Investing in stocks and participating in the capital market is inherently meaningful, and rising stock prices are a natural consequence of economic growth. Unfortunately, most investors adopted the wrong approach, believing that to profit in the stock market, they must buy low and sell high, earning the difference.  In reality, short-term trading is not only time-consuming and laborious but also incurs huge transaction costs, resulting in most investors losing money. The stock market is almost equated with a casino.</p>
<p>The purpose of this book is to enlighten the public&rsquo;s financial mindset by providing new perspectives, concepts, and methods to cope with the important yet complex investment environment. The author sincerely hopes that after reading this book, readers will develop a new financial mentality and adopt correct financial management methods.</p>
<p>&ldquo;Getting rich&rdquo; is almost everyone&rsquo;s desire, and most people think that their monthly income is not much, and the amount they can save is even less. At this rate of wealth accumulation, it seems impossible to get rich. But in fact, with enough time and proper financial management, becoming a millionaire is not impossible.  Wealth accumulation through financial management requires only three basic conditions: regular savings, the pursuit of high returns, and long-term waiting.</p>
<p>The easiest way to achieve wealth through financial management is to learn from those who have done so. What are their methods? The secret of most successful wealth managers is not that they are smarter, harder working, or luckier than others, but that they have the habits and practices of wealth creation.</p>
<p>In the past, family financial management was rarely mentioned in school education.  Perhaps this is because investment and financial management involve money, and most people think that making money with money has a connotation of getting something for nothing.  In formal school education, teachers avoid mentioning it, believing that talking about money in education may corrupt people&rsquo;s minds, especially making money with money, which doesn&rsquo;t seem noble.  However, long-term avoidance of this issue has only exacerbated the problem.</p>
<p>The people of Taiwan, through years of joint efforts, have created an economic miracle and accumulated a large amount of wealth. However, most individuals and families only know how to make money but not how to manage it, let alone how to use it wisely.  After acquiring wealth, individuals, families, and even the entire society have suffered rather than benefited. For example, in recent years, money games have been prevalent.  Many people are busy speculating in stocks and real estate, and various forms of gambling such as the Mark Six lottery, futures, and foreign exchange margin trading are still popular and becoming increasingly rampant.  Many people are obsessed with money games, all for the purpose of making money and improving their family&rsquo;s financial situation.  However, if we calmly review the investment results of the past few years, it is not difficult to find that in the end, few have profited, many have lost, and even more have gone bankrupt.  Everyone has worked in vain, and the result is only a rapid redistribution of wealth and a prevalence of unhealthy speculation in society. The wealth of individuals and society as a whole does not increase. This is all due to the public&rsquo;s lack of clear understanding of financial management concepts.</p>
<p>The consequence of poor financial literacy is not only personal loss and family misfortune but also a waste of overall social resources.  Let&rsquo;s face this issue that is crucial to individuals, families, and the entire society: family financial management.</p>
<p>As the saying goes, &ldquo;When a couple is poor, everything is sad.&rdquo;  This shows that if a family&rsquo;s financial situation cannot meet the needs of family life, or if finances are not managed properly, happiness is hard to come by. Of course, there are many factors that contribute to a happy family, and wealth is only one of them, as many family problems cannot be solved with money. There is a saying: &ldquo;Money is not everything, but without money, you can do nothing.&rdquo; Although money is not the center of a family, in our real society, most good things require money. Wealthy families are not necessarily happy, but families without money are usually even less so. To make ourselves and our families happier, investment and financial management are indeed imperative. Investment and financial management can not only improve the financial situation of an individual or a family, but it is also a good way to accumulate wealth.  Using financial management to achieve wealth is achievable for everyone, and it is something everyone should do.</p>
<p>Future wealth depends on the future investment environment, and the biggest characteristic of the investment environment, in a word, is change.  The entire financial environment is ever-changing and unpredictable. This has been true in the past and will be even more so in the future. In the world of investment and financial management, there is constant change. It can be said that &ldquo;the only constant is change.&rdquo; It is foreseeable that the changes in the next 10 years will exceed those of the previous 50 years. Changes are not only becoming faster, but also more complex, diversified, and international. Whether we like it or not, we are already in a rapidly changing environment.</p>
<p>Facing change, you can remain calm, adapt, and adopt the appropriate mental attitude. However, if you know how change will affect you, you may not dare to take it lightly. Because the natural consequence of any change is redistribution, including wealth, power, markets, personnel&hellip; In terms of wealth, any change in the investment environment will naturally affect the flow of money at all levels.  Indeed, in financial markets, capital markets, commodity markets, spot or futures markets worldwide, billions of dollars are traded every day, and wealth is constantly being redistributed.  Your wealth may increase significantly during the redistribution process, or it may shrink rapidly.  After long-term redistribution, you may become a billionaire, or you may become penniless, depending on how you face and deal with the changes.</p>
<p>Any change and the resulting redistribution poses a &ldquo;crisis&rdquo; to your wealth to a greater or lesser extent. The Chinese characters for &ldquo;crisis&rdquo; are profound and often quoted in foreign books because they contain both danger and opportunity. &ldquo;Wei&rdquo; represents the threat to wealth, and &ldquo;Ji&rdquo; represents the opportunity for wealth creation.</p>
<p>We can wait for changes and redistribution to determine our future wealth level, or we can make good use of the opportunities brought about by change and try to reduce its destructive power.  In this era of accelerating change, cultivating the ability to manage and respond to change is essential to controlling our own future.</p>
<p>Looking ahead, changes in business, economy, finance, politics, society, and other aspects will accelerate. The overall financial environment will become more complex and unpredictable, and it is foreseeable that future wealth redistribution will inevitably accelerate. Therefore, for ourselves, our families, and society, everyone should play the role of a financial manager.</p>
<p>This is an era of rapid change and abundant wealth, and it is also an era that forces us to manage our finances.  Everyone desires to become rich and improve their living standards or achieve their life goals. There are many ways to get rich, but the concept the author wants to elaborate on in this book is: Investment and financial management is one of the effective methods to achieve wealth. As long as you have the correct financial management concepts and put them into practice, whether you are rich or poor now, over time, you may become a millionaire through investment and financial management.</p>
<p>In this critical era related to our future wealth, you can no longer remain indifferent to financial management or ignorant of investment.  You must adopt the correct financial concepts as early as possible, constantly acquire new knowledge, and avoid mistakes in order to win in the process of wealth redistribution.</p>
<p><strong>The Story of the Mailman Who Got Rich</strong></p>
<p>My brother-in-law has a friend in Taichung, a middle-aged man with a dark complexion and an occasional shy smile. My first impression of him wasn&rsquo;t memorable until he drove away in a new BMW. The second time we met, he arrived in a Mercedes-Benz, which made me admire him.  I realized that appearances can be deceiving and quickly asked him what kind of big business he was in. He said he wasn&rsquo;t a businessman, just an ordinary office worker.  I pressed him further, asking which big company he worked for. He said he worked at the post office. I thought he must be a senior executive to be so prestigious and own two luxury cars.  The answer, however, was surprising. He replied, &ldquo;I&rsquo;m a mailman. I deliver mail by motorcycle in the morning, with a monthly salary of NT$30,000-40,000.&rdquo; I secretly speculated that he must specialize in delivering registered mail and was pocketing some of the contents.  He then told me his story. His previous generation were poor farmers who left behind some land, which he had always regarded as ancestral property and kept without selling. No one expected that recent land consolidation would increase the value of his land by dozens of times. Now, just by renting out houses, he earns NT$500,000 in rent every month.  This 48-year-old mailman didn&rsquo;t rely on increasing income and reducing expenditure, but simply by putting his assets in the right place, he now has assets of more than NT$300 million. This is one of the examples of wealth accumulation through financial management in Taiwanese society.</p>
<p>Similar stories seem to happen frequently around us. Before I taught at the university, I worked for an investment company. Once, during the election of directors and supervisors at a shareholders&rsquo; meeting, I discovered that a major shareholder holding more than NT$200 million worth of shares was actually a clerk in the company&rsquo;s personnel department.  It turned out that 35 years ago, when she joined the company as an employee, her salary was very low and her life was insecure, so she saved her meager salary. When company employees had fractional shares to transfer, she would buy them. After many years, this woman in her 50s, although unremarkable and not looking like a rich woman, now has a net worth of more than NT$200 million, enough to enjoy her retirement. In fact, there are countless examples of such ordinary office workers who have become wealthy through investment and financial management. Many people say that office workers cannot become rich, but in reality, wealthy office workers mostly don&rsquo;t like to show off, so the way to get rich through investment and financial management is often overlooked.</p>
<p><strong>What Differentiates the Rich from the Poor?</strong></p>
<p>Many hardworking office workers who toil daily for money have had the common experience of watching rich people in expensive clothes, living in luxurious villas, and driving by in luxury cars, looking impressive and enviable. While admiring them, you may have wondered: &ldquo;What makes them rich, but not me?&rdquo;</p>
<p>Many people attribute the wealth of these rich people directly to their being born rich, their successful entrepreneurial ventures, their being smarter, harder working, or luckier than others. However, family background, entrepreneurship, intelligence, hard work, and luck cannot explain all the reasons for wealth accumulation. We have all encountered many rich people, such as &ldquo;nouveau riche&rdquo; or &ldquo;landowners.&rdquo; They were not born into wealthy families, nor are they businessmen. They are not necessarily very smart, haven&rsquo;t received much higher education, and are not more frugal than us. Some of them even idle around all day. The only thing they seem to be better at than you is that they are rich.</p>
<p>What special skills do these rich people possess that are lacking in those office workers who diligently save money and work hard every day? How can they accumulate such enormous wealth in their lifetime? This is the question the author has been eager to explore for many years.  I have tried to explain their wealth with factors such as family background, entrepreneurship, occupation, education, IQ, and effort, but all seem to have failed. After years of observation, induction, and academic research, I have discovered a very important factor that is often overlooked by most people: the ability to invest and manage finances. At the same time, I have also discovered the following three facts:</p>
<p><em>1. One of the important factors that distinguishes the rich from the poor is: the ability to invest and manage finances.</em></p>
<p><em>2. Everyone can achieve wealth through investment and financial management.</em></p>
<p><em>3. The first thing to do to improve your financial situation is: to understand the basic concepts of investment and financial management.</em>
content_copy
Use code with caution.</p>
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Personal Investment Bible: The Correct Concept of Financial Management</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1731056005959/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1731056005959/</guid><description>This article explores the correct concept of financial management, pointing out that investment is the key to wealth, rather than simply relying on increasing income and reducing expenditure. Using the wealth comparison between Koo Chen-fu and Koo Li-hsiung, the financial management methods of the Lien Chan family, and an example of becoming a billionaire by investing $1,200 monthly for 40 years, the article illustrates the importance of investment and emphasizes the power of compound interest. Furthermore, it analyzes the impact of financial habits on the wealth gap and how to educate the next generation to establish a correct concept of financial management, suggesting incorporating “Don&amp;#39;t keep money in the bank” into family precepts to cultivate investment awareness from an early age.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[

<h2 class="relative group">The Correct Concept of Financial Management 
    <div id="the-correct-concept-of-financial-management" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#the-correct-concept-of-financial-management" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>The key to winning the wealth race lies not in the starting point, but in choosing the right track.</p>
</blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">Investment Leads to Wealth 
    <div id="investment-leads-to-wealth" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#investment-leads-to-wealth" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>The Chinatrust Financial Holding Co., one of the top five conglomerates in Taiwan, was led by Koo Chen-fu, chairman of the Koo&rsquo;s Group, and Jeffrey Koo, chairman of Chinatrust Commercial Bank. The Koo&rsquo;s Group encompassed seven major business segments: finance, manufacturing, construction, hotels, media, services, and overseas operations, with over 50 affiliated companies and total assets exceeding NT$460 billion. Many wondered how this uncle-nephew duo achieved both political and business success, and who was wealthier.</p>
<p><strong>The Wealth Race Between Koo Chen-fu and Jeffrey Koo</strong></p>
<p>Wealth often correlates with personality. Koo Chen-fu was a slow and steady type, while Jeffrey Koo was more of a go-getter.  Due to their vastly different personalities, their investment approaches also differed significantly.  Koo Chen-fu&rsquo;s eldest son, Eugene Koo, the general manager of China Life Insurance in Taiwan, understood them well. He once said, &ldquo;Money put in Koo Chen-fu&rsquo;s pocket would never come out, but money put in Jeffrey Koo&rsquo;s pocket would disappear.&rdquo;  This was because Jeffrey Koo continuously reinvested his money, leading to greater wealth accumulation than his uncle. Jeffrey Koo&rsquo;s personal assets were spread across the US and Japan, invested in real estate, funds, hotels, golf courses, and banks.  Koo Chen-fu, in his 80s, was quite conservative. Regarding his financial management philosophy, he said, &ldquo;I neglect financial management and don&rsquo;t want to worry about money.&rdquo;  His personal income was deposited in the bank by his secretary, and aside from necessary expenses, the rest was converted into fixed-term deposits.</p>
<p>Over the years, Koo Chen-fu naturally had more cash on hand, as his money remained in the bank. However, in terms of wealth creation, Jeffrey Koo far surpassed him. Despite a 17-year age difference, with proper investment, one could still come out ahead.</p>
<p><strong>Investing $1,200 Monthly Can Make You a Billionaire in 40 Years</strong></p>
<p><em>It&rsquo;s not what you don&rsquo;t know that gets you into trouble. It&rsquo;s what you know for sure that just ain&rsquo;t so.</em></p>
<p>The first concept to understand about investment is: <strong>Investment not only improves financial situations but also allows anyone to achieve wealth.</strong></p>
<p>Let&rsquo;s illustrate with a simple example:</p>
<p>Suppose a young person with no savings starts saving NT$14,000 annually for 40 years.  If this money is invested in stocks or real estate with an average annual return of 20%, how much wealth will they accumulate after 40 years?</p>
<p>The author often asks this question in lectures. Most guesses range from NT$2 million to NT$8 million, with a maximum of NT$10 million. The correct answer, however, is a surprising NT$102.81 million!  For a 25-year-old, saving NT$14,000 annually (equivalent to $1,200 monthly) for 40 years, with a total investment of NT$560,000, could result in becoming a billionaire by age 65, assuming a 20% annual return in stocks or real estate.</p>
<p>This figure is calculated using the future value of an annuity formula in finance and investment. The calculation is as follows:</p>
<p><math xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" display="block"><mn>1.4</mn><mo>×</mo><mfrac><mrow><msup><mrow><mo stretchy="false">(</mo><mn>1</mn><mo>+</mo><mn>0.20</mn><mo stretchy="false">)</mo></mrow><mrow><mn>40</mn></mrow></msup><mo>−</mo><mn>1</mn></mrow><mn>0.20</mn></mfrac><mo>=</mo><mn>10281</mn><mspace linebreak="newline"></mspace></math>
(Units are in NT$10,000)</p>
<p>This formula illustrates how small amounts of money can grow significantly through investment.  Understanding the formula isn&rsquo;t crucial; most people who become billionaires through investment don&rsquo;t know it, and knowing it doesn&rsquo;t guarantee success.</p>
<p>Therefore, with youth, ambition, investment knowledge, and three key factors—saving NT$14,000 annually, investing in stocks or real estate, and patiently waiting for 40 years—anyone can achieve wealth through investment, regardless of their current economic situation.  These three factors are attainable for everyone:</p>
<ol>
<li>
<p>Saving NT$14,000 annually (NT$1,200 monthly) should be manageable for most. (If you can&rsquo;t save this much, focus on saving before investing. This book may not be as helpful yet, as you need some capital to start investing.)</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Historically, the long-term average return on stocks and real estate has been above 20%.  Consistently investing in these assets and holding them long-term can yield a 20% average return. These investment tools are accessible to everyone. (Data shows that the Taiwan stock market has averaged around 20% annual returns over the past 20 years; studies show similar returns for Taiwan real estate over the past 40 years.)</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>40 years seems long, but it&rsquo;s a timeframe most people have.  Starting work between 20 and 25 and retiring at 65 provides a 40-year investment window.  While some are born rich and others poor, most have a fair chance at accumulating wealth over 40 years.</p>
</li>
</ol>
<p>This example shows that investment not only improves finances but also provides a path to wealth.  With the right concepts and practices, anyone can achieve wealth through investment.</p>
<p><strong>Smart Investing Can Shorten the Journey by 10 Years</strong></p>
<p>While the initial example uses 40 years to demonstrate the power of investing, most readers are likely in a better position. They may already have savings and can save more than NT$14,000 annually, shortening their path to wealth.</p>
<p>The table below illustrates the wealth accumulation over 10-year intervals using the previous example (investing NT$14,000 annually with a 20% return):</p>
<p>If you have NT$360,000, congratulations! You&rsquo;ve saved 10 years of effort. By continuing to invest in stocks or real estate, you could become a billionaire in 30 years. With NT$2.61 million, you&rsquo;ve saved 20 years. With NT$16.55 million, you&rsquo;re even closer, needing only 10 more years.</p>
<table>
  <thead>
      <tr>
          <th>Investment Years</th>
          <th>Accumulated Amount (NT$10,000)</th>
          <th>Amount Accumulated in the Last Decade (NT$10,000)</th>
      </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
      <tr>
          <td>10</td>
          <td>36</td>
          <td>36</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>20</td>
          <td>261</td>
          <td>225</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>30</td>
          <td>1655</td>
          <td>1394</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>40</td>
          <td>10281</td>
          <td>8626</td>
      </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>
<p>Most readers likely have some savings, allowing them to achieve significant wealth in 20-30 years.</p>
<p><strong>Investing Doesn&rsquo;t Require Advanced Knowledge</strong></p>
<p><em>The trouble with the world is not that people know too little, but that they know so many things that just aren&rsquo;t so.</em></p>
<p>Many believe investing requires perfect timing and extensive financial knowledge.  This isn&rsquo;t entirely true.  After years of studying investment, and witnessing ordinary people achieve wealth through it, I can confidently say that investment success doesn&rsquo;t depend on academic qualifications, intelligence, technical skills, or predictive abilities.  It depends on doing the right things. Successful investors aren&rsquo;t necessarily highly educated or technically skilled; they can be ordinary people who understand fundamental principles.</p>
<p>By doing the right things, anyone can achieve wealth through investment, regardless of their background or effort. Investing doesn&rsquo;t require genius or specialized knowledge; common sense and consistent action are key. Investors don&rsquo;t need to rely on experts; with the right mindset, you can outperform them.</p>
<p>Investing isn&rsquo;t about complex techniques; it&rsquo;s about having the right mindset.  Successful investors simply cultivate habits that most people find uncomfortable or difficult to maintain. Do you understand that investing can create wealth? If so, are you actively pursuing it?</p>
<p>From another perspective, investing can be challenging. The difficulty lies not in needing advanced knowledge, but in going against ingrained habits. This is difficult for most people.</p>
<p>This book presents seemingly simple investment concepts, but wealth is built through consistent, correct habits. Start your investment journey by building the right habits!</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The amount of money you accumulate in your lifetime depends not on how much you earn, but on how you manage it.</p>
</blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">Saving Alone Is Not Enough 
    <div id="saving-alone-is-not-enough" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#saving-alone-is-not-enough" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>A Taiwanese proverb says, &ldquo;People have two legs, money has four.&rdquo; Money chases money faster than people chase money.</p>
<p>Traditional wisdom dictates that &ldquo;the path to wealth lies in diligence and frugality.&rdquo;  This held true in times of economic stagnation, but in today&rsquo;s rapidly changing economy, this mindset requires adjustment.</p>
<p>A century ago, before modern economics became widespread, during periods of economic stagnation and frequent wars, saving was indeed crucial for wealth accumulation. Today, however, with global economic growth and soaring stock and real estate prices, the focus should shift from saving to leveraging the power of compound interest for exponential growth.</p>
<p><strong>How Did Lien Chan Become Wealthy?</strong></p>
<p><em>With so many assets, it&rsquo;s impossible to monitor everything closely. During the period of entrusted management, the principle was to hold existing investments and not trade stocks or dispose of real estate.</em></p>
<p>Lien Chan, with an estimated net worth of nearly NT$6 billion, was one of Taiwan&rsquo;s wealthiest officials. His wealth wasn&rsquo;t accumulated through decades of frugal living on a government salary or through earning a doctoral degree.  It stemmed from his mother&rsquo;s shift in investment strategy over 40 years prior.</p>
<p>Around 1951, Chang Pin-san, former chairman of Chang Hwa Bank, advised Lien Chan&rsquo;s father, Lien Chen-tung, to invest in shares of the &ldquo;Big Three&rdquo; commercial banks.  Following this advice, Lien Chan&rsquo;s mother, Chao Lan-kun, invested her savings in hundreds of shares of Chang Hwa Bank, holding them long-term and letting their value appreciate naturally. This laid the foundation for the Lien family&rsquo;s fortune. Chao Lan-kun had a keen financial mind. Unlike other women who participated in rotating savings and credit associations or simply deposited money in banks, she actively invested.  She sold ancestral farmland in Miaoli and co-developed a property on Nanjing West Road with Huang Lie-huo, founder of Wei Chuan Foods Corporation, splitting the profits. This prime real estate became a significant source of wealth for the Lien family.</p>
<p>Stocks, real estate, and land were the Lien family&rsquo;s wealth-generating tools. Over the years, Lien Chan accumulated holdings in 19 different stocks, including Chang Hwa Bank, Taipei Business Bank, Hua Nan Bank, and Cathay Life Insurance.  His real estate holdings were located in prime areas like the Da&rsquo;an, Shilin, and Zhongshan districts, including 11 plots of land and 26 properties.</p>
<p>Lien Chan once described his family&rsquo;s investment approach as &ldquo;Wu Wei Er Zhi&rdquo; (doing nothing and achieving everything), meaning buying and holding long-term.  By investing in stocks and real estate 40 years ago and patiently holding them, with minimal trading and benefiting from annual returns exceeding 20%, they amassed a fortune nearing NT$10 billion.</p>
<p>You might argue that the Lien family was already wealthy 40 years ago. This might be true, but the point is that while they were prominent, many families in Taiwan were wealthier back then. Today, very few families surpass the Liens in wealth.  This is attributed to their early adoption of the correct investment strategy – focusing on stocks and real estate.</p>
<p><strong>The Key to Wealth Lies in Financial Management, Not Just Saving</strong></p>
<p><em>The ability to earn money is less important than having a mind for financial management, understanding how to make money work for you.</em></p>
<p>Chinese culture values diligence and frugality.  Older generations often teach younger ones that the path to wealth lies in these principles and careful budgeting.  The saying &ldquo;Great wealth comes from heaven, small wealth from frugality&rdquo; encourages thriftiness, as it&rsquo;s seen as the key to wealth.  This emphasis on saving is reflected in Taiwan&rsquo;s high savings rate.  However, I want to convey a crucial message: while saving is important, financial management is even more so.</p>
<p>In the previous example, how much of the NT$100+ million fortune came from diligence and frugality? The answer is NT$560,000, accumulated by saving NT$14,000 annually for 40 years.  This represents only 0.5% of the total.  The remaining 99.5% came from investment, specifically the power of compound interest at a 20% annual return over 40 years.  Which is more important, saving or investing? <strong>Therefore, lifetime wealth accumulation depends not on how much you earn, but on how you manage your money.</strong></p>
<p>If a worker realizes in old age that their wealth primarily comes from a lifetime of hard work and saving, it&rsquo;s almost certain they won&rsquo;t be very wealthy.  The key to wealth through investment isn&rsquo;t the ability to &ldquo;earn and save,&rdquo; but the ability to leverage the &ldquo;compounding power of money.&rdquo;  For most, improving their financial situation requires focusing on investment, not just saving.</p>
<p>Consider this: saving NT$1 million annually without investing would take 100 years to reach NT$100 million. In contrast, investing NT$14,000 annually could make you a billionaire in 40 years. If Chao Lan-kun had only focused on saving and not investing, would the Lien family be as wealthy as they are today?</p>
<p>I&rsquo;m not dismissing the importance of saving, but I want to emphasize that it shouldn&rsquo;t overshadow investment. Investment plays a crucial role in wealth accumulation.  For successful investors, wealth comes primarily from &ldquo;making money work for you,&rdquo; not from earning or saving. Therefore, in addition to being diligent and frugal, learn how to invest.</p>
<p>To improve your financial situation, remember: earning is important, but managing your money is more so. <strong>A correct investment mindset and wise investment choices have a greater impact on your future financial status than your current wealth or future income.</strong> For most, the first step towards improving their finances is not to increase saving, but to understand the correct investment concepts and take action.</p>
<p><em>1. For those who achieve wealth through investment, their fortune comes primarily from making money work for them, not from earning or saving.</em></p>
<p><em>2.  Less than 1% of a NT$100 million fortune comes directly from earned income.</em></p>
<p><em>3.  Investment is not a technique, but a mindset.</em></p>
<p><em>4. The key to financial management is having money to manage, not the amount of money.</em></p>
<blockquote>
<p>Those who learn to invest are like having a money-printing machine.</p>
</blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">How Investment Strategies Create the Wealth Gap 
    <div id="how-investment-strategies-create-the-wealth-gap" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#how-investment-strategies-create-the-wealth-gap" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>A study indicates that in recent years, the public has perceived a serious wealth gap in Taiwan, with a trend towards wealth polarization. Over 47% of respondents believe that &ldquo;speculation in stocks or real estate&rdquo; is the main cause of this widening gap, followed by &ldquo;personal work ability and effort&rdquo; (14%) and &ldquo;family background&rdquo; (11%).  This suggests a common belief that the wealth gap isn&rsquo;t solely due to individual effort, but also to systemic issues, luck, and unequal opportunities.</p>
<p>Indeed, &ldquo;stocks and real estate&rdquo; are major contributors to the wealth gap, while &ldquo;personal work ability and effort&rdquo; and &ldquo;family background&rdquo; have less impact. <strong>People often attribute their poverty to external factors like systemic issues, luck, or lack of opportunity, or use negative terms like &ldquo;speculation&rdquo; to explain their lack of action.</strong> Wealthy individuals often accumulate their wealth through real estate or stock investments, not primarily through &ldquo;speculation,&rdquo; but through &ldquo;holding appropriate investment assets.&rdquo;</p>
<p>Looking ahead, the wealth gap will likely continue to widen. Some will benefit, while others will suffer, depending on their ability to navigate the changing landscape. External factors alone don&rsquo;t determine our financial situation; our investment abilities play a crucial role.</p>
<p><em>1. Financial habits create the difference between the rich and the poor.</em></p>
<p><em>2. The prerequisite for building wealth through investment is allocating assets to high-return investments like stocks or real estate.</em></p>
<p><em>3. One way for the government to address the widening wealth gap is to educate the public about proper financial management.</em></p>
<p><strong>Greater Investment, Greater Returns</strong></p>
<p><em>&ldquo;Thoughts change actions, actions change habits, habits change character, and character changes destiny.&rdquo;</em></p>
<p>Imagine two classmates who join the same company after graduation, holding similar positions with the same salary.  Both are equally frugal, saving NT$14,000 annually for investment. The difference lies in their approach: one keeps their savings in the bank, while the other invests in stocks. Both largely leave their money untouched after depositing or investing it.</p>
<p>After 40 years, the stock investor becomes a billionaire, while the bank saver becomes a &ldquo;millionaire.&rdquo;  While a billion represents significant wealth, &ldquo;millionaire&rdquo; now evokes laughter, being synonymous with &ldquo;homeless&rdquo; in Taiwan&rsquo;s expensive housing market.</p>
<p>The &ldquo;millionaire&rdquo; classmate, seeing their former colleague with the same starting conditions become a billionaire, might assume foul play or lottery winnings. How could their wealth differ so drastically, with one rich and the other struggling?</p>
<p>Those with less wealth often attribute the success of the wealthy to luck or illicit activities. A more positive view might be that they worked harder or were more frugal.  However, they often overlook the critical factor: financial habits. The rich and poor manage their money differently: the rich hold assets like real estate and stocks, while the poor keep their money in the bank.</p>
<p>To become wealthy through investment, one must break free from conventional thinking. An adult who couldn&rsquo;t ride a bicycle saw a child doing so and complained, &ldquo;Only agile children can ride bikes.&rdquo; The child responded, &ldquo;Agility isn&rsquo;t necessary,&rdquo; and taught the adult to ride.  The adult quickly learned but, upon parting ways, instinctively pushed the bicycle home instead of riding it.  This illustrates the difficulty of breaking free from ingrained habits.</p>
<p>If financial management is the primary cause of the wealth gap, the solution lies in improving financial literacy and encouraging people to learn more about investing.</p>
<p><strong>Focusing Solely on Saving is Outdated</strong></p>
<p><em>If one adheres to the principles of investment, it&rsquo;s hard not to become wealthy. If one doesn&rsquo;t, it&rsquo;s hard to become wealthy.</em></p>
<p>I often wonder why, after over 200 years since their ancestors arrived in Taiwan with nothing, most Taiwanese families aren&rsquo;t significantly wealthy. Perhaps the problem lies in outdated family precepts that hinder wealth accumulation.</p>
<p>Family precepts are the guiding principles passed down through generations.  Most families emphasize diligence, frugality, and academic excellence, believing these are the keys to success and wealth.</p>
<p>Many families diligently follow these precepts, raising children who are both frugal and well-educated.  However, few families achieve significant wealth through these alone.  These precepts focus on earning money, not on managing it.  To build generational wealth, families need to update their guiding principles.  While &ldquo;diligence and frugality&rdquo; and &ldquo;academic excellence&rdquo; remain valuable, add another: &ldquo;Don&rsquo;t keep money in the bank.&rdquo;</p>
<p>Why retain &ldquo;diligence and frugality&rdquo;? While saving alone won&rsquo;t lead to great wealth, it&rsquo;s a virtue and a necessary foundation for investment.</p>
<p><strong>Educating the Next Generation Requires a Balanced Approach</strong></p>
<p>Why keep &ldquo;academic excellence&rdquo;?  Studies show a weak correlation between education and wealth.  Academic success doesn&rsquo;t guarantee financial success.  Based on this, I once stopped emphasizing academics with my children, resulting in declining grades.  Their teacher, puzzled, asked, &ldquo;You and your wife are both highly educated, why don&rsquo;t your children share this trait?&rdquo; I was ashamed.</p>
<p>I immediately reinstated the emphasis on academics. I realized it was partly for our own pride, but also because education can enhance social standing and job security. So, for both parents and children, academic pursuits remain important.</p>
<p>However, for future generations to prosper, add another precept: &ldquo;Don&rsquo;t keep money in the bank!&rdquo;  Encourage children to invest in assets like stocks and real estate, rather than leaving money in low-interest bank accounts.  Otherwise, building significant wealth might take generations.</p>
<p>Every Lunar New Year, I buy stocks for my children instead of giving cash. My second-grader is already learning the importance of investing over saving. This concept should be ingrained early as part of family values, fostering a healthy financial mindset from a young age.</p>
<p>In conclusion, most family precepts are outdated.  Building wealth for future generations requires new concepts and practices.  By updating family values and changing how we accumulate wealth, families can achieve lasting prosperity.</p>
<p><em>1. Diligence, frugality, and academic excellence alone are not enough for building lasting wealth.</em></p>
<p><em>2. Teach children not to keep money in the bank, cultivating a proper investment mindset from a young age.</em></p>
<p><em>3.  Leaving money to children might sustain them for a few years; teaching them how to manage it can provide for a lifetime and for generations to come.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded></item></channel></rss>