<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Stock Pledge on QQQ Investor</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/tags/stock-pledge/</link><description>Recent content in Stock Pledge on QQQ Investor</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jomonylw.github.io/en/tags/stock-pledge/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>00500 The Balance Between Asset Appreciation and Spending: Spending Should Reflect Your Asset's Capacity</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1737905023775/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1737905023775/</guid><description>This episode mainly discusses the power of compound interest in long-term investing. For example, the final benefits of investing $10,000 at different ages vary greatly. It also addresses questions from students regarding whether retired individuals can use the 80/20 asset allocation strategy for collateralization and related issues.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<lite-youtube videoid="JGxThQ20wak" playlabel="JGxThQ20wak" params=""></lite-youtube>



<h2 class="relative group">I. Current Topic 
    <div id="i-current-topic" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-current-topic" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This episode primarily shares the power of compound interest in long-term investing and discusses whether the 80/20 asset allocation strategy for retirees can be used for collateralization. James uses specific examples and data analysis to emphasize the importance of compound interest in long-term investing and the key issues to consider when using the 80/20 asset allocation for collateralization. For example, while it&rsquo;s possible for retirees to use the 80/20 allocation for collateral, there are many restrictions. For safety, retirees should stick to the 433 allocation for collateralization.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">II. Briefing Content 
    <div id="ii-briefing-content" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii-briefing-content" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">1. Program Suspension Notice and Disclaimer 
    <div id="1-program-suspension-notice-and-disclaimer" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#1-program-suspension-notice-and-disclaimer" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Suspension Notice</strong>: Next Thursday (February 1, 2025) is the fourth day of the Chinese New Year. Considering that everyone may still be celebrating, there will be no program. The program will resume as usual on February 8, 2025.</li>
<li><strong>Disclaimer</strong>: All content shared on the CLEC channel is solely based on James&rsquo;s personal experience. James is not a professional investment advisor and does not provide professional tax advice. Investing involves extremely high risk, so please be cautious. It&rsquo;s important to note that the possibility of your assets being halved (i.e., a 50% drop) can happen at any time.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">2. Learning Materials and Viewing Recommendations 
    <div id="2-learning-materials-and-viewing-recommendations" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#2-learning-materials-and-viewing-recommendations" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Learning Materials</strong>: Newcomers are advised to watch <strong>video 00451</strong> first. We have also compiled a playlist of short videos. The subtitles for the &ldquo;<strong>One Hundred Million Yuan Investment Lecture</strong>&rdquo; series have been re-proofread, including English and various global language versions, making the translation more accurate.</li>
<li><strong>Viewing Recommendations</strong>: James advises everyone to watch the entire video, as the amount of information is large. Asking questions based on watching only parts of the video makes it difficult to get complete and comprehensive answers.</li>
<li><strong>About Groups</strong>: CLEC does not have any groups. The existing groups are organized by enthusiastic students, like the &ldquo;00662&rdquo; group. These groups mainly help new friends answer basic investment questions. However, it&rsquo;s important to note that these groups are not affiliated with CLEC, and James does not participate in any groups.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">3. Investment Strategies and Precautions 
    <div id="3-investment-strategies-and-precautions" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#3-investment-strategies-and-precautions" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Investment Target</strong>: CLEC focuses solely on investing in the Nasdaq 100 Index Fund. There are many instruments worldwide that allow direct investment in the Nasdaq 100 Index Fund, with relevant links provided in CLEC-related videos. For example, the ticker symbol for the Canadian 2x Leveraged Fund has changed. James will explain the specific changes in later videos.</li>
<li><strong>CLEC Video Quantity</strong>: Since 2018, CLEC has accumulated almost 1000 videos, covering content from investment basics to advanced levels.</li>
<li><strong>Investment Philosophy</strong>: Always maintain extreme optimism in investing and believe that the market will always go up.</li>
<li><strong>Prohibited Behaviors</strong>: We have a one-voice policy here. Activities unrelated to investing in the Nasdaq 100 Index Fund are not allowed. For example, recommending insurance, real estate, etc., is prohibited.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">4. Supplementary Remarks on Chen Feng&rsquo;s Sharing 
    <div id="4-supplementary-remarks-on-chen-fengs-sharing" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#4-supplementary-remarks-on-chen-fengs-sharing" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>About Chen Feng</strong>: Chen Feng is a senior and enthusiastic student who has voluntarily started a group and manages it with Nai Xin and others.</li>
<li><strong>Chen Feng&rsquo;s Content</strong>: Recently, Chen Feng shared a three-hour condensed course on YouTube. James provided supplementary remarks on some of the issues:
<ul>
<li><strong>About Long-Term Annualized Returns</strong>: The long-term annualized returns mentioned by Chen Feng are the actual returns after deducting inflation.</li>
<li><strong>About Excel Demonstrations</strong>: In his sharing, Chen Feng used Excel spreadsheets to demonstrate the returns of different asset ratios. Students can check his Excel spreadsheets for more accurate data results. Chen Feng may also add supplements and corrections in the notes of his YouTube video.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Supplementary Explanation</strong>: Chen Feng&rsquo;s sharing was for his group&rsquo;s internal use. While these senior students have understood 99% of James&rsquo;s content, there may still be some non-mainstream or less precise points. Therefore, James made a few supplementary explanations regarding his sharing.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">5. Collateralized Borrowing and Spending Adjustment Strategies 
    <div id="5-collateralized-borrowing-and-spending-adjustment-strategies" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#5-collateralized-borrowing-and-spending-adjustment-strategies" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Usable Funds Ratio for Collateralized Borrowing</strong>: The annual available funds for collateralized borrowing are 2% of retirement reserves (assuming your retirement reserves are 50 times your annual expenses). If your retirement reserves are NT$30 million, the annual available funds are NT$600,000 (NT$30 million * 2% = NT$600,000). This NT$600,000 is fixed. Even if the NT$30 million becomes NT$20 million due to market fluctuations, you can still use NT$600,000. You don&rsquo;t have to worry about a decrease in available funds because of market drop.</li>
<li><strong>Spending Strategy During Market Downturns</strong>: You do not need to reduce spending during a market downturn. You can increase spending during a market upswing. In other words, our annual spending will only increase, not decrease.</li>
<li><strong>Spending Adjustment Strategies</strong>:
<ul>
<li><strong>Upswing Scenario</strong>: For example, with a retirement reserve of NT$30 million, after 5 years, assets increase from NT$30 million to NT$50 million, and the net assets (after deducting debt, including 5 years of expenses, and annual interest, totaling NT$3.22 million) are NT$46.78 million (NT$50 million - NT$3.22 million = NT$46.78 million). At this point, annual available funds can be adjusted to NT$930,000 (NT$46.78 million * 2% = NT$930,000). However, this NT$930,000 includes interest expenses. Assuming the previous loan of NT$3.22 million and a 3% interest rate, the annual interest expense is about NT$100,000, and the actual available funds are NT$830,000 (NT$930,000 - NT$100,000 = NT$830,000).</li>
<li><strong>Downturn Scenario</strong>: There is no need to reduce spending during a market downturn. You can still maintain the peak spending level (e.g., if the peak spending was NT$900,000, you can still maintain NT$900,000 per year even if assets drop to NT$30 million). This allocation strategy is based on a model that assumes a 10-year decline from the peak, which can be fully sustained even under the extreme scenario of a 10-year decline.</li>
<li><strong>Core Principle for Spending Adjustments</strong>: Only increase spending, not decrease it, and it&rsquo;s recommended to adjust it every 5 years to avoid frequent adjustments.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">6. Retirement Asset Allocation and Collateralization Strategies 
    <div id="6-retirement-asset-allocation-and-collateralization-strategies" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#6-retirement-asset-allocation-and-collateralization-strategies" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Retirees who do not utilize collateralization can use an 80/20 asset allocation, i.e., 80% invested in QQQ and 20% in cash.</strong></li>
<li><strong>An 80/20 asset allocation, without collateralization, allows for simple rebalancing yearly without risk of bankruptcy.</strong></li>
<li><strong>If you must utilize the 80/20 asset allocation for collateralization, please be aware:</strong>
<ul>
<li><strong>Absolutely do not use cash to rebalance in the market, cash must only increase, not decrease.</strong></li>
<li><strong>Market downturns may last up to 10 years. If you borrow 2% annually, you will borrow more than 20% in 10 years. If you then invest cash, your total assets may be less than 20%. Therefore, using an 80/20 asset allocation for collateralization is high risk.</strong></li>
<li><strong>A safer approach is still a 433 allocation.</strong></li>
<li><strong>If you must use the 80/20 allocation for collateralization, rebalancing intelligently only during upswing years, that is, can only transfer cash from the prototype fund (QQQ), it is not allowed to transfer cash into QQQ during downswing years, can transfer cash into QQQ during upswing years.</strong></li>
<li><strong>This approach is complex and requires simulation to ensure feasibility.</strong></li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">7. Core Principles for Asset Allocation 
    <div id="7-core-principles-for-asset-allocation" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#7-core-principles-for-asset-allocation" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Whenever making an asset allocation or adjustment, assume that it&rsquo;s the market&rsquo;s highest point.</strong></li>
<li><strong>Spending does not need to be reduced during a 10-year decline, as the allocation strategy has been verified through simulations as feasible.</strong></li>
<li>When assets have risen to a new high (e.g., from NT$30 million to NT$45 million), you can reset the spending amount. Even if the market declines again afterwards, you don&rsquo;t need to reduce spending because it is already close to the bottom, and risk is reduced.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">8. Yuanta Securities Finance Information 
    <div id="8-yuanta-securities-finance-information" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#8-yuanta-securities-finance-information" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Yuanta Securities Finance is an institution that specializes in lending money out. Its interest rates are low (below 3%), and it doesn&rsquo;t experience liquidity shortages like other brokerages or institutions. Its website operation and fund transfers are also convenient.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">9. Risks of Real Estate Investment 
    <div id="9-risks-of-real-estate-investment" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#9-risks-of-real-estate-investment" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Real estate is not a good asset and carries extremely high risks.</strong></li>
<li>Natural disasters like fires and earthquakes can cause the value of real estate to drop to zero. In some countries or regions, you still have to repay the loan even if the house is destroyed.</li>
<li>Real estate involves putting all your eggs in one basket, and the risk is too concentrated. Moreover, real estate depreciates and loses value.</li>
<li><strong>Investments should be diversified. Avoid putting all your assets into real estate.</strong></li>
<li><strong>You should only buy a house if you could afford to buy another one if the first one was destroyed.</strong></li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">10. Information on German Stock Pledge 
    <div id="10-information-on-german-stock-pledge" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#10-information-on-german-stock-pledge" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>See page 30 of the handout. This is information provided by students on German stock pledges. James did not provide a detailed interpretation.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">11. Tax Issues of American Retirement Accounts (Traditional IRA &amp; Roth IRA) 
    <div id="11-tax-issues-of-american-retirement-accounts-traditional-ira--roth-ira" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#11-tax-issues-of-american-retirement-accounts-traditional-ira--roth-ira" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>When the Traditional IRA becomes an inheritance, the heir must withdraw all the funds within 10 years. The principal and appreciation are both taxed, and there are almost no inheritance tax exemptions.</strong></li>
<li><strong>When the Roth IRA becomes an inheritance, the heir has 10 years to withdraw the funds, and neither the principal nor the appreciation is taxed.</strong></li>
<li><strong>Converting Traditional IRA to Roth IRA as soon as possible can effectively reduce the tax burden when RMD (Required Minimum Distribution) occurs.</strong></li>
<li>Many financial planners or accountants do not advise converting all your Traditional IRA to Roth IRA at once because they want to minimize your current year&rsquo;s taxes, rather than focusing on long-term tax planning.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">12. The Value of Life and the Meaning of Wealth 
    <div id="12-the-value-of-life-and-the-meaning-of-wealth" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#12-the-value-of-life-and-the-meaning-of-wealth" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>The value of life lies in learning, thinking, serving others, and growing, not just working and making money.</li>
<li>Money is a tool to help us achieve our life&rsquo;s purpose, enhancing our spiritual energy and fulfilling our dreams.</li>
<li><strong>The ideal state is to have 10 billion dollars in assets but owe the bank 10.1 billion dollars.</strong></li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">III. Q&amp;A Session 
    <div id="iii-qa-session" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii-qa-session" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Angel 
    <div id="angel" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#angel" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing</strong>: Angel is a young man currently studying in the United States. He turns 21 the next day. His parents are very supportive and hardworking, allowing Angel to study in the U.S. without worry. Angel&rsquo;s parents hope he can live a wealthy life, so they advised him to learn investment and financial management with James and promised to give him funds to invest.</li>
<li><strong>Question 1</strong>: If James were 21 again, with his current knowledge and parental support, how would he invest?
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response</strong>: If James were 21 again with his current knowledge and parental support, he would use a 442 allocation to buy in all at once. Additionally, the teacher shared two investment mistakes he made when he was young: investing in real estate, which he bought for 8 million and sold for only 6 million after 10 years, resulting in a significant loss; and selling company stock to buy a car. These two poor decisions resulted in his assets being reduced by half. The teacher used his own example to emphasize: <strong>$100,000 for a young person, with time, compounded at 14% annually, will be $25 million in 60 years; $10,000 for a young person is $2.6 million in the future, so young people should learn to save and invest first and then learn to spend money when the time is right.</strong></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question 2</strong>: Besides human nature, why is it not advisable for someone of my age to put all my money into QQQ, but rather 433 or 442?
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response</strong>: Human nature is the most important factor that must be considered in investment. You cannot exclude the factor of &ldquo;human nature&rdquo;. If you don&rsquo;t consider human nature, then don&rsquo;t invest. For example, investors often overestimate their risk tolerance. Investment should avoid getting yourself into a state of extreme panic. Allocating all your assets to QQQ or half in QQQ and half in cash overestimates your risk tolerance. Although the market will eventually go up in the long term, your assets may fall to extremely low values during a market downswing, for example: from 100 to 80, 70, 60, then finally falling down to 5, 1. During this process, you might have already gone bankrupt and exited, even if you survive until market rise, it no longer has anything to do with you. It’s like playing Russian roulette: a revolver with 6 chambers, and 1 bullet. If the person firing doesn’t die, they will get 10 million; if they do die, they die. You should not participate because of the high reward. You could die. So young people&rsquo;s beta should not exceed 1.2.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Lisa 
    <div id="lisa" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#lisa" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing 1</strong>: Has retired and currently uses a power account as a reserve for daily living. The account balance is usually 0. Money is only used when a large expense happens or an emergency occurs. This practice brings her peace of mind. She doesn&rsquo;t need to keep a lot of cash in her daily account so that she could effectively use cash for investment purposes.</li>
<li><strong>Question 1</strong>: After retiring, I do not want to use leveraged funds (like QLD), but I am worried about a stock market crash. Is it feasible to use the 80/20 (80% in QQQ and 20% in cash) asset allocation strategy?
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response</strong>: Yes, it is feasible. An 80/20 asset allocation, if you don&rsquo;t do collateralization, can do simple rebalancing yearly. Because she is retired, and the funds in her collateralization account have not been used, which is equivalent to her not using collateralization, she can use the 80/20 asset allocation strategy under that circumstance.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Sharing 2</strong>: Has started Roth IRA conversion and plans to complete all the conversion within the next few years when the tax rate is lower.</li>
<li><strong>Question 2</strong>: Some people suggested using up the 32% tax rate, but I cannot mentally accept it, as it may mean paying higher taxes. Is it okay to just use up the 24% tax rate and deal with the rest during RMD time?
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response</strong>: You can complete all the conversions before the RMD age, as long as you finish before RMD, as money cannot be transferred into a Roth IRA after RMD age. Money can only be transferred into a brokerage account, which is not beneficial to inheritance. It is recommended to transfer the funds from the retirement account to a Roth IRA as much as possible, as the Roth IRA&rsquo;s heir does not need to pay taxes within 10 years, while the Traditional IRA&rsquo;s heir needs to pay taxes. Converting early can avoid higher taxes in the future. If you still do the conversion when the market drops, it means your conversion decision is correct. Although you may have to pay as high as 30% tax now during conversion, you can avoid higher taxes in the future in the long run (because your assets will grow significantly over time, so you will have to pay more taxes later).</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">YJ 
    <div id="yj" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#yj" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing 1</strong>: YJ would first like to thank James and the &ldquo;00662&rdquo; group, especially for Chen Feng&rsquo;s sharing and James&rsquo;s supplementation, which make everyone&rsquo;s investment concepts clearer.</li>
<li><strong>Sharing 2</strong>: The Chinese concept of &ldquo;having land is having wealth&rdquo; needs to be updated. In the current era, this &ldquo;land&rdquo; should not be real estate but rather &ldquo;stocks&rdquo;. The old concept of &ldquo;having land is having wealth&rdquo; refers to farmland that can be cultivated and has output, which is similar concept to current day investing in stocks.</li>
<li><strong>Suggestion</strong>: There are no more lectures on the 100 Million Investment topic this year. The 9 situations in the 00005 topic have been simplified into 2 situations. Can there be a &ldquo;00006&rdquo; topic, specifically on the &ldquo;collateralization&rdquo; part, with a simpler presentation?
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response</strong>: &ldquo;Having land is having wealth&rdquo; did not refer to houses in the past, as houses were not valuable in those eras and this term referred to farmlands. Today&rsquo;s &ldquo;having land is having wealth&rdquo; should be changed to &ldquo;having stocks is having wealth&rdquo;, stocks are the true assets. Regarding your suggestion of topic 00006, James believes the existing sharing is already simplified enough. Users using collateralization should use the 433 allocation and make &ldquo;smart rebalancing&rdquo; using 2% of their assets yearly, and there is no need for a more complicated topical presentation.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question 1</strong>: Previously, I sent a message on YouTube mentioning the video 00303 in March 2022, and you suggested to not use TQ (TQQQ) back then. However, two months ago (around November), you replied that a 6TQQ+2U+2Cash strategy can be used with a 6:2:2 allocation. Does this strategy and comparison with the 442 strategy feasible?
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response</strong>: TQQ can be used. The suggestion in previous videos was based on the understanding at the time, so single-asset investment in TQQ was not recommended. However, now, if you have an asset allocation (like 6:2:2, which is 60% in TQQ, 20% in U, and 20% in Cash) and do &ldquo;smart rebalancing&rdquo;, this strategy is viable. Investment strategies and concepts are constantly evolving and improving. Ideas considered impossible in the past may now be proven to be feasible.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Bill 
    <div id="bill" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#bill" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Question</strong>: I previously learned about BOXX as an investment target that is not correlated to the stock market. However, I learned that it&rsquo;s related to blockchain, so there are concerns about its safety, and whether its risk is too high?
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response</strong>: BOXX&rsquo;s operating mechanism is similar to 00864B. As long as its return is trending similarly to the US Federal Funds Rate, its risk is controllable. You should pay serious attention when the return is much higher or lower than the US Federal Funds Rate, as it may indicate some irregular financial operations. BOXX&rsquo;s primary function is to reasonably avoid investment income tax, and it can be used as a short-term investment target.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Henry 
    <div id="henry" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#henry" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Question</strong>: Henry runs his own business and used to have a company 401K. He has stopped it now, and he is not sure whether he should continue contributing into it or put the money designated for company contributions into his investment account.
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response</strong>: The main purpose of a 401K is to save on taxes. If you can do a Roth Solo 401k, you should prioritize it. You can consult your tax consultant or search the web and consult ChatGPT to confirm if you can do a Roth Solo 401k.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Yuqiao 
    <div id="yuqiao" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#yuqiao" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Question</strong>: I am retired and have benefited from this investment method. I want to recommend this investment method to my younger sister in China (who is 50 years old, runs a small business, has a tight budget, and has almost no knowledge of investment). Should I give her investment advice?</li>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response</strong>: Yes, you should. You can be her benefactor. However, she may not accept advice directly. Furthermore, opening an account and the follow-up operations are complex. So, if you really want to help her, you can open an account for her first and invest a small amount of money (such as $1,000 USD for about ¥7,000 to ¥8,000 RMB), tell her that if there are losses, you will bear it, if there are profits, it&rsquo;s hers. You can also co-invest with her proportionally, for example, if she invests ¥100, you can invest ¥100 for her. Once she sees a return, she will then invest automatically.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">IAM 
    <div id="iam" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iam" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing 1</strong>: IAM has recently met a doctor in his 70s. When he was young in his 30s, he trusted brokers and made careless investments. After several failed investments, he not only had real estate and stocks but was also in debt at 40 years old. He had to work to repay his debts even in his 70s. IAM is very grateful he found CLEC in 2022 and avoided going down the same path as the doctor.</li>
<li><strong>Question 1</strong>: James often says &ldquo;slow is fast,&rdquo; and investment should not be rushed. However, everyone&rsquo;s understanding of &ldquo;fast&rdquo; and &ldquo;slow&rdquo; is different. Can you please explain how to measure &ldquo;fast&rdquo; and &ldquo;slow&rdquo; in investing and how to view the concept of &ldquo;40 years is too long&rdquo;?
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response</strong>: Everything has its own rules and timings, like pregnancy and childbirth, which takes ten months and cannot be shortened. The same applies to investing. Wealth growth takes time. You cannot expect to harvest tomorrow what you planted today. It takes 10 years of investment to feel wealthy, 20 years to retire, 30 years to be prosperous, and 40 years to become rich. This requires time, one cannot be hasty. Warren Buffett did not become the world&rsquo;s richest man at 30 or 40, but after 55 years old. Investing requires understanding the essence and rules of time. Do not be impatient. Every thing operates following its rules and timings. It&rsquo;s a rule of nature and cannot be rushed.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question 2</strong>: Why do people haggle over small amounts of money, but at the same time act recklessly like gamblers when it comes to investing?
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response</strong>: This all stems from humanity&rsquo;s &ldquo;loss aversion&rdquo; mentality. People do not like to lose, so they haggle over prices when shopping, but they tend to focus only on the gains and ignore the risks when investing. During investment, people often forget past losses and only think about making more money in the future. This is the gambler&rsquo;s mentality. When shopping, people compare prices since they can lose less and, by nature, they will haggle. In investing, people think that the more they invest, the more they will earn; while ignoring the possibility of losses, hence they will not haggle. It&rsquo;s like if you go to buy a cake, and the owner says the cake is 100, you might haggle and say can it be 90? But if the owner says you buy my cake and tomorrow I&rsquo;ll return 300, you won&rsquo;t haggle anymore, you&rsquo;d think the more expensive, the better.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Mike 
    <div id="mike" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#mike" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing 1</strong>: Shared a story about a CNBC interview with Buffett and Bill Gates: If Buffett and Bill Gates went to McDonald&rsquo;s and they see 1 cent on the ground, what would they do? Buffett would pick it up without hesitation and check if there are any other coins around; and Bill Gates would also pick up that cent. This story illustrates the principles of &ldquo;every little bit counts&rdquo; and &ldquo;compound interest.&rdquo; Even the wealthy do not overlook the importance of &ldquo;saving&rdquo; because when Mike was on a business trip to Microsoft in 1992, Microsoft was already a listed company, and Bill Gates was already very wealthy at that time. One of the employees criticized Bill Gates for using coupons when shopping for groceries. Later, one time, Bill Gates was looking for his coupon when checking out. The person behind him said, don&rsquo;t worry, I will pay, you earn more than this in one minute. However, Bill Gates did not ignore the person behind him, he continued to search for his coupon.</li>
<li><strong>Sharing 2</strong>: Opinions regarding Deep Seek: Recently, AI technology is developing rapidly, with various new technologies and applications emerging, including Deep Seek, which will have a significant impact on QQQ&rsquo;s future. Currently, American technology giants seem to have a &ldquo;big brother&rdquo; mentality, believing that they can win the AI race as long as they invest enough resources. However, historical experience shows that technological leadership does not necessarily win the market, the business model is also important.</li>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response</strong>:</li>
<li>Deep Seek, like many other AI technologies, is still in the early stages, and there will be many uncertainties in the future. But what is certain is that AI will have a profound impact on human society and bring huge opportunities for investors.</li>
<li>Regarding the competition between the US and China in the field of AI, it is still difficult to judge who will ultimately win. The US has advantages in technology and funds, but China also has its own advantages, such as large amounts of data and government support.</li>
<li>AI is not only large language models (LLM), there are many other applications, for example: Tesla&rsquo;s autonomous driving. Tesla&rsquo;s autonomous driving model is already very mature, it can automatically drive out from the parking lot and the driving experience is very smooth, just like a professional driver is driving for you.</li>
<li>AI will not completely replace human jobs but increase our work efficiency. For example, even for translators, you can use AI to improve the efficiency and quality of translation. Therefore, humans need to learn how to utilize AI, not reject it.</li>
<li>Currently, the biggest problem is that many large companies want to introduce AI, but they do not have a clear idea, they do not know whether it needs to be from top down or from bottom-up. James thinks it needs to be from bottom-up, the employees should use them first, so they are accustomed before moving up. But this requires time and because everyone is changing the thinking process of using AI.</li>
<li>AI will cause QQQ&rsquo;s annual returns to be much higher than 14%, or even 20% or 30%. James is very optimistic about this.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Eric 
    <div id="eric" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#eric" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing</strong>: Based in Canada, 35 years old, plans to sell his house and invest the proceeds from the sale. Both he and his wife are currently working.</li>
<li><strong>Question 1</strong>: A plan to invest 20% in cash, 40% in QLD, 40% in QQ for long term investment and do smart rebalancing, is this investment plan correct?
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response</strong>: The plan is correct. Young people who are still working can use a 442 asset allocation, which is 40% in QQQ, 40% in QLD, and 20% in cash, and then do smart rebalancing.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question 2</strong>: Canada has high taxes, and capital gains tax is heavy. What are your suggestions for long-term planning?
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response</strong>: People&rsquo;s destiny is controlled by three factors: the first is fate (DNA); the second is destiny (place of birth); and the third is luck. The place of birth determines one&rsquo;s destiny. Canada, Europe, and Australia are not as good as the US. If financially possible, consider immigrating to the US, not just for yourself but also for your descendants.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Hao Qing 
    <div id="hao-qing" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#hao-qing" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing 1</strong>:
<ul>
<li><strong>Event 1</strong>: Shared two experiences of encountering potential &ldquo;scams&rdquo;. One time was meeting someone on a highway who claimed to be from Dubai, needing help. This person was dressed neatly, drove a BMW, and claimed to have run out of gas and had no money or was robbed. This person wore gold and asked Hao Qing for help, claiming that he could give his gold to Hao Qing. Hao Qing gave him 40 yuan, but he wanted more. Hao Qing felt that something was wrong, and so did not give any more. The second time, he encountered the same person on the road again, so he called the police.</li>
<li><strong>Event 2</strong>: A colleague&rsquo;s relative, an 80-year-old, was scammed for 600,000 yuan. This old person did not believe what nearby people said about it being a scam, and believed that since he raised his children for so many years, it was not unfilial to ask them for money to invest and everyone was stopping him. When going to the bank, the bank employees also told him that it was a scam. The police also came to give him risk warnings that the money could not be transferred, but this old person still did not believe it and was scammed for 600,000 yuan.</li>
<li><strong>Personal Views</strong>: Hao Qing thinks that he is a kind-hearted person. When he sees someone in trouble, he will help to the best of his ability. However, he will be more careful when it comes to money. Also, there are now many scams and the success rate for solving them is extremely low. He is not sure if it&rsquo;s the government&rsquo;s problem or individual&rsquo;s problem.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Sharing 2</strong>: While discussing &ldquo;US-China trade&rdquo; with colleagues, his colleagues think that China may devalue the renminbi to deal with the US tariffs. He does not agree with this point of view but does not know how to explain it.</li>
<li><strong>Questions</strong>: How should we view the three problems of &ldquo;scams&rdquo;, &ldquo;Taiwan policy&rdquo;, and “RMB devaluation”?
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response</strong>:
<ul>
<li><strong>About Scams:</strong> The US does not care because the US thinks that if you are scammed, it means you are stupid. Furthermore, the person that Hao Qing encountered is technically not breaking a legal law, even if you report, it is useless. All the police can do is to chase him away. Why are there scams? It&rsquo;s because of &ldquo;poverty&rdquo;. When it&rsquo;s difficult to earn money through normal ways, &ldquo;scamming&rdquo; becomes a way to get rich quickly. So, you still need to start from the systems, and education aspect.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>About Taiwan policies</strong>: The US has completely free capitalism where the market determines prices. When prices increase, wages increase, which will then increase interest rates and suppress inflation, ultimately creating a positive economic cycle. Taiwan&rsquo;s policies, to a certain degree, hinders this positive economic cycle.</li>
<li><strong>Regarding the RMB devaluation expectations</strong>: This problem is complex and interlinked. It cannot be simply solved via devaluation.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Martin 
    <div id="martin" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#martin" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing</strong>: Previously talked with James about the DPC open-source model, and he is also involved in the implementation of his company&rsquo;s AI project. Therefore, he would like to share and communicate with everyone.</li>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response</strong>: Okay, you can come and share it with us next time.</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">IV. Key Insights 
    <div id="iv-key-insights" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv-key-insights" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>When investing, you need to see results. You want to see results like Buffett&rsquo;s. Of course, everyone&rsquo;s level is different. When you feel you are living a prosperous life, you will also need 40 years. You cannot be hasty.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>This point explains the importance of &ldquo;time&rdquo; and the power of &ldquo;compound interest&rdquo; in long-term investing.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The value of life lies in learning, thinking, serving others, and growing, not just working and making money.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>This point emphasizes that the meaning of life lies in continuous learning, growth, and serving society, not just the pursuit of material wealth.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>You also need an appropriate amount of time to grow wealth to a certain extent. Therefore, you need to recognize that time exists first.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>This emphasizes that wealth accumulation requires time and patience, and one should not take any shortcuts.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>What do you do when everything is destroyed? You need a way out.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>Whether you&rsquo;re investing or doing anything else, you have to consider if this thing fails, and whether you have a way out. Or whether you can bear the losses caused by that failure.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Today if you buy a Tesla car but you&rsquo;re afraid of it getting scratched, you&rsquo;re afraid of washing it. After washing it, you&rsquo;re afraid to drive it. Every time you drive it out, you&rsquo;re afraid of people wanting to borrow it, or when your daughter wants to borrow it, you&rsquo;d always say no and no. You&rsquo;re a slave to wealth. It&rsquo;s okay to drive. I have insurance. If it is crashed I can buy a new one. This is wealth. Therefore, don&rsquo;t be a slave to your assets, never be.  It&rsquo;s better not to buy it, instead of buying it and then using up your mental energy over it. We should not spend any mental energy on material things. This is very important. This is the key to happiness.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>We should not be slaves to &ldquo;wealth,&rdquo; and should not be controlled by &ldquo;material things.&rdquo; If something affects your mood, do not buy it because you cannot afford it.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>People&rsquo;s destiny is controlled by three factors: The first is fate (DNA); the second is destiny (place of birth); and the third is luck.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>The place of birth determines destiny. If you are born in the United States, you have the American destiny; if you are born in Taiwan, you have the Taiwan destiny; if you are born in Australia, you have the Australian destiny.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>I am still going to tell everyone that we are going to be very wealthy, so when you want to immigrate you have to think twice. If it&rsquo;s me, I&rsquo;d rather spend 800,000 USD to immigrate to the US instead of using less money to immigrate to Canada, Europe, or the NSW. Because the destinies are different. Look at the world&rsquo;s top ten companies, and nine are from the US. Only one is TSMC from China, but TSMC is also cultivated in the US. To say it bluntly, all the world&rsquo;s top ten companies were founded by Americans, this is fate.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>When considering immigration, one should think not only for themselves but also the fate of future generations.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>An 80/20 allocation without collateralization can do simple rebalancing yearly without risk of bankruptcy.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>Retirees that do not do collateralization may utilize an 80/20 asset allocation where 80% is invested in QQQ and 20% is kept in cash, and can do simple rebalancing without risk of bankruptcy.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The US does not care about scams, they don&rsquo;t even care about the 0-dollar purchase scams, so why would they care about scams? Therefore, there is a cost accounting issue. If a country wants to be strong, it needs strong cost accounting. What do you want? Right and wrong is about competing, and everyone needs to know that prosperity is a key, and poverty is a disease. Being poor for an emerging country is a disease, if one is poor it&rsquo;s a disease.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>The United States is strong due to its sound system and market economy.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Always maintain extreme optimism in investing and believe that the market will always go up.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>Maintain an optimistic attitude throughout the investment process.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>AI may not necessarily solely rely on computing power. It can also rely on the human brain.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>This point explains that in the development of AI, in addition to computing power, the human brain can also play an important role.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">V. Summary 
    <div id="v-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#v-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This episode mainly focused on discussions surrounding compound interest, asset allocation, and various social phenomena. James emphasized the power of &ldquo;compound interest&rdquo; and the importance of &ldquo;time&rdquo; in long-term investing. He also provided detailed answers and specific operational suggestions regarding asset allocation strategies for retirees, particularly addressing the question of whether an 80/20 allocation is suitable for collateralization. Furthermore, he incorporated current events to share his perspectives on social phenomena such as US-China trade, AI development, and scams, pointing out that &ldquo;wealth&rdquo; is a key factor in a nation&rsquo;s strength. Overall, this episode was packed with information, offering specific guidance on investment strategies along with profound reflections on life, wealth, and social issues, making it worthy of repeated study.</p>

  



<div
  
    class="flex px-4 py-3 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900"
  >

  <span
    
      class="text-primary-400 ltr:pr-3 rtl:pl-3 flex items-center"
    >

    

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M506.3 417l-213.3-364c-16.33-28-57.54-28-73.98 0l-213.2 364C-10.59 444.9 9.849 480 42.74 480h426.6C502.1 480 522.6 445 506.3 417zM232 168c0-13.25 10.75-24 24-24S280 154.8 280 168v128c0 13.25-10.75 24-23.1 24S232 309.3 232 296V168zM256 416c-17.36 0-31.44-14.08-31.44-31.44c0-17.36 14.07-31.44 31.44-31.44s31.44 14.08 31.44 31.44C287.4 401.9 273.4 416 256 416z"/></svg>

  </span>


  </span>

  <span
    
      class="dark:text-neutral-300"
    >Disclaimer: This article is solely for personal study notes and does not constitute any investment advice.</span>
</div>

]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>A One Hundred Million Investment Life Lecture</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1736045402069/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1736045402069/</guid><description>This session delves into how ordinary people can achieve financial freedom through correct investment concepts and methods. Key points include: everyone has an innate talent for wealth; vision determines the height of wealth; it&amp;#39;s hard for salaried workers to escape the &amp;#39;rat race&amp;#39; because they are trapped in a carefully designed cycle; poverty is not an individual&amp;#39;s fault but rather caused by social structures; money is a tool for achieving goals; ordinary people can absolutely achieve financial freedom through long-term investment in index funds; one must shed the &amp;#39;poor mindset&amp;#39; and recognize their own wealth potential and rights; it&amp;#39;s best to start investing as early as possible, because the power of compounding requires time; bonds and real estate are not ideal long-term investment vehicles; investing in the future of humanity is investing in technological progress; the U.S. market is worth investing in due to its innovation capabilities and market mechanisms; the Nasdaq 100 index fund is an ideal choice for sharing the dividends of technological development; the method for investing in index funds is simple but not easy to execute; avoid common pitfalls on the investment journey; employ the &amp;#39;buy when you have money&amp;#39; and &amp;#39;never sell&amp;#39; investment strategies; market downturns are opportunities; stock pledges can help investors address capital needs without selling shares; independent thinking is crucial in investing.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<lite-youtube videoid="4FMjmyBpTzw" playlabel="4FMjmyBpTzw" params=""></lite-youtube>



<h3 class="relative group"><strong>Re-Examining Our Wealth Potential: You Could Have Been Richer</strong> 
    <div id="re-examining-our-wealth-potential-you-could-have-been-richer" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#re-examining-our-wealth-potential-you-could-have-been-richer" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>Many of us spend our entire lives struggling with money, working tirelessly for monthly bills, children&rsquo;s tuition, and meager retirement savings, like a hamster trapped in a cage, running hard but never escaping. Have you ever considered that you could have been richer? Have you ever thought that the sense of security you seek actually binds you, causing you to miss out on greater wealth?</p>
<p>Yes, everyone has an innate talent for wealth, a right we are born with, as natural as breathing, as natural as birds flying and fish swimming. Unfortunately, this right, this talent, has been forgotten, or even buried by our own hands through the &ldquo;education&rdquo; of reality and the &ldquo;discipline&rdquo; of society. From a young age, we are told: study hard, find a good job, work hard to earn money to support the family. No one tells us: you can be very rich, you have the right to be very rich, you don&rsquo;t even have to work so hard to have it all!</p>
<p>The value of this lecture is far more than teaching you one or two investment techniques; its true value lies in awakening you from that “hamster dilemma,” making you realize your dormant wealth potential, and showing you a path to financial freedom. This path does not require you to have Einstein&rsquo;s brain, nor does it require you to have Buffett&rsquo;s luck, it only requires you to change your mindset, and then, to move forward steadfastly.</p>


<h3 class="relative group"><strong>Vision Determines Wealth: How Far into the Future Do You See?</strong> 
    <div id="vision-determines-wealth-how-far-into-the-future-do-you-see" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#vision-determines-wealth-how-far-into-the-future-do-you-see" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>The extent of your vision dictates the height of your wealth. This isn&rsquo;t just some motivational slogan; it&rsquo;s a conclusion derived from rigorous logic and data analysis. Don&rsquo;t believe it? Let&rsquo;s crunch some numbers.</p>
<p>Many people find investing for something decades into the future to be too distant and unrealistic. But what if we look 60 years into the future? If you have 1 million now, through sensible investments and factoring in the power of compounding, you could have assets worth hundreds of millions or even billions of dollars in a few decades. This is entirely possible; it’s actually a conservative estimate.</p>
<p>Why don&rsquo;t ordinary people realize they can have so much wealth? The reason is simple: our concept of money is too narrow, we have insufficient understanding of our potential, and we lack a deep understanding of compounding, the &ldquo;eighth wonder of the world!&rdquo; Our understanding of money is still at the kindergarten level, while financial giants have a Ph.D.-level understanding of money, at least.</p>


<h3 class="relative group"><strong>The &ldquo;Rat Race&rdquo; Dilemma: Who Stole Your Wealth Dreams?</strong> 
    <div id="the" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#the" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>Why is it so hard for most salaried workers to escape the &ldquo;rat race&rdquo; dilemma? Because they are trapped in a carefully designed cycle: you work hard for a month, and before the paycheck even warms up, it has to go to capitalists, the government, and the bank. For that meager salary, you have to work like a rat running tirelessly in a cage, never escaping that vicious circle.</p>
<p>What&rsquo;s worse is that society constantly brainwashes you with &ldquo;consumerism,&rdquo; telling you that buying big houses, luxury cars, and branded bags is the standard for successful people. So, you&rsquo;re burdened with heavy loans, barely able to breathe under the weight of monthly interest payments. You don&rsquo;t dare to quit your job easily, and you don&rsquo;t dare to challenge your boss. You become a complete slave to capital.</p>
<p>Do you think this is your own choice? Do you think it&rsquo;s because you&rsquo;re not working hard enough? No! This is a structure intentionally or unintentionally maintained by the entire society and education system. What do schools cultivate? Compliant cogs in a machine, not independent-thinking creators. Financial institutions design complex financial products, ostensibly to help you manage your money, but in reality? They earn high fees and interest, while you can&rsquo;t even outpace inflation.</p>
<p>This “controlled environment” prevents you from realizing your potential for wealth, let alone changing your situation. You are like that hamster in the fable, the faster you run, the further you get from freedom.</p>


<h3 class="relative group"><strong>Re-Examining Poverty and Wealth: Breaking Down Class Barriers</strong> 
    <div id="re-examining-poverty-and-wealth-breaking-down-class-barriers" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#re-examining-poverty-and-wealth-breaking-down-class-barriers" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>Poverty is not your fault; it is the result of social structures that create class inequality. This structural inequality is like a thick curtain that obscures your innate talent for wealth, making you believe that you can only live a poor or middle-class life.</p>
<p>The statement &ldquo;wealth is a talent&rdquo; is not just a platitude, but a declaration, a solemn proclamation of your right! It tells you: you have the right to pursue a life of abundance, you have the right to enjoy beautiful things, you don&rsquo;t have to sacrifice your health, your happiness, or your dreams for money!</p>
<p>Recognizing this is the first step, and the most important step, to achieving financial freedom.</p>


<h3 class="relative group"><strong>The Essence of Money: Not an End, but a Bridge to Freedom</strong> 
    <div id="the-essence-of-money-not-an-end-but-a-bridge-to-freedom" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#the-essence-of-money-not-an-end-but-a-bridge-to-freedom" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>What is money? Money is a kind of energy, a tool. In a capitalist society, money can be used to exchange for various resources and services, including time, happiness, health, and even freedom. Money can also be used for investment, growing more money like seeds.</p>
<p>But remember, money itself is not the goal, but a means to achieve our life goals. We make money not to become slaves to it, but to live better, to realize our own dreams and those of our families, to have the ability to help those in need, and to better serve society.</p>
<p>Only by truly understanding the essence of money can we view it and use it correctly, rather than being enslaved by it.</p>


<h3 class="relative group"><strong>How Can Ordinary People Achieve Financial Freedom? It&rsquo;s Actually Very Simple!</strong> 
    <div id="how-can-ordinary-people-achieve-financial-freedom-it" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#how-can-ordinary-people-achieve-financial-freedom-it" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>Can ordinary people really achieve financial freedom? The answer is: of course they can! Moreover, achieving financial freedom is much simpler than you imagine.</p>
<p>The key to financial freedom is not about having a high IQ, or mastering complex techniques, but rather whether you have the correct investment mindset and whether you can persevere in executing it.</p>
<p>The path to financial freedom for ordinary people is actually very simple: choose the right investment vehicle, hold it for the long term, and let the power of compounding increase your wealth like a snowball. Specifically, it&rsquo;s recommended to invest in the U.S. Nasdaq 100 index fund, a relatively low-risk investment choice with excellent long-term performance. In the long run, its annualized return is considerable.</p>
<p>Many people might say, investing in index funds, isn&rsquo;t that something even an idiot can do? Yes, it&rsquo;s that simple! But the problem is, how many people can truly hold on for the long term?</p>
<p>Financial freedom is not achieved overnight; it requires patience and perseverance. In the course of investing, you will encounter all sorts of challenges and temptations, but as long as you believe in your choice and continue steadfastly, you will surely reach the other shore.</p>


<h3 class="relative group"><strong>Shedding the &ldquo;Poor Mindset&rdquo;: From &ldquo;Impossible&rdquo; to &ldquo;I Can Do It&rdquo;</strong> 
    <div id="shedding-the" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#shedding-the" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>The biggest characteristic of the &ldquo;poor mindset&rdquo; is self-limitation. They habitually limit themselves with &ldquo;impossible,&rdquo; &ldquo;can&rsquo;t do it,&rdquo; and &ldquo;too difficult.&rdquo; They don&rsquo;t see their potential or the hope for the future.</p>
<p>The key to shedding the &ldquo;poor mindset&rdquo; lies in changing your mindset and recognizing your wealth potential and rights. You have to believe that poverty is not your destiny, and that you have the ability to change your fate.</p>
<p>Specifically, you need to learn the right investment knowledge, rather than being led by so-called financial experts or the media. You need to understand that true wealth comes from long-term investment, not short-term speculation or blind consumption. You need to learn to delay gratification, using the money you save for investment, rather than for buying things that are non-essential.</p>
<p>More importantly, you need to cultivate the ability to think independently, not to be swayed by others or blindly follow trends. You need to develop an investment plan suitable for your own circumstances, and then steadfastly execute it.</p>
<p>Finally, you must remember that financial freedom is not something that happens overnight; it requires patience and perseverance, believing in the power of compounding, and adhering to long-term investment.</p>


<h3 class="relative group"><strong>Why Invest? Make Money Work for You, Not You for Money!</strong> 
    <div id="why-invest-make-money-work-for-you-not-you-for-money" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#why-invest-make-money-work-for-you-not-you-for-money" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>Why invest? The answer is simple: to make money work for us, not us for money.</p>
<p>Through investing, we can make our money grow continuously in the capital markets, thus realizing an increase in wealth. This increase can help us withstand inflation, ensure our future quality of life, and ultimately achieve financial freedom, so we no longer have to toil for a living.</p>
<p>Investing is also a way to plan for and secure the future. Through investment, we can accumulate funds for retirement, prepare for our children&rsquo;s education, and create conditions for realizing our dreams. Imagine, when you retire, you don&rsquo;t have to worry about whether your pension is enough, you can travel the world freely, do things you love, what a wonderful life that would be!</p>
<p>In addition, investing is also a way to participate in economic development. By investing in excellent companies, we can share the dividends of their growth, and also create value for society, promoting social progress.</p>


<h3 class="relative group"><strong>Why is it Better to Invest Early? Compounding: The Magic of Time</strong> 
    <div id="why-is-it-better-to-invest-early-compounding-the-magic-of-time" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#why-is-it-better-to-invest-early-compounding-the-magic-of-time" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>Why is it better to start investing early? The answer lies in the word &ldquo;compounding.&rdquo; Compounding, which Einstein called the &ldquo;eighth wonder of the world,&rdquo; is more powerful than you think.</p>
<p>For example, if we calculate with a 12% annual rate of return (a figure that can be achieved over the long term), a 30-year-old who invests $283 per month can accumulate approximately $1 million by the age of 60. But if they started investing at the age of 20, they would only need to invest $85 per month to reach the same goal!</p>
<p>See that? That is the power of compounding! The earlier you start investing, the less principal you need, and the shorter the time it takes to achieve your wealth goals. Because the effect of compounding causes your wealth to grow like a snowball, the longer the time, the faster the growth rate, and the greater the power.</p>
<p>Therefore, even if you don&rsquo;t have much capital right now, as long as you start investing early and stick with it over the long term, you can accumulate a considerable amount of wealth. Time is the best friend of investment.</p>


<h3 class="relative group"><strong>The Misunderstood Bonds and Real Estate: Don&rsquo;t Let Them Steal Your Future</strong> 
    <div id="the-misunderstood-bonds-and-real-estate-don" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#the-misunderstood-bonds-and-real-estate-don" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>Many people think bonds are a stable investment, and some even say they&rsquo;re safer than stocks. Is this really the case?</p>
<p>In the long term, bonds can actually be riskier than stocks. Don&rsquo;t believe it? Let&rsquo;s look at the data. How have different asset classes performed over the past 200 years, from the early 19th century to the early 21st century? The results show that the long-term returns of stocks are far higher than those of bonds, and bonds have sometimes even lost money over periods of 20 or even 30 years!</p>
<p>Why is this the case? Because the yield on bonds is usually low, making it difficult to withstand the erosion of inflation. Moreover, bond prices are affected by interest rate fluctuations and carry some risk. In contrast, although stocks fluctuate more in the short term, they have higher growth potential in the long term.</p>
<p>Let&rsquo;s talk about real estate. Many people believe that buying a house is the most value-preserving investment, and some even consider their house their most important asset. However, have you ever considered whether real estate is really a good investment?</p>
<p>From an investment perspective, the main problems with real estate are its poor liquidity, high maintenance costs, and unremarkable long-term returns. Imagine if someone spent 10 million Taiwan dollars to build a villa 35 years ago, could that villa be worth 30 million Taiwan dollars 35 years later? It’s unlikely. However, if they had invested that 10 million Taiwan dollars in the stock market, based on historical average returns, the current value would have increased by two orders of magnitude, possibly becoming 1 billion Taiwan dollars!</p>
<p>More importantly, real estate also involves complex factors such as location and market fluctuations, all of which can affect its investment returns, and ordinary people find it difficult to control them.</p>
<p>And what if you treat your home as a place to live? Then you&rsquo;ll be burdened with decades of loan payments, and monthly mortgage repayments will weigh you down. For this house, you have to work hard, not dare to quit easily, and not dare to pursue your dreams, you become a complete “house slave.” Isn&rsquo;t that putting the cart before the horse?</p>
<p>Remember, a home to live in is essentially a consumption, not an investment.</p>


<h3 class="relative group"><strong>Investing in the Future of Humanity is Investing in Technological Progress</strong> 
    <div id="investing-in-the-future-of-humanity-is-investing-in-technological-progress" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#investing-in-the-future-of-humanity-is-investing-in-technological-progress" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>Investing in the future of humanity is actually investing in technological progress and social development. Look at our history, from the agricultural age to the industrial age, and then to the information age, each significant social advancement has been accompanied by a leap in technology. This progress has led to tremendous improvements in productivity and an explosive growth in wealth.</p>
<p>Data shows that over the past 200 years, the long-term returns of the stock market have been far higher than those of bonds and gold. This reflects the continuous progress of human technology and productivity.</p>
<p>In the future, human society will continue to move forward, technology will continue to advance, which will bring more investment opportunities and space for wealth growth. By investing in excellent companies that represent the future and the direction of technological development, we can share in the enormous dividends that this growth will bring.</p>


<h3 class="relative group"><strong>Why the U.S.? Because That&rsquo;s Where Innovation Flourishes</strong> 
    <div id="why-the-us-because-that" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#why-the-us-because-that" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>Why should we look to the United States? Because it is a fertile ground for innovation, an environment where great companies are born.</p>
<p>The United States is home to the world&rsquo;s best companies and top scientific talent. These companies are like perpetual motion machines, continuously driving technological progress, creating new products and services, and leading global economic development.</p>
<p>Moreover, the U.S. is highly innovative, and the government usually supports the development of businesses. Furthermore, the U.S. capital markets are relatively mature and transparent, with well-established regulatory mechanisms that protect the rights of investors. This provides a relatively fair and safe investment environment for investors.</p>


<h3 class="relative group"><strong>Why the Nasdaq 100 Index Fund? Share the Dividends of Technology Giant Growth</strong> 
    <div id="why-the-nasdaq-100-index-fund-share-the-dividends-of-technology-giant-growth" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#why-the-nasdaq-100-index-fund-share-the-dividends-of-technology-giant-growth" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>For ordinary people, investing in individual stocks requires specialized knowledge and a lot of effort, and the risks are also relatively high. Is there a simpler, more effective way for us to share in the dividends of U.S. technological development?</p>
<p>The answer is: the Nasdaq 100 index fund.</p>
<p>The Nasdaq 100 index fund includes the 100 largest and most representative non-financial companies listed on the Nasdaq, which include many well-known tech giants such as Apple, Microsoft, and Amazon.</p>
<p>These companies represent the future development direction, the future of technology, with strong innovation capabilities and huge growth potential. By investing in the Nasdaq 100 index fund, we are investing in these excellent tech companies at the same time, sharing in the generous returns from their growth.</p>
<p>Moreover, investing in index funds is very simple, transparent, and relatively low-cost, making it particularly suitable for ordinary investors to hold for the long term. Compared to actively managed funds that require a lot of time and effort for research, index funds often outperform in the long run.</p>
<p>The Nasdaq 100 index fund is more focused on the tech sector compared to other broad market indices, which means it has higher growth potential. If you believe that technology is the core driving force behind future development, then the Nasdaq 100 index fund is an investment choice you cannot afford to miss.</p>


<h3 class="relative group"><strong>A Simple but Not Easy Investment Path: Why, When We Understand the Logic, Do We Still Not Do Well?</strong> 
    <div id="a-simple-but-not-easy-investment-path-why-when-we-understand-the-logic-do-we-still-not-do-well" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#a-simple-but-not-easy-investment-path-why-when-we-understand-the-logic-do-we-still-not-do-well" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>The method of investing in index funds is really simple: choose a good index fund, such as the Nasdaq 100 index fund, and then buy in regularly, holding it for the long term. It&rsquo;s that simple. You don&rsquo;t need a background in finance, nor do you need to monitor the market every day. You can even leave it untouched for years.</p>
<p>But why is it that so few people are actually able to do this simple thing?</p>
<p>First, it requires you to have a long-term perspective and firm conviction. During market fluctuations, especially when the market is down, many people feel panic and anxiety, and even doubt their choice, eventually giving in and selling, and as a result? They often sell at the lowest point, missing out on the rebound that follows.</p>
<p>Second, it requires you to overcome your human weaknesses. In the course of investing, you&rsquo;ll encounter all sorts of temptations: today, this stock has hit its limit up, tomorrow, that concept is hot, the day after tomorrow, experts predict the market will plummet… this noise will interfere with your judgment, leading you to deviate from your original investment plan.</p>
<p>Many people, even those who have learned this simple investment method, still cannot do it well. Some investors are impatient to sell as soon as the market rises slightly, missing out on the big gains that come later; some investors, although they have set a fixed investment plan, are always unable to stick to it, going at it haphazardly; and other investors, because they hold other types of stocks or investments, are unable to make up their minds to switch to index funds.</p>
<p>What does all of this show? It shows that the success of investing depends not only on the method, but also on your mindset, whether you can overcome your human weaknesses, and whether you can steadfastly execute your investment plan.</p>
<p>Investing in index funds requires &ldquo;patience&rdquo; and &ldquo;waiting,&rdquo; the determination to &ldquo;stay the course&rdquo;, which is what most people lack.</p>


<h3 class="relative group"><strong>&ldquo;Pits&rdquo; on the Investment Path: Don&rsquo;t Let These Traps Swallow Your Wealth</strong> 
    <div id="heading" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#heading" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>The path of investment is full of all sorts of &ldquo;pits,&rdquo; and one wrong step can lead to total ruin.</p>
<ol>
<li><strong>The &ldquo;Financial Expert&rdquo; Scam:</strong> Many so-called &ldquo;financial experts&rdquo; are actually just salespeople for financial products. In order to earn commissions, they will recommend various complex financial products to you, such as insurance, bonds, annuities, etc. These products often come with high fees and less-than-ideal long-term returns. Annuity products in particular, are not only low-yielding and high-risk, but also severely impact your asset allocation and tax planning. Remember, truly good investments are often simple, and those complicated products are often traps.</li>
<li><strong>Noise from the Media and &ldquo;Experts&rdquo;:</strong> Many media outlets and so-called &ldquo;investment experts,&rdquo; in order to grab attention, publish all sorts of sensational market predictions. One minute they&rsquo;re saying a bull market is coming, the next a bear market is coming, and the next, that a certain industry is about to explode… This noise severely interferes with your judgment, making you unable to focus on long-term investment. Remember, what really matters is the long-term trend, not the short-term fluctuations.</li>
<li><strong>The Temptation of Short-Term Trading:</strong> Many people dream of getting rich overnight, so they like to buy and sell frequently, trying to capture every market fluctuation. However, short-term trading not only requires you to have superb skills and keen market intuition, but also to bear enormous risks. For ordinary investors, short-term trading is often not worth the effort, and can even lead to serious losses. Frequent trading is like a gambler in a casino, often eventually losing it all.</li>
<li><strong>The Risks of High Leverage:</strong> Some investors, in order to pursue higher returns, use excessive leverage, such as margin accounts. However, leverage is a double-edged sword, it can amplify your returns, but also amplify your losses. If used improperly, it can easily lead to total ruin, and even bankruptcy. Remember, the first priority of investment is to control risk, not to pursue high returns. Never put your fate in the hands of luck, especially not with leveraged fate.</li>
<li><strong>The Risk of Not Learning:</strong> Many people know nothing about investment. They don&rsquo;t understand the essence of investment, nor their own risk tolerance, nor the characteristics of the products they are investing in. Such blind investment is like crossing the road with your eyes closed, full of risks.</li>
</ol>


<h3 class="relative group"><strong>The Wisdom of &ldquo;Buy When You Have Money&rdquo;: Simple, Crude but Effective</strong> 
    <div id="the-wisdom-of" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#the-wisdom-of" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>&ldquo;Buy when you have money.&rdquo; These four words sound very simple, even a bit &ldquo;silly,&rdquo; right? But they are based on a deep understanding and insight into the long-term trends of the market.</p>
<p>We all know that the long-term trend of the market is upwards, driven by economic development and technological progress, and it&rsquo;s an unstoppable historical trend. Although the market will fluctuate in the short term and even fall sharply, these are all temporary. In the long run, the market will always return to the upward trend and continue to reach new highs.</p>
<p>Many people always want to buy at the lowest point and sell at the highest point. But ask yourself, do you really have the ability to do this? Not to mention ordinary investors, how many professional fund managers can actually do it?</p>
<p>Trying to choose the best time to buy is often futile, even foolish, because no one can accurately predict market bottoms and tops. Instead of wasting a lot of time and energy researching market trends, it&rsquo;s better to adopt a &ldquo;buy when you have money&rdquo; strategy, and use that time and energy to work and live life, enjoying life to the fullest.</p>


<h3 class="relative group"><strong>The Determination to &ldquo;Never Sell&rdquo;: The Secret to Enduring Market Cycles</strong> 
    <div id="the-determination-to" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#the-determination-to" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>&ldquo;Never sell,&rdquo; these four words, don&rsquo;t they sound a bit extreme? But they are the secret to enduring market cycles, the essence of long-term investing.</p>
<p>The essence of investing is to share in the growth dividends of excellent companies, not to gamble, in a casino, diving in and out. The logic behind &ldquo;never sell&rdquo; is actually very simple: as long as you are investing in excellent companies, and as long as you believe that these companies can continue to grow, then you should hold them for the long term, sharing in the dividends that their growth brings.</p>
<p>Frequent buying and selling will not only increase your transaction costs, but will also cause you to miss out on the compounding effect of long-term holding. More importantly, it will expose you to human weaknesses.</p>
<p>When the market is falling, you will feel panicked and will want to sell; when the market rises, you will become greedy and will want to chase after the price increases. As a result? You are often buying high and selling low, and are constantly harvested by the market.</p>
<p>The &ldquo;never sell&rdquo; strategy can help you overcome fear and greed, and allow you to always stay in the market, sharing in the dividends of economic growth.</p>


<h3 class="relative group"><strong>Market Downturns: Be Greedy When Others are Fearful</strong> 
    <div id="market-downturns-be-greedy-when-others-are-fearful" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#market-downturns-be-greedy-when-others-are-fearful" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>Market downturns, for many people, are a nightmare, a disaster. But for true investors, they are a once-in-a-lifetime opportunity.</p>
<p>Why is that? Because when the market is down, the stock prices of many high-quality companies will be severely undervalued, like a discounted sale, and buying at this time is like picking up a bargain.</p>
<p>Warren Buffett once famously said, &ldquo;Be fearful when others are greedy, and be greedy when others are fearful.&rdquo; This quote is about this very principle.</p>
<p>Market downturns are temporary, while the market&rsquo;s long-term trend is upward. As long as you can overcome your fear and stick to your long-term investment strategy, you will be able to seize opportunities during market downturns, buy undervalued high-quality assets, and lay a solid foundation for future wealth growth.</p>


<h3 class="relative group"><strong>&ldquo;Stock Pledges&rdquo;: Make Your Assets More Flexible</strong> 
    <div id="heading-1" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#heading-1" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>The strategy of &ldquo;living off stock pledges&rdquo; can help you address your daily capital needs without selling your stock. This is a smarter way to manage finances.</p>
<p>Many people might ask, what is a stock pledge? Simply put, it is using your stock as collateral to borrow money from a financial institution. In this way, you can gain access to liquidity without selling your stock, and you can continue to enjoy the long-term appreciation of your stock.</p>
<p>Through stock pledges, you can avoid being forced to sell stocks with long-term growth potential due to temporary funding shortages. Furthermore, in many countries and regions, the capital gains tax rate is usually higher than the borrowing interest rate. Through stock pledges, you can also reasonably reduce your tax burden.</p>
<p>Of course, stock pledges also carry some risks. If the stock price drops sharply, you may need to provide additional collateral or face the risk of forced liquidation. Therefore, when using stock pledges, you must control your leverage ratio, and it is generally recommended that the pledge ratio not exceed 20% of your total assets.</p>


<h3 class="relative group"><strong>Independent Thinking: Stay Clear-Headed in the Noisy Market</strong> 
    <div id="independent-thinking-stay-clear-headed-in-the-noisy-market" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#independent-thinking-stay-clear-headed-in-the-noisy-market" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>In this age of information overload, we are bombarded daily with all sorts of information, especially in the field of investment. The opinions of various &ldquo;experts,&rdquo; various media reports, and various rumors, are difficult to distinguish between true and false, making people dizzy.</p>
<p>If you don&rsquo;t have the ability to think independently, you can easily be swayed by this information and make wrong investment decisions.</p>
<p>Independent thinking is key to investment success. It means having your own judgment, not blindly following trends, not blindly believing in authority, and not being swayed by market sentiment.</p>
<p>The basis for independent thinking is learning and research. You need to continuously learn investment knowledge, study market laws, and understand the investment target. Only in this way can you form your own investment system and make correct decisions in the complex market environment.</p>
<p>Always remember that investment is your own business, and no one can make decisions for you.</p>
<hr>

<section class="space-y-10 w-full">
    
    
        
            






















  <a class="flex flex-wrap article " href="/en/posts/1728723295012-invest-qqq/">
    
        
        <div class="w-full md:w-auto h-full thumbnail nozoom thumbnailshadow md:mr-7" style="background-image:url(/posts/1728723295012-invest-qqq/featured_hu_6a34f16c918fab99.jpg);"></div>
        
      <div class=" mt-3 md:mt-0">
      <div class="items-center text-left text-xl font-semibold">
        
        <div class="font-bold text-xl text-neutral-800 decoration-primary-500 hover:underline hover:underline-offset-2 dark:text-neutral"
          href="/en/posts/1728723295012-invest-qqq/">How to Invest in NASDAQ 100</div>
        
        
        
      </div>
      <div class="text-sm text-neutral-500 dark:text-neutral-400">
        











  



















<div class="flex flex-row flex-wrap items-center">
  
  
  <time datetime="2024-10-12T00:00:00&#43;00:00">12 October 2024</time>
  

  
  
</div>





<div class="flex flex-row flex-wrap items-center">
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  <span style="margin-top:0.5rem" class="mr-2" onclick="window.open(&#34;/en/tags/investing/&#34;,'_self');">
    <span class="flex" style="cursor: pointer;">
  <span class="rounded-md border border-primary-400 px-1 py-[1px] text-xs font-normal text-primary-700 dark:border-primary-600 dark:text-primary-400">
    Investing
  </span>
</span>
  </span>
  
  <span style="margin-top:0.5rem" class="mr-2" onclick="window.open(&#34;/en/tags/finance/&#34;,'_self');">
    <span class="flex" style="cursor: pointer;">
  <span class="rounded-md border border-primary-400 px-1 py-[1px] text-xs font-normal text-primary-700 dark:border-primary-600 dark:text-primary-400">
    Finance
  </span>
</span>
  </span>
  
  <span style="margin-top:0.5rem" class="mr-2" onclick="window.open(&#34;/en/tags/qqq/&#34;,'_self');">
    <span class="flex" style="cursor: pointer;">
  <span class="rounded-md border border-primary-400 px-1 py-[1px] text-xs font-normal text-primary-700 dark:border-primary-600 dark:text-primary-400">
    QQQ
  </span>
</span>
  </span>
  
  <span style="margin-top:0.5rem" class="mr-2" onclick="window.open(&#34;/en/tags/securities/&#34;,'_self');">
    <span class="flex" style="cursor: pointer;">
  <span class="rounded-md border border-primary-400 px-1 py-[1px] text-xs font-normal text-primary-700 dark:border-primary-600 dark:text-primary-400">
    Securities
  </span>
</span>
  </span>
  
  <span style="margin-top:0.5rem" class="mr-2" onclick="window.open(&#34;/en/tags/account-opening/&#34;,'_self');">
    <span class="flex" style="cursor: pointer;">
  <span class="rounded-md border border-primary-400 px-1 py-[1px] text-xs font-normal text-primary-700 dark:border-primary-600 dark:text-primary-400">
    Account Opening
  </span>
</span>
  </span>
  
  <span style="margin-top:0.5rem" class="mr-2" onclick="window.open(&#34;/en/tags/nasdaq-100/&#34;,'_self');">
    <span class="flex" style="cursor: pointer;">
  <span class="rounded-md border border-primary-400 px-1 py-[1px] text-xs font-normal text-primary-700 dark:border-primary-600 dark:text-primary-400">
    Nasdaq 100
  </span>
</span>
  </span>
  
  
  
  
</div>




      </div>
      
    </div>
  </a>

        
    
</section>
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>00493 Financial Risks and Investment Wisdom: How to Accumulate and Utilize Assets; Stock Pledge and Asset Allocation: Smart Choices for Risk Reduction</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1733026874385/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1733026874385/</guid><description>In this episode, James reiterates the current market highs and advises investors to remain patient, adhere to long-term investment strategies, and avoid being swayed by short-term fluctuations. He also addresses questions from students regarding asset allocation, stock pledging, insurance, annuities, children&amp;#39;s education, and how to cope with market volatility, sharing his understanding of Modern Monetary Theory (MMT).</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<lite-youtube videoid="V0d8y8-Jl-w" playlabel="V0d8y8-Jl-w" params=""></lite-youtube>



<h2 class="relative group">I. Main Topic 
    <div id="i-main-topic" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-main-topic" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>The market continues to reach new highs.  Investing doesn&rsquo;t require constant attention; the key is to stick to a long-term investment strategy, maintain a well-diversified asset allocation, and remain patient. The real risk isn&rsquo;t short-term volatility, but the inability to accumulate sufficient wealth over the long term, and not knowing how to utilize accumulated wealth effectively.  Furthermore, it&rsquo;s crucial to be wary of various financial traps and maintain rational investment practices.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">II. Briefing Content 
    <div id="ii-briefing-content" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii-briefing-content" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Market Trends and Investment Strategies 
    <div id="market-trends-and-investment-strategies" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#market-trends-and-investment-strategies" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>The market is at a new high. Don&rsquo;t waste time over-analyzing; stick to long-term investing, buy and hold.  The market generally trends upwards; instead of predicting pullbacks, enter the market early.</li>
<li>Investing doesn&rsquo;t require excessive time. After placing your order, step away and let time work its magic through compounding.</li>
<li>Be wary of scams. Don&rsquo;t trust any investment advice that guarantees stable returns or daily gains.  Be extremely cautious of &ldquo;guaranteed profit&rdquo; schemes.</li>
<li>Ignore the advice of financial advisors and insurance agents. They rarely have the investor&rsquo;s best interests at heart and are often motivated by their own profits. Many financial products are designed to benefit the seller, not the investor.</li>
<li>Investing isn&rsquo;t simple. Even asset allocation within a Nasdaq 100 index fund requires in-depth research and adjustments based on individual circumstances.</li>
<li>Investors should always remain optimistic. The market will eventually rise. Patiently await wealth accumulation. Time is an investor&rsquo;s friend.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Risk Management and Wealth Goals 
    <div id="risk-management-and-wealth-goals" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#risk-management-and-wealth-goals" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>The biggest risks are not market fluctuations, but the failure to accumulate sufficient wealth over the long term and not knowing how to utilize accumulated wealth effectively. The ultimate goal of investing is to achieve financial freedom and enjoy life.</li>
<li>Avoid the instinctive reaction to short-term losses. Overcome fear and don&rsquo;t panic sell. Market downturns are normal and present buying opportunities.</li>
<li>View bear markets as opportunities. Buying low translates to higher future returns. Learn to think contrarily and utilize market fluctuations for mindless rebalancing.</li>
<li>The investment objective is to mitigate the risk of financial hardship, not to maximize returns. A sound investment strategy is more crucial than chasing high returns.</li>
<li>Choose a simple, low-cost, passive index investment strategy, such as a Nasdaq 100 index fund, and hold a portion in cash to maintain psychological balance and cope with market volatility.</li>
<li>Holding safe assets (like certificates of deposit and money market funds) can mitigate short-term risks, stabilize emotions during market fluctuations, and provide a sense of security.</li>
<li>The proportion of safe assets held should be adjusted based on age and risk tolerance. Retirees are advised to hold cash equivalent to 5 years of living expenses, while those yet to retire can hold more.</li>
<li>Young people should prioritize term life insurance to protect their families and avoid other types of insurance to prevent being misled by insurance companies.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Other Advice 
    <div id="other-advice" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#other-advice" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Be skeptical of all information, especially regarding money. Learn to think independently and don&rsquo;t blindly trust so-called &ldquo;experts.&rdquo;</li>
<li>Don&rsquo;t buy insurance or annuities for investment purposes. The essence of insurance is protection, not investment; annuities have high fees and low returns.</li>
<li>Don&rsquo;t disclose your wealth to your children. Encourage them to strive independently and create wealth through their own abilities.</li>
<li>Engage in rational discussions, view investments with a mathematical mindset, and analyze investment results with data.</li>
<li>Avoid over-investing in real estate. Maintain ample cash flow. Real estate has poor liquidity and is difficult to liquidate.</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">III. Q&amp;A Session 
    <div id="iii-qa-session" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii-qa-session" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Ke An 
    <div id="ke-an" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ke-an" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: 16 years old, living in the Netherlands.  Thanked James for his investment methods, which allowed her parents to take her on trips throughout Europe. She also shared that she finds her business management classes easier to understand than her classmates, thanks to James&rsquo;s teachings.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s comments: Praised Ke An&rsquo;s travel experiences and learning attitude, encouraging her to continue learning and explore her career interests.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question: Concerned about starting investing late, wants to open an account and start investing soon. Has saved NT$200,000 and plans to invest in 00662.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s reply: Affirmed the advantage of starting to invest at 16, emphasizing that time is the greatest asset.  Advised her to balance learning, life, and investment, and to enjoy her youth.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Ji Ya 
    <div id="ji-ya" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ji-ya" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question: Has savings equivalent to 8 years of living expenses. Working 40 hours a week only covers expenses. Driving for Uber could increase income but wants more free time. Unsure how to balance work and life and whether early retirement is possible. Is currently 42 years old.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s reply: In 15 years, the 8x annual expenses will grow to 50x due to compounding, enabling retirement. Suggested a BETA of 1.2 to increase investment returns, or driving for Uber a few hours a week to accelerate wealth accumulation and achieve early retirement.  Emphasized that pursuing early retirement shouldn&rsquo;t be the sole focus and that finding a balance between work and life is important. Health is paramount.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chun Xia 
    <div id="chun-xia" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chun-xia" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question 1: Plans to invest a loan of NT$7 million and aims for a return of NT$20-30 million within 10-15 years. Should the investment be lump-sum or staggered?  Has additional monthly income of NT$30,000-40,000.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s reply: Based on a 14% annualized return, there will be NT$67 million after 15 years, reaching the NT$20-30 million target within 10 years. Recommended a lump-sum investment to capitalize on market growth.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2: Wants to share investment philosophy with family in China.  Inquired about account opening procedures and trading software options in China.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s reply: Suggested Chun Xia email him for an introduction to a leader familiar with the Chinese market who can provide specific guidance on account opening and software selection.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Peter 
    <div id="peter" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#peter" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question: How to persuade family members to invest? They&rsquo;ve heard the advice but haven&rsquo;t acted, finding it difficult.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s reply: Acknowledged the &ldquo;familiarity bias&rdquo; that makes it difficult for family members to accept advice. Suggested Peter lead by example, sharing his investment philosophy and success stories. Encourage them to start with a small investment, like $100,000 in QQQ, and offer to cover any losses to build their confidence. He particularly recommended starting with retirement accounts and broad market index funds.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Ling 
    <div id="ling" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ling" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question:  Regarding children&rsquo;s education fund investment plan. Initially planned to invest all children&rsquo;s allowances in 00662 with monthly contributions, but has doubts after hearing James&rsquo;s lessons on children&rsquo;s education.  Should the plan be adjusted?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s reply: Advised prioritizing personal wealth accumulation and achieving financial freedom before focusing on children&rsquo;s education funds. Suggested redirecting the monthly contributions to personal investments to accelerate wealth growth.  Income like Lunar New Year red envelopes can continue to be invested for the children.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Dennis 
    <div id="dennis" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#dennis" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing 1: An insurance agent passed away due to financial problems, highlighting the importance of risk management, even for insurance professionals.</li>
<li>Sharing 2: Family recommended a video by an MIT professor about national debt, who argued that national debt is another form of taxation.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s reply: Explained Modern Monetary Theory (MMT).  U.S. national debt represents savings held by the public. The U.S. government&rsquo;s debt is repaid by Americans. The value of the dollar lies in its credit and the goods and services it can buy, not the level of debt. The government can stimulate the economy by issuing national debt without worrying about excessive debt.  Issuing national debt and lottery tickets are essentially providing investment channels, not just taxation.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Sharing 3: Wants to learn more about MMT.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s reply: Recommended Dennis search for books and materials on &ldquo;Modern Monetary Theory&rdquo; for a deeper understanding of its principles and applications.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Hao Xin 
    <div id="hao-xin" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#hao-xin" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question:  Are the P/E ratios of QQQ and SPY overvalued? How to deal with market fluctuations? Concerned that a prolonged stagnant market will cause borrowing interest to exceed cash reserves.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s reply: P/E ratios are unreliable and unpredictable. Recommended passive rebalancing.  Cash reserves will increase as the market rises; reinvest during downturns. Suggested simulating the 2000-2009 market scenario to test the robustness of the asset allocation strategy. If the market does stagnate for a long time, adjust lifestyle, reduce expenses, or consider other income sources. In the long run, the market will always go up; maintain confidence.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Sharing: Received a suspected scam call where the caller claimed to be from the bank and requested personal information verification.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s comments:  Commended Hao Xin&rsquo;s vigilance and reminded everyone to be cautious of calls requesting personal information to avoid being scammed.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">IV. Key Takeaways 
    <div id="iv-key-takeaways" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv-key-takeaways" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;The first investment earns the most; that performance can never be replicated.&rdquo;
&ndash; Monica</p></blockquote>
<p>Monica&rsquo;s statement highlights the importance of early investment and the difficulty of timing the market. Early investments enjoy higher returns, and over time, even with the same investment strategy, it&rsquo;s hard to replicate those early gains.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;The U.S. government&rsquo;s debt is the public&rsquo;s savings.&rdquo;
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>This perspective challenges the traditional understanding of national debt, emphasizing the unique nature of U.S. Treasury bonds.  U.S. national debt represents dollar-denominated assets held by U.S. citizens and global investors, reflecting confidence in the American economy.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;Survival is key, not maximizing returns.&rdquo;
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>This statement pinpoints the core goal of investing, reminding investors not to be tempted by high returns at the expense of risk management. Preserving capital is more important than chasing high returns during market fluctuations.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;Time is an investor&rsquo;s friend.&rdquo;
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>Only long-term investments can fully benefit from the power of compounding. Time is an investor&rsquo;s best ally.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">V. Summary 
    <div id="v-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#v-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>In this episode, James once again emphasized the importance of long-term investing and risk management, offering personalized advice tailored to each student&rsquo;s circumstances. His clear explanations helped students better understand market trends, investment strategies, and the essence of wealth management. He also shared his understanding of Modern Monetary Theory (MMT) and awareness of various financial traps, reminding investors to remain rational and avoid blindly chasing high returns.</p>

  



<div
  
    class="flex px-4 py-3 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900"
  >

  <span
    
      class="text-primary-400 ltr:pr-3 rtl:pl-3 flex items-center"
    >

    

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M506.3 417l-213.3-364c-16.33-28-57.54-28-73.98 0l-213.2 364C-10.59 444.9 9.849 480 42.74 480h426.6C502.1 480 522.6 445 506.3 417zM232 168c0-13.25 10.75-24 24-24S280 154.8 280 168v128c0 13.25-10.75 24-23.1 24S232 309.3 232 296V168zM256 416c-17.36 0-31.44-14.08-31.44-31.44c0-17.36 14.07-31.44 31.44-31.44s31.44 14.08 31.44 31.44C287.4 401.9 273.4 416 256 416z"/></svg>

  </span>


  </span>

  <span
    
      class="dark:text-neutral-300"
    ><strong>Disclaimer:</strong> This article is for personal learning notes only and does not constitute any investment advice.</span>
</div>

]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>00480 Is investing in Index Fund guaranteed to be profitable? How can one consistently make profits in the market?</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1728203545381/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1728203545381/</guid><description>This session focuses on investment cycles, covering how to identify market cycles, emphasizing the challenge of differentiating between premature and incorrect judgments, and illustrating with Buffett&amp;#39;s actions during the 2008 financial crisis. It also touches upon risks associated with real estate investment, insurance choices, stock pledges, and asset allocation strategies, particularly comparing and offering advice for the Taiwanese and US markets. In the Q&amp;amp;A section, students raised questions and shared insights on topics such as the aircraft carrier investment strategy, property tax, central bank policy, currency devaluation, and James addressed each one in detail.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Part 1:
<lite-youtube videoid="ztdWeAncmqY" playlabel="ztdWeAncmqY" params=""></lite-youtube>
</li>
<li>Part 2:
<lite-youtube videoid="Xvv1cCV3dHA" playlabel="Xvv1cCV3dHA" params=""></lite-youtube>
</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">I. Main Topic 
    <div id="i-main-topic" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-main-topic" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This session centered around investment cycles, exploring how to assess market cycles, highlighting the difficulty in distinguishing between acting too early and making wrong judgments during cycle shifts. It used Buffett&rsquo;s actions during the 2008 financial crisis as a case study. Additionally, it discussed risks related to real estate investment, insurance, and stock pledges, while providing an in-depth analysis of asset allocation strategies, particularly comparing and recommending approaches for the Taiwanese and US markets.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">II.  Briefing Content 
    <div id="ii--briefing-content" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii--briefing-content" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<ol>
<li>
<p><strong>Investment Cycles</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Investor sentiment is likened to a pendulum, swinging between extreme fear and extreme optimism.</li>
<li>Differentiating between premature judgments and incorrect ones during cycle changes is challenging, as exemplified by Buffett&rsquo;s public announcement of buying stocks in late 2008, followed by a further 30% market decline.</li>
<li>Swing trading is no longer recommended, as the market perpetually rises, making long-term investment the key.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Risks of Real Estate Investment</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Real estate investment is considered high-risk, requiring maintenance and incurring high holding costs like property taxes and HOA fees.</li>
<li>US property tax is a holding tax; the longer you hold, the more tax you pay.</li>
<li>Rental yields are low, around 2% in the US Bay Area after deducting expenses.</li>
<li>The biggest risks of buying a house are job loss and having outstanding mortgage debt at retirement.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Insurance Choices</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Avoid commercial insurance, such as life insurance, long-term care insurance, universal life insurance, etc.</li>
<li>Necessary insurance includes health insurance and term life insurance. Term life insurance is suitable for those who are the sole income source for their family, providing support for children under 18.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Risks of Stock Pledging</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Stock pledging is extremely risky, especially in the Taiwanese market, with a maintenance ratio requirement of 167%.</li>
<li>Absolutely forbid using borrowed funds from stock pledges for reinvestment.</li>
<li>In Taiwan, leveraged ETFs can be pledged, but risks still exist.</li>
<li>Be cautious about diversifying risks in stock pledging in Taiwan. Do not pledge all assets to the same financial institution, and avoid pledging everything at once.</li>
<li>Taiwanese investors are advised to adopt the &ldquo;Situation 3&rdquo; asset allocation strategy: 30% cash, 30% leverage, and 40% QQQ or other broad-based index funds.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Asset Allocation Strategies</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>When selecting investment targets, understand their risk and return characteristics, and allocate assets reasonably based on your circumstances.</li>
<li>Long-term investment in QQQ index funds is like piloting an aircraft carrier—stable and offering considerable returns.</li>
<li>Investing in individual stocks and sectors is like sailing a small boat—high risk and susceptible to market fluctuations.</li>
<li>Investments in individual stocks and sectors are similar to the once-booming railway industry, which was eventually replaced by new technologies and industries. For example, the semiconductor industry may also be eliminated in the future.</li>
<li>QQQ index funds have a replacement mechanism to promptly remove underperforming stocks, maintaining overall growth momentum.</li>
<li>Investing in individual stocks requires the ability to identify potential opportunities and understand market and industry trends, as exemplified by James&rsquo; interaction with NVIDIA&rsquo;s CEO before its IPO and his purchase of Amazon shares during its slump.</li>
<li>For retirement accounts, it&rsquo;s recommended to invest all Rust account funds in leveraged ETFs, while 401K accounts can hold cash or bonds.</li>
<li>Be cautious when borrowing for investment; ensure cash flow can cover interest payments and manage risks effectively.</li>
<li>In the US, if capital gains tax is implemented, consider transferring funds to other countries.</li>
<li>Avoid investing in the Chinese market due to policy risks and economic downturn pressures.</li>
<li>Do not purchase annuity products; they offer low returns and carry risks.</li>
<li>After selling a house, do not deposit funds into IRA or traditional IRA accounts.</li>
<li>Be decisive in investing and avoid hesitation. For example, loss-making properties should be sold as soon as possible, and the funds should be invested in the stock market.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ol>


<h2 class="relative group">III. Q&amp;A Session 
    <div id="iii-qa-session" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii-qa-session" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p><strong>Eric:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing:</strong>  Used the analogy of QQQ index funds being like aircraft carriers and individual stocks being like small boats to illustrate the advantages of index fund investing.</li>
<li><strong>Sharing:</strong>  James&rsquo; channel not only shares investment knowledge but also many life stories, such as estate planning and tax planning, from which valuable lessons can be learned.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Brian:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Question:</strong>  For employed individuals using the &ldquo;Situation 2&rdquo; asset allocation strategy, is it possible to set a higher Beta value, such as 1.1 or 1.2?</li>
<li><strong>Answer:</strong>  There is no upper limit for Beta, as long as cash is at least twice the amount of borrowed funds. Excel spreadsheets can be used to simulate investment outcomes under different scenarios, allowing adjustments based on individual risk tolerance.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Mike:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing:</strong> The US is like a Bogue bird, adept at concealing its strength and waiting for the opportune moment to reap the rewards, which aligns with the long-term investment philosophy.</li>
<li><strong>Question:</strong>  Will the central bank ignore economic recession and focus solely on inflation?</li>
<li><strong>Answer:</strong>  The central bank will not ignore economic recession because it leads to increased unemployment, which is one of the central bank&rsquo;s key concerns. Economic recession and unemployment are closely related.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Cheng Ge (PC):</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing:</strong>  Illustrated the drawbacks of investment-linked insurance policies through a real-life case study, recommending early surrender and transferring funds to QQQ index funds to recoup losses within a shorter timeframe and achieve higher returns.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Lang:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Question:</strong>  Is it feasible to utilize market downturns to buy QLD leveraged ETFs using a Roth IRA account and convert a 401K account to cash, aiming to increase the proportion of funds in the Roth IRA account?</li>
<li><strong>Answer:</strong>  If Rust account funds are limited, they should all be invested in leveraged ETFs. The 401K account can hold cash as a hedge. There&rsquo;s no need to wait for market downturns to make the switch; asset allocation should be completed as early as possible.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Tina:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Question:</strong>  If the 401K account is already maxed out, is it still possible to invest in an IRA account?</li>
<li><strong>Answer:</strong> After maxing out the 401K account, you cannot contribute to a traditional IRA account, but you can contribute to a Roth IRA account. Specific eligibility depends on income level and IRA contribution limits. It&rsquo;s recommended to check the IRA contribution limit for relevant information.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>IAM:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Question:</strong>  Will events like the Malaysian currency devaluation and the Hong Kong emigration wave impact the US economy and the US dollar? How does the US prevent currency devaluation? Will the companies in the QQQ index fund be affected?</li>
<li><strong>Answer:</strong> A country&rsquo;s currency value depends on its creditworthiness, which is backed by national industries and power. The US possesses strong national strength and diversified industries, allowing the US dollar to maintain its strong position. The US government will safeguard the interests of American companies and citizens. It&rsquo;s uncertain whether US companies will be directly affected by US dollar devaluation, but they will undoubtedly be protected by the US government.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>TT:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Question:</strong>  Are you still considering cycle investing at present?</li>
<li><strong>Answer:</strong>  Yes, cycle investing will be considered, but not through the all-in, all-out approach used in the past. Instead, Beta adjustments will be employed to navigate market volatility, as it&rsquo;s difficult for a large number of investors to keep up with rapid trading, thus requiring a more robust strategy.</li>
<li><strong>Question:</strong>  Which US political party, Democrat or Republican, is more favorable to investors?</li>
<li><strong>Answer:</strong>  In the long run, policies of both parties have minimal impact on investors. The market adjusts according to policies; for example, higher tax rates may induce investors to hold assets for longer periods.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>YJ:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Question:</strong> Are there any differences in asset allocation strategies between Taiwan and the US? What is the role of the 00864B bond? Why is investing in 00757 no longer recommended?</li>
<li><strong>Answer:</strong> Asset allocation strategies are universally applicable. The main differences between Taiwan and the US lie in stock pledging rules and leveraged ETF choices. 00864B can be used as a cash alternative, similar to a USD fixed deposit. Reasons for no longer recommending investment in 00757 can be found in the videos from 2021 and 2022.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Jason:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Question:</strong> Can dollar-cost averaging (DCA) be used to invest in leveraged ETFs like Q2D?</li>
<li><strong>Answer:</strong> When investing in any asset, including leveraged ETFs, lump-sum purchasing should be adopted instead of DCA. Returns from DCA are likely to be lower than lump-sum purchasing.</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">IV. Key Takeaways 
    <div id="iv-key-takeaways" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv-key-takeaways" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>QQQ index funds are like aircraft carriers, offering stability and substantial returns, while individual stock and sector investments are like sailing small boats, carrying high risk and vulnerability to market fluctuations.
&ndash; James &amp; Eric</p></blockquote>
<p>Choosing long-term investment in QQQ index funds can mitigate the risks associated with individual stocks and sector investments, providing more stable returns.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The central bank will not disregard economic recession, as it leads to rising unemployment, a key indicator that the central bank monitors.
&ndash;  James</p></blockquote>
<p>One of the objectives of the central bank&rsquo;s monetary policy is to maintain low unemployment; therefore, it will not stand idly by in the face of economic recession.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Loss aversion is a common mistake among investors. Losses should be cut promptly, and funds should be reallocated to higher-quality assets.
&ndash; Cheng Ge (PC)</p></blockquote>
<p>It&rsquo;s crucial to overcome the psychological barrier of loss aversion in investing, decisively cutting losses to prevent them from escalating.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The US&rsquo;s national strength rests on four pillars: government, the financial industry, businesses, and national defense. These four pillars work in synergy to achieve strategic goals.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>America&rsquo;s robust, comprehensive national strength is the cornerstone of the US dollar&rsquo;s strong position.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>In the long term, policies of both US parties have a limited impact on investors; the market adjusts itself based on policies.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>The market has a self-regulating mechanism, enabling it to adapt to various policy environments.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>When investing in any asset, including leveraged ETFs, lump-sum purchasing should be adopted instead of dollar-cost averaging (DCA). Returns from DCA are likely to be lower than lump-sum purchasing.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;Buy whenever you have money&rdquo; is the investment strategy James consistently emphasizes. DCA is less efficient for long-term investment.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">V. Summary 
    <div id="v-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#v-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This session primarily revolved around investment cycles, with James explaining how to identify market cycles and emphasizing the distinction between premature and incorrect judgments, using Buffett&rsquo;s actions during the 2008 financial crisis as an example. Furthermore, it provided detailed insights into the risks of real estate investment, insurance selection, stock pledging, and asset allocation strategies. In the Q&amp;A segment, students raised questions and shared their perspectives on topics such as the aircraft carrier investment strategy, property tax, central bank policy, currency devaluation, and investment strategy in the Taiwanese market. James offered comprehensive answers to each question and reiterated the importance of long-term investment in QQQ index funds, along with the &ldquo;buy whenever you have money&rdquo; investment strategy.</p>

  



<div
  
    class="flex px-4 py-3 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900"
  >

  <span
    
      class="text-primary-400 ltr:pr-3 rtl:pl-3 flex items-center"
    >

    

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M506.3 417l-213.3-364c-16.33-28-57.54-28-73.98 0l-213.2 364C-10.59 444.9 9.849 480 42.74 480h426.6C502.1 480 522.6 445 506.3 417zM232 168c0-13.25 10.75-24 24-24S280 154.8 280 168v128c0 13.25-10.75 24-23.1 24S232 309.3 232 296V168zM256 416c-17.36 0-31.44-14.08-31.44-31.44c0-17.36 14.07-31.44 31.44-31.44s31.44 14.08 31.44 31.44C287.4 401.9 273.4 416 256 416z"/></svg>

  </span>


  </span>

  <span
    
      class="dark:text-neutral-300"
    ><strong>Disclaimer:</strong> This document is for personal learning and note-taking purposes only and does not constitute any investment advice.</span>
</div>

]]></content:encoded></item></channel></rss>