<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>QQQ on QQQ Investor</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/tags/qqq/</link><description>Recent content in QQQ on QQQ Investor</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jomonylw.github.io/en/tags/qqq/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>00487 The Truth About Investing：Maximizing the Probability of Success, Not Returns; How to Navigate Market Volatility：Strategies to Avoid Interrupting Compound Growth</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1728777529388/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1728777529388/</guid><description>James announces the discontinuation of short video updates, with content to be condensed into a Saturday briefing format. This session emphasizes the importance of risk control and how to maximize the success probability of an investment portfolio. James addresses audience questions on stock pledging, asset allocation, individual stock investments, and reiterates warnings about pump-and-dump schemes and scams. He also shares insights on market volatility, A-share market fluctuations, and investment psychology.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<lite-youtube videoid="ThLEX-IsszE" playlabel="ThLEX-IsszE" params=""></lite-youtube>



<h2 class="relative group">I. Main Topic 
    <div id="i-main-topic" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-main-topic" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>The most important thing in investing is <strong>maximizing the probability of success</strong>, not maximizing returns. Investors should <strong>control risks</strong>, <strong>avoid being forced to interrupt compounding due to market fluctuations</strong>, and choose investment portfolios that can be <strong>held for the long term</strong>. James emphasizes the importance of asset allocation, especially the role of cash, and the need to choose appropriate investment strategies based on different individuals (retired/not retired, different asset sizes).</p>


<h2 class="relative group">II. Briefing Content 
    <div id="ii-briefing-content" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii-briefing-content" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<ol>
<li><strong>The Most Important Thing in Investing:</strong>
<ul>
<li>The goal of investing is to maximize the probability of success, not to maximize the rate of return.</li>
<li>Risk management is to maximize the success of the investment portfolio and avoid interrupting compound growth due to being forced to sell because of market fluctuations.</li>
<li>Good investment assets must be able to withstand fear and panic. The best investment strategies are those that do not create fear and panic.</li>
<li>Sufficient cash is the best asset to help you sleep well and survive a sharp market decline.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Risks of Stock Pledging:</strong>
<ul>
<li>Stock pledging can easily lead to bankruptcy if asset allocation is not done properly.</li>
<li>Do not try stock pledging lightly if you do not understand the operating principles of stock pledging, otherwise, you will most likely go bankrupt.</li>
<li>Most people do not need to do stock pledging. Good asset allocation can make you rich without pledging.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Asset Allocation for Different Individuals:</strong>
<ul>
<li><strong>Individuals who are not retired and have salary income:</strong> Refer to the article &ldquo;Asset Allocation for Those Who Are Still Some Time Away from Retirement&rdquo;, with QQQ as the main investment.</li>
<li><strong>Individuals who are retired and have no income:</strong> Refer to the article &ldquo;Asset Allocation for Those Who Are Retired and Have No Income&rdquo;, and choose QQQ, SPY, or high-dividend ETFs for allocation based on asset size, and consider the withdrawal rate.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Investment and Life Philosophy:</strong>
<ul>
<li>Investing is like life. It requires continuous learning and experiencing different stages to find an investment strategy that suits you.</li>
<li>Resist temptation, avoid chasing short-term hotspots, and adhere to long-term investment.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>A-share Market Volatility:</strong>
<ul>
<li>The A-share market has recently experienced a surge and a plunge, with many investors being trapped due to chasing hotspots.</li>
<li>Market fluctuations are normal, especially in emerging markets. Investors need to be rational and adhere to long-term investment strategies.</li>
<li>The Chinese government&rsquo;s cooling measures are aimed at preventing further expansion of the bubble and protecting the interests of investors.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Beware of Pump and Dump Schemes:</strong>
<ul>
<li>Some online groups and &ldquo;teachers&rdquo; use market forecasts and insider information to induce investors to make trades and profit from them. Be wary of these pump and dump schemes.</li>
<li>The futures market, due to its smaller scale, is more susceptible to manipulation. Be wary of pump and dump schemes in the futures market as well.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>CLEC Investment and Financial Management Channel Update Plan:</strong>
<ul>
<li>Due to the time-consuming nature of producing short videos and the low viewership, we plan to stop updating short videos.</li>
<li>The content of the produced short videos will be condensed into a briefing format and shared with you on Saturdays for discussion.</li>
<li>It is recommended that you listen to long videos several times or listen to them in segments to achieve the same learning effect.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ol>


<h2 class="relative group">III. Q&amp;A Session 
    <div id="iii-qa-session" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii-qa-session" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p><strong>Ethan:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing:</strong> In China, a similar effect to stock pledging can be achieved through the margin financing function of securities firms.</li>
<li><strong>Sharing:</strong> The A-share market has recently experienced drastic fluctuations, and many investors have been influenced by the media to chase hotspots, resulting in heavy losses.</li>
<li><strong>Viewpoint:</strong> If you don&rsquo;t have the right understanding of the stock market, you are the victim.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Jackie:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing:</strong>  Her personal journey of investing in the Nasdaq, from skepticism to firm holding, and finally overcoming psychological barriers to achieve &ldquo;buy whenever you have money&rdquo;.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>H:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing:</strong>  Followed recommendations for meme stocks in 2021, resulting in heavy losses. Started gradually transferring funds to QQQ in 2023 and using leverage.</li>
<li><strong>Question:</strong>  The current proportions of QQQ, QLD, and SGOV have deviated from the initial 70%, 20%, and 10%. Is rebalancing needed? How should it be rebalanced?</li>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Reply:</strong>  It is recommended to adopt a smart rebalancing strategy. Transfer 30% of the QLD profits to SGOV. When the market falls, transfer 2% of the total assets in cash to QLD.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Im:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing:</strong>  Uses the mural story of Journey to the West as an analogy for the different stages of investment, reminding investors not to chase short-term gains and to adhere to long-term investment and continuous learning.</li>
<li><strong>Question:</strong>  How to persuade people who spend extravagantly to develop the habit of saving?</li>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Reply:</strong>  You can introduce them to the concept of long-term investment in index funds and the power of compound growth. Provide help within your means.</li>
<li><strong>Question:</strong>  If you also have the habit of spending extravagantly, how do you control it?</li>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Reply:</strong>  Live within your means. As your wealth grows, it is normal for your living standards to gradually improve within the scope of risk control, but avoid excessive consumption and spending beyond your means.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Sunny:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing:</strong>  The CLEC course not only teaches investment knowledge but also conveys life philosophy, helping everyone maintain a stable mindset in life and work.</li>
<li><strong>Viewpoint:</strong>  People with stable emotions are the most valuable. Investing in QQQ also brings peace of mind.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Beisen:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Background:</strong>  Assets of 70 million, monthly mortgage payment of 125,000.</li>
<li><strong>Question:</strong>  How to allocate assets to achieve early retirement?</li>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Reply:</strong>  Based on the current assets and expenses, immediate retirement is not possible. It is recommended to try the SPY asset allocation strategy, or use part of the funds to invest in high-dividend ETFs, and control the withdrawal rate.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Kevin:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Question:</strong>  Why has Tesla fallen so much?</li>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Reply:</strong>  Investing in individual stocks requires understanding the company better than the CEO to grasp the ups and downs of the stock price. If you don&rsquo;t understand Tesla&rsquo;s business model, you shouldn&rsquo;t invest in it.</li>
<li><strong>Question:</strong>  If you are very confident in Tesla, can you hold it for the long term?</li>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Reply:</strong>  If you truly understand and are optimistic about Tesla, you can hold it for the long term, but you must manage risks well.</li>
<li><strong>Question:</strong>  Does the teacher think the stock market will fall to zero?</li>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Reply:</strong>  &ldquo;Falling to zero&rdquo; is a figure of speech, which means that even if the stock does not completely fall to zero, it will not be able to be realized if it falls to a certain level, and cash is needed to maintain life.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Ming:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing:</strong>  I have invested in individual stocks before, and they all ended up going to zero in the end, so now I want to learn how to invest in index ETFs.</li>
<li><strong>Background:</strong>  Total assets of 3.3 million, of which 2 million are in a brokerage account, 300,000 are in a Roth account, and 1 million are in a traditional IRA account.  About to retire.</li>
<li><strong>Question:</strong>  How to allocate cash and index ETFs?</li>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Reply:</strong>  It is recommended to fully invest the brokerage account in SPY, the Roth account in TQQQ, and 60% of the traditional IRA account in money market funds and 40% in SPY.</li>
<li><strong>Question:</strong>  How to withdraw funds after retirement? Do you sell even in a loss state?</li>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Reply:</strong>  After retirement, you can withdraw 3% of your total assets for living expenses. You can sell SPY or obtain funds through stock pledging loans. You have to sell even in a loss state because you need cash to maintain your life.</li>
<li><strong>Question:</strong>  Is the risk of investing in TQQQ in a Roth account too high?</li>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Reply:</strong>  It is to maintain a certain cash ratio while obtaining relatively high returns. In extreme cases, you can transfer cash from the traditional IRA to the brokerage account or sell TQQQ to supplement cash.</li>
<li><strong>Question:</strong>  How to transfer funds from a traditional IRA to a Roth account?</li>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Reply:</strong>  Transfer out a portion of the money every year and use loans or salary to pay taxes.</li>
<li><strong>Question:</strong>  Why is the borrowing interest rate 5% and the cash interest rate only 2.5% when calculating interest in SPACE?</li>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Reply:</strong>  This is just a conservative estimate. The yield of money market funds is usually lower than the borrowing interest rate.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Sara:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing:</strong>  I have been investing in QQQ for three years and recently also invested in meme stocks.</li>
<li><strong>Question:</strong>  I plan to borrow money to invest. Should I buy QLD? How should cash be allocated?</li>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Reply:</strong>  Based on Sara&rsquo;s questions, it can be seen that she does not understand the concepts of stock pledging, leveraged ETFs, and asset allocation. Borrowing money to invest is not recommended. It is recommended to continue holding the 80% QQQ + 20% cash portfolio, and cash can be invested in BOXS.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Tom:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Question:</strong>  How to maintain the cash ratio and avoid excessive tax rates in the case of long-term borrowing to live?</li>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Reply:</strong>
<ul>
<li>Leveraged ETFs and cash should be placed in retirement accounts as much as possible.</li>
<li>Borrowing from a brokerage account should not exceed 70% of the account assets.</li>
<li>Invest Roth IRA in TQQQ and hold cash in a traditional IRA.</li>
<li>In extreme cases, the cash in the traditional IRA can be transferred to the brokerage account or TQQQ can be sold to supplement cash.</li>
<li>The borrowing amount should be controlled within a certain range, for example, not exceeding 2% of the total assets per year.</li>
<li>Taxes incurred by transferring a traditional IRA to a Roth IRA can be paid with loans or salary.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question:</strong>  Why is the borrowing interest rate 5% while the cash interest rate is only calculated as 2.5% in SPACE?</li>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Reply:</strong>  This is just a conservative estimate. Money market fund yields are usually lower than borrowing rates.</li>
<li><strong>Question:</strong>  How to handle it if funds in the Brokerage account need to be used before retirement?</li>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Reply:</strong>  You can use the funds in the Brokerage account for a pledge loan, but you need sufficient cash as a guarantee.</li>
<li><strong>Question:</strong>  What if the cash in the Brokerage account is insufficient to cover the loan in the event of an extreme stock market decline?</li>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Reply:</strong>  In extreme cases, you can transfer the cash in the Roth or Traditional IRA account to the Brokerage account, but this is an emergency measure and will incur penalties.</li>
<li><strong>Question:</strong>  Is investing TQQQ in a Roth IRA too risky?</li>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Reply:</strong>  Investing Roth IRA in TQQQ is to obtain higher returns while ensuring a certain cash ratio. If you are concerned about risks, you can appropriately reduce the proportion of TQQQ and increase the proportion of money market funds.</li>
<li><strong>Question:</strong>  In the long run, will borrowing from a Brokerage account lead to paying high taxes?</li>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Reply:</strong>  Borrowing itself does not increase the tax burden, but it can avoid the tax burden caused by selling stocks. However, if you transfer funds from a Traditional IRA to a Roth IRA, it will increase your taxable income for the year and you will need to pay additional taxes.</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">IV. Highlights 
    <div id="iv-highlights" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv-highlights" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p><strong>The most important thing in investing is maximizing the probability of success, not maximizing the rate of return.</strong>
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>To achieve long-term stable returns, control risks, avoid being forced to interrupt compound growth due to market fluctuations, and choose investment portfolios that can be held for the long term.</p>
<blockquote>
<p><strong>Don&rsquo;t try stock pledging lightly if you don&rsquo;t understand it.</strong>
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Stock pledging is very risky if not done properly and can lead to bankruptcy.</p>
<blockquote>
<p><strong>Most people don&rsquo;t need to do stock pledging and can still become wealthy without it.</strong>
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Good asset allocation and long-term investment can lead to financial freedom even without stock pledging.</p>
<blockquote>
<p><strong>If you don&rsquo;t have the right understanding of the stock market, you are the victim.</strong>
&ndash; Ethan</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Learn investment knowledge, understand market rules, and avoid becoming a韭菜 (leek, a metaphor for someone easily exploited in the stock market).</p>
<blockquote>
<p><strong>Investing is like life. You need to keep learning to find an investment strategy that suits you.</strong>
&ndash; Im</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Investing is a continuous learning process. You need to constantly improve your cognitive level to succeed in the market.</p>
<blockquote>
<p><strong>People with stable emotions are the most valuable. Investing in QQQ also brings peace of mind.</strong>
&ndash; Sunny</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Investing requires rationality and avoiding emotional trading to succeed in market volatility.</p>
<blockquote>
<p><strong>Rotten apples don&rsquo;t get better, and broken elevators don&rsquo;t fix themselves.</strong>
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>If the individual stocks you hold are not performing well, cut your losses in time and switch to more potential investment targets.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">V. Summary 
    <div id="v-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#v-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This episode emphasizes the importance of risk management and asset allocation and gives specific investment advice for different groups of people. James answers the audience&rsquo;s questions about stock pledging, asset allocation, individual stock selection, market fluctuations, pump and dump schemes, etc., to help everyone better understand the concept and methods of long-term investment. At the same time, James also announced the future update plan of the CLEC Investment and Financial Management Channel, which will stop updating short videos and condense the content of the short videos into a briefing format for sharing on Saturdays.</p>

  



<div
  
    class="flex px-4 py-3 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900"
  >

  <span
    
      class="text-primary-400 ltr:pr-3 rtl:pl-3 flex items-center"
    >

    

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M506.3 417l-213.3-364c-16.33-28-57.54-28-73.98 0l-213.2 364C-10.59 444.9 9.849 480 42.74 480h426.6C502.1 480 522.6 445 506.3 417zM232 168c0-13.25 10.75-24 24-24S280 154.8 280 168v128c0 13.25-10.75 24-23.1 24S232 309.3 232 296V168zM256 416c-17.36 0-31.44-14.08-31.44-31.44c0-17.36 14.07-31.44 31.44-31.44s31.44 14.08 31.44 31.44C287.4 401.9 273.4 416 256 416z"/></svg>

  </span>


  </span>

  <span
    
      class="dark:text-neutral-300"
    ><strong>Disclaimer:</strong> This article is for personal learning notes only and does not constitute any investment advice.</span>
</div>

]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>How to Invest in NASDAQ 100</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1728723295012-invest-qqq/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1728723295012-invest-qqq/</guid><description>a description</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="qqq-tradingview">
    <script>
        const container = document.getElementById('qqq-tradingview');
        const script = document.createElement('script');
        script.type = 'text/javascript';
        script.src = 'https://s3.tradingview.com/external-embedding/embed-widget-mini-symbol-overview.js';  // 加载TradingView库
        script.async = true; //  异步加载，不阻塞页面渲染
        script.textContent = `{"symbol": "NASDAQ:NDX",
                                "width": "100%",
                                "height": "220",
                                "locale": "EN",
                                "dateRange": "ALL",
                                "colorTheme": "dark",
                                "isTransparent": true,
                                "autosize": true}`;
        container.appendChild(script);  //  将 <script> 标签添加到容器中
    </script>
</div>


<h2 class="relative group">North America 
    <div id="north-america" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#north-america" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">United States 
    <div id="united-states" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#united-states" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<table>
  <thead>
      <tr>
          <th>Ticker</th>
          <th>Product Name</th>
          <th>Remarks</th>
      </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
      <tr>
          <td><strong>QQQ</strong></td>
          <td>Invesco QQQ Trust</td>
          <td></td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td><strong>QQQM</strong></td>
          <td>Invesco NASDAQ 100 ETF</td>
          <td></td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>QLD</td>
          <td>ProShares Ultra QQQ</td>
          <td>2x</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>TQQQ</td>
          <td>ProShares UltraPro QQQ</td>
          <td>3x</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>PSQ</td>
          <td>ProShares Short QQQ</td>
          <td>-1x</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>QID</td>
          <td>ProShares UltraShort QQQ</td>
          <td>-2x</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>SQQQ</td>
          <td>ProShares UltraPro Short QQQ</td>
          <td>-3x</td>
      </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>


<h3 class="relative group">Canada 
    <div id="canada" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#canada" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<table>
  <thead>
      <tr>
          <th>Ticker</th>
          <th>Product Name</th>
          <th>Remarks</th>
      </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
      <tr>
          <td>XQQ</td>
          <td>iShares NASDAQ 100 (CAD Hedged)</td>
          <td></td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>QQC</td>
          <td>Invesco NASDAQ 100 Index Fund</td>
          <td></td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>HQU</td>
          <td>BetaPro NASDAQ-100 2x Daily Bull</td>
          <td>2x</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>HQD</td>
          <td>BetaPro NASDAQ-100 2x Daily Bear</td>
          <td>-2x</td>
      </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>


<h2 class="relative group">Asia 
    <div id="asia" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#asia" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">China 
    <div id="china" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#china" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<table>
  <thead>
      <tr>
          <th>Ticker</th>
          <th>Product Name</th>
          <th>Remarks</th>
      </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
      <tr>
          <td>159941</td>
          <td>GF Fund NASDAQ-100 ETF</td>
          <td></td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>513100</td>
          <td>Cathay NASDAQ-100 ETF</td>
          <td></td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>513300</td>
          <td>ChinaAMC NASDAQ-100 ETF</td>
          <td></td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>159513</td>
          <td>Dacheng NASDAQ-100 ETF</td>
          <td></td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>159632</td>
          <td>HuaAn NASDAQ-100 ETF</td>
          <td></td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>159501</td>
          <td>Harvest NASDAQ-100 ETF</td>
          <td></td>
      </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>


<h3 class="relative group">Hong Kong, China 
    <div id="hong-kong-china" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#hong-kong-china" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<table>
  <thead>
      <tr>
          <th>Ticker</th>
          <th>Product Name</th>
          <th>Remarks</th>
      </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
      <tr>
          <td>02834</td>
          <td>iShares NASDAQ 100</td>
          <td></td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>03034</td>
          <td>CSOP NASDAQ 100</td>
          <td></td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>07266</td>
          <td>FL 2X CSOP NASDAQ 100</td>
          <td>2x</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>07261</td>
          <td>FL 2X ChinaAMC NASDAQ 100</td>
          <td>2x</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>07568</td>
          <td>FI 2X Inverse CSOP NASDAQ 100</td>
          <td>-2x</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>07522</td>
          <td>FI 2X Inverse ChinaAMC NASDAQ 100</td>
          <td>-2x</td>
      </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>


<h3 class="relative group">Taiwan, China 
    <div id="taiwan-china" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#taiwan-china" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<table>
  <thead>
      <tr>
          <th>Ticker</th>
          <th>Product Name</th>
          <th>Remarks</th>
      </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
      <tr>
          <td>00662</td>
          <td>Fubon NASDAQ 100</td>
          <td></td>
      </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>


<h3 class="relative group">India 
    <div id="india" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#india" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<table>
  <thead>
      <tr>
          <th>Ticker</th>
          <th>Product Name</th>
          <th>Remarks</th>
      </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
      <tr>
          <td>N100</td>
          <td>Motilal Oswal MOSt Shares NASDAQ 100</td>
          <td></td>
      </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>


<h3 class="relative group">Japan 
    <div id="japan" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#japan" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<table>
  <thead>
      <tr>
          <th>Ticker</th>
          <th>Product Name</th>
          <th>Remarks</th>
      </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
      <tr>
          <td>2569</td>
          <td>Listed Index Fund US Equity (NASDAQ100) Currency Hedged</td>
          <td></td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>1545</td>
          <td>NEXT FUNDS NASDAQ-100</td>
          <td></td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>2568</td>
          <td>Listed Index Fund US Equity (NASDAQ100) No Currency Hedging</td>
          <td></td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>2631</td>
          <td>MUKAM MAXIS NASDAQ100 ETF</td>
          <td></td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>2842</td>
          <td>iFreeETF NASDAQ100 Inverse</td>
          <td>-1x</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>2869</td>
          <td>iFreeETF NASDAQ100 Leveraged (2x)</td>
          <td>2x</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>2870</td>
          <td>iFreeETF NASDAQ100 Double Inverse (-2x)</td>
          <td>-2x</td>
      </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>


<h3 class="relative group">South Korea 
    <div id="south-korea" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#south-korea" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<table>
  <thead>
      <tr>
          <th>Ticker</th>
          <th>Product Name</th>
          <th>Remarks</th>
      </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
      <tr>
          <td>379810</td>
          <td>Samsung KODEX US NASDAQ100 Total Return</td>
          <td></td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>409820</td>
          <td>SAMSUNG KODEX US NASDAQ100 Leverage (SYNTH H)</td>
          <td></td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>367380</td>
          <td>KIM KINDEX NASDAQ100</td>
          <td></td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>368590</td>
          <td>KB KBSTAR US NASDAQ100</td>
          <td></td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>133690</td>
          <td>Mirae Asset TIGER NASDAQ 100 ETF</td>
          <td></td>
      </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>


<h2 class="relative group">Europe 
    <div id="europe" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#europe" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Germany 
    <div id="germany" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#germany" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<table>
  <thead>
      <tr>
          <th>Ticker</th>
          <th>Product Name</th>
          <th>Remarks</th>
      </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
      <tr>
          <td>NDXEX</td>
          <td>iShares NASDAQ-100 UCITS ETF</td>
          <td></td>
      </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>


<h3 class="relative group">United Kingdom 
    <div id="united-kingdom" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#united-kingdom" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<table>
  <thead>
      <tr>
          <th>Ticker</th>
          <th>Product Name</th>
          <th>Remarks</th>
      </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
      <tr>
          <td>CNDX</td>
          <td>iShares NASDAQ 100 UCITS ETF</td>
          <td></td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>EQQQ</td>
          <td>INVESCO MARKETS III PLC INVESCO EQQQ NASDAQ 100 UCITS ETF</td>
          <td></td>
      </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>


<h3 class="relative group">France 
    <div id="france" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#france" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<table>
  <thead>
      <tr>
          <th>Ticker</th>
          <th>Product Name</th>
          <th>Remarks</th>
      </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
      <tr>
          <td>USTE</td>
          <td>Lyxor UCITS Nasdaq-100 D-EUR</td>
          <td></td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>PUST</td>
          <td>Lyxor PEA Nasdaq 100 C</td>
          <td></td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>PANX</td>
          <td>Amundi ETF PEA Nasdaq-100 UCITS</td>
          <td></td>
      </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>


<h3 class="relative group">Austria 
    <div id="austria" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#austria" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<table>
  <thead>
      <tr>
          <th>Ticker</th>
          <th>Product Name</th>
          <th>Remarks</th>
      </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
      <tr>
          <td>EXXT</td>
          <td>iShares NASDAQ-100 UCITS</td>
          <td></td>
      </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>


<h3 class="relative group">Hungary 
    <div id="hungary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#hungary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<table>
  <thead>
      <tr>
          <th>Ticker</th>
          <th>Product Name</th>
          <th>Remarks</th>
      </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
      <tr>
          <td>DE0A0F.</td>
          <td>iShares NASDAQ-100 UCITS</td>
          <td></td>
      </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>


<h3 class="relative group">Switzerland 
    <div id="switzerland" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#switzerland" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<table>
  <thead>
      <tr>
          <th>Ticker</th>
          <th>Product Name</th>
          <th>Remarks</th>
      </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
      <tr>
          <td>CSNDX</td>
          <td>iShares Nasdaq 100 UCITS</td>
          <td></td>
      </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>


<h2 class="relative group">South America 
    <div id="south-america" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#south-america" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Brazil 
    <div id="brazil" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#brazil" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<table>
  <thead>
      <tr>
          <th>Ticker</th>
          <th>Product Name</th>
          <th>Remarks</th>
      </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
      <tr>
          <td>NASD11</td>
          <td>Trend ETF Nasdaq 100 Fundo de Índice</td>
          <td></td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>QQQI11</td>
          <td>Buena Vista Nasdaq-100 High Income</td>
          <td></td>
      </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>


<h2 class="relative group">Africa 
    <div id="africa" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#africa" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">South Africa 
    <div id="south-africa" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#south-africa" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<table>
  <thead>
      <tr>
          <th>Ticker</th>
          <th>Product Name</th>
          <th>Remarks</th>
      </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
      <tr>
          <td>STXNDQJ</td>
          <td>Satrix Nasdaq 100 Feeder Portfolio</td>
          <td></td>
      </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>


<h2 class="relative group">Oceania 
    <div id="oceania" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#oceania" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Australia 
    <div id="australia" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#australia" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<table>
  <thead>
      <tr>
          <th>Ticker</th>
          <th>Product Name</th>
          <th>Remarks</th>
      </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
      <tr>
          <td>NDQ</td>
          <td>Betashares Nasdaq 100</td>
          <td></td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>HNDQ</td>
          <td>BetaShares NASDAQ 100 ETF - Currency Hedged</td>
          <td></td>
      </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>


<h2 class="relative group">Middle East 
    <div id="middle-east" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#middle-east" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Israel 
    <div id="israel" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#israel" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<table>
  <thead>
      <tr>
          <th>Ticker</th>
          <th>Product Name</th>
          <th>Remarks</th>
      </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
      <tr>
          <td>MTFF96</td>
          <td>MTF Sal (4A) Nasdaq 100 Currency Hedged</td>
          <td></td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>MTFF95</td>
          <td>MTF Sal (4D) Nasdaq 100</td>
          <td></td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>KSMF83</td>
          <td>KSM 4A NASDAQ 100 Currency Hedged</td>
          <td></td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>HRLF49</td>
          <td>Harel Sal 4A NASDAQ 100 Currency Hedged</td>
          <td></td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>HRLF217</td>
          <td>Harel Sal (E) 3 Time Lvrg Nasdaq 100 Mnth CH (6A)</td>
          <td>3x</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>KSMF115</td>
          <td>KSM 6D Short Leveraged NASDAQ 100 x3 Monthly</td>
          <td>-3x</td>
      </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>
<hr>
<img src="https://www.uscreditcardguide.com/wp-content/uploads/ibkr-300x203.png" alt="ibkr" style="display: block; margin: 0 auto; border-radius: 6px;">


<h2 class="relative group">Interactive Brokers (IBKR) 
    <div id="interactive-brokers-ibkr" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#interactive-brokers-ibkr" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p><a href="https://www.interactivebrokers.com/en/general/about/ibkr-fact-sheet.php" target="_blank">Interactive Brokers LLC (IBKR)</a>, a US-based online brokerage firm, is the largest online broker in the United States. Founded in 1977 by Thomas Peterffy in the US, Interactive Brokers Group has its headquarters in Greenwich, Connecticut. The company went public in 2007 and is listed on the Nasdaq Stock Market under the ticker symbol <a href="https://www.nasdaq.com/market-activity/stocks/ibkr" target="_blank"><strong>IBKR</strong></a>.</p>
<p>Interactive Brokers Group affiliates provide automated trade execution and custody of securities, commodities and foreign exchange around the clock on over 150 markets in 27 currencies, from a single integrated platform, to clients from over 200 countries and territories. We service individual investors, hedge funds, proprietary trading groups, financial advisors and introducing brokers. Our four decades of focus on technology and automation have enabled us to equip our clients with a uniquely sophisticated platform to manage their investment portfolios. We strive to provide our clients with advantageous execution prices and trading, risk and portfolio management tools, research facilities and investment products, all at low or no cost, positioning them to achieve superior returns on investments. For the sixth consecutive year, Barron&rsquo;s ranked Interactive Brokers #1 with 5 out of 5 stars in its June 9, 2023, Best Online Brokers Review.</p>
<ul>
<li>IBG LLC was founded by its Chairman, Thomas Peterffy. Over the last 47 years, it has grown internally to become a major securities firm with equity capital of 15.2 billion .</li>
<li>Interactive Brokers&rsquo; headquarters is in Greenwich Connecticut, and it has 2,950+ employees in its offices in the United States, Switzerland, Canada, Hong Kong, United Kingdom, Australia, Japan, Hungary, Russia, India, China, Luxembourg, Ireland, Singapore and Estonia. IBKR is regulated by the SEC, FINRA, SFA and other regulatory agencies around the world.</li>
<li>IBKR is among the largest electronic brokers based on daily average revenue trades (DARTs) executing 2,634,000 trades per day.</li>
<li>Interactive Brokers Group has consistently been at the <a href="https://www.interactivebrokers.com/en/general/about/about.php" target="_blank">forefront of trading innovation</a>, starting with the invention of the first floor-based handheld computer in 1983.</li>
<li>Standard &amp; Poor&rsquo;s issues investment grade ratings to both <a href="https://www.interactivebrokers.com/download/IBG_SandP-Rating-06-2022.pdf" target="_blank">IBG LLC</a> and <a href="https://www.interactivebrokers.com/download/IBG_SandP-Rating-06-2022.pdf" target="_blank">IB LLC (IBKR)</a>.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Referral Link for Account Opening 
    <div id="referral-link-for-account-opening" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#referral-link-for-account-opening" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://ibkr.com/referral/zumou900" target="_blank">Interactive Brokers (IBKR)</a></li>
</ul>

  



<div
  
    class="flex px-4 py-3 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900"
  >

  <span
    
      class="text-primary-400 ltr:pr-3 rtl:pl-3 flex items-center"
    >

    

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M256 0C114.6 0 0 114.6 0 256s114.6 256 256 256s256-114.6 256-256S397.4 0 256 0zM256 128c17.67 0 32 14.33 32 32c0 17.67-14.33 32-32 32S224 177.7 224 160C224 142.3 238.3 128 256 128zM296 384h-80C202.8 384 192 373.3 192 360s10.75-24 24-24h16v-64H224c-13.25 0-24-10.75-24-24S210.8 224 224 224h32c13.25 0 24 10.75 24 24v88h16c13.25 0 24 10.75 24 24S309.3 384 296 384z"/></svg>

  </span>


  </span>

  <span
    
      class="dark:text-neutral-300"
    >For every $100 in assets (cash or other assets) you deposit in your account after opening an account using <strong>the link above</strong>, you&rsquo;ll receive $1 worth of IBKR stock, up to a maximum value of $1,000. The average balance must be maintained for at least one year for the stock to vest.  <a href="https://www.ibtws.com/en/trading/referral-member-to-member.php" target="_blank">(Official Instructions)</a></span>
</div>

]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>00486 Market Trends and Future Investment Strategies:Navigating the New Economic Era</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1728231523948/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1728231523948/</guid><description>In this session, James shares his analysis of the current market situation and investment advice. He also answers questions from the audience on topics like asset allocation, retirement planning, children&amp;#39;s education, handling stock options, leverage, and tax planning.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<lite-youtube videoid="mwchPrvkFMA" playlabel="mwchPrvkFMA" params=""></lite-youtube>



<h2 class="relative group">I. Main Topic 
    <div id="i-main-topic" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-main-topic" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>The theme of this session is <strong>Embrace the New Bull Market and Invest Long-Term.</strong> James believes that the global monetary easing policy and the rapid development of AI technology herald the arrival of a new bull market. He advises everyone to invest in the Nasdaq 100 index fund (QQQ or 00662) and view market fluctuations with a long-term perspective.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">II.  Content Summary 
    <div id="ii--content-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii--content-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<ul>
<li><strong>A new bull market is coming:</strong>  The world has entered an era of loose monetary policy with the start of a rate cut cycle, which will drive the stock market up. This bull market may be a slow one but will continuously rise.</li>
<li><strong>Invest confidently in the Nasdaq 100 index fund:</strong> QQQ could increase by 50 times in the next 20 years, with an annualized return of over 20%, making it the best investment target.</li>
<li><strong>Individual stocks are unreliable:</strong> Individual stock investment is risky, and in the long run, almost all of them will disappear. They are very difficult to outperform the market in the long term. It is recommended not to waste time and energy on stock selection.</li>
<li><strong>Do not invest in the Chinese stock market:</strong> The Chinese stock market is not mature enough; consider investing in it after 30 years.</li>
<li><strong>Comparison of household asset allocation in the US and Taiwan:</strong>  American families invest most of their assets in securities to create social value, while Taiwanese families prefer cash, insurance, and real estate, locking up funds in non-appreciating areas.</li>
<li><strong>Leveraging through stock pledges:</strong> Using stock pledges to borrow increases liquidity and allows for continued investment to enjoy the benefits of compound growth. With an understanding of asset allocation, the interest cost of borrowing can be almost negligible.</li>
<li><strong>Plan for retirement early:</strong> Young people are advised to invest in 00662, and retirees can choose 00646 (SPY) or 0056 according to their fund size.</li>
<li><strong>Emphasize family education:</strong> Parents should cultivate their children&rsquo;s financial management concepts from an early age, guide them to make long-term investments, stay away from bad habits such as short-term speculation and gambling, and lead by example.</li>
<li><strong>Don&rsquo;t blindly trust high-yield investment products:</strong> Any investment product promising high returns may be a scam. It is important to understand its operating mechanism and learn to discern between true and false.</li>
<li><strong>The dangers of short-term trading:</strong> Short-term trading will miss the best investment opportunities. Long-term investment in index funds will yield more stable returns.</li>
<li><strong>The purpose of cash allocation:</strong> It is not for profit, but for dealing with emergencies like unemployment or a market crash. It is advisable to keep more than 10% of your assets in cash.</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">III. Q&amp;A Session 
    <div id="iii-qa-session" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii-qa-session" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<ul>
<li>
<p><strong>Retired Doctor Poch:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: After learning about James&rsquo; investment philosophy, he found a more relaxing and suitable investment method.</li>
<li>Question: How to obtain a stable cash flow after retirement? Is it necessary to adjust the investment strategy of 00662?
<ul>
<li>Answer:  The investment target can be adjusted according to the size of the retirement fund. Choose 00646 (SPY) or 0056 with lower volatility to guarantee cash flow.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>IM:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: He tried to guide his child to invest by matching contributions and increased his vigilance against high-yield traps.</li>
<li>Question 1: How to guide a child to invest and prevent them from spending investment income?
<ul>
<li>Answer: Emphasize that investment is a long-term behavior. Income cannot be withdrawn for consumption. Funds should grow continuously through compound interest.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2: How to choose a safe and reliable trust company? How to avoid the traps of high-yield trust products?
<ul>
<li>Answer: Any trust company that promises high returns may be a scam. You should take control of your own investment and financial management rights, clearly stipulate investment in index funds in the trust clause, and set up a regulatory unit to ensure fund security.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Rose:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: She frankly talked about her past investment failures and the process of gradually establishing the correct investment concept under the guidance of James.</li>
<li>Question 1: What are the differences and pros and cons of Margin Loan and Pledge Loan?  The interest rate of Margin Loan from IB is relatively low. Is it necessary to transfer to Charles Schwab for Pledge Loan?
<ul>
<li>Answer:  Margin Loan is riskier, and Pledge Loan is relatively safe. If the interest rate of IB&rsquo;s Margin Loan is low, you can continue to use it, but pay attention to controlling the borrowing ratio, preferably no more than 20%.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2: The return on cash allocation will decrease in the interest rate cut cycle. Is it still necessary to allocate cash?
<ul>
<li>Answer: The purpose of cash allocation is not for profit but to deal with contingencies, such as unemployment or a market crash. It is advisable to keep more than 10% of your assets in cash.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 3: How to manage children&rsquo;s investment accounts? Under whose name should it be, yours or the child&rsquo;s?
<ul>
<li>Answer: It is recommended to open an account in the child&rsquo;s name to cultivate their financial management concept, but control the amount and provide proper investment guidance. Estate planning can be done after the child becomes an adult.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Phoenix:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: He shared his confusion about handling company stock options and finally adopted James&rsquo; suggestion.</li>
<li>Question 1: How to deal with the stock options of unlisted companies?
<ul>
<li>Answer: If the company has a high possibility of going public, it is recommended to sell it to an investment company before the listing to get cash and invest in QQQ.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2: What do you think of Bitcoin? Can I invest in it?
<ul>
<li>Answer: If you already hold a small amount of Bitcoin, you can continue to hold it, but do not invest any more capital. It is recommended to focus on investing in QQQ.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Allen:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: He shared his questions about 401k and stock investment and eventually made adjustments under James&rsquo; advice.</li>
<li>Question 1: What should I do if I have too much money in my 401k account?
<ul>
<li>Answer:  It is recommended to stop making further contributions to 401k and transfer some funds to the Roth IRA account through the Backdoor Roth IRA.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2: How to switch from holding Nvidia stock to QQQ?
<ul>
<li>Answer: Sell Nvidia stock as soon as possible, transfer funds to QQQ, and pledge stocks to borrow money to pay taxes.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Haoqing:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: He demonstrated the difficulty of stock selection through data analysis and illustrated the advantages of long-term investment in QQQ with practical examples.</li>
<li>Question: Can stock picking beat QQQ?
<ul>
<li>Answer: Stock selection is difficult to outperform QQQ in the long run. Even if it beats the market in the short term, transaction costs and taxes need to be considered.  Invest in index funds for the long term.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Xiang:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: He shared his confusion about saving for children&rsquo;s education and inheritance and finally found a solution under James&rsquo; advice.</li>
<li>Question 1: Is it better to use a 529 Education Fund or invest in QQQ for children&rsquo;s education savings?
<ul>
<li>Answer:  Investing in QQQ is recommended because it has higher long-term returns and is more flexible.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2: How to do estate planning?
<ul>
<li>Answer:  For larger estates, it is recommended to set up an irrevocable trust and consult an estate lawyer for planning.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Kevin:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Frankly admitted his past investment failures and regained confidence under the guidance of James, starting to embark on the road of steady investment.</li>
<li>Question: How many listeners are losing money on investments?
<ul>
<li>Answer: Past investment experience is not important. What is important is to establish the correct investment concept and believe in the value of long-term investment in index funds.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Julia:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Shared her lessons learned from investing in Chinese concept stocks and second-tier growth stocks, and how to guide children to make long-term investments.</li>
<li>Question 1: How to deal with losses caused by investment in Chinese concept stocks and second-tier growth stocks?
- Answer: It is advisable to &ldquo;cut your losses&rdquo; and switch funds to QQQ in a timely manner.</li>
<li>Question 2: How to guide children to make long-term investments?
- Answer: You can use an investment calculator to show children the power of compound interest and guide them with your own investment experience.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Peter:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Shared his experience working at Apple and confirmed that many high-income earners also choose to invest in index funds.</li>
<li>Question: How to balance family expenses and investment?
- Answer: It is recommended to use stock pledges to borrow money to meet living expenses and continue investing in QQQ, so that assets can continue to grow through compound interest.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Jason:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: He shared his confusion about company tax declaration and finally found a suitable solution under James&rsquo; advice.</li>
<li>Question: How to choose the tax filing method?
<ul>
<li>Answer: If your income is low, you can choose to file a 1099; if your income is high, you are advised to establish an S Corporation.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Cindy:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Shared her experience of guiding her child to invest in Roth IRA and keep away from gambling.</li>
<li>Question: How to guide children to invest in Roth IRA? How to guide children to stay away from gambling?
<ul>
<li>Answer: Open a Roth IRA account for the child and make matching contributions. Lead by example and educate your child with the experiences and stories of people around you.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">IV.  Highlights 
    <div id="iv--highlights" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv--highlights" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>Lending is more powerful than the atomic bomb; it&rsquo;s ten times the atomic bomb!
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>When encouraging people to use stock pledges for borrowing and investment, James used this analogy to vividly illustrate the power of leverage.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Investing should be easy and fun.
&ndash;  Hola</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This is what a listener said when she shared her investment experience. She also tried short-term trading, but finally found that long-term investment suited her better.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Each person has a different destiny when it comes to money.
&ndash; Peter</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Peter said this thought-provoking sentence when he shared his experience of persuading his father to invest in QQQ. This also reflects that investment and financial management should be combined with one&rsquo;s own situation to find a suitable way.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>All the money in the world is mine; you just need to take it and use it.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>James used humorous words to express his confidence in the market when encouraging everyone to invest, which also reflects his optimistic and positive attitude towards life.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">V. Conclusion 
    <div id="v-conclusion" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#v-conclusion" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>In this live broadcast, James once again emphasized the concept of long-term investment in index funds. He also provided specific investment advice for the audience based on the current market situation, covering asset allocation, retirement planning, children&rsquo;s education, stock options handling, leverage, and tax planning. The sharing from the students provided other listeners with valuable reference experience, showing their growth and earnings during the process of learning about investment and financial management.</p>

  



<div
  
    class="flex px-4 py-3 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900"
  >

  <span
    
      class="text-primary-400 ltr:pr-3 rtl:pl-3 flex items-center"
    >

    

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M506.3 417l-213.3-364c-16.33-28-57.54-28-73.98 0l-213.2 364C-10.59 444.9 9.849 480 42.74 480h426.6C502.1 480 522.6 445 506.3 417zM232 168c0-13.25 10.75-24 24-24S280 154.8 280 168v128c0 13.25-10.75 24-23.1 24S232 309.3 232 296V168zM256 416c-17.36 0-31.44-14.08-31.44-31.44c0-17.36 14.07-31.44 31.44-31.44s31.44 14.08 31.44 31.44C287.4 401.9 273.4 416 256 416z"/></svg>

  </span>


  </span>

  <span
    
      class="dark:text-neutral-300"
    ><strong>Disclaimer:</strong> This article is only for personal learning notes and does not constitute any investment advice.</span>
</div>

]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>00485 Buying a house will only make you poor. Investing makes you rich. Borrowing money to keep your assets growing is the way to become wealthy</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1728259977859/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1728259977859/</guid><description>This episode focuses on investment philosophy, strategies to avoid scams, and the impact of China&amp;#39;s newest economic policies on the global market. James reiterates the importance of long-term investment in index funds, specifically QQQ, and advises investors to control their emotions and resist market volatility. He uses real-life examples and data to illustrate the concept of &amp;#34;borrowing for consumption, investing for asset growth&amp;#34;, and analyzes China&amp;#39;s recent economic stimulus policies, viewing them as a positive sign for global economic recovery.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<lite-youtube videoid="zJdXwFaec2c" playlabel="zJdXwFaec2c" params=""></lite-youtube>



<h2 class="relative group">I. Main Topic 
    <div id="i-main-topic" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-main-topic" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This episode primarily discusses proper investment philosophy, ways to avoid investment traps, and the implications of China&rsquo;s latest economic policies for the global market. James emphasizes the importance of long-term investment in index funds, particularly QQQ, and reminds investors to maintain emotional control and not be swayed by market fluctuations. He uses specific examples and data to illustrate the concept of &ldquo;borrow for consumption, invest for asset growth,&rdquo; while also analyzing China&rsquo;s recently introduced series of economic stimulus policies, believing them to be a positive signal for a global economic recovery.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">II. Briefing Content 
    <div id="ii-briefing-content" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii-briefing-content" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<ul>
<li><strong>Investment Philosophy:</strong>
<ul>
<li>Emotions are the biggest enemy in investing. You need to avoid being influenced by news and information, stay rational, and refrain from chasing rising or falling markets.</li>
<li>Investing requires a long-term perspective, aiming for a timeframe of 40 years or more. Warren Buffett acquired 99% of his wealth after the age of 50, demonstrating that patience is key to wealth creation.</li>
<li>Choose investment targets that are consistently stable and provide high returns. Index funds are the best option, especially QQQ, which boasts a long-term annualized return of 14%.</li>
<li>Adhere to the &ldquo;never sell&rdquo; strategy to allow assets to continue appreciating. Avoid selling stocks unless absolutely necessary.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Scam Avoidance Guide:</strong>
<ul>
<li>Be wary of various investment traps. Do not trust any projects that guarantee high returns, especially those that require you to sell existing assets for new investments.</li>
<li>Do not readily believe any investment or financial management information received via phone, text messages, or online platforms. Any information involving bank accounts or government departments must be verified through official channels.</li>
<li>Be cautious of aggressive sales tactics from financial institutions. Stick to your investment plan and avoid being lured by various fancy financial products.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Regarding Real Estate Investment:</strong>
<ul>
<li>James advises against homeownership for average working individuals, believing it turns them into &ldquo;mortgage slaves&rdquo; burdened with heavy loan pressure, hindering wealth accumulation.</li>
<li>He advocates for a &ldquo;rent instead of buy&rdquo; approach, suggesting using a stock pledge loan to rent high-quality housing at lower interest rates, then investing the saved funds for higher returns.</li>
<li>Consider purchasing real estate only when your assets reach a certain scale and you can comfortably afford the payment.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>New Trends in China&rsquo;s Economy:</strong>
<ul>
<li>The People&rsquo;s Bank of China recently introduced a series of potent fiscal policies, including reserve requirement ratio and interest rate cuts, injecting funds into banks, and encouraging stock purchases, to stimulate economic growth.</li>
<li>These policies will contribute positively to stabilizing China&rsquo;s real estate market, boosting consumer confidence, and promoting global economic recovery.</li>
<li>Investors should pay attention to developments in the Chinese market and seize new investment opportunities.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">III. Q&amp;A Session 
    <div id="iii-qa-session" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii-qa-session" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p><strong>IM:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Through conversations with individuals of different age groups, IM discovered that most people have insufficient awareness of long-term savings and are often constrained by mortgages and other factors. By comparing the returns of index funds in different countries and regions with those of fixed deposits and pensions, IM illustrated the advantages of long-term investment in index funds.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>INGYNYING:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: INGYNYING&rsquo;s mother wanted to sell all her assets to purchase a house but, after persuasion, realized that this would lead to losing opportunities for asset appreciation. Many of INGYNYING&rsquo;s friends are afraid of change, preferring to endure the hardships of their current situation rather than attempt new investment methods.</li>
<li>Question: How to convince family members to accept new investment concepts?</li>
<li>James&rsquo; answer: Utilize data and case studies for illustration, such as comparing the long-term returns of fixed deposits and index funds, and sharing success stories of investors. It&rsquo;s also important to respect family members&rsquo; choices and refrain from forcing them to accept new ideas.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Allen:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Questions:  Should someone with assets worth 50 times their annual living expenses use their salary to pay for a car? How can a couple combine their stock accounts for collateral purposes?</li>
<li>James&rsquo; answer: It is recommended to utilize Tesla&rsquo;s official website loan to purchase a vehicle, then use funds from a stock pledge loan to repay the car loan. Dedicate your salary entirely to investment. Couples can combine their accounts through a joint account for collateral, sharing the limit, while their accounts remain individually managed.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Eric:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Question: Eric&rsquo;s mother is visiting the US and is concerned about medical expenses. How should this be  handled?</li>
<li>James&rsquo; answer:  Purchasing travel insurance is advised, but excessive worry is unnecessary. Most non-emergency situations can be treated back home. If encountering extremely high medical costs, attempting negotiation with the hospital or seeking alternative solutions is possible. Due to the specific circumstances of foreign nationality and lack of income, the hospital may choose not to pursue the medical expenses.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Dean:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Dean purchased a new car using Tesla&rsquo;s website loan and a stock pledge loan, conserving a significant amount of capital. Learning about investing boosted Dean&rsquo;s confidence to decline a high-paying job and choose to stay home with their child.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Michael:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Questions: How to secure a loan from Tesla&rsquo;s official website for a car purchase? Can funds from 401k or IRA accounts be used for collateral? What are the options if QQQ is not available in their company&rsquo;s 401k plan?</li>
<li>James&rsquo; answer: To apply for a car loan through Tesla&rsquo;s website, choose the desired model and configuration, click &ldquo;Order Now&rdquo;, and select &ldquo;Finance&rdquo;. Funds in retirement accounts cannot be used as collateral; it is recommended to transfer part of those funds to a brokerage account for collateral purposes.  Alternative options include choosing an S&amp;P 500 index fund or inquiring with the company about the possibility of Blockage Link to invest in QQQ.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>EVA:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Question: As a single, middle-aged woman with limited savings, how to balance work and investment? Should selling the house be considered for investment purposes?</li>
<li>James&rsquo; answer: Continue working diligently while consistently making monthly investments. Even small amounts will accumulate over 8-9 years, reaching the threshold for collateral, allowing you to leverage and accelerate wealth growth. Selling a house for investment is an option but requires careful consideration based on personal circumstances.  If renting is more cost-effective, choose to rent and allocate the funds to investments yielding higher returns.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Jenny:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Questions:  Any knowledge regarding the latest Roth SEP IRA policy?</li>
<li>James&rsquo; answer: The policy information is quite recent, and the accuracy of the $69,000 limit requires verification. Consulting with professionals like a financial advisor at Chase or Lisa is recommended. As it is a new product, not all institutions may offer it.</li>
<li>Sharing: Jenny shared a personal experience of being scammed, reminding everyone to exercise caution and avoid trusting any investment information, particularly those spread through unofficial channels.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Haoqing:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Haoqing relayed the experiences of close friends falling victim to scams, lamenting that scam tactics are constantly evolving and are hard to guard against, even for highly educated individuals.</li>
<li>Question: How can investment concepts be better conveyed to people around us to prevent them from being deceived? Is there a need to explain professional investment knowledge?</li>
<li>James&rsquo; answer: Avoid explaining intricate investment knowledge; simply emphasize the core principle of long-term investment in index funds. Excessive professional details may confuse them, making them more susceptible to being misled by other investment information and ultimately falling prey to scams.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Jason:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Recounted an NFT scam incident encountered on Clubhouse, warning everyone to be wary of risks in the cryptocurrency world. Expressed gratitude toward James&rsquo; investment philosophy for helping them avoid such traps.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Amy:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Amy shared personal encounters with scams, including impersonations of government departments and courier companies. She emphasized the importance of relying only on written communication and ignoring any investment information delivered through phone calls or text messages. Amy suggested that, when in doubt, contact official channels for clarification.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Becky:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Suggestion: Avoid answering calls from unfamiliar numbers, set up spam filters, and use a less important email address when necessary to share personal information to minimize the risk of scams.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Mike:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Question: What are your thoughts on China&rsquo;s most recent economic policies? Are they sustainable?</li>
<li>James&rsquo; answer: The People&rsquo;s Bank of China has introduced powerful policies that are having a positive impact on economic confidence. Investors should keep an eye on these developments. Although the policies appear to be heading in a positive direction, their sustainability remains to be seen.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Julia:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Question:  Any updates on the Roth SEP IRA policy? Are there any financial institutions already offering related products?</li>
<li>James&rsquo; answer: The policy information is fairly new, and the $69,000 limit&rsquo;s accuracy is debatable. Consulting with a professional is advised. Being a new product, not all institutions might offer it yet.</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">IV. Noteworthy Points 
    <div id="iv-noteworthy-points" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv-noteworthy-points" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>“You have enough money when you have enough.&quot;
&ndash; Many people</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Many individuals believe that having just enough to get by is sufficient. This is a mistaken notion, as money is never truly enough. True financial freedom lies in possessing the power of choice – going wherever you want, doing whatever you desire – instead of being constrained by finances.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;Never borrow money for investments.&rdquo;
&ndash; Many people</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Many believe that borrowing for investment is unwise; however, this viewpoint is overly cautious. True investors, like Warren Buffett, skillfully leverage debt. Following the principle of &ldquo;borrow for consumption, invest for asset growth&rdquo;, the correct approach is to use borrowed money for expenses and personal money for investment. This enables rapid wealth accumulation.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“All investment information received through phone calls, text messages, or online platforms is not trustworthy.”
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Nowadays, numerous scams operate through these channels. It&rsquo;s crucial to exercise caution and avoid blindly believing any financial advice or information. Anything involving bank accounts or government departments must be verified through official sources. Additionally, seeking guidance from qualified professionals is essential.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“Investment must be consistently stable over the long term, which is why index funds are the only viable option.&quot;
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Within the complex investment landscape, index funds stand out as a few reliable options capable of offering consistent stability and high returns. Index funds are like living organisms; they will never die, whereas all individual stocks will eventually disappear within a century.  If you&rsquo;re looking for generational wealth, index funds are the way to go.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">V. Summary 
    <div id="v-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#v-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This episode is packed with valuable information and insights. It not only reiterates the importance of long-term index fund investment but also offers practical tips on scam prevention and provides an in-depth analysis of China&rsquo;s newest economic policies.  It is recommended to apply this knowledge to your investment practices and strive for financial freedom.</p>

  



<div
  
    class="flex px-4 py-3 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900"
  >

  <span
    
      class="text-primary-400 ltr:pr-3 rtl:pl-3 flex items-center"
    >

    

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M506.3 417l-213.3-364c-16.33-28-57.54-28-73.98 0l-213.2 364C-10.59 444.9 9.849 480 42.74 480h426.6C502.1 480 522.6 445 506.3 417zM232 168c0-13.25 10.75-24 24-24S280 154.8 280 168v128c0 13.25-10.75 24-23.1 24S232 309.3 232 296V168zM256 416c-17.36 0-31.44-14.08-31.44-31.44c0-17.36 14.07-31.44 31.44-31.44s31.44 14.08 31.44 31.44C287.4 401.9 273.4 416 256 416z"/></svg>

  </span>


  </span>

  <span
    
      class="dark:text-neutral-300"
    ><strong>Disclaimer:</strong> This article serves solely as personal study notes and does not constitute any investment advice.</span>
</div>

]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>00484 Buying at the market price immediately when you have money is the best investment strategy:a market with an unbreakable asset allocation doesn't exist</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1728261371758/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1728261371758/</guid><description>This live session focused on long-term investment strategies, delving into investment philosophy, risk management, and values. James shared personal experiences and insights, offering valuable guidance on understanding the nature of investing and its inherent risks, emphasizing the importance of being rational, patient, and vigilant.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<lite-youtube videoid="UGUV4GIqKVg" playlabel="UGUV4GIqKVg" params=""></lite-youtube>



<h2 class="relative group">I. Topic of the Session 
    <div id="i-topic-of-the-session" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-topic-of-the-session" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>The session centered on the core principle of long-term investment strategies. James reiterated his investment philosophy: &ldquo;Buy QQQ whenever you have money and hold it for the long term.&rdquo; The discussion expanded to cover aspects like investment philosophy, risk management, and values, incorporating current events and questions from attendees. James also shared insights from legendary investors like Warren Buffett, encouraging attendees to cultivate a sound investment mindset.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">II. Briefing Highlights 
    <div id="ii-briefing-highlights" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii-briefing-highlights" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<ol>
<li><strong>Buying at the Dip vs. Buying When You Have Money:</strong> James cited research from ChatGPT, indicating that even with the ability to accurately predict and buy at market dips, the long-term returns differed minimally compared to simply buying when one has available funds. Over a 20-year period, the difference was merely 8%, translating to a difference in annualized returns of less than 0.2%. Hence, rather than expending time and effort predicting market bottoms, it&rsquo;s more effective to seize opportunities and buy QQQ when you have the money.</li>
<li><strong>Risks of Leveraged Funds:</strong>  Using the 2000 tech bubble as an example, James explained how leveraged funds can accelerate losses in bear markets, potentially leading to devastating financial setbacks, even bankruptcy. He simulated a scenario where an investor repeatedly buys more leveraged funds as the market declines, culminating in financial ruin. This served as a cautionary tale against the &ldquo;buy the dip&rdquo; strategy with leveraged funds, emphasizing the importance of risk management.</li>
<li><strong>Keys to Investment Success:</strong> James emphasized that the key to successful investment lies in overcoming human weaknesses. Maintaining a detached and &ldquo;unfeeling&rdquo; attitude towards invested capital and short-term market fluctuations is crucial for adhering to a long-term investment approach.</li>
<li><strong>Market Cycles:</strong> James stated he wouldn&rsquo;t teach attendees about predicting market cycles or any trading techniques. He considers these unimportant and prone to misinterpretation and misapplication, potentially leading to increased risks. He advocated for a long-term investment strategy, likening it to riding a cable car, a smooth and steady ascent to the summit of financial success.</li>
<li><strong>Money and Values:</strong> Acknowledging that individuals have different values regarding money, James advised understanding and respecting diverse values, discouraging attempts to impose one&rsquo;s own values upon others. He used the example shared by an attendee about a mother preferring a financial subsidy over a family trip to illustrate the diverse ways people assign value to things.</li>
</ol>


<h2 class="relative group">III. Q&amp;A Session 
    <div id="iii-qa-session" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii-qa-session" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p><strong>IIM:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Shared:</strong> A story about a deceased friend, leading to reflections on money and values, and expressing confusion about balancing personal values with those of others.</li>
<li><strong>Question 1:</strong>  How to understand some people&rsquo;s &ldquo;frugality&rdquo; with money while being &ldquo;generous&rdquo; towards their pets.
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response:</strong> People manage their finances differently based on what they consider important and valuable. What might be significant to one person may hold little value for another.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question 2:</strong> How to understand a mother who prioritizes money over a family trip? How to better understand the needs of others?
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response:</strong>  This mother might have certain unmet needs, possibly requiring material security before pursuing leisurely experiences. Understanding true needs involves offering more choices (e.g., money plus a trip). Avoid trying to change others&rsquo; values; focus on understanding and respecting them.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Brian:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Shared:</strong> Encountering a friend who suggested leveraging to purchase Nvidia stock, leading to questions about investment advice.</li>
<li><strong>Question:</strong> How to evaluate investment advice received from others?
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response:</strong>   The validity of investment advice depends on individual judgment and risk tolerance. It&rsquo;s important to avoid blindly following the advice of others and to think independently.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Iny:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Shared:</strong>  Experiencing a sense of calm and reduced anxiety after adopting James&rsquo;s investment approach.  This newfound peace of mind allows for dedicating more time to important matters like family, and interestingly, focusing on work has led to increased income.</li>
<li><strong>Question:</strong>  How to understand the phenomenon of increased income resulting from a dedicated focus on work?
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response:</strong> This exemplifies the principle that altruism ultimately benefits oneself. By focusing on serving clients and enhancing product or service quality, one ultimately gains client recognition and rewards, leading to higher income and a sense of accomplishment.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Haoqing:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Shared 1:</strong>  An experience with check fraud, prompting concerns about bank security and the risks of using checks.
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response:</strong>  Banks do not verify the identity of check depositors. Checks present security vulnerabilities, making it advisable to use safer online banking and digital payment methods like Apple Pay.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Shared 2:</strong> Thoughts on the decline of US manufacturing and the rise of Asia, attributing this to factors like US regulations, labor laws, and unions.
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response:</strong> The decline of US manufacturing and the rise of Asia are multifaceted issues stemming from a complex interplay of factors, including national policies, labor laws, and unions. While Asian countries might resort to suppressing labor rights and environmental regulations to gain a competitive edge, the US places a higher value on worker well-being and environmental protection. This divergence in values contributes to different developmental paths.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Becky:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Shared:</strong> Based on personal experience working in a digital payment company, Becky recommended that everyone stop using checks due to inherent security risks. Digital payment methods offer greater security and convenience, with features such as spending alerts that enable prompt response and recovery in case of issues.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Mike:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Shared:</strong> As a long-time follower of James, Mike witnessed the evolution of his investment philosophy, from initially holding 30% SPY to converting to 100% QQQ, and eventually incorporating leveraged funds. He also shared personal investment experiences, like selling NIO and allocating a portion of his portfolio to private market investments.</li>
<li><strong>Question 1:</strong> Is investing in Intel after its acquisition worthwhile?
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response:</strong>  James advised against investing in large companies that are acquisitive. Acquisitions often lack efficiency, posing integration challenges and potentially hindering productivity. While acquiring smaller companies for technological advantages makes sense, acquiring large companies is akin to amassing a pile of scrap metal.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question 2:</strong>  How to view the supply chain security concerns stemming from the US outsourcing 3C product manufacturing, citing examples like the BBB Call explosion and walkie-talkie incidents?
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response:</strong> Espionage is ubiquitous, and supply chain security is just one facet of this broader issue. Governments might implant spy codes in chips and software for surveillance purposes. Explosions are a relatively rudimentary form of espionage; more sophisticated methods can be extremely difficult to detect and prevent.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question 3:</strong> Is it possible to offer advanced courses for more experienced attendees? He suggested using portfolio sharing as a means to differentiate attendees&rsquo; learning progress.
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response:</strong> James stated he wouldn&rsquo;t differentiate between attendees nor offer advanced courses. Assessing whether a student is genuinely learning is primarily based on their attitude, not investment returns or holding duration. Even portfolio sharing can&rsquo;t truly gauge learning progress. James mentioned his personal sensitivity to words and language, enabling him to discern learning attitudes from attendees&rsquo; emails and the way they pose questions.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">IV. Noteworthy Insights 
    <div id="iv-noteworthy-insights" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv-noteworthy-insights" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>The best time to buy is when you have money.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Many obsess over finding the perfect entry point, but research indicates that even if you could perfectly time market dips, the long-term returns barely differ from simply buying when funds are available. Instead of wasting time trying to predict the market, seize the opportunity and act promptly.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>To succeed in investing, you must be indifferent to the money you invest and the fluctuations in stock prices.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Overcoming the human tendency to fixate on money and fear short-term market swings is essential for maintaining a long-term investment strategy and achieving stable returns.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>To achieve effortless investing, you need to be numb to money.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>When investing becomes a habit, free from emotional impulses and external distractions, you can achieve optimal results.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The concept of a &ldquo;benefactor&rdquo; is relative.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>People perceive and absorb information differently. Who you consider a benefactor might not be perceived as such by others.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Don&rsquo;t try to change other people&rsquo;s values.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Everyone has their own values and ways of life. It&rsquo;s important to understand and respect diverse choices.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Espionage is everywhere.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Information security is a growing concern. Be vigilant and protect your personal data.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Acquisitions of large companies are generally inefficient, and leaders who are fond of acquisitions usually have inflated egos.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Integration complexities and high management costs associated with mergers often outweigh the benefits gained.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The US excels in areas such as finance and technology design, while Asian countries can only substitute and supplement in specific aspects.
&ndash; Haoqing</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Within the global division of labor, different countries have distinct strengths and weaknesses, leading to divergent paths of development.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The best judgments are validated by facts.
&ndash; Mike</p>
</blockquote>
<p>The success of an investment philosophy is ultimately determined by its long-term returns, not short-term fluctuations or gut feelings.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Your attitude determines my response.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>James adjusts his responses based on the learning attitude of the attendees. Attendees who are truly dedicated to learning will receive greater guidance.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Investing in individual stocks will ultimately lead to bankruptcy; holding onto individual stocks will also ultimately lead to bankruptcy.<br>
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Companies have lifecycles.  Holding onto a single stock long term significantly increases the risk of encountering bankruptcy. Diversification is key in investing.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">V. Summary 
    <div id="v-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#v-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This live session once again emphasized the importance of long-term investing while reminding attendees to stay rational, patient, and vigilant. James addressed attendees&rsquo; questions regarding investment strategies, risk management, and the relationship between money and values, sharing personal experiences and insights. Key takeaways include avoiding market timing, leveraged funds, and individual stock investments, and embracing an attitude of indifference towards money. Attendees actively shared their own investment experiences and reflections, prompting deeper contemplation on investment, money, life, and more. The session also delved into the philosophies of renowned investors like Warren Buffett and discussed various social phenomena, creating a rich and informative experience.</p>

  



<div
  
    class="flex px-4 py-3 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900"
  >

  <span
    
      class="text-primary-400 ltr:pr-3 rtl:pl-3 flex items-center"
    >

    

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M506.3 417l-213.3-364c-16.33-28-57.54-28-73.98 0l-213.2 364C-10.59 444.9 9.849 480 42.74 480h426.6C502.1 480 522.6 445 506.3 417zM232 168c0-13.25 10.75-24 24-24S280 154.8 280 168v128c0 13.25-10.75 24-23.1 24S232 309.3 232 296V168zM256 416c-17.36 0-31.44-14.08-31.44-31.44c0-17.36 14.07-31.44 31.44-31.44s31.44 14.08 31.44 31.44C287.4 401.9 273.4 416 256 416z"/></svg>

  </span>


  </span>

  <span
    
      class="dark:text-neutral-300"
    ><strong>Disclaimer:</strong> This transcript serves as personal learning notes only and does not constitute investment advice.</span>
</div>

]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>00477 Eternal Freedom from Worry and Stress：Wisdom and Strategies for Long-Term Investing</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1728565408053/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1728565408053/</guid><description>In this session, James shares his investment philosophy, emphasizing the importance of independent thinking and risk management. He also answers questions from students on topics such as TQQQ, emergency funds, MAGS fund, and real estate investment.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<lite-youtube videoid="CfFEQJkTCBw" playlabel="CfFEQJkTCBw" params=""></lite-youtube>



<h2 class="relative group">I. Main Theme 
    <div id="i-main-theme" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-main-theme" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This session focuses on the philosophy of long-term investing, emphasizing the importance of independent thinking and risk management. James reiterates his long-held investment philosophy: choose the right investment target (such as QQQ), buy in early and hold for the long term, ignoring short-term market fluctuations, and ultimately achieve steady wealth growth. In addition, he discusses how to maintain a positive mindset, deal with stress and anxiety that may arise during the investment process, and how to choose a reliable brokerage to ensure account security.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">II. Briefing Content 
    <div id="ii-briefing-content" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii-briefing-content" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<ul>
<li><strong>Wealth is accumulated slowly, and enjoying the process of wealth accumulation is the meaning of life.</strong> Getting rich overnight or quickly is not the best way. Slowly accumulating wealth and enjoying it allows you to experience the true meaning of life and learn and grow from it.</li>
<li><strong>Don&rsquo;t blindly pursue high returns while ignoring risks.</strong> Many people pursue quick riches and hope for super high returns, but often overlook the risks involved, which may ultimately lead to losses outweighing gains. Learn to assess risk and choose an investment strategy that matches your risk tolerance.</li>
<li><strong>Investing requires finding a definite eternity, ignoring market noise, and maintaining inner peace.</strong> Index fund investing is a definite and eternal strategy that does not require painstaking research and operation. Simply holding for the long term can yield considerable returns.</li>
<li><strong>Investment is a loser&rsquo;s game, not seeking to win, but seeking not to lose.</strong>  In investing, avoiding mistakes is more important than pursuing victory. Index fund investing can help investors reduce mistakes and ultimately achieve victory.</li>
<li><strong>Buying in a lump sum at any time and holding for the long term is superior to other investment methods.</strong> Investing early and holding for the long term maximizes returns and delivers the best investment returns.</li>
<li><strong>Learn to distinguish between what can be done, what is effective, what can be worried about, and what is not worth worrying about.</strong> Focus your energy on important and solvable issues, ignore those that are irrelevant or beyond your control to improve efficiency and reduce unnecessary anxiety.</li>
<li><strong>Don&rsquo;t work too hard, let your money work for you.</strong> Put your money into the market and let it create wealth for you instead of devoting all your energy to work. Learn to utilize investment tools to achieve passive wealth growth.</li>
<li><strong>All pressure comes from expectations, and all worries come from not having a solution.</strong> Lower your expectations and actively seek solutions to relieve stress and anxiety.</li>
<li><strong>Learn to transfer pressure to those who can bear it and think about solutions for the worst-case scenario.</strong> Don&rsquo;t bear the pressure alone, learn to seek help, and think in advance about solutions to the worst-case scenario to calmly deal with challenges.</li>
<li><strong>Maintain inner peace, focus on the important things, and ignore the insignificant things.</strong> Stick to simple things, don&rsquo;t get involved in complex things, to maintain inner peace and focus on what really matters in life.</li>
<li><strong>Account security is the primary issue in investing. Choose a large, reputable brokerage to open an account and avoid using online brokers.</strong> Online brokers have security risks, such as account theft and asset freezing. Choosing a large, reputable brokerage can better protect your account security.</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">III. Q&amp;A Session 
    <div id="iii-qa-session" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii-qa-session" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p><strong>Dave:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing:</strong>
Shared the results of James&rsquo; TQQQ simulation backtest and raised the question of how to avoid the risk of a sharp TQQQ drawdown.</li>
<li><strong>Question and James&rsquo;s Reply:</strong>
James believes that it is impossible to predict the market and avoid all risks completely. The important thing is to control risk exposure and avoid over-betting. If you are worried about the volatility of TQQQ, you can choose a more conservative investment strategy, such as QQQ. James also reminds everyone to distinguish between personal thinking and public advice, and not to be easily swayed by the thoughts of others.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Minjianlian:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing:</strong>
Shared his experience of investing in stocks through his company&rsquo;s savings association, as well as discussions about the MAGS fund and emergency funds.</li>
<li><strong>Question and James&rsquo;s Reply:</strong>
<ol>
<li>About the MAGS fund: James believes that it is uncertain whether the MAGS fund can outperform QQQ in the long term. Investment should choose targets that have been tested by time, such as QQQ or SPY.</li>
<li>About emergency funds: James believes that emergency funds are a personal responsibility and government policies cannot be relied upon entirely. Everyone should prepare sufficient emergency funds according to their own circumstances to cope with contingencies.</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Learn:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Question and James&rsquo;s Reply:</strong>
Regarding the performance of 00670L, James explained the performance difference caused by USD hedging and how to solve it by investing in QLD through sub-brokerage. He emphasized that Beta and ROI are different concepts. Beta represents volatility, not ROI. The investment model in Taiwan needs to be adjusted according to specific circumstances, such as  maintenance margin requirements and exchange rate fluctuations.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>JJU:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing:</strong>
Shared his insights on market unpredictability and the importance of mentors and friends. He believes that investing, in addition to selecting good targets, is more about maintaining inner peace and enhancing one&rsquo;s spiritual level.</li>
<li><strong>Question and James&rsquo;s Reply:</strong>
<ol>
<li>About the difference between reinvest and buy share: James explained the difference between reinvesting and buying shares. The former automatically invests dividends or capital gains into the investment target, while the latter uses new funds to buy shares.</li>
<li>About the fund ratio of Roth IRA and Individual Brokerage Account: It is recommended to maximize the Roth IRA limit if possible.</li>
<li>About real estate mortgage investment: It is recommended to sell the property if possible to reduce the risk of investing in real estate. Otherwise, consider a Home Equity Line of Credit (HELOC) for investment, but pay attention to risk control and ensure that you can repay the loan on time. HELOC is a revolving credit line, similar to a credit card, which can be withdrawn and repaid at any time.</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Draft down:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing:</strong>
Proposed the possibility of leveraging 0% interest credit cards for investment and using the box spread strategy to increase capital utilization.</li>
<li><strong>Question and James&rsquo;s Reply:</strong>
<ol>
<li>About credit card investment: James believes that credit card limits are limited and there is a risk of not being able to renew the loan, making it unsuitable as a main source of investment funds. It is only suitable for short-term turnover of small amounts of funds.</li>
<li>About the box spread strategy: James believes that the box spread strategy is too complex and risky and is not recommended for ordinary investors.</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Jason:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Question and James&rsquo;s Reply:</strong>
<ol>
<li>How to overcome short-term pain in the investment process: James suggested lowering expectations, not pursuing perfection or getting rich quickly, finding solutions to problems, and transferring the pressure to those who can bear it, such as superiors or more experienced individuals. Think about solutions for the worst-case scenario, such as job loss or investment losses, and maintain a positive mindset, believing that the problem will eventually be solved.</li>
<li>About non-US tax resident investing in US stocks: James believes that non-US tax residents can use their passports to open brokerage accounts in the US without a Social Security Number. It is recommended to choose large, reputable brokers, such as Charles Schwab, and avoid using online brokers, such as Webull and Robinhood, as online brokers have security risks and imperfect regulations.</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">IV. Key Insights 
    <div id="iv-key-insights" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv-key-insights" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>Investment is a loser&rsquo;s game, not seeking to win, but seeking not to lose.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>In investing, avoiding mistakes is more important than pursuing victory. Choosing the right investment target, formulating a reasonable investment strategy and strictly adhering to discipline can reduce mistakes and ultimately achieve long-term stable returns.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Buying in a lump sum at any time and holding for the long term is superior to other investment methods.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Investing early and holding for the long term maximizes returns and delivers the best investment returns. Time is a friend of investment. Starting early allows time to work its magic of compounding.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>All pressure comes from expectations, and all worries come from not having a solution.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Lower your expectations and actively seek solutions to relieve stress and anxiety. When facing challenges, maintain a positive attitude and believe that you can find a way to solve the problem.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Wealth is accumulated slowly, and enjoying the process of wealth accumulation is the meaning of life.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Getting rich overnight or quickly is not the best way. Slowly accumulating wealth and enjoying it allows you to experience the true meaning of life. Investing is a long-term process. Don&rsquo;t be impatient and enjoy the process of wealth accumulation, learning and growing from it.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Good teachers and helpful friends are important. You may not be right if you agree with someone.
&ndash; JJU</p>
</blockquote>
<p>In the investment process, be good at learning and thinking. Don&rsquo;t blindly believe anyone&rsquo;s point of view, including teachers and friends. Make your own independent thinking and judgment to make the right investment decisions.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Account security is the primary issue in investing.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Choosing a large, reputable brokerage to open an account, such as Charles Schwab, can better protect your account security. Avoid using online brokers as online brokers have security risks and imperfect regulations.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">V. Summary 
    <div id="v-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#v-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This session focuses on the long-term investment philosophy, risk control, and mindset management. James helps students better understand the essence of investment through vivid examples and in-depth explanations. He answers students&rsquo; various questions encountered in the investment process, such as the risks of TQQQ, the importance of emergency funds, and real estate investment strategies. At the same time, students also actively share their experiences and confusion, such as using credit cards for investment and using the box spread strategy, triggering deeper thinking and discussion. James emphasizes the importance of independent thinking, advising against blindly believing anyone&rsquo;s point of view. He encourages making independent thinking and judgment to make the right investment decisions. At the same time, he also reminds everyone to pay attention to account security, choose large, reputable brokers to open accounts, and avoid using online brokers.</p>

  



<div
  
    class="flex px-4 py-3 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900"
  >

  <span
    
      class="text-primary-400 ltr:pr-3 rtl:pl-3 flex items-center"
    >

    

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M506.3 417l-213.3-364c-16.33-28-57.54-28-73.98 0l-213.2 364C-10.59 444.9 9.849 480 42.74 480h426.6C502.1 480 522.6 445 506.3 417zM232 168c0-13.25 10.75-24 24-24S280 154.8 280 168v128c0 13.25-10.75 24-23.1 24S232 309.3 232 296V168zM256 416c-17.36 0-31.44-14.08-31.44-31.44c0-17.36 14.07-31.44 31.44-31.44s31.44 14.08 31.44 31.44C287.4 401.9 273.4 416 256 416z"/></svg>

  </span>


  </span>

  <span
    
      class="dark:text-neutral-300"
    ><strong>Disclaimer:</strong> This article is only for personal learning notes and does not constitute any investment advice.</span>
</div>

]]></content:encoded></item></channel></rss>