<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Market Psychology on QQQ Investor</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/tags/market-psychology/</link><description>Recent content in Market Psychology on QQQ Investor</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jomonylw.github.io/en/tags/market-psychology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>00543 What to Do When the Market Is Fearful? Market Fear and the Mindset for Getting Rich in the Prison of Real Estate!</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1765076605184/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1765076605184/</guid><description>In this session, Teacher James shares his optimistic forecast for the December market, emphasizing that investors should get in as soon as possible. The core idea is &amp;#39;survival first, profit later,&amp;#39; meaning long-term returns are contingent on being able to withstand market volatility without being liquidated. This session highlights QQQI as a retirement cash flow tool and delves into the concept of real estate as a consumer good rather than an investment. Additionally, James provides updates on Canadian tax regulations, market capital flow (end of QT), and reiterates the importance of fraud prevention and the compliance of US stock pledging.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<lite-youtube videoid="cQSeuySP8jk" playlabel="cQSeuySP8jk" params=""></lite-youtube>



<h2 class="relative group">I. Topic of the Session 
    <div id="i-topic-of-the-session" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-topic-of-the-session" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This session focuses on <strong>the mindset and actions investors should adopt amidst optimistic market expectations</strong>. The core idea is that the market is on the verge of a significant rally, and investors should enter decisively without hesitation. Teacher James emphasizes that the key to successful investing is <strong>&ldquo;survival first, profit later.&rdquo;</strong> Only by staying in the market for the long term and enduring all volatility can one ultimately enjoy the rich rewards of compounding. Therefore, constructing an asset allocation that allows you to weather any storm is crucial.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">II. Briefing Content 
    <div id="ii-briefing-content" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii-briefing-content" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Market Views &amp; Investment Mentality 
    <div id="market-views--investment-mentality" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#market-views--investment-mentality" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Market Outlook &amp; Capital Flow</strong>: The market is poised for a breakout to new highs. A strong rally is expected in December. An important backdrop is that QT (Quantitative Tightening) ended on December 1st. The central bank will now inject about $15 billion into the market weekly, totaling around $50 billion per month. This will create a massive capital flow, driving the market upward.</li>
<li><strong>The First Principle of Investing: Survive</strong>:
<ul>
<li>An annualized return of 15% is predicated on being able to stay invested for over 30 years without being liquidated due to fear or excessive leverage. If you exit midway, even the highest returns are irrelevant to you.</li>
<li>It&rsquo;s better to choose a stable asset allocation that can survive any risk, even if the annualized return is only 7%. The key is to survive for 30 years or even longer.</li>
<li>The core of investing is <strong>doing the right thing</strong>. Regardless of the market&rsquo;s current state, you should always be buying. Be happy when it goes up, and don&rsquo;t panic when it goes down.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Coping with Market Sentiment</strong>:
<ul>
<li>The principle of &ldquo;be greedy when others are fearful, and fearful when others are greedy&rdquo; is hard to execute. The simplest way to practice it is to <strong>resolutely not sell</strong>.</li>
<li>Investors need to admit that they &ldquo;know nothing&rdquo; and cannot predict market highs or lows. This allows them to respect the market and hold for the long term.</li>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo;s channel teaches only one thing: buy bravely and consistently, never sell, and you will succeed.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Investment Tools &amp; Strategy Introduction (QQQI) 
    <div id="investment-tools--strategy-introduction-qqqi" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#investment-tools--strategy-introduction-qqqi" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Background</strong>: To provide a new option for retirees who need a stable cash flow.</li>
<li><strong>Ticker Introduction</strong>: QQQI (Nasdaq-100 Enhanced Opt &amp; Growth ETF).</li>
<li><strong>Features &amp; Advantages</strong>:
<ol>
<li><strong>High Dividend</strong>: The dividend yield can reach 12%. For example, an investment of $1 million can generate $120,000 in cash flow per year ($10,000 per month); an investment of $5 million can yield $600,000 per year ($50,000 per month).</li>
<li><strong>Lowers the Retirement Threshold</strong>: For retirees who haven&rsquo;t prepared 25-30 times their annual expenses, investing just 8-10 times their annual expenses in QQQI can generate enough cash flow to cover living costs.</li>
<li><strong>Operational &amp; Tax Advantages</strong>: QQQI distributes dividends derived from a portion of capital gains (from selling appreciated stocks) and income from selling covered call options (about 4-5% annually). For Taiwanese investors using a brokerage with QI (Qualified Intermediary) status (like E.Sun, Yuanta, Cathay, SinoPac, etc.), most of the dividend income, being sourced from capital gains, is eligible for a tax refund. Approximately 96% of the dividends can be refunded.</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Personal Finance &amp; Life Philosophy 
    <div id="personal-finance--life-philosophy" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#personal-finance--life-philosophy" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Act Decisively</strong>: Investors who are still hesitating and haven&rsquo;t entered the market should stop &ldquo;daydreaming.&rdquo; Be &ldquo;ruthless&rdquo; in your actions—immediately sell what you shouldn&rsquo;t hold, buy the correct asset allocation, and then &ldquo;get on the bus and go to sleep.&rdquo; Financial freedom won&rsquo;t be far off.</li>
<li><strong>A House is a Consumer Good, Not an Investment</strong>:
<ul>
<li>If you&rsquo;ve reached a level of wealth where &ldquo;buying a house is like buying a pair of slippers,&rdquo; then buying a luxury home to enjoy life is perfectly fine.</li>
<li>But beware of becoming &ldquo;high-income but exquisitely poor,&rdquo; where your cash flow is extremely tight just to maintain a lavish home. This is akin to buying yourself a giant &ldquo;cage.&rdquo;</li>
<li><strong>The Correct Sequence</strong>: You should invest first and let your money make money. For example, <strong>if you have $1 million now, first invest it to grow into $200 million, and only then take out $100 million to buy a house.</strong> This way, you can truly enjoy the pleasure of living without being shackled by your property.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Subconscious and Manifestation</strong>: It is recommended to watch a video in the presentation notes that teaches how to connect your subconscious with universal energy. The core principle is to &ldquo;believe&rdquo; first, then meditate in a state of peace, happiness, and love, which makes it easier to manifest your desires.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Other Supplements &amp; Reminders 
    <div id="other-supplements--reminders" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#other-supplements--reminders" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Fraud Prevention</strong>: A reminder that there are many impersonators and scams on Clubhouse and other platforms. Scammer IDs (like <code>clecchman</code>) are very similar to the teacher&rsquo;s ID (<code>clecchirman</code>) and use GPT to mimic his tone in private messages. Please be sure to verify by checking follower counts (the teacher has 4.3K followers) and other means.</li>
<li><strong>Book Commentary</strong>: Mentioned that &ldquo;Dr. Huang Pei-Yuan&rsquo;s Bible of Financial Management&rdquo; is a good book, but its sequel, &ldquo;Financial EQ,&rdquo; was likely a cash grab by the publisher with mostly filler content. Reading the first book is sufficient.</li>
<li><strong>Canadian Tax Update</strong>:
<ul>
<li>2025: 50% of capital gains will be included in the year&rsquo;s income.</li>
<li>Starting 2026: For capital gains exceeding C$250,000, 67% of the excess amount will be included in the year&rsquo;s income.</li>
<li>As long as you don&rsquo;t sell, no capital gains tax will be incurred.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">III. Q&amp;A Session 
    <div id="iii-qa-session" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii-qa-session" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Celine 
    <div id="celine" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#celine" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing:
<ol>
<li><strong>Regarding QQQI Tax Refund</strong>: Taiwanese investors need to confirm if their brokerage has &ldquo;QI status.&rdquo; If so, they can get a tax refund on their QQQI investment. The method may vary; some brokerages don&rsquo;t withhold tax upfront, while others withhold and then refund it. Most medium to large brokerages have QI status.</li>
<li><strong>The Ease and Persistence of Investing</strong>: Any diligent investment method can make money, but Teacher James&rsquo;s method is the most effortless and worry-free. However, &ldquo;buy whenever you have money, and never sell&rdquo; is easier said than done. It requires personally experiencing severe market volatility (like in 2022) to truly test one&rsquo;s mentality.</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Haiwai Guzhong 
    <div id="haiwai-guzhong" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#haiwai-guzhong" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question: With the development of AI, will countries like Vietnam and Indonesia lose the opportunity to transition from labor-intensive to tech-based economies, as Taiwan and South Korea did, and thus be permanently locked at the bottom of the value chain?
<ul>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo;s Reply: This issue is more severe than imagined. The impact of AI is global, not just limited to developing countries. Taiwan&rsquo;s semiconductor industry could also be replaced by fully automated AI factories. The future society will be divided into a tiny minority of capitalists (about 0.1%) and a vast majority of ordinary people (99.9%) dependent on social welfare. The only way out is to become a capitalist—get on board (invest) as soon as possible to enjoy the dividends of this technological revolution. Otherwise, everyone could be left behind by the times.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Zhihong 
    <div id="zhihong" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#zhihong" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question: I am 45, my father has cancer. After selling a house, we have NT$8 million in cash, but annual expenses are NT$1.1 million. I want to take out a NT$6 million loan against my mortgage-free house to invest in QQQI, using the cash flow to support my father. I also hope my father will invest, but it&rsquo;s hard to convince him. What is your advice?
<ul>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo;s Reply: You are very filial, but you don&rsquo;t need to worry excessively about your father&rsquo;s finances. Right now, <strong>companionship and care are far more important to your father than investment advice.</strong> You should spend more time with him and cherish this period. You can use the NT$6 million loan to invest for yourself, and the returns can be used to support your mother in the future. You don&rsquo;t need to spend excessively on talent classes for your children; playing with them is the best education.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Yue Feng 
    <div id="yue-feng" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#yue-feng" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question: Fubon in Taiwan recently launched a Nasdaq-100 index fund with an &ldquo;automatic dip-buying&rdquo; feature. Can I buy this instead of 00662?
<ul>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo;s Reply: Don&rsquo;t buy it. It&rsquo;s a mutual fund with extra custodian fees. And you don&rsquo;t need a &ldquo;dip-buying&rdquo; feature; the market is about to rally strongly. If you have money, you should buy 00662 immediately. Don&rsquo;t play around with those complicated, esoteric products.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Sherry 
    <div id="sherry" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#sherry" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question 1: I have initial capital and a monthly salary. Should I DCA monthly, or accumulate for a year and then rebalance according to the 433 strategy?
<ul>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo;s Reply: Buy whenever you have money each month. Don&rsquo;t wait a year.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2: Using the 433 allocation, what should I do with the money borrowed from a stock pledge if I don&rsquo;t need it immediately?
<ul>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo;s Reply: <strong>(Extremely Important Warning!)</strong> If you are in the United States, money borrowed from a pledge <strong>absolutely cannot</strong> be put back into a securities account. The fund flow must be clearly for consumption. A friend has already been asked by Schwab to close their pledge account for this reason, or face a forced sale of stocks to repay the loan. The consequences are severe. If you are not in the US, this amount (at most 2% of assets borrowed annually) is small, so reinvesting it won&rsquo;t have a major impact.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Frank 
    <div id="frank" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#frank" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question: I am 40, with a NT$5.5 million personal loan and NT$7 million in my own funds. Can I use the most aggressive &ldquo;442&rdquo; asset allocation?
<ul>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo;s Reply: Absolutely not recommended. The risk is too high; even I wouldn&rsquo;t do that. Use the &ldquo;433&rdquo; allocation at most. As long as there is debt, there is risk. You cannot be overly aggressive.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Luu 
    <div id="luu" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#luu" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Sending greetings from Bali, complimenting the teacher for looking like Chow Yun-fat with sunglasses on in a group photo, saying he looked very charming.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Lily 
    <div id="lily" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#lily" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing:
<ol>
<li><strong>Stocks vs. Real Estate</strong>: After some thought, she concluded that stocks grow through compounding, while real estate&rsquo;s advantage is leverage. However, due to the growth rate difference between stocks (~10%) and real estate (~6%), plus loan interest, the leverage advantage of real estate is depleted after about 7-8 years. After that, the growth curve of stocks will far surpass that of real estate.</li>
<li><strong>Cash Management in China</strong>: In the Chinese stock market, unused cash can earn interest through &ldquo;government bond reverse repos,&rdquo; which can be selected on a daily basis and are very flexible. The interest rates can sometimes be very high before public holidays.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>Question:
<ol>
<li>Which Nasdaq-100 ETF should I invest in in China?</li>
<li>My personal financial situation is very good, and I hope to maximize long-term returns. How should I allocate my assets?</li>
<li>My current small brokerage in the US charges commissions as high as 1.5-2%. Should I move to Schwab?</li>
<li>How can I join the LINE group?</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo;s Reply:
<ol>
<li>The 159509 she bought before is a technology fund, not a Nasdaq-100 index. It&rsquo;s recommended to choose the tickers we suggest.</li>
<li>Since you can tolerate high volatility, you can use a very aggressive allocation: <strong>85% QQQ + 10% QLD + 5% TQQQ</strong>, and rebalance once a year.</li>
<li><strong>Transfer immediately!</strong> Your brokerage&rsquo;s fees are extremely high and it&rsquo;s not safe. Schwab is the best choice—it&rsquo;s secure and commission-free.</li>
<li>The LINE group has regional restrictions; US numbers might not be able to join, but you can try.</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Susan (AV) 
    <div id="susan-av" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#susan-av" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: She is a Buddhist. After listening to the teacher&rsquo;s class, she felt like the &ldquo;God of Wealth had arrived,&rdquo; and she was finally liberated from the &ldquo;samsara&rdquo; of daily market-watching, chasing highs and lows, and constant anxiety. She converted all her stocks to 00662, feels an unprecedented sense of peace, and has started teaching her children to invest so they can all be wealthy in the future. She also strongly agrees with the teacher&rsquo;s educational philosophy, sharing her own experience of supporting her son&rsquo;s dream to pursue photography instead of going to university, and how he ultimately lived a wonderful life.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Danken 
    <div id="danken" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#danken" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question: I just arrived in the US. The best option in my 401K is an S&amp;P 500 fund. My Roth IRA is allocated to QLD, and I have cash (in BOX) in my personal brokerage account. In the long run, the proportion of the S&amp;P 500 will become too high. How should I adjust?
<ul>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo;s Reply: Your setup is fine. Max out your 401K with the S&amp;P 500 and max out your Roth IRA with QLD. In your personal brokerage account, keep six months of living expenses in BOX (don&rsquo;t buy SGOV, as the dividends are taxable), and invest the rest of the funds <strong>entirely in QQQ</strong>.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chris 
    <div id="chris" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chris" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: He helped his mother get a home equity line of credit for investment purposes. In the process, he discovered that a &ldquo;villa&rdquo; his mother was proud of was actually built on agricultural and pastoral land, which the bank would not appraise, making its value very low. This experience made his mother realize that the value of real estate is not as stable as she thought, and she began to accept the idea of investing in 00662.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Washing, W 
    <div id="washing-w" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#washing-w" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question: I am 62 and a half. Should I start collecting my own Social Security now, or collect half of my ex-husband&rsquo;s first and wait until I&rsquo;m 71 to collect my own?
<ul>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo;s Reply: Don&rsquo;t wait. Compare which amount is higher right now and start collecting that one immediately. The returns from investing the money you receive will far exceed the increase from waiting.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Paiqing 
    <div id="paiqing" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#paiqing" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Responding to a previous member whose family member has lung cancer, she shared her own experience of her father passing away from the same illness 10 years ago. She comforted the member, saying that health insurance covers a lot of the costs, so money is not the biggest issue. What&rsquo;s more important is to cherish the time with your father. Take him out more, because in the later stages of lung cancer, bone metastasis can affect mobility. You will have money in the future, but the time for companionship is finite.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Li Xianhong 
    <div id="li-xianhong" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#li-xianhong" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question: The teacher said not to buy insurance. Does that include term life insurance?
<ul>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo;s Reply: If you still have young children to support, buying term life insurance is acceptable.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">YKY 
    <div id="yky" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#yky" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing and Questions:
<ol>
<li>Sharing: From mainland China, he just discovered the channel last week and felt a sense of &ldquo;sudden enlightenment,&rdquo; with hope for his future. He and his wife had followed the traditional path of buying a house and taking on a mortgage, leading to immense pressure. After listening to the teacher&rsquo;s classes, his mindset completely changed. He no longer frets over grievances at work because he knows he will be wealthy in the future.</li>
<li>Question 1: I have a mortgage (covered by the Housing Provident Fund) and a personal loan. How should I handle them?</li>
<li>Question 2: I have 100,000 RMB available for investment (after setting aside six months of living expenses). Should I allocate it as 80% index / 20% cash?</li>
<li>Question 3: I&rsquo;ve opened a Schwab account and plan to open an account in Hong Kong in the future for pledging. Is this plan feasible?</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo;s Reply:
<ol>
<li>Continue to use the Provident Fund for the mortgage. For the personal loan, don&rsquo;t rush to pay off the principal; just pay the interest and use it as a revolving line of credit.</li>
<li>Yes, apply an 80/20 allocation to all your investable assets. The 20% cash can be put into a money market fund.</li>
<li>The plan is excellent. Start transferring some funds to Hong Kong annually now. Once the capital reaches a certain size, you can start pledging. This is a correct ten-year plan. Also, don&rsquo;t be afraid to have a second child because of financial pressure. You will be very wealthy in the future, and having more children will make your family happier.</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">IV. Insightful Quotes 
    <div id="iv-insightful-quotes" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv-insightful-quotes" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>You only have a tomorrow in the market if you survive; only then can you talk about a rate of return.
&ndash; Teacher James</p></blockquote>
<p>This quote emphasizes that the prerequisite for long-term investment success is the ability to withstand any market fluctuation without being forced out. Survival is the first element of profit.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>If you can buy a house like you buy a pair of slippers—just get another pair if you don&rsquo;t like them—then you can buy one. If you can&rsquo;t be that magnanimous, then a house is just a big cage.
&ndash; Teacher James</p></blockquote>
<p>This quote vividly defines a house as a consumer good rather than an investment, advising people not to be shackled by property and become &ldquo;exquisitely poor.&rdquo;</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Only the capitalists can enjoy the greatest dividends of human transformation&hellip; otherwise, everyone will perish.
&ndash; Teacher James</p></blockquote>
<p>In response to the impact of AI on future social structures, the teacher points out that in the face of disruptive technological change, becoming a capitalist (an investor) is the only way out for ordinary people.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>After I learned about the teacher, I felt as if the God of Wealth had arrived. I am about to escape that cycle of samsara.
&ndash; Susan</p></blockquote>
<p>A student shares her feeling of liberation from the &ldquo;samsara&rdquo; of chasing highs and lows and daily anxiety after learning the investment philosophy, expressing her hope for the future.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>When I saw the teacher&rsquo;s video on Saturday, I had a sudden enlightenment. I feel there is still hope for my future.
&ndash; YKY</p></blockquote>
<p>A young student from mainland China, who was feeling suffocated by the &ldquo;buy a house, pay off the mortgage&rdquo; model, felt his life was illuminated and his hope was renewed after being exposed to the investment philosophy.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Money is actually the least of your worries. What matters is how you accompany your father to the end&hellip; cherish the time you have with him.
&ndash; Paiqing</p></blockquote>
<p>A student uses her personal experience to comfort another member whose family member has cancer, reminding everyone that in the face of life&rsquo;s ultimate challenges, money is far less important than love and companionship.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">V. Summary 
    <div id="v-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#v-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This session began with a very optimistic market forecast (end of QT, influx of capital) and reinforced CLEC&rsquo;s core investment philosophy: <strong>simple, persistent, and brave</strong>. Teacher James not only gave clear instructions—&ldquo;keep buying, don&rsquo;t sell&rdquo;—but also built a solid theoretical foundation from both psychological and strategic standpoints. Whether it was emphasizing the importance of &ldquo;survival,&rdquo; introducing the powerful retirement cash flow tool QQQI, or subverting the traditional concept that &ldquo;a house is a cage,&rdquo; the goal was to help investors establish a correct view of wealth, break free from anxiety, and embark on a relaxed yet firm path to financial freedom. The enthusiastic sharing and questions from the students also provided vivid interpretations and applications of these concepts in real-life situations.</p>

  



<div
  
    class="flex px-4 py-3 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900"
  >

  <span
    
      class="text-primary-400 ltr:pr-3 rtl:pl-3 flex items-center"
    >

    

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M506.3 417l-213.3-364c-16.33-28-57.54-28-73.98 0l-213.2 364C-10.59 444.9 9.849 480 42.74 480h426.6C502.1 480 522.6 445 506.3 417zM232 168c0-13.25 10.75-24 24-24S280 154.8 280 168v128c0 13.25-10.75 24-23.1 24S232 309.3 232 296V168zM256 416c-17.36 0-31.44-14.08-31.44-31.44c0-17.36 14.07-31.44 31.44-31.44s31.44 14.08 31.44 31.44C287.4 401.9 273.4 416 256 416z"/></svg>

  </span>


  </span>

  <span
    
      class="dark:text-neutral-300"
    ><strong>Disclaimer:</strong> This article is for personal study notes only and does not constitute any investment advice.</span>
</div>

]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>00529 Raising Children is Better Than Maintaining a House: The Truth About Reverse Mortgages and Retirement Cash Flow</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1756605737350/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1756605737350/</guid><description>In this session, Teacher James shares the core mindset of investing: the market always goes up, and investors should focus on their own lives rather than external distractions. The content covers life philosophy, children&amp;#39;s education, asset allocation, reverse mortgages, and pledged loans, emphasizing the importance of intrinsic value and a long-term perspective.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<lite-youtube videoid="6znudRqitcQ" playlabel="6znudRqitcQ" params=""></lite-youtube>



<h2 class="relative group">I. Main Theme 
    <div id="i-main-theme" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-main-theme" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This session&rsquo;s theme revolves around &ldquo;The market always goes up, live for yourself.&rdquo; The core idea is that the essence of investing is very simple: believe in the market&rsquo;s long-term upward trend and hold on. The real challenge is psychological. Therefore, we should not be disturbed by short-term market fluctuations, financial news, world events, or other external information. Instead, we should shift our focus back to life itself—concentrating on health, happiness, family, and personal values, viewing money as a tool to achieve freedom and abundance in life, not as the ultimate goal.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">II. Briefing Content 
    <div id="ii-briefing-content" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii-briefing-content" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Life is More Important Than Investing 
    <div id="life-is-more-important-than-investing" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#life-is-more-important-than-investing" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Wealth and Happiness</strong>: Wealth is a gift, happiness is a human right, and health is the foundation. Money is just a tool to achieve a free, abundant, and happy life; investing itself is not the purpose of life.</li>
<li><strong>Children&rsquo;s Education</strong>:
<ul>
<li>Focus on cultivating the right values in children (not stealing, robbing, breaking the law, or taking drugs) and appreciating their talents, rather than just focusing on academic performance.</li>
<li>Parents should not impose their own expectations or unfulfilled dreams on their children, such as forcing them to study abroad. This puts immense pressure on the children.</li>
<li>A true home is where the parents are. Children should be encouraged to pursue their own ideals, not to satisfy their parents&rsquo; expectations.</li>
<li>Compared to buying a house for a child, it&rsquo;s better to have and raise the child first, because wealth can be created, but childbirth has a time window.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Live in the Present, Focus on Yourself</strong>:
<ul>
<li>In life, focus on your own goals. Don&rsquo;t get sidetracked by trivial matters (like fussing over exchange rates or searching for better investments), as this will only delay the process of achieving financial freedom.</li>
<li>Teacher James uses his own management experience as an example: At the company, he focused on only the three most important tasks each day. Once completed, he could go home. This approach is efficient and goal-oriented. Conversely, trying to do everything results in being busy all day with nothing accomplished.</li>
<li>Live your own life, not one led by the media and online information. Cutting off useless external information will not result in any loss.</li>
<li>True living is about &ldquo;presence&rdquo;—living in the moment. Whether eating, gardening, or traveling, you should be fully engaged and feel the beauty of life itself. External distractions, like what Trump said, have no bearing on our lives or investments.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Investment Strategies and Financial Tools 
    <div id="investment-strategies-and-financial-tools" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#investment-strategies-and-financial-tools" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Do the Right Thing and Persist</strong>: The secret to successful investing is to &ldquo;do the right thing and stick with it for the long term.&rdquo; For example, invest whenever you have money, regardless of the exchange rate, without timing the market. Once you have identified the right path (like investing in QQQ), you should forge ahead without looking back.</li>
<li><strong>Reverse Mortgage</strong>:
<ul>
<li>This is an excellent tool for &ldquo;activating assets&rdquo; and is not just for people short on cash.</li>
<li>It provides a steady cash flow, as if the house is working for you. This money can be used for investment, thus increasing your assets while retaining the property.</li>
<li>It&rsquo;s a great option for parents with insufficient retirement funds, allowing them to live better lives without their children needing to provide financial support.</li>
<li>For elderly individuals with weak financial management skills and only one house left, a reverse mortgage is more stable than selling the house to invest, avoiding the risk of losing their last home.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>The Power of Borrowing to Invest</strong>:
<ul>
<li>An example: If you use your own $30,000 to buy a car, the potential value of that money in 50 years (about $32 million) is lost. But if you take a pledged loan of $30,000 to buy the car and invest your own $30,000, in 50 years you will have $32 million in assets, while the debt is only $340,000.</li>
<li>Conclusion: Make good use of financial leverage. Borrow for consumption or investment, and let your own money continue to grow.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Example of Leveraged Asset Allocation</strong>:
<ul>
<li>Teacher James shares his asset allocation model: 40% QQQ (1x), 15% QLD (2x), 10% TQQQ (3x), and 35% cash.</li>
<li>The Beta value of this portfolio is calculated as: (40% * 1) + (15% * 2) + (10% * 3) = 0.4 + 0.3 + 0.3 = 1.0.</li>
<li>This allocation, while having an overall risk comparable to holding 100% QQQ (Beta=1.0), retains a large amount of cash (35%) for risk control and rebalancing during market downturns.</li>
<li><strong>Key Point</strong>: Any asset allocation that includes leveraged funds <strong>must</strong> implement a smart rebalancing strategy.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">III. Q&amp;A Session 
    <div id="iii-qa-session" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii-qa-session" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Cady 
    <div id="cady" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#cady" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: She once went against everyone&rsquo;s advice to support her sister&rsquo;s dream of a working holiday in Australia. Now, her sister is living very happily in Germany. She has come to realize that since her child doesn&rsquo;t want to study abroad, she&rsquo;ll save the money for her own study tours in retirement. She is practicing not imposing her expectations on her child.
<ul>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo;s Comment: That&rsquo;s excellent. One must live for oneself, not for others. Don&rsquo;t impose your expectations on people. For children, parents only have the duty to agree, not the right to disagree. Your child&rsquo;s life is not under your jurisdiction.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chen Feng 
    <div id="chen-feng" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chen-feng" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing:
<ol>
<li>He has compiled his years of learning from the teacher into the &ldquo;Great Way is Simple Investment Method&rdquo; and created the &ldquo;Chen Feng Leads the Way&rdquo; website to share it.</li>
<li>He summarizes the CLEC investment method into three simple but not easy things: <strong>Asset Allocation</strong> (70/30 for beginners, eventually 433), <strong>Rebalancing</strong> (once a year), and <strong>Living off Pledged Loans</strong>.</li>
<li>He believes the hardest part of investing is psychology, which is why the teacher insists on holding weekly classes to help everyone adjust their mindset.</li>
<li>He announced his official retirement in August 2025 and will have more time in the future to share his experiences and help more people achieve the ideal that &ldquo;wealth is a gift, happiness is a human right.&rdquo;</li>
</ol>
<ul>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo;s Comment: Thank you to Chen Feng (a senior executive at a high-tech company in Taiwan) for his sharing and contributions. He has done a lot for the community (website, AI training) and actively helps everyone in the LINE group. Teacher James announced that he is making him a community Moderator.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Hai Wai Gu Zhong 
    <div id="hai-wai-gu-zhong" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#hai-wai-gu-zhong" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: After renting out a house he owns, he recently took it back for his own use and found being a landlord very troublesome. He had to deal with various damages and cleaning for walls, doors, and windows, and deeply realized that the actual return on real estate investment is not as high as it seems.</li>
<li>Question 1: Since the house was bought by his family, he can&rsquo;t sell it freely. He&rsquo;s thinking of taking out a mortgage-like loan on the house (interest-only payments) and investing the cash into 00662. Is this idea feasible?
<ul>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo;s Reply: Absolutely correct, you should do it immediately. Borrow any money you can as soon as possible. The power of borrowing to invest is immense. He demonstrated the huge opportunity cost difference by calculating the 50-year outcomes of buying a car with $30,000 versus borrowing $1 million.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2: The teacher advises young people to invest first and buy a house later when they are &ldquo;old.&rdquo; What age does &ldquo;old&rdquo; approximately refer to?
<ul>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo;s Reply: You will know when the time comes; you don&rsquo;t need someone else to tell you. When you are wealthy enough, buying a house will be as easy as buying slippers, and you can even use borrowed money to buy one casually. At that point, you could also choose to live in a luxurious retirement community—the choice is yours.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">May 
    <div id="may" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#may" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question: She is in her fifties/sixties and wants to take out a pledged loan in China on her fully paid-off house, but banks only offer a maximum term of 3-5 years, which is too risky. How does the teacher obtain long-term loans?
<ul>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo;s Reply: The best long-term loan is a &ldquo;stock-pledged loan,&rdquo; which can be structured to never pay back the principal, and even the interest can be rolled into the principal. Mortgages and personal loans have fixed terms and are not suitable. For short-term loans (like 3-5 years), don&rsquo;t borrow unless you are confident you can repay even if the market crashes. He suggests she sell her house in China, even at a lower price, as long as she can liquidate it. Abroad, she can try using Interactive Brokers (IB) for stock-pledged loans.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Rui 
    <div id="rui" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#rui" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Inspired by the teacher, he successfully borrowed a large sum of money from the bank against his assets and discovered that car loans don&rsquo;t count towards his debt ratio. He plans to use a 2% pledged loan to pay off the car loan, thereby investing more funds into the 433 allocation. He now feels that the speed of his asset growth has surpassed his annual salary.</li>
<li>Question: He saw a YouTuber say that Chinese engineers in Silicon Valley are unhappy due to endless &ldquo;comparisons&rdquo; (of degrees, companies, salaries, houses, wives, children). As someone with a master&rsquo;s degree, he also felt insecure in an environment full of PhDs. How does the teacher view &ldquo;comparison&rdquo;? And how can the teacher confidently pay his subordinates a higher salary than his own?
<ul>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo;s Reply: Quoting Munger, &ldquo;Envy is a really stupid sin.&rdquo; Don&rsquo;t compare; the key is a strong inner self. You must affirm from within that you are the best. The way you see yourself is more important than how others see you. He uses his own experience of leading a team of PhDs without a PhD himself, and designing Microsoft&rsquo;s Media architecture and the computer Hibernate patent, to illustrate that success is unrelated to academic degrees but is related to confidence and intellect.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Mindy 
    <div id="mindy" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#mindy" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question 1: She is 60 and retired. As recommended, she has allocated TQQQ in her smaller Roth IRA account. However, the AI on Chen Feng&rsquo;s website advises her not to use leverage at her age and to keep many years of cash. How much cash should a retiree actually keep? Is it 30% or 15 years&rsquo; worth of living expenses?
<ul>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo;s Reply: Don&rsquo;t fully trust the AI; follow the teacher&rsquo;s instruction. Her allocation (TQQQ in Roth, cash in Traditional IRA) is correct. Retirees should keep <strong>30% cash</strong>, which is approximately equivalent to <strong>15 years&rsquo; worth</strong> of living expenses. This is not due to pessimism about the market; on the contrary, the market may rise even faster in the future. This is the result of the CLEC investment system&rsquo;s &ldquo;DNA evolution&rdquo; after being tested by the market, making it better able to withstand future extreme risks.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2: She saw other financial bloggers advocating for market timing using &ldquo;economic indicator signals&rdquo; and is worried that buying TQQQ at a market high will lead to significant decay.
<ul>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo;s Reply: Don&rsquo;t refer to other people&rsquo;s investment systems; they won&rsquo;t be compatible. Within the 433 asset allocation, there is no so-called &ldquo;decay&rdquo; problem for TQQQ because the large cash reserve acts as a buffer, and the actual drop of the portfolio during a downturn will be less than that of 100% QQQ.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Tina 
    <div id="tina" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#tina" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question 1: She is 43 and just immigrated to the US. Her 401k and IRA accounts have very little money. To implement the 433 allocation, it seems she can only buy leveraged ETFs in a taxable brokerage account. Is this acceptable?
<ul>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo;s Reply: Yes. In the early stages when funds are insufficient, you can use a 433 allocation in a brokerage account to maintain a higher Beta and sufficient cash. Although rebalancing will generate taxes, the priority is to &ldquo;make money first.&rdquo; However, you must <strong>do smart rebalancing every year</strong>, because a 30% leveraged position is very risky and cannot be left unattended.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2: For dollar-cost averaging for an 11-year-old child, the teacher previously recommended QLD. Why not the better TQQQ?
<ul>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo;s Reply: TQQQ has extremely high volatility. Calculating from the 2000 peak, it might take over 20 years to break even, whereas QLD breaks even faster. For a child&rsquo;s long-term investment of over 20 years, both are acceptable, but the premise is that you <strong>must persist in buying continuously</strong>, regardless of market ups and downs. If the investment horizon is uncertain or you want to be more conservative, QLD is the safer choice.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Xin 
    <div id="xin" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#xin" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question: Should high-net-worth families be concerned about the 40% US estate tax? Should they set up an irrevocable trust in advance to avoid it?
<ul>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo;s Reply: First, the US estate tax exemption has been permanently set at $15 million per person, meaning a couple has a $30 million exemption. Most families don&rsquo;t need to worry. Second, he does not recommend setting up an irrevocable charitable trust because they usually require an annual donation of 5% of assets, which is a huge burden and constraint on the children. A better way is to use the annual gift tax exclusion (e.g., $20,000) and start gifting early. Over the long term, the growth of the gifted assets will far exceed the estate tax exemption amount.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Bill 
    <div id="bill" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#bill" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question: When the market drops and rebalancing is needed for the TQQQ in a Roth account, if the annual contribution limit of $7,000 is not enough, can funds be converted from a Traditional IRA?
<ul>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo;s Reply: Yes, that is exactly the correct operation. You can use the annual contribution limit, and if that&rsquo;s not enough, use a Roth Conversion to supplement the cash.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Lucy 
    <div id="lucy" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#lucy" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question: She (in Canada) obtained extra cash for investment through a home refinance. Can the interest on this portion of the loan be deducted as an investment expense for tax purposes?
<ul>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo;s Reply: Only when you sell an asset and generate a realized capital gain do you have taxable investment income against which related expenses might be deducted. If you just hold and don&rsquo;t sell, there is no taxable event. Canada&rsquo;s Tax-Free Savings Account (TFSA) is similar to the US Roth IRA, and investment and rebalancing operations should be conducted within it.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Vincent 
    <div id="vincent" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#vincent" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question (from the comment section): With 30 million TWD in assets, if I withdraw 2% for living expenses, 600,000 per year is not enough. Do I have to wait until my assets double to 60 million to live a good life?
<ul>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo;s Reply: Not necessarily. You can increase the withdrawal rate by adjusting your asset allocation. For example, you can change the 433 allocation (Beta=1) to a 424 or 514 allocation with a higher cash percentage, which lowers the portfolio&rsquo;s volatility (Beta&lt;1). Once the volatility is reduced, the annual withdrawal rate can be safely increased to 3% or 3.5%.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Student 
    <div id="student" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#student" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question (from the comment section): Is it okay for a 12-year-old child to dollar-cost average into 00670L (a 2x leveraged ETF in Taiwan)?
<ul>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo;s Reply: If you can ensure continuous investment for over 20 years (e.g., until age 32), it is acceptable. However, if the investment horizon is shorter (e.g., until they become independent at 24), it is recommended to do half-and-half (half leveraged, half non-leveraged) or invest entirely in the non-leveraged ETF to reduce risk.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">IV. Highlighted Quotes 
    <div id="iv-highlighted-quotes" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv-highlighted-quotes" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>Wealth is a gift, happiness is a human right, and health is the foundation of life.
&ndash; Teacher James</p></blockquote>
<p>Context: At the beginning of the class, the teacher explained the relationship between investment and life, emphasizing that our ultimate goals are happiness and health, while wealth is an innate right and a tool to achieve those goals.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Are you living your own life, or a life defined by the external environment? Don&rsquo;t be led by outside information.
&ndash; Teacher James</p></blockquote>
<p>Context: The teacher advised students not to be engrossed in media and online information all day, as that is living a life defined by others, not their own. One should return to their inner self and focus on their own life.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Envy is a really stupid sin.
&ndash; Teacher James (quoting Charlie Munger)</p></blockquote>
<p>Context: When answering a student&rsquo;s question about &ldquo;comparison,&rdquo; the teacher quoted Munger&rsquo;s famous line, pointing out that comparing oneself to others is a source of unhappiness and a foolish act.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>You are what you think you are, and that is more important than how others see you. If you don&rsquo;t even believe in what you are, how can others believe in what you are?
&ndash; Teacher James</p></blockquote>
<p>Context: The teacher encouraged students to build self-confidence. He believes that personal value is determined by self-perception, not by external evaluations or labels like academic degrees.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>When borrowing money, we don&rsquo;t fear high interest rates; we fear that the term is too short.
&ndash; Teacher James</p></blockquote>
<p>Context: When answering a question about loans, the teacher stressed the importance of the loan term. As long as the term is long enough, even with a higher interest rate, the long-term growth of assets is sufficient to cover the costs, whereas short-term loans carry immense risk.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Be clear about what you want. For everything else that is different from what you want, you don&rsquo;t need to care, you don&rsquo;t need to mind, and you don&rsquo;t need to compare.
&ndash; Chen Feng</p></blockquote>
<p>Context: Student Chen Feng shared this perspective when explaining how he avoids the &ldquo;comparison&rdquo; mindset. He believes that as long as you are clear about your own goals, you will not be disturbed by external factors unrelated to them.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>If you keep following our DNA, your DNA will evolve. This is how you can prepare for potential future risks and changes.
&ndash; Teacher James</p></blockquote>
<p>Context: When explaining why he now recommends holding more cash (30%), the teacher compared the CLEC investment system to a biological DNA. This system continuously evolves after being tested by the market, becoming better adapted to various future environments. Therefore, students need to keep learning to acquire this &ldquo;evolved&rdquo; and robust system.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>If you are 100% in leveraged funds, you might go to hell; it would be like a dream that ends in 30 years.
&ndash; Teacher James</p></blockquote>
<p>Context: When reminding students of the risks of leveraged funds, the teacher seriously pointed out that being fully invested in leveraged funds without asset allocation and rebalancing could ultimately lead to a total loss in a major market crash.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">V. Summary 
    <div id="v-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#v-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This session once again emphasized the core of the CLEC investment philosophy: investing is simple, mindset is supreme. Starting from a high-level life philosophy, Teacher James guided everyone to shift their focus from the complex noise of the market to the simple purity of their personal lives, fostering the belief to &ldquo;live for yourself.&rdquo; The course not only shared profound insights on children&rsquo;s education and self-worth realization but also delved into the practical application of financial tools like &ldquo;reverse mortgages&rdquo; and &ldquo;pledged loans.&rdquo; It also provided detailed explanations on the risk control and long-term operational principles of asset allocation (especially the 433 strategy involving leveraged funds). Through active questions and sharing from students, many practical confusions—such as allocation in different accounts, tax issues, and retirement cash flow planning—were clearly answered. Ultimately, the course returned to a fundamental point: build a strong inner self and adhere to the right principles, and wealth will naturally follow.</p>

  



<div
  
    class="flex px-4 py-3 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900"
  >

  <span
    
      class="text-primary-400 ltr:pr-3 rtl:pl-3 flex items-center"
    >

    

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M506.3 417l-213.3-364c-16.33-28-57.54-28-73.98 0l-213.2 364C-10.59 444.9 9.849 480 42.74 480h426.6C502.1 480 522.6 445 506.3 417zM232 168c0-13.25 10.75-24 24-24S280 154.8 280 168v128c0 13.25-10.75 24-23.1 24S232 309.3 232 296V168zM256 416c-17.36 0-31.44-14.08-31.44-31.44c0-17.36 14.07-31.44 31.44-31.44s31.44 14.08 31.44 31.44C287.4 401.9 273.4 416 256 416z"/></svg>

  </span>


  </span>

  <span
    
      class="dark:text-neutral-300"
    ><strong>Disclaimer:</strong> This article is for personal learning notes only and does not constitute any investment advice.</span>
</div>

]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>00513 The world is evolving: choosing the top index (e.g., Nasdaq 100), a reverie of the AI age</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1745714790157/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1745714790157/</guid><description>In this episode, James first announced the upcoming two-week Clubhouse hiatus and then emphasized that market volatility is normal and there&amp;#39;s no need to over-analyze the reasons behind it. The core arguments revolved around the importance of long-term investing and index funds (especially the Nasdaq 100), and discussed the selection of specific ETFs (such as 00864B/00865B, BRK, HXQ). He also shared his fantasies about the future development of AI, exploring its potential impact on social structures, work, and the meaning of life. The Q&amp;amp;A session covered a range of practical issues, including market predictions, asset allocation ratios (70/30 rule, Beta value), ETF selection in different countries, digital currency risks, differences in investment philosophies between spouses, and retirement cash reserves.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<lite-youtube videoid="5WJ_23Gpcg0" playlabel="5WJ_23Gpcg0" params=""></lite-youtube>



<h2 class="relative group">I. Episode Theme 
    <div id="i-episode-theme" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-episode-theme" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This episode revolves around the core concept of long-term investing, emphasizing the importance of maintaining composure amidst inevitable market fluctuations, adhering to investments in high-quality index funds (such as the Nasdaq 100), and exploring the profound impact of AI development on the future of society and personal wealth. It also provides in-depth answers to specific questions raised by students regarding investment tool selection, asset allocation strategies, and market psychology.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">II. Summary 
    <div id="ii-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Operations and Reminders 
    <div id="operations-and-reminders" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#operations-and-reminders" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Clubhouse Hiatus Announcement</strong>: Clubhouse and video uploads will be suspended for the next two weeks (May 3rd and May 10th), resuming on May 17th (Saturday).</li>
<li><strong>Clubhouse Technical Issues</strong>: Recent issues with sound being inaudible or too low. It&rsquo;s recommended to leave and re-enter the room, or completely close and reopen the app.</li>
<li><strong>Speaking Rules</strong>: Accidental stage entries are fine, just stay on stage; no need to repeatedly enter and exit.</li>
<li><strong>Disclaimer</strong>: All sharing is for reference only. Investment decisions are the individual&rsquo;s responsibility. We are not professional investment advisors or tax professionals; sharing is based on personal experience. Long-term investment has low risk, short-term investment has high risk. Those who cannot tolerate short-term losses or are worried about asset devaluation should not invest and can choose fixed deposits instead.</li>
<li><strong>Learning Resources</strong>: Lecture notes are pinned in the Clubhouse comment section or the YouTube comment section. Newcomers are advised to start with video 00451, then 398-402, and then the latest for systematic learning (although there are as many as four or five hundred videos).</li>
<li><strong>Community Groups</strong>: No official groups are established. Participation in unofficial groups requires caution. If the group information is noisy, annoying, and not beneficial to life, it is recommended to leave. Groups aimed at sharing CLEC concepts, helping each other answer questions, and providing information are welcome.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Investment Philosophy and Strategies 
    <div id="investment-philosophy-and-strategies" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#investment-philosophy-and-strategies" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Market Volatility is Normal</strong>: The market is always fluctuating; this is the unchanging rule. No need to analyze specific reasons (international situation, trade war, financial report forecasts, etc.). Many analysts themselves do not truly understand. The market is like the sea, unaffected by streams and storms.</li>
<li><strong>Long-Term Investing</strong>: True investment is buying with the intention of never selling. Intending to sell at a high point is speculation. Investment must be long-term.</li>
<li><strong>Index Investing</strong>:
<ul>
<li><strong>Core Recommendation</strong>: Nasdaq 100 Index Fund (QQQ and its global equivalents). Reason: Compared to the S&amp;P 500 (500 companies, possibly 450 &ldquo;bad companies&rdquo;), the Nasdaq 100 focuses more on high-quality technology companies, aligning with the &ldquo;the bigger, the stronger&rdquo; trend.</li>
<li><strong>Retirees/Those with Less Capital</strong>: Consider Taiwan 0056 or US SPHD (dividend yield ~3.5%, providing stable cash flow).</li>
<li><strong>Nasdaq 100 ETF List</strong>: Provides a list of relevant ETFs including various countries (Canada HXQ.t, Singapore, Malaysia, Norway, UK, Australia, etc.). HXQ.t is recommended because it does not pay dividends (tax-free).</li>
<li><strong>Historical Experience</strong>: Watching videos since 2018 can provide insights into investor sentiment and responses during market fluctuations, giving a sense of the long-term perspective.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Stay Optimistic</strong>: Investors need to be extremely optimistic, always facing the sunlight, believing that the market will be good in the long run, even if there is a world war, the market still exists and continues to rise (only rises, never falls).</li>
<li><strong>Investment Target Selection</strong>:
<ul>
<li><strong>00864B vs 00865B (Taiwan Bond ETF)</strong>:
<ul>
<li>00864B: Pays dividends, generating National Health Insurance Supplementary Premium (2.11%), requires manual reinvestment (with handling fees, easy to forget resulting in no compounding), dividends are considered overseas income (requires declaration if it exceeds the limit, but usually not a problem with annual income below NT$1 million; according to student feedback, it is exempt from the second-generation health insurance supplementary premium).</li>
<li>00865B: Does not pay dividends, avoiding the above problems, simpler and more effective in the long run. Low trading volume is not a problem (market makers provide liquidity), initial performance differences will shrink as scale increases. <strong>Strongly recommend switching to 00865B; convenience is a value.</strong> Conversion will incur a one-time transaction cost, but worth it in the long run.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Berkshire Hathaway (BRK.A/B)</strong>:
<ul>
<li><strong>Not recommended for investment</strong>. Reason: Actively managed fund, more volatile than the index; times are changing, performance has lagged behind the S&amp;P 500; uncertainty after Buffett (&ldquo;the devil will come out&rdquo;); learning Buffett should be about learning his long-term investment spirit, investment discourse (such as the definition of investment), rather than stock picking. Investing in the S&amp;P 500 may be better than investing in BRK.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Asset Allocation (Beta)</strong>:
<ul>
<li><strong>Basic Principle</strong>: It is recommended that most people allocate an investment portfolio with a Beta value of less than 1, such as 70% index funds + 30% cash/money market funds (Beta is approximately 0.7).</li>
<li><strong>Risk Tolerance</strong>: The recent 20% drop has made many people uncomfortable (even those with a Beta of 1.2 configured at 4:4:2), indicating that actual risk tolerance may be lower than expected. Do not sacrifice the comfort of holding enough cash (&ldquo;don&rsquo;t gamble with the money you need for the money you don&rsquo;t need&rdquo;) for an extra 1-2% of return.</li>
<li><strong>Adjustment</strong>: If the initial Beta is high (such as 1.2), it is recommended to review it at the end of each year. If the market rises, you can sell part of the leveraged/index position and supplement the cash to more than 30%, gradually reducing the Beta to below 1.0. Consider smart rebalancing after the Beta is below 1.0.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Platform Interaction</strong>: Please subscribe, like, and leave comments on videos on various platforms.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">AI Development Fantasies and Impact 
    <div id="ai-development-fantasies-and-impact" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ai-development-fantasies-and-impact" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>AI Optimized Future</strong>:
<ul>
<li>Productivity greatly improved, most output is completed by AI (robots), and the cost of goods approaches zero.</li>
<li>Total social wealth accelerates, basic living needs (food, clothing, housing, transportation) may be free, uniformly supplied by the state/society (AI robots complete production, construction, and maintenance).</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Social Structure Changes</strong>:
<ul>
<li><strong>Classes Still Exist</strong>:
<ul>
<li><strong>Capitalists</strong>: Earn profits by investing in and holding the means of production (AI systems) without labor; the wealthiest. Everyone can become a capitalist (just need to know how to invest).</li>
<li><strong>High-Tech Workers</strong>: Personnel who maintain and manage AI systems, with excellent income, can enjoy entertainment beyond basic needs (such as space travel), but may fall into the &ldquo;cared-for&rdquo; class if they stop working and do not become capitalists.</li>
<li><strong>Cared-For Class (approximately 80%)</strong>: No need to work, basic life is guaranteed (food, clothing, housing, transportation, medical care), but cannot enjoy additional entertainment or resources. The standard of living may be similar to the current upper-middle class, but without work.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Philosophical Challenges</strong>:
<ul>
<li>When most people do not need to contribute for livelihood (&ldquo;nothing to serve&rdquo;), what is the meaning and purpose of life? (Analogous to being idle after retirement). May lead to widespread depression or social problems.</li>
<li>Human development may enter a stage of eternal life, facing greater philosophical and existential questions.</li>
<li>The focus should shift from &ldquo;unemployment&rdquo; to &ldquo;the meaning of life.&rdquo;</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Implications for Investors</strong>:
<ul>
<li>As capitalists, there is no need to worry about job loss due to AI development; on the contrary, they will become wealthier.</li>
<li>Start investing now to become part of the capitalist class.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">III. Q&amp;A Session 
    <div id="iii-qa-session" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii-qa-session" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Jacel 
    <div id="jacel" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#jacel" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question: SPY and QQQ have risen for three days, will they continue to rise or fall next week?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo; Response: Short-term market cannot be predicted, like flipping a coin. We invest for the long term (20+ years), focusing on long-term trends. Buy when you have money, never sell. Don&rsquo;t try to predict next week&rsquo;s market; ask the temple or the &ldquo;stock god&rdquo; in Clubhouse.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Sharing: Just started learning from the teacher&rsquo;s course two months ago, introduced by a friend in the United States. Currently in the learning stage, and has invested in some QQQ (cost between 515-530). After returning to Taiwan, considering investing in 00662. In the process of canceling previous insurance and converting individual stocks to 00662.</li>
<li>Question: Should I invest in US stocks (Firstrade account, worried about political risks in Taiwan for the child) or Taiwan stocks 00662? How to allocate at the beginning?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo; Response: Recommend investing in 00662 in Taiwan, no need to use a US broker (Firstrade). It&rsquo;s better for the child to rely on themselves rather than worry about politics. When starting to learn, it is recommended to divide the total funds into three parts: 1/3 buy 00662 immediately, 1/3 buy in batches over the next 3-6 months, and 1/3 hold in cash. The ultimate goal is 70% 00662 + 30% cash. Then slowly learn whether and how to allocate leveraged funds (adjust the Beta value to 0.8-0.9).</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Nibalao 
    <div id="nibalao" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#nibalao" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question 1: Who are QQQ and SPHD suitable for in terms of capital size?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo; Response: (Points out that students should watch the videos for repeated questions) This is a consideration for retirees. Need to calculate annual expenses after retirement. If 50 times the expenses equals your total assets, you can invest in QQQ (equivalent to a 2% annual withdrawal rate). If 2% is not enough, you need 3%, you may consider the S&amp;P 500. Only consider SPHD if you need even higher (~3.5-4%). Non-retirees should prioritize the high-growth QQQ.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2: Explain Beta value. Beta=1 is synchronized with the market? Beta=1.2 is 1.2 times the volatility? Is the Beta of an 80% QQQ + 20% SGOV portfolio 0.8?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo; Response: Basic understanding is correct. Beta measures the volatility of an asset relative to the market. The Beta of an 80/20 portfolio is approximately 0.8. (Reminds again that the videos explain it)</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 3: Will the principal of SGOV (Short-Term US Treasury ETF) fall and lose money?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo; Response: The principal risk is extremely low, almost no losses (except for minor fluctuations before and after dividend payments). SGOV invests in short-term Treasury bills (T-Bills) issued by the US Treasury Department with a maturity of 0-3 months (or within one year), backed by the credit of the United States.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Rui 
    <div id="rui" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#rui" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Joined for more than a month and reviewed the market decline in 2022 and the teacher&rsquo;s videos (especially #398 graduation episode, learned investment psychology).</li>
<li>Question 1: In January 2023 (#401), the teacher used technical indicators (50/100-day moving average crossover) to judge the market bottom and predict that 2023 would be a bull market, which was also verified afterwards. However, in later videos (#491), he emphasized not to predict market cycles and not to look at macroeconomic indicators (prosperity signals, macroeconomics, inventory cycles, etc.). Why this change? Are these indicators really useless in the long run? What was the basis for judging the bottom (just because of being optimistic about the stock market)? Should we just follow discipline and rebalance once a year?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo; Response: QQQ includes many industries (semiconductors, software, AI, biotechnology, retail such as Costco, Pepsico, Amazon, Google, Apple, etc.), and indicators for a single industry or country (such as Taiwan semiconductor economy, Taiwan prosperity signals, US prosperity signals) cannot reflect the overall index. Looking at all indicators is the same as looking at the index itself, so it is better to just focus on QQQ. The judgment in early 2023 was based on 40 years of experience (calculated that the 6-month moving average would cross upward), which is difficult to convey (&ldquo;unspeakable&rdquo;), and teaching technical analysis may cause students to misuse it and be harmed (&ldquo;go crazy&rdquo;), so it is not taught. Adhering to long-term investment discipline and holding enough cash buffer (such as 30%) is a more reliable method. Even if judging the bottom at that time, all cash would not be invested (such as still maintaining Beta 0.7), still maintaining a margin of safety. No need to take too much risk for small potential gains (referring to Buffett&rsquo;s philosophy).</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2: About the currency hedging of 00670L (Taiwan Leveraged QQQ ETF). Is the impact of exchange rate fluctuations significant in the long run? If the US dollar falls sharply (such as 1:13 against the Taiwan dollar), how will 00670L perform? (The teacher mentioned before that 00670L performs poorly when the US dollar rises)
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo; Response: 00670L is usually paired with 00865B (cash/short-term bonds). Exchange rate fluctuations have a hedging effect on both (when the US dollar rises, the hedging cost of 00670L increases, but the value of US dollar assets increases; the opposite is true when the US dollar falls). In the long run, exchange rate fluctuations are normal (such as the Taiwan dollar fluctuating between 28-32), but there is no fixed trend, and the expected value is zero. Currency hedging itself has a cost (wasting funds), which may not be necessary in the long run (it is recommended that fund companies consider canceling it), but the ETF is designed that way, and it does not hurt. The key is whether 00670L can achieve approximately twice the return of 00662 in the long run.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Mike 
    <div id="mike" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#mike" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Trump mentioned that 5.6 trillion in foreign investment may be invested in the United States in the future (may be exaggerated, even if halved, 2.8 trillion is also considerable), but the direction is beneficial to AI and QQQ. Observed that QQQ rebounded more strongly than SPY, DIA, and BRK recently, confirming the teacher&rsquo;s point of view (such as Katy Wood investing in AI-related companies when she saw mobile internet access). Compare the leadership styles of Chinese and American leaders (leader vs. manager) and the direction of attracting foreign investment (Saudi Arabia/Dubai vs. Myanmar/Vietnam/Malaysia).</li>
<li>Question: Please explain the difference between CIPS (Chinese RMB Cross-Border Payment System) and SWIFT. Why is CIPS faster (completed in 6 seconds)? Why does SWIFT take days? Can SWIFT be improved? Will this affect the status of the US dollar (AI replied that the two will coexist)?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo; Response: SWIFT is based on the traditional telegram transmission model (like a relay station), and information needs to be transferred through multiple layers (local bank -&gt; regional major bank -&gt; central bank -&gt; SWIFT center (Switzerland) -&gt; the other party&rsquo;s central bank -&gt; the other party&rsquo;s head office -&gt; the other party&rsquo;s branch), involving compliance checks (anti-money laundering), time difference, manual processing, etc., so it takes a long time (2+ days). CIPS is a modern real-time gross settlement system, similar to domestic payment systems in various countries, point-to-point or directly cleared through the central bank, and the speed is fast. CIPS uses RMB and is an alternative developed to deal with SWIFT being weaponized (such as sanctions against Russia), making people distrust the US dollar system. US sanctions opened a Pandora&rsquo;s box. Currently, CIPS is small (such as shipbuilding transactions between Malaysia and China), but it represents the trend of &ldquo;currency wars&rdquo; (such as Saudi Arabia and China being linked). Trump&rsquo;s visit to Saudi Arabia may be related to maintaining the status of the US dollar. Just watch the show.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Xiu 
    <div id="xiu" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#xiu" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question: Regarding the customized version of ChatGPT (CCTeams Investment Advisor) shared by the teacher, its knowledge cutoff date seems to be June of last year. Is the teacher using an updated version? Will the link change after the update? (Previously confused HXQ/HSQ).
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo; Response: Indeed, this AI is constantly being updated and trained. The link may change with updates. The latest link (showing content updated on April 26, such as 70/30 allocation recommendations) has been shared in the chat area. New links will be provided regularly (such as weekly or monthly) in the future. The teacher himself uses a more advanced personal &ldquo;Super AI&rdquo; account (possibly GPT-4o or higher, with memory function) to process and extract information, and then &ldquo;feeds&rdquo; the essence to this publicly shared GPTs version (similar to DIPS extraction). Feedback on AI answers is welcome for improvement.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Yao 
    <div id="yao" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#yao" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Because of recent trade tensions, I re-listened to the 2022 recordings. Two points are profound: 1. The biggest risk is missing the market (leaving the market). 2. Focus on long-term returns, not short-term fluctuations/shocks. The market is full of contradictory information (repeated presidential statements, pessimistic commentators) and bad news, but it often rebounds unintentionally. Friends who wait for a clear trend (such as buying after the big trend comes back) miss the rise. No one can accurately time the market. It is extremely difficult to obtain stable and high returns in the long term (such as an annualized return of 10% or more), like the sustained performance of top athletes (such as playing ball for 20 years); it is easy to have a good shot occasionally, but difficult to be stable in the long term. It is essential to stay in the market for a long time and focus on long-term growth.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo; Response: Strongly agree. Investing is like a long-distance race, continuing to stay in the front (such as 3rd or 4th place) will eventually win, because the leaders often make mistakes. This is how index funds are, not the best in a single year, but leading in the long term. Need an investment horizon of 15+ years. The key to persistence is having sufficient cash reserves (especially for retirees, it is recommended to have living expenses for 15+ years) or a continuous work income.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Monmon 
    <div id="monmon" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#monmon" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing 1: Started following the teacher last year, investing on my own and encouraging elders (sold insurance and invested). Recently, I have experienced a market decline and am at peace, but the elders are experiencing large fluctuations for the first time (they adopted a Beta 1.2 allocation). Through repeatedly watching videos and communicating, the elders&rsquo; confidence is still stable.</li>
<li>Sharing 2: Selling a house has been tortuous: difficulty communicating with my husband (disagreed at first, had disputes), cold market (the central bank fought housing speculation in September, difficult to get loans), price reduction (applied the teacher&rsquo;s concept of &ldquo;there is no house that cannot be sold, only a price that cannot be sold&rdquo;) to complete the sale (in February this year). The process was painful (communication, management, market changes, funds stuck, high taxes), and I learned a lesson that I don&rsquo;t want to experience again.</li>
<li>Sharing 3: Currently, half of the investment portfolio is QQQ-like, half is TSMC, and there is also a mortgage line of credit (financial mortgage). My husband wants to use this line of credit to increase positions when the market falls (TSMC?), but hesitates and is afraid in the middle of the actual fall (soft-handed, unable to do it). This decline allowed him to experience his true risk tolerance. My husband did not accept the full QQQ allocation before, but now he has some experience. It verifies the stability of the teacher&rsquo;s asset allocation method.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo; Response: Appreciate Monmon&rsquo;s peaceful state of mind (a good quality for investors, &ldquo;destiny&rdquo; + &ldquo;luck&rdquo; to meet the teacher). Communicating with family requires patience (it is a 15-30 year undertaking, no rush). The funds from the financial mortgage should be invested as soon as possible (such as 00662), buy blindly, and don&rsquo;t time the market. When investing, consider the overall asset allocation, include the loan amount in the total asset calculation, and ensure that the total Beta value is within the desired range (such as about 0.7, that is, maintaining an overall ratio of about 70/30), rather than investing all the borrowed money in high-risk assets. It is recommended to keep at least 30% cash (can be 4:1:5 or 5:1:4, Beta 0.6 or 0.7). This decline is a touchstone for risk tolerance, proving the necessity of conservative allocation. Even if young and have a job, 30% cash is also recommended.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">From Taiwan 
    <div id="from-taiwan" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#from-taiwan" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: The situation is similar to Monmon&rsquo;s. Both myself and the elders invested in 00662/00670L, using Beta 1.2 (4:4:2, that is, 40% 00662, 40% 00670L, 20% cash/00865B) allocation. I can bear the recent fluctuations (the government is quite amazing), but I am not sure whether the elders (who have not watched YouTube, have no financial common sense, but believe and invest) can bear greater future declines (such as 40-80%). Continuously accompany the elders and give them confidence. The elders have a good mentality so far.</li>
<li>Question: If I want to reduce the Beta for the elders, when and how should I operate?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo; Response: It is generally recommended now that the Beta should not exceed 1.0 (such as 70/30). For an existing allocation of 1.2, it is recommended to evaluate it at the end of each year: if the market rises (such as 00662 returning to the level at the beginning of the year or higher), you can sell part of the leveraged position (00670L) and transfer the funds to cash (00865B), so that the cash ratio is adjusted to 30% or higher. If the market is down at the end of the year, then do not move. The goal is to gradually reduce the Beta to below 1.0. Before that, there is no need to consider complicated rebalancing strategies. Don&rsquo;t operate too frequently (once a year) to avoid increasing the elders&rsquo; anxiety (they may secretly look at the APP).</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Lucy 
    <div id="lucy" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#lucy" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question 1: Investing in QQQ in Canada, the teacher recommends QQC, etc., and mentions avoiding Hedged funds? It seems that most Canadian versions are Hedged? Which one should I choose? (Previously confused HXQ/HSQ).
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo; Response: Recommend HXQ.t because it does not pay dividends, making tax treatment simpler. If you already hold QQC.to or ZQQ, there is no need to sell it, and new investments can be bought in HXQ.t. It is also acceptable if only Hedged versions are available locally.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2: Please explain the asset allocation ratio (such as 70/30, 4:4:2). Time is limited (working, back problems requiring exercise, blood sugar problems), it is difficult to find specific content in videos, and listening to Clubhouse is also time-consuming.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo; Response: (Emphasizing the importance of learning, earning money from work only accounts for a small part of a lifetime of wealth, so you should spend time learning about investment) For ordinary investors working in Canada, the simplest allocation is: 70% HXQ.t + 30% cash/money market fund (Money Market). Check and adjust annually (sell the ones that have risen more to supplement cash, or use cash to buy the ones that have fallen more) to maintain this ratio.</li>
<li>(Nibalao Supplement): Canadian local stock dividends have tax advantages, while US-sourced dividends (such as QQC) are taxed (I don&rsquo;t know how much, but higher than Canadian stock taxes). I agree with the teacher&rsquo;s point of view: focus on investment returns is higher than focusing on work.</li>
<li>James&rsquo; Response: Reiterating the advantage of HXQ.t not paying dividends. Canadian funds seem to be performing well, possibly because better compounding due to not paying dividends.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Sharing (Follow-up): Listening to the teacher&rsquo;s criticism is very comfortable and helpful. I am impatient, but after listening to the teacher&rsquo;s patient answers to &ldquo;stupid questions,&rdquo; I am more patient in helping others.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo; Response: Asking questions bravely is important.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Jason 
    <div id="jason" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#jason" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Detailed comparison of the advantages and disadvantages of Bitcoin/cryptocurrencies and QQQ, based on his personal experience in the blockchain industry (entered the industry in 2017, experienced the blockchain/cryptocurrency community, ICO explosion, 2018 bear market):
<ul>
<li>Storage Security: BTC requires self-management of private keys/hardware wallets (cold wallets), which are easy to lose or damage, high risk; QQQ is托管ed by brokers, which is safe.</li>
<li>Transaction Security: BTC is vulnerable to hacker attacks, phishing, and platform crashes; QQQ is protected by regulations.</li>
<li>Staking/Liquidity: BTC lacks standardized and safe staking channels (DeFi is high risk); QQQ can be easily staked and borrowed (pledged) through brokers without selling.</li>
<li>Taxes: Selling BTC requires capital gains tax; holding QQQ for a long time and using pledges can avoid/defer taxes.</li>
<li>Legality: BTC has legal risks in China (trading and mining are illegal), and cashing out may be frozen; QQQ (and QDII 513100/513300) are legal and compliant.</li>
<li>Volatility/Risk: BTC is extremely volatile (short-term drops of 50-80% are common, such as an 85% drop in 2018), and ordinary people cannot withstand the mental stress; QQQ has a much lower frequency of large fluctuations.</li>
<li>Liquidity: The actual circulating volume of BTC is limited (locked by large holders, lost coins), which is not as high as the global liquidity of QQQ.</li>
<li>Practicality: Not detailed.</li>
<li>Future Returns: BTC has a high market value (nearly 2 trillion US dollars, comparable to top technology companies), and the possibility of super high multiple growth in the future is reduced (even if it rises to 200,000 US dollars/coin, it is only 2-3 times), and the rate of return may tend to be stable, lower than QQQ.</li>
<li>Conclusion: Cryptocurrencies are &ldquo;demons and ghosts,&rdquo; not suitable for ordinary investors, highly tempting but extremely risky.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>James&rsquo; Comment: Completely agree, cryptocurrencies should not be touched. Shared cases of others losing huge amounts of Bitcoin (equivalent to 15 million US dollars) due to unfamiliarity with cross-chain transfer rules (such as transferring between different chains or exchanges that do not support the target chain), emphasizing its complexity and risk (may be a technical problem or fraud).</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Responding to Chat Room Questions 
    <div id="responding-to-chat-room-questions" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#responding-to-chat-room-questions" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>File Access</strong>: In areas with limited Google service, you can download the files and open them with local software (such as Excel).</li>
<li><strong>00864B Taxes</strong>: According to Angela&rsquo;s feedback, it is overseas income, which is tax-free if it is less than 1 million Taiwan dollars (or other high limit such as 7.5 million) per year, and is exempt from the second-generation supplementary health insurance premium. The main problem becomes the trouble of manual reinvestment. You need a principal of 25 million to possibly exceed 1 million in interest.</li>
<li><strong>AI Link</strong>: Confirmed that the latest link has been provided.</li>
<li><strong>Buying QQQ in China</strong>: Through QDII funds, such as 513100, 513300. See page 10 of the lecture notes.</li>
<li><strong>Conflicting Ideas Between Spouses</strong>: Patience, use your own controllable funds to set an example. Sometimes even if you prove it, the other person does not recognize it (&ldquo;past performance does not represent the future&rdquo;), it depends on fate (destiny).</li>
<li><strong>Technical Analysis/Prediction</strong>: The teacher does not make predictions (when will it bottom out, will there be a recession or crash).</li>
<li><strong>Robert Kiyosaki</strong>: The teacher is critical of him (&ldquo;he will go bankrupt&rdquo;).</li>
<li><strong>Trump Policy</strong>: No need to pay attention, high uncertainty, just &ldquo;drizzle,&rdquo; impossible to have zero income tax. In the long run, US taxes may increase to deal with the deficit. Do not make decisions based on unconfirmed conclusions.</li>
<li><strong>Mean Reversion</strong>: There is no simple mean reversion in the stock market. The growth of high-tech companies (such as TSMC) will not revert to traditional industries (such as China Steel, Formosa Plastics). Those who think it will revert are &ldquo;bookworms.&rdquo; Value stocks (such as Starbucks, McDonald&rsquo;s) also perform differently.</li>
<li><strong>442 Allocation</strong>: Not recommended for office workers, it is too risky. Those who have already used it should handle it according to the MM case.</li>
<li><strong>Investment vs Speculation</strong>: The teacher does not agree with the statement that &ldquo;all investments are speculation.&rdquo;</li>
<li><strong>12-Year Certificates of Deposit vs Compounding</strong>: 00865B/VOO etc. are compounded.</li>
<li><strong>AI Asset Allocation Advice</strong>: May be &ldquo;incorrect&rdquo; due to questioning methods or AI model understanding deviations.</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">IV. Highlights 
    <div id="iv-highlights" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv-highlights" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>The market is always fluctuating, the constant in the market is fluctuation, so fluctuation is certain to happen in the market, so you don&rsquo;t need to analyze where the fluctuation comes from&hellip; You see everyone talking so eloquently, in fact, he doesn&rsquo;t even know what he is talking about&hellip;
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>Context: James emphasized the normality and unpredictability of market fluctuations, advising investors not to waste time analyzing the causes of short-term fluctuations.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Investment is buying with the intention of never selling, this is investment. Buying with the intention of selling at a high point is called speculation.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>Context: James clearly distinguished the core criteria of investment and speculation: whether the purpose is to hold for the long term.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Making a decision about all investment and financial life is very simple, which is long-term, simple and effective&hellip; Convenience is a value. No trouble is a value.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>Context: When comparing 00864B and 00865B, James emphasized that choosing an investment method that is simpler and less troublesome in the long run has value in itself.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>You don&rsquo;t need to risk the money you need for the money you don&rsquo;t need.
&ndash; James (quoting/paraphrasing Buffett&rsquo;s idea)</p></blockquote>
<p>Context: Explained why even if it is judged that the market may rise, you should keep enough cash buffer (the money you need) and should not take too much risk for additional, potentially unnecessary returns (the money you don&rsquo;t need).</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Later you will find that when humans develop to the extreme, food, clothing, housing, and transportation are all free, all free&hellip; Then what does it mean to be alive?&hellip; But what is the meaning of a dog? This may be the question that the last 80% of people have to think about.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>Context: When fantasizing about the future when AI is extremely developed, James raised the question of the profound crisis of existential meaning that humans (especially the majority who do not need to work) will face after material needs are completely satisfied.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The biggest risk comes from [missing] the market&hellip; Focus on long-term returns, not this short-term [fluctuation].
&ndash; Yao</p></blockquote>
<p>Context: Sharing the profound experience after reviewing the teacher&rsquo;s teachings when the market information is chaotic, emphasizing the importance of being in the market for a long time and focusing on long-term goals.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>We don&rsquo;t want to be the first every time, we only want to be the third or fourth every time&hellip; Over the long term, we will be the first.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>Context: Using the analogy of racing to explain the logic of index investing: not pursuing short-term leadership, relying on continuous and steady performance, and ultimately winning in the long cycle.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>There is no house that cannot be sold, only a price that cannot be sold.
&ndash; Monmon</p></blockquote>
<p>Context: Sharing the experience of selling a house, mentioning that applying this point of view ultimately successfully sold the property.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>You should put your focus on investing, and the return is definitely much higher than if you put your focus on working.
&ndash; Nibalao</p></blockquote>
<p>Context: When discussing that students do not have time to learn about investment, this student emphasized that based on their own experience, the long-term return of putting energy into investment learning far exceeds that of putting it into work itself.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>[Cryptocurrencies] are one of the demons and ghosts&hellip; The future return of Bitcoin may tend to be stable, and the teacher also mentioned this issue before.
&ndash; Jason</p></blockquote>
<p>Context: Based on industry experience and risk analysis, the student qualified cryptocurrencies as a high-risk category unsuitable for ordinary investors, and pointed out that its future return may not be as good as index funds.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">V. Summary 
    <div id="v-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#v-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This Clubhouse episode was rich and insightful, ranging from the macro market philosophy (fluctuation is normal, long-term perspective, optimistic mentality), AI&rsquo;s disruptive vision of the future (productivity, social structure, meaning of life), to the micro investment practice (ETF selection such as 00865B vs 00864B, Canadian HXQ.t, asset allocation principles such as 70/30, Beta management, risk awareness), all detailed explanations and discussions were provided. The core information is still focused on: adhering to long-term holding of high-quality index funds (especially the Nasdaq 100), understanding and accepting market fluctuations, maintaining rationality and patience, using time compounding, and conducting sound asset allocation according to personal risk tolerance (emphasizing the importance of at least 30% cash), and being vigilant about market noise and high-risk speculative products (such as cryptocurrencies). The Q&amp;A session answered in detail the specific questions encountered by students in different countries, different stages, and different product selections, and emphasized the importance of continuous learning of investment knowledge. Finally, it was reminded again that the Clubhouse will be suspended for the next two weeks.</p>

  



<div
  
    class="flex px-4 py-3 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900"
  >

  <span
    
      class="text-primary-400 ltr:pr-3 rtl:pl-3 flex items-center"
    >

    

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M506.3 417l-213.3-364c-16.33-28-57.54-28-73.98 0l-213.2 364C-10.59 444.9 9.849 480 42.74 480h426.6C502.1 480 522.6 445 506.3 417zM232 168c0-13.25 10.75-24 24-24S280 154.8 280 168v128c0 13.25-10.75 24-23.1 24S232 309.3 232 296V168zM256 416c-17.36 0-31.44-14.08-31.44-31.44c0-17.36 14.07-31.44 31.44-31.44s31.44 14.08 31.44 31.44C287.4 401.9 273.4 416 256 416z"/></svg>

  </span>


  </span>

  <span
    
      class="dark:text-neutral-300"
    ><strong>Disclaimer:</strong> This article is only a personal learning note and does not constitute any investment advice.</span>
</div>

]]></content:encoded></item></channel></rss>