<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Psychology on QQQ Investor</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/tags/psychology/</link><description>Recent content in Psychology on QQQ Investor</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jomonylw.github.io/en/tags/psychology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Psychology of Money：Book Notes</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1728478918602/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1728478918602/</guid><description>This book, focusing on the psychology of money, states that the key to financial success is not intellect but behavior. Through numerous real-life examples and stories, it reveals the psychological weaknesses, biases, and behavioral patterns that influence human financial decisions, proposing strategies for making smarter choices in personal finance.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[

<h2 class="relative group">I. Summary 
    <div id="i-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>The central argument of the book is that financial success is less about IQ and more about how you behave. Author Morgan Housel argues that by understanding the common psychological pitfalls associated with money, we can make better decisions. He illustrates this through a series of compelling stories and case studies, shedding light on our financial decision-making process.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">II. Chapter Summaries 
    <div id="ii-chapter-summaries" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii-chapter-summaries" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p><strong>1. No One&rsquo;s Crazy</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>People’s unique experiences shape their financial perspectives and actions, leading to seemingly irrational yet logically justifiable behaviors.</li>
<li>For example, low-income individuals might be drawn to lotteries as their perceived only shot at a life-altering fortune.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>2. Luck &amp; Risk</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Nothing is as good or as bad as it seems, as luck and risk play crucial roles in personal outcomes.</li>
<li>Bill Gates getting into a high school with a computer was luck. His friend Kent Evans dying in a mountain climbing accident was risk.</li>
<li>Recognizing the influence of luck and risk helps avoid over-attributing success or failure solely to personal effort or poor decisions.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>3. Never Enough</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Contentment is key in finance. The pursuit of &ldquo;never enough&rdquo; leads to a dangerous cycle of insatiable desire that can ultimately lead to ruin.</li>
<li>Former McKinsey CEO Rajat Gupta and Ponzi schemer Bernie Madoff are cited as examples of individuals who lost everything due to greed.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>4. Confounding Compounding</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Compounding’s power lies in long-term accumulation, allowing even small gains to snowball into extraordinary results.</li>
<li>Warren Buffett&rsquo;s immense wealth is attributed not just to skilled investment but to 70 years of consistent investing, highlighting the power of time.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>5. Getting Wealthy vs. Staying Wealthy</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Getting wealthy requires taking risks, while staying wealthy requires humility, frugality, and respecting the fleeting nature of good fortune.</li>
<li>Trading legend Jesse Livermore, despite remarkable success, fell victim to overconfidence and excessive risk-taking, ultimately leading to bankruptcy and suicide.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>6. Tails, You Win</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>In business and investing, &ldquo;tail events&rdquo; (rare, high-impact events) often disproportionately drive overall results.</li>
<li>Walt Disney produced hundreds of films, but the success of a single one, Snow White, propelled his entire enterprise to unimaginable heights.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>7. Freedom</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>The greatest dividend of wealth is the ability to control your time, offering the ultimate flexibility to pursue your passions and spend time with loved ones.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>8. The Ferrari Fallacy</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>People care less about your wealth than you think. Their attention is often directed towards their own desires and comparing themselves to you.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>9. Wealth is What You Don&rsquo;t See</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>True wealth lies not in flashy possessions but in the unseen: financial security, flexibility, and the ability to make choices.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>10. Save Money</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Building wealth hinges on your savings rate, which is driven by lifestyle choices and managing desires.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>11. Reasonable &gt; Rational</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>In financial decisions, making reasonable choices that you can stick with is often more effective than striving for absolute rationality.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>12. Surprise!</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>History is full of surprises, so relying solely on historical patterns to predict the future is unreliable. Recognizing the constant possibility of the unexpected is crucial.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>13. Room for Error</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>The most important part of every plan is planning on your plan not going according to plan: Building in a margin of safety is crucial.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>14. You&rsquo;ll Change</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Our goals, thoughts, and aspirations change over time. Acknowledging this is essential when making long-term financial plans. Avoid extreme financial goals, embracing the fluid nature of life.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>15. Nothing&rsquo;s Free</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Everything has a price. Success in investing comes with costs: volatility, fear, and uncertainty. Viewing these as fees for a valuable service rather than penalties to avoid helps navigate the emotional rollercoaster of investing.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>16. No One&rsquo;s Crazy (Reprise)</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Avoid blindly following financial advice from people with different circumstances and timelines than your own.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>17. The Seduction of Pessimism</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Pessimism often seems more intelligent and gains more attention, even though the world has generally improved significantly over time.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>18. When You Believe Anything</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>The power of narratives shapes our beliefs. The more we want something to be true, the more likely we are to embrace narratives that inflate its likelihood, especially in high-risk, high-reward scenarios like investing.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>19. Summary</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>This chapter provides a recap of the key principles and advice from previous chapters to guide sound financial decision-making.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>20. Confessions</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>The author shares his own personal approach to money management, highlighting the importance of seeking financial independence and emphasizing long-term investing.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Appendix: A Brief History of the American Consumer</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Post-WWII, the US deliberately engineered the American consumer through low-interest rates, consumer credit, and programs like the GI Bill, fostering a culture of consumption and economic growth.</li>
<li>From the 1950s to the 1970s, income distribution remained relatively equitable, the debt was manageable, and confidence in a better future was high.</li>
<li>The 1980s onwards witnessed growing income inequality. The aspirational lifestyles of a small group of prosperous individuals diverged drastically from those of the average person, fostering a culture of keeping up appearances, fueled by debt.</li>
<li>The 2008 financial crisis, a culmination of a debt bubble, exposed the cracks in this system.</li>
<li>Recent years have seen a rise in social unrest tied to income inequality, prompting individuals to question the current economic and social model.</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">III. Memorable Quotes 
    <div id="iii-memorable-quotes" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii-memorable-quotes" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;Nothing is as good or as bad as it seems.&rdquo;</p>
</blockquote>
<ul>
<li>Life’s outcomes are influenced by chance and factors outside our control. This quote urges us to be mindful of the unpredictable nature of events.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;The hardest financial skill is getting the goalpost to stop moving.&rdquo;</p>
</blockquote>
<ul>
<li>Contentment is essential for financial well-being. Constantly shifting financial goals in pursuit of &ldquo;more&rdquo; can become a destructive cycle.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;The greatest dividend of wealth is the ability to control your time.&rdquo;</p>
</blockquote>
<ul>
<li>Wealth allows us to free ourselves from time constraints, enabling us to spend our time as we see fit.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;Wealth is what you don&rsquo;t see.&rdquo;</p>
</blockquote>
<ul>
<li>True wealth resides in our ability to make choices and have options, not in material possessions.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>“Save Money. Just save.”</p>
</blockquote>
<ul>
<li>Saving should be a default behavior, a fundamental habit for financial stability and future flexibility.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>“No One’s Crazy (Reprise).”</p>
</blockquote>
<ul>
<li>Recognize that financial advice must be individualized. Avoid mimicking strategies without considering personal circumstances and goals.</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">IV. Practical Takeaways 
    <div id="iv-practical-takeaways" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv-practical-takeaways" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<ul>
<li><strong>Acknowledge your psychological biases</strong> – Understand your weaknesses related to managing money and avoid impulsive decisions.</li>
<li><strong>View money as a tool, not an end goal</strong> – Strive to use wealth as a means to achieve freedom and happiness, not to pursue material possessions.</li>
<li><strong>Create a financial plan that makes sense to you</strong> – Develop a plan, tailored to your needs and risk tolerance, that fosters financial stability. Incorporate a margin of safety for unforeseen events and market fluctuations.</li>
<li><strong>Invest for the long-term and stay the course</strong> – Compounding works best over long periods. Choose an investment strategy that resonates with your goals and  commit to it, riding out the inevitable market ups and downs.</li>
<li><strong>Pursue time freedom and happiness</strong> –  Remember that the ultimate goal of acquiring wealth is to create a life of greater freedom and happiness.</li>
</ul>
<hr>

<section class="space-y-10 w-full">
    
    
        
            






















  <a class="flex flex-wrap article " href="/en/posts/1728295490690-book-list/">
    
        
        <div class="w-full md:w-auto h-full thumbnail nozoom thumbnailshadow md:mr-7" style="background-image:url(/posts/1728295490690-book-list/featured_hu4424409690304057825.jpg);"></div>
        
      <div class=" mt-3 md:mt-0">
      <div class="items-center text-left text-xl font-semibold">
        
        <div class="font-bold text-xl text-neutral-800 decoration-primary-500 hover:underline hover:underline-offset-2 dark:text-neutral"
          href="/en/posts/1728295490690-book-list/">Recommended Reading List</div>
        
        
        
      </div>
      <div class="text-sm text-neutral-500 dark:text-neutral-400">
        











  









  



  









<div class="flex flex-row flex-wrap items-center">
  
  
  <time datetime="2024-10-01T00:00:00&#43;00:00">1 October 2024</time><span class="px-2 text-primary-500">&middot;</span><span>
  
  
    
    
      
      
        
        
      
        
        
      
      
    
  
  <span id="views_posts/1728295490690-book-list/index.md" class="animate-pulse inline-block text-transparent max-h-3 rounded-full mt-[-2px] align-middle bg-neutral-300 dark:bg-neutral-400" title="views">loading</span>
  <span class="inline-block align-text-bottom">

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 576 512">
<path fill="currentColor" d="M288 32c-80.8 0-145.5 36.8-192.6 80.6C48.6 156 17.3 208 2.5 243.7c-3.3 7.9-3.3 16.7 0 24.6C17.3 304 48.6 356 95.4 399.4C142.5 443.2 207.2 480 288 480s145.5-36.8 192.6-80.6c46.8-43.5 78.1-95.4 93-131.1c3.3-7.9 3.3-16.7 0-24.6c-14.9-35.7-46.2-87.7-93-131.1C433.5 68.8 368.8 32 288 32zM432 256c0 79.5-64.5 144-144 144s-144-64.5-144-144s64.5-144 144-144s144 64.5 144 144zM288 192c0 35.3-28.7 64-64 64c-11.5 0-22.3-3-31.6-8.4c-.2 2.8-.4 5.5-.4 8.4c0 53 43 96 96 96s96-43 96-96s-43-96-96-96c-2.8 0-5.6 .1-8.4 .4c5.3 9.3 8.4 20.1 8.4 31.6z"/></svg>
  </span>

</span>
</span><span class="px-2 text-primary-500">&middot;</span><span>
  
  
    
    
      
      
        
        
      
        
        
      
      
    
  
  <span id="likes_posts/1728295490690-book-list/index.md"
    class="animate-pulse inline-block text-transparent max-h-3 rounded-full mt-[-2px] align-middle bg-neutral-300 dark:bg-neutral-400"
    title="likes">loading</span>
  <span class="inline-block align-text-bottom">

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512">
<path fill="currentColor" d="M47.6 300.4L228.3 469.1c7.5 7 17.4 10.9 27.7 10.9s20.2-3.9 27.7-10.9L464.4 300.4c30.4-28.3 47.6-68 47.6-109.5v-5.8c0-69.9-50.5-129.5-119.4-141C347 36.5 300.6 51.4 268 84L256 96 244 84c-32.6-32.6-79-47.5-124.6-39.9C50.5 55.6 0 115.2 0 185.1v5.8c0 41.5 17.2 81.2 47.6 109.5z"/></svg>
  </span>

</span>
</span>
  

  
  
</div>





<div class="flex flex-row flex-wrap items-center">
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  <span style="margin-top:0.5rem" class="mr-2" onclick="window.open(&#34;/en/tags/recommended/&#34;,'_self');">
    <span class="flex" style="cursor: pointer;">
  <span class="rounded-md border border-primary-400 px-1 py-[1px] text-xs font-normal text-primary-700 dark:border-primary-600 dark:text-primary-400">
    Recommended
  </span>
</span>
  </span>
  
  <span style="margin-top:0.5rem" class="mr-2" onclick="window.open(&#34;/en/tags/book/&#34;,'_self');">
    <span class="flex" style="cursor: pointer;">
  <span class="rounded-md border border-primary-400 px-1 py-[1px] text-xs font-normal text-primary-700 dark:border-primary-600 dark:text-primary-400">
    Book
  </span>
</span>
  </span>
  
  
  
  
</div>




      </div>
      
    </div>
  </a>

        
    
</section>
]]></content:encoded></item></channel></rss>