<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Stock Pledging on QQQ Investor</title>
    <link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/tags/stock-pledging/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Stock Pledging on QQQ Investor</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jomonylw.github.io/en/tags/stock-pledging/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>00504 Asset Allocation Wisdom: How to Build Financial Freedom with Leverage and Pledging? Cash is King? Investment Wisdom in a Volatile Market</title>
      <link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1740895441407/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1740895441407/</guid>
      <description>This episode of CLEC Investment and Financial Management Channel focuses on the concept of easy investing, emphasizing that international situations should not interfere with personal investment decisions, and investing in the United States remains a wise choice. It delves into index fund investment strategies, shares tips on using YouTube Music Podcast features, and interprets Buffett&amp;#39;s latest shareholder letter. In the Q&amp;amp;A session, students actively participated, and James provided detailed answers to questions on taxation, insurance, asset allocation, retirement planning, and the philosophy of life, encouraging everyone to stick to long-term investment and achieve both financial and spiritual freedom.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<lite-youtube videoid="pw6ORn1yTOI" playlabel="pw6ORn1yTOI" params=""></lite-youtube>



<h2 class="relative group">I. Current Theme 
    <div id="i-current-theme" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-current-theme" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This episode of the CLEC Investment and Financial Management Channel adopts the theme of &ldquo;Easy Chat on Investment,&rdquo; with the core idea that market chaos is irrelevant to personal investment, and reiterating the correctness of investing in the U.S. market. James emphasized that investors should adhere to their established index fund investment strategies and not pay excessive attention to international political and economic fluctuations. At the same time, he also introduced the new features of YouTube Music Podcast, recommended learning resources, and patiently answered students&rsquo; questions about taxation, insurance, asset allocation, and life planning, aiming to help everyone establish a more mature investment mindset and strategy.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">II. Briefing Content 
    <div id="ii-briefing-content" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii-briefing-content" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Market and Investment Philosophy 
    <div id="market-and-investment-philosophy" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#market-and-investment-philosophy" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Market Situation and Personal Investment:</strong> Emphasized that even in the face of international events such as the Wol War and Trump&rsquo;s election, personal investment decisions should not be changed as a result. These external factors are not directly related to long-term investment goals and should not be overemphasized, but rather focus on the execution of one&rsquo;s own investment plan.</li>
<li><strong>Investing in the United States:</strong> Reaffirmed that the U.S. economy remains strong in the long term, so investing in the United States is still the right choice. Even if the world situation is turbulent, long-term confidence in the U.S. economy should not be shaken.</li>
<li><strong>Easy Investment:</strong> Advocated a simplified approach to investment, choosing to buy index funds and then reducing attention to short-term market fluctuations, sticking to a long-term hold. This &ldquo;buy and hold&rdquo; strategy can reduce anxiety and operational errors.</li>
<li><strong>Risk Warning:</strong> Emphasized the inherent risks of investing, especially the risks associated with leveraged funds and stock pledging. James strongly recommends that new students listen to several episodes of videos and be sure to carefully study the relevant handouts before making any investment operations, especially to understand the operating mechanisms and potential risks of leveraged funds and pledging.</li>
<li><strong>Non-Profit and Personal Experience Sharing:</strong> Re-emphasized that the CLAC channel, as a non-profit organization, does not charge students any fees and will not ask for remittances. All sharing on the channel is based on personal experience and is not professional investment advice. Therefore, students need to think, research, and bear all investment risks on their own. At the same time, students are reminded to beware of external fraudulent information impersonating CLEC.</li>
<li><strong>Market Volatility is Normal:</strong> Pointed out that market volatility is normal, with declines possible every year, 20% declines every three to five years, and 50% declines every ten to fifteen years. Investors should recognize that this is normal and not panic excessively, and they will get used to it by staying in the market long enough.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Learning Resources and Tools 
    <div id="learning-resources-and-tools" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#learning-resources-and-tools" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Learning Resources:</strong> Suggested that new friends start by watching past videos from 2023, and then go back to review content from 2022 and earlier. At the same time, emphasized the importance of the handouts provided on the message board, with relevant links available on YouTube and the Cross House message board.</li>
<li><strong>Community Resources:</strong> Introduced the Taiwan 00662 Endurance Group and thanked the group administrator for their selfless contribution. Students can ask questions within the group, and the administrator will do their best to answer them, but emphasized that the group mainly answers basic questions from the handouts, such as what is 442, what is pledging, etc., to avoid off-topic discussions unrelated to the investment theme within the group. The group may have regional restrictions, and users in Asia may find it easier to join.</li>
<li><strong>NASDAQ 100 Index Funds:</strong> Recommended investing in NASDAQ 100 index funds, and pointed out that there are related products in many places around the world, including the United States, Taiwan, Hong Kong, Canada, Australia, the United Kingdom, Brazil, Japan, Malaysia, South Korea, etc. In Malaysia, it may be necessary to purchase through Phillip Securities.</li>
<li><strong>Best NASDAQ Document:</strong> Strongly recommended consulting the document titled &ldquo;World&rsquo;s Best NASDAQ United States NASDAQ 100 Index Fund Investment,&rdquo; which contains information on NASDAQ funds and leveraged funds in various countries, with links on the message board. The document contains local information provided by friends from various regions, helping investors find suitable investment targets.</li>
<li><strong>YouTube Music Podcast:</strong> Detailed instructions on how to use the YouTube Music Podcast feature. Parts of the CLEC channel content can be transferred to YouTube Music, allowing you to enjoy ad-free listening and offline downloads, and guiding users on how to operate on mobile phones and web pages. Emphasized the difference between YouTube Music and a regular YouTube account, and that after joining a Podcast playlist, it will be displayed in the YouTube Music APP.</li>
<li><strong>Buffett Shareholder Letter:</strong> Emphasized the importance of reading the latest Buffett shareholder letter, especially the part about paying taxes. Shared a YouTube link and encouraged everyone to learn from Buffett&rsquo;s investment wisdom and values.</li>
<li><strong>China NASDAQ 100 Index Fund:</strong> Introduced that there are already 12 NASDAQ 100 index funds in the Chinese market, and provided links to related ETFs to facilitate local purchases for Chinese investors. Even if there are purchase restrictions or premiums, these locally issued ETFs can be considered.</li>
<li><strong>Adlerian Purpose Theory:</strong> Strongly recommended watching videos related to Adlerian purpose theory as extracurricular homework to enhance happiness and self-awareness. Emphasized that understanding the purpose and meaning of life helps to maintain a peaceful state of mind in investing.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Asset Allocation and Pledging 
    <div id="asset-allocation-and-pledging" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#asset-allocation-and-pledging" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Asset Allocation Briefing:</strong> Mentioned the asset allocation briefing produced by Chen Feng and the 00662 group, mainly for investors participating in stock pledging, covering allocation schemes for different situations, such as different allocations with and without pledging (442, 80/20) and related Excel analysis tables. Recommended watching the relevant videos, and if you have any questions, you can ask them within the group.</li>
<li><strong>Stock Pledging Information:</strong> Shared information on stock pledging from E.SUN Securities, with the current interest rate at approximately 3%, which can be applied for online, and provided contact information for interested students to inquire.</li>
<li><strong>Leveraged Funds and Pledging:</strong> Re-emphasized that leveraged funds should not be used for pledging, and emphasized that U.S. leveraged funds should be placed in a retirement account (Roth IRA) and not pledged.</li>
<li><strong>Importance of Roth IRA:</strong> Emphasized that leveraged funds must be placed in a Roth IRA retirement account, rather than a Block 9 com account, to avoid unnecessary tax burdens and pledging risks.</li>
<li><strong>Rust IRA&rsquo;s Importance:</strong> Pointed out that even if a Rust IRA account has little initial capital, it should be gradually increased to eventually achieve a 442 allocation. Emphasized the importance of time accumulation and the benefits of long-term compounding.</li>
<li><strong>Retirement Fund Withdrawal:</strong> Discussed fund withdrawal strategies when there is no income after retirement. Emphasized that in the case of non-pledging, in order to cope with market risks, only a conservative 80/20 allocation can be used to avoid over-reliance on leverage.</li>
<li><strong>Other Income After Retirement:</strong> If there are other sources of income after retirement, such as rental income or side hustle income, leveraged funds can be held, and a more aggressive 433 allocation can be considered, but a 442 allocation is not recommended.</li>
<li><strong>Pledging and Asset Allocation:</strong> Whether retired or not, as long as pledging is carried out, it is recommended to use a 433 allocation and cooperate with a smart rebalancing strategy.</li>
<li><strong>Yuanta Securities Pledging:</strong> Reminded friends who pledge stocks at Yuanta Securities in Taiwan to pay attention to the need to renew their contracts every 18 months to avoid forced sale of stocks. Even if there is no borrowing, timely renewal is still required.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Investment Mentality and Insights 
    <div id="investment-mentality-and-insights" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#investment-mentality-and-insights" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Individual Stocks and Index Funds:</strong> Emphasized the advantages of investing in index funds, pointing out that individual stocks are more volatile than index funds, and cited the stock price fluctuations of NVIDIA and Tesla as examples to illustrate that index funds can avoid affecting the mentality due to large rises and falls in individual stocks.</li>
<li><strong>Value of Long-Term Investment:</strong> Shared a case of a student who started investing in index funds in 2020 and earned eight figures by 2024, emphasizing the huge returns of long-term investment, which is better than short-term operations.</li>
<li><strong>Avoid Sub-Entrustment:</strong> Reminded to avoid investing through sub-entrustment to avoid increasing the complexity of tax filing due to excessive profits.</li>
<li><strong>Investment Philosophy and Market Cognition:</strong> Shared the transformation of a student from initial unfamiliarity with the market to ultimately understanding the concept of long-term investment, emphasizing that the highest realm of investment is to not pay attention to short-term returns, focus on long-term value, and achieve a selfless investment state.</li>
<li><strong>No Selling Principle:</strong> Emphasized the strategy of using stock pledges to borrow money to live on, the core of which is not to sell assets to achieve sustainable wealth. Criticized the idea of needing to sell assets for profit as short-sighted and a lack of financial knowledge.</li>
<li><strong>Channel Purpose:</strong> Re-emphasized that the goal of the CLEC channel is to help everyone achieve financial peace of mind and improve the quality of life.</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">III. Q&amp;A Session 
    <div id="iii-qa-session" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii-qa-session" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Haoqing 
    <div id="haoqing" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#haoqing" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Share 1: Shared the evolution of the tax system in the United States and views on the current government&rsquo;s tax cut policy.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s comment: Future tax reforms will not be retroactive, and existing Traditional IRAs will still be taxed. Even if the Trump administration does succeed in implementing large-scale tax cuts, tariff revenues will not be able to fully compensate for the reduction in individual income taxes.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 1: The impact of the new U.S. government&rsquo;s tax cut policy on investment?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s reply: The world will not achieve a perfect tax-free state. Even if income tax is eliminated in the future, traditional retirement accounts (Traditional IRA) will still be taxed because the government needs alternative tax sources. Alternative tax sources such as tariffs may only be a transfer of the form of taxation, and the final tax burden may be comparable. The current retirement account investment strategy should not be adjusted based on future uncertain tax changes, but should be carried out according to the established plan. Even if there are adjustments in the future, there will be corresponding alternatives, so there is no need to worry too much. Don&rsquo;t bet on something that may not happen in the future.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2: Views on the U.S. health insurance system and the impact of future tax systems and AI development on investment strategies?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s reply: The U.S. health insurance system does have shortcomings, such as rejection of claims and delays, but health is very important and should not be sacrificed for the sake of saving money. Encourage everyone to have the ability to distinguish between minor and serious illnesses, and not to turn minor illnesses into major illnesses. Minor illnesses and pains can be observed on your own, but you must have the knowledge to judge major illnesses, and you must go to the hospital when necessary, and you cannot sacrifice your life in order to save money. Rich people can not rely on insurance and cover medical expenses through wealth. In the future, even if AI develops and the tax system changes, it will not have much impact on the current retirement account investment strategy, so there is no need to worry too much. Encourage looking at government taxation from a business perspective and understanding the logic of increasing revenue and reducing expenditure. If a zero tax rate is really implemented, then consider how the government can increase revenue, such as selling gold card immigration.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Summer 
    <div id="summer" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#summer" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question 1: A non-U.S. resident (NR) in mainland China, holding a U.S. dollar account, has purchased QQQM and QLD. Considering the risk of estate tax, wants to switch to EQQQ issued in Europe. Inquired about the reasons for the price difference between European and American market ETFs and suggestions for operation?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s reply: It is strongly not recommended to open an account with a brokerage firm outside the United States because there is a risk of estate tax. It is recommended to close the U.S. account as soon as possible and consider opening an account with a Hong Kong brokerage firm to purchase NASDAQ index funds listed in Hong Kong, such as 7261 (double leverage), 7266 (Southern NASDAQ). Emphasized that it is also feasible to purchase U.S. dollar-denominated funds in Hong Kong. You shouldn&rsquo;t care about the U.S. situation.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2: Regarding the understanding of whether holding non-U.S.-issued ETFs in a U.S. brokerage account can avoid estate tax?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s reply: Estate tax is related to where the brokerage account is located, not where the ETF is issued. As long as you open an account with a U.S. brokerage firm and fill out the W-8BEN form, you are subject to U.S. estate tax. Even if you purchase ETFs issued outside the United States, you still need to pay estate tax. U.S. tax residents have estate tax, and if they need to fill out a W-8BEN, they have to pay estate tax. It is recommended to consult IBKR to confirm specific tax issues, or consider brokers in other regions such as Phillip Securities in Singapore to avoid U.S. estate tax.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Brian 
    <div id="brian" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#brian" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Share 1: Shared that he has been under a lot of work pressure recently and feels slightly depressed, but feels comforted when spending time with his children, and said that CLEC content has been helpful to him.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s comment: Recommended watching videos related to Adlerian purpose theory, the focus should not only be on work, but should be shifted, work is not everything in life. Money will not bring happiness, it can only reduce worries and increase choices. The meaning of life lies in love and being loved, and success lies in how many people remember and love you after you pass away. Emphasized finding comfort in Lao Zhuang philosophy. It is common to run into walls at work, the important thing is to shift your focus away.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Sophia 
    <div id="sophia" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#sophia" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question 1: Retired, using an 80/20 allocation, QQQ holdings are less than 80%, some funds are in cash, considering converting some QQQ to QLD for long-term holding, is it feasible? Some of the money wants to be left to her grandchildren.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s reply: It is not recommended to transfer funds from a retirement account to QLD. QLD still needs to be converted back to QQQ in the end, which is suitable for young people or children&rsquo;s accounts with a long-term tax-free period. If your child is 5 years old, and has a hundred or two dollars, it is no problem to buy QLD. For retirement accounts, just maintain an 80/20 allocation, and don&rsquo;t pursue high risk. Emphasized that you must calculate clearly whether you can file your own taxes at age 18, and that children have $50,000 of long-term tax-free funds. For the money that is to be left to grandchildren, if the funds have reached more than 55 times the annual expenditure, the excess part can be considered to set up a custodial account for the grandchildren, and donate a certain amount each year, which can avoid estate tax and allow the grandchildren to get in touch with investment and financial management as early as possible. The key is that you must first be financially free.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Shufen 
    <div id="shufen" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#shufen" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Share 1: Shared the comparison between her mother&rsquo;s hospitalization experience in Taiwan and her friend&rsquo;s father&rsquo;s experience in a nursing home in the United States, reflecting on Taiwan&rsquo;s national health insurance and the U.S.养老体系 (pension system/care system), hesitant about where to spend the future, and not knowing where home is.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s comment: The United States has a safety net of social security systems such as Medicare and Medicaid, which provide basic medical and pension security for low-income people, and the country will support those over 65 who have no money. Nursing home services in the United States are luxurious but expensive, while Taiwan&rsquo;s national health insurance benefits are good but may not be luxurious. The choice of where to spend your time should take into account personal financial status, comfort of life, and relationships with relatives and friends. If you don&rsquo;t have money, you can get Medicare. Emphasized that the meaning of life lies in connection, and encouraged young people to have children as early as possible to establish family connections. Wherever the children are, that is where the home is, and you should have children as soon as possible. Emphasized the importance of connections in old age, and encouraged having children even if you are not married.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">IAM 
    <div id="iam" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iam" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question 1: Regarding wealth awakening, early earning goals are easy to achieve, but larger wealth goals create doubt, how to understand this change in mentality?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s reply: After the early material desires are satisfied, a sense of emptiness will follow, and the happiness brought by material consumption is short-lived, and you should turn to spiritual consumption. The real happiness lies in having the ability to buy but choosing not to buy, and using money to improve your spiritual life, such as family gatherings, travel, etc. Material things should be reduced as much as possible. Wealth accumulation should look to the future and see the potential of long-term compounding. For example, the current 7 million assets may grow to hundreds of millions under long-term investment. You should not look at 7 million, but at 300 million. You see the present, he sees the future.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Jimmy 
    <div id="jimmy" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#jimmy" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Share 1: Supplemented the view on境界提升 (jingjie tisheng - elevation of one&rsquo;s spiritual state), citing Zhuangzi philosophy, emphasizing the importance of mind state, and how to improve cognitive境界 (jingjie - realm/state) through practice. Emphasized the Tao Te Ching, and the view of all things in the world.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s comment: Knowledge itself is simple, but it is not easy to improve cognitive境界 (jingjie - realm/state). Practice is the key to improving境界 (jingjie - realm/state), and encouraged everyone to try operations such as stock pledging, so that they can truly understand after experiencing it personally.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">IV. Highlighted Quotes 
    <div id="iv-highlighted-quotes" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv-highlighted-quotes" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>The market situation has nothing to do with us anymore.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This view emphasizes that personal investment decisions should be independent of external market noise and focus on the execution of long-term investment strategies.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Investing in the United States is absolutely correct.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Reiterated confidence in the U.S. economy and market, encouraging investors to stick to investing in the United States.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Investing in index funds is so simple, just buy them and don&rsquo;t pay attention to them.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Emphasized simplifying the investment process, holding index funds for the long term, and reducing unnecessary market attention and operations.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The highest realm of investment is the view of no reward.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Pointed out that true investment should transcend the obsession with short-term returns and focus on long-term value and asset accumulation.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Borrowing money and never selling, borrowing money to live on will never run out.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Summarized the core idea of the stock pledging strategy, emphasizing the sustainability of assets and the liquidity of funds.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Money really won&rsquo;t bring you happiness, remember this thing forever, don&rsquo;t say that if I have money, I have everything, no, having money just eliminates a lot of worries or troubles, or adds more choices.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Emphasized the limitations of money, true happiness comes from the spiritual level and interpersonal relationships, not material wealth itself.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>We can&rsquo;t please everyone, nor do we need to, but we shouldn&rsquo;t become someone who is annoying.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Provided a guideline for interpersonal communication, not to deliberately please, but to avoid becoming an obnoxious person.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>What is悟 (wu - enlightenment)? It&rsquo;s no past, no future.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Explained the realm of &ldquo;悟 (wu - enlightenment)&rdquo;, emphasizing the importance of living in the present and reducing worries about the past and future.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The world exists only in our hearts.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Emphasized the importance of subjective consciousness, the impact of external things on individuals depends on inner cognition and attitude.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>People are selfish, I am here today to talk to you a lot, you think you have benefited, in fact I am selfish, I am satisfying my sense of accomplishment.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Frankly shared the motivation for personal behavior, emphasizing that altruistic behavior also includes selfish elements, and encouraging treating yourself well.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">V. Summary 
    <div id="v-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#v-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This episode of the CLEC Investment and Financial Management Channel once again conveyed the core concepts of easy investing and long-term holding. James explained the index fund investment strategy in a simple and understandable way, and combined practical cases and philosophies of life to answer the questions of students in investment and life. He emphasized that investors should stick to long-term investment and not be shaken by short-term market fluctuations. At the same time, they should also pay attention to the spiritual level in life and pursue both financial and spiritual freedom. Through this exchange, students not only gained knowledge of investment and financial management, but also had a deeper understanding of the true meaning of life value and happiness.</p>

  



<div
  
    class="flex px-4 py-3 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900"
  >

  <span
    
      class="text-primary-400 ltr:pr-3 rtl:pl-3 flex items-center"
    >

    

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M506.3 417l-213.3-364c-16.33-28-57.54-28-73.98 0l-213.2 364C-10.59 444.9 9.849 480 42.74 480h426.6C502.1 480 522.6 445 506.3 417zM232 168c0-13.25 10.75-24 24-24S280 154.8 280 168v128c0 13.25-10.75 24-23.1 24S232 309.3 232 296V168zM256 416c-17.36 0-31.44-14.08-31.44-31.44c0-17.36 14.07-31.44 31.44-31.44s31.44 14.08 31.44 31.44C287.4 401.9 273.4 416 256 416z"/></svg>

  </span>


  </span>

  <span
    
      class="dark:text-neutral-300"
    ><strong>Disclaimer:</strong> This article is for personal study notes only and does not constitute any investment advice.</span>
</div>

]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>00488 AI Demand and Market Future: Insights from TSMC and Investment Trends; Ever-Growing Assets and Smart Spending without Repaying Principal</title>
      <link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1729384159255/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1729384159255/</guid>
      <description>This session focuses on strategies for long-term investment in Nasdaq 100 index funds amidst market volatility and changing international landscapes.  It also covers leveraging investments, smart spending habits, and navigating the job market in the age of AI.  Additionally, the discussion touches upon comparing different types of economic crises, estate planning, the synergy between real estate and stock investments, the feasibility of long-term investing in Taiwanese and US stock markets, and government policies regarding economic stimulus and social welfare.  Specific advice for Chinese investors accessing US markets and related tax implications are also addressed.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<lite-youtube videoid="y6smxG48k4M" playlabel="y6smxG48k4M" params=""></lite-youtube>



<h2 class="relative group">I. Main Topic 
    <div id="i-main-topic" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-main-topic" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>Trust in the power of technology and maintain a long-term investment strategy focused on Nasdaq 100 index funds, learning how to utilize stock pledging and spend wisely, especially during market fluctuations and shifts in the international situation.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">II. Presentation Content 
    <div id="ii-presentation-content" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii-presentation-content" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<ol>
<li><strong>Market Trends and Investment Philosophy:</strong>
<ul>
<li><strong>AI Drives the Future:</strong> AI demand is not a bubble, but a genuine driving force behind technological advancement, promising a bull market spanning two decades.  We are currently in the early stages of this growth.  Morris Chang (TSMC Chairman)&rsquo;s perspective and TSMC&rsquo;s investments in AI corroborate this judgment. The long bull market has begun, seize the opportunity to join the wealth train.</li>
<li><strong>Market Volatility and Long-Term Investment:</strong> Market fluctuations are inherent to investing.  Downswings are followed by even greater upswings. Using historical data from the Taiwan Weighted Index, Nikkei Index, and the US stock market as examples, the session illustrates the long-term market development pattern: an initial period of rapid growth followed by a period of stagnation (e.g., 32 years in Taiwan, 35 years in Japan, 24 years in the US), before entering a phase of stable growth.  Therefore, overcoming panic caused by market volatility and adhering to a long-term investment strategy is crucial for ultimate success.</li>
<li><strong>Capitalism and Investment:</strong>  The side effects of capitalism are wealth disparity and the exploitation of labor. Learn to operate like a capitalist and profit from investment.  Hard work and saving money to buy government bonds will ultimately result in wealth erosion due to inflation.</li>
<li><strong>Benefits of Quantitative Easing:</strong> Quantitative easing is beneficial for investors, fostering a low-interest-rate environment and driving asset price appreciation.  Those who fail to understand quantitative easing and complain about government money printing are often victims of capitalism, missing out on the benefits of asset appreciation.</li>
<li><strong>Characteristics of a Mature Market:</strong> Mature markets are characterized by fair, just, and transparent regulatory mechanisms, companies focused on their core businesses, and a high proportion of long-term investors and institutional holdings. The Taiwanese market is gradually maturing.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Investment Strategies and Recommendations:</strong>
<ul>
<li><strong>Invest in Nasdaq 100:</strong>  The session recommends investing in Nasdaq 100 index funds (QQQ), with the option to allocate to S&amp;P 500 or high-dividend ETFs based on individual circumstances.  References to Nasdaq 100 index funds globally are provided for the convenience of investors worldwide.</li>
<li><strong>Avoid Penny Stocks:</strong>  Refrain from investing in penny stocks, as they generally offer low long-term returns.  Real investment opportunities lie in companies that demonstrate sustained growth and lead technological advancements.</li>
<li><strong>Advantages of Stock Pledging:</strong> Stock pledging offers advantages over real estate mortgages, as stocks, unlike real estate, do not depreciate and can be held long-term, potentially allowing for &ldquo;borrowing without repayment or interest&rdquo; (specific instructions are available in related videos).</li>
<li><strong>Avoid Flawed Rebalancing Strategies:</strong> Avoid a 50% principal + 50% leveraged ETF rebalancing strategy, as it carries high risk and can easily deplete cash reserves during market downturns.</li>
<li><strong>Estate Planning and Stock Pledging:</strong> When engaging in stock pledging, it is advisable to diversify assets across multiple brokerage firms, pledging a portion and keeping the rest as cash to facilitate estate handling for inheritors.  Cat supplemented this with a detailed explanation of the stock pledging inheritance process, emphasizing the importance of advance planning.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Other Important Matters:</strong>
<ul>
<li><strong>Risk Warning and Disclaimer:</strong>  The content is for informational purposes only and does not constitute investment advice.  Do not remit funds to unknown accounts.</li>
<li><strong>Program Format Adjustment:</strong>  The presentation content will be expanded to include material previously covered in short videos.</li>
<li><strong>QQQ Stock Selection Mechanism:</strong>  Addresses audience questions regarding the QQQ stock selection mechanism, explaining the advantages of the Nasdaq exchange and why technology companies prefer listing on Nasdaq.</li>
<li><strong>Stock Pledging for Non-US Residents:</strong> Explains the regulations for non-US residents engaging in stock pledging with US brokers.</li>
<li><strong>Learning to Spend:</strong> Shares the philosophy of spending after achieving investment success, emphasizing the importance of focusing on future wealth growth and utilizing financial leverage for consumption.  Don&rsquo;t let wealth sit idle; learn how to use it.  This point is illustrated with the example of a listener who has $4 million but doesn&rsquo;t know how to spend it, calculating their potential wealth growth over 40 years and a reasonable spending level.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ol>


<h2 class="relative group">III. Q&amp;A Session 
    <div id="iii-qa-session" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii-qa-session" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p><strong>IAM:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Shared:</strong>  Expressed confusion about different types of economic crises and how the 2020-2023 pandemic period compares to previous bubbles after reading a book about economic crises.</li>
<li><strong>Question 1:</strong>  Which historical economic crisis is most similar to the economic downturn during the 2020-2023 pandemic?</li>
<li><strong>Answer:</strong> The 2020-2023 pandemic was an economic shock caused by an external event, distinct from previous bubble economies. The 2000 dot-com bubble was an industry bubble with limited impact; the 2008 financial crisis resembled the 1929 Great Depression, both being asset bubble bursts, but the 2008 crisis recovered faster due to quantitative easing. The 2022 market decline was not a bubble burst, but a revaluation caused by central bank interest rate hikes.</li>
<li><strong>Question 2:</strong> What did the US do to stimulate the economy that other countries couldn&rsquo;t replicate?</li>
<li><strong>Answer:</strong> The US is less constrained by fiscal discipline and is willing to borrow and issue debt, allocating funds to social welfare programs for the elderly, children, and healthcare, while guiding domestic capital towards overseas investment to mitigate inflation.  Taiwan&rsquo;s government was advised to learn from the US&rsquo;s fiscal spending approach and guide capital towards investment, while also focusing on efficient capital utilization and building a social safety net.</li>
<li><strong>Question 3:</strong> Why are Chinese people so keen on buying houses?</li>
<li><strong>Answer:</strong> This is a vestige of the agrarian &ldquo;land is wealth&rdquo; mentality, which is no longer applicable today.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Eason (Doctor):</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Shared:</strong>  Points to consider for Chinese investors buying Nasdaq ETFs:
<ul>
<li>Different brokerage firms have different fee policies and financing rates; careful comparison is necessary.</li>
<li>Domestic Nasdaq ETFs have premiums; buying during periods of low or negative premiums is recommended.  There are no limits for buying ETFs on the exchange, but there are limits for off-exchange subscriptions.</li>
<li>Recommends allocating a portion of assets to USD-denominated investments like QQQ, which can be purchased by opening brokerage accounts in Singapore or Hong Kong.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Added:</strong>  Chinese residents have a $50,000 annual foreign exchange quota for overseas investments.  Hong Kong and mainland China identities have different withholding tax rates on US stock investments.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Dave:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Question 1:</strong> Will the Nasdaq 100 index become stagnant like the Dow Jones index?</li>
<li><strong>Answer:</strong> Currently, the Nasdaq 100 is the most competitive; excessive worry about the future is unnecessary.</li>
<li><strong>Question 2:</strong> Is it feasible to only buy the top 10 companies in the Nasdaq 100 index?</li>
<li><strong>Answer:</strong> The top ten companies change frequently; individual stock selection and portfolio adjustments are too cumbersome, and returns may not be higher.  Investing directly in index funds is more efficient.</li>
<li><strong>Question 3:</strong> How do VGT and XLK compare to QQQ?</li>
<li><strong>Answer:</strong> VGT and XLK track different indices than QQQ, with different constituent stocks and concentration. QQQ is more robust and has broader coverage.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Jiawen:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Question:</strong> Can an 80% leveraged ETF + 10% cash + 10% bond portfolio be directly pledged? How is this done?</li>
<li><strong>Answer:</strong> Yes, but a small-scale trial is recommended, for instance, borrowing $200,000 against $5 million in principal, or borrowing within $1 million against $10 million. Long-term borrowing strategies should be adjusted according to circumstances. It&rsquo;s possible to pledge only a portion of the stocks, leaving the remainder for additional purchases or other uses.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Peter:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Shared:</strong>  Personal investment journey, transitioning from real estate to stocks, learning about stock pledging and asset allocation.</li>
<li><strong>Question:</strong> Is there synergy between real estate and stock investment? How can real estate cash flow be used for stock investment?</li>
<li><strong>Answer:</strong>  Buying a house is not recommended for young people. Real estate investment returns are lower than stocks and come with various risks (e.g., natural disasters, property taxes).  Even with positive cash flow, opportunity costs should be considered; investing that capital in stocks might yield higher returns.  Used Texas real estate as an example to illustrate the drawbacks of real estate investment.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Qiu Xiao:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Question 1:</strong>  What are the Canadian equivalents of US retirement accounts like IRA, Roth IRA, and 401k? Which account should cash be held in?</li>
<li><strong>Answer:</strong> Roth IRA corresponds to Canada&rsquo;s TFSA, Traditional IRA to RRSP, and 401k to DCPP. The choice of retirement account for cash depends on the individual&rsquo;s balance between taxable and tax-free accounts and their asset allocation strategy.  One should choose to place cash in either a tax-free or taxable account based on their specific circumstances for tax optimization.</li>
<li><strong>Question 2 (Related to Eason&rsquo;s question):</strong> How can one invest in Nasdaq ETFs in China, and how can quota limitations be addressed?</li>
<li><strong>Answer:</strong> Off-exchange subscriptions have quota limits, while on-exchange ETF purchases do not, but premiums should be considered.  Opening multiple brokerage accounts or opening an account in Hong Kong for US stock investment can be considered.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Haoqing:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Shared:</strong>  Used the example of SpaceX launching rockets with a small team to highlight concerns about AI replacing human labor and the difficulties young people face in finding employment.</li>
<li><strong>Question:</strong> How can we address the challenge of youth unemployment in the AI era?</li>
<li><strong>Answer:</strong>  Young people need to acquire AI skills to adapt to the future job market.  Recommends that schools incorporate AI courses into their core curriculum, cultivating AI talent from a young age. Philosophy is an important foundational subject but should not be a primary career focus.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Jimmy:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Shared:</strong>  Discussed the changing times and the need for young people to adapt, sharing observations about the youthful demographics of Xiamen. Mentioned the importance of aligning investments with the times and shared some common misunderstandings about investing he had encountered.</li>
<li><strong>Question:</strong> What are your views on index fund investing? Is the long-term return of 0050 sufficient? What are your thoughts on individual stock investing (e.g., TSMC)?</li>
<li><strong>Answer:</strong> Index fund investing is a method accessible to the general public, but many don&rsquo;t understand it and require time and experience to appreciate it. In the long run, QQQ and SPY offer higher returns and are more suitable for long-term investment. Individual stock picking demands specialized knowledge and skills and carries higher risks; it is difficult for average investors to select and hold high-quality stocks like TSMC for the long term.  The key to investing is finding investment targets that can be held long-term and sticking with them.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Other Q&amp;A:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>TQQQ Pledging:</strong>  Learn about stock pledging and how to achieve interest-free borrowing through the recommended videos.</li>
<li><strong>Top 10 QQQ Holdings:</strong>  Frequent trading is discouraged; holding the index fund long-term is sufficient.</li>
<li><strong>BOX vs. SWVXX:</strong>  BOX is recommended for brokerage accounts to avoid dividend taxes.</li>
<li><strong>Conservative Investing:</strong>  Conservative investing can involve holding cash or holding index funds long-term.</li>
<li><strong>How to Spend Money:</strong>  Focus on future wealth growth and utilize financial leverage for consumption.</li>
<li><strong>Investing in US Stocks from within China:</strong>  Coming to the US to invest or remitting funds to the US for investment is recommended.  Consider opening an account in Hong Kong or using other compliant channels for investment.</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">IV. Key Takeaways 
    <div id="iv-key-takeaways" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv-key-takeaways" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>AI demand is not a bubble; technological advancements will drive a bull market lasting 20 years.  We are just at the beginning.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>James emphasizes his belief that AI is a long-term trend and encourages investors to recognize the current market as the starting point of a significant bull run.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>High returns are meaningless if the probability of success is low.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>James reiterates that a successful investment strategy prioritizes long-term holding and consistency over chasing high returns with low success rates.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Young people need to learn AI skills to adapt to the future job market. AI courses should be core curriculum in all departments.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>James stresses the importance of acquiring AI skills for future employment and advocates for integrating AI education into all academic disciplines.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Earning money is easy; spending it wisely is difficult.  Don&rsquo;t let your wealth sit idle; learn how to use it.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>James offers a unique perspective on wealth management, urging listeners to become skilled spenders and maximize their wealth&rsquo;s potential.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Governments should invest in the elderly and children, building a strong social safety net.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>James underscores the importance of social welfare, suggesting that nations prioritize investing in the well-being of their youngest and oldest citizens.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">V. Summary 
    <div id="v-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#v-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This session centers on long-term investment in the Nasdaq 100 index fund, covering market trends, investment strategies, the use of financial leverage, and personal development in the AI era.  James not only shares professional investment concepts and techniques but also encourages listeners to shift their mindsets, embrace the opportunities presented by technological advancements, and learn how to better manage and utilize their wealth. He also emphasizes the government&rsquo;s responsibility in social welfare development, advocating for a more robust social safety net to protect the well-being of the elderly and children.  Furthermore, the session addresses the needs of Chinese investors by answering questions about accessing US markets from China and related tax implications.</p>

  



<div
  
    class="flex px-4 py-3 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900"
  >

  <span
    
      class="text-primary-400 ltr:pr-3 rtl:pl-3 flex items-center"
    >

    

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M506.3 417l-213.3-364c-16.33-28-57.54-28-73.98 0l-213.2 364C-10.59 444.9 9.849 480 42.74 480h426.6C502.1 480 522.6 445 506.3 417zM232 168c0-13.25 10.75-24 24-24S280 154.8 280 168v128c0 13.25-10.75 24-23.1 24S232 309.3 232 296V168zM256 416c-17.36 0-31.44-14.08-31.44-31.44c0-17.36 14.07-31.44 31.44-31.44s31.44 14.08 31.44 31.44C287.4 401.9 273.4 416 256 416z"/></svg>

  </span>


  </span>

  <span
    
      class="dark:text-neutral-300"
    ><strong>Disclaimer:</strong> This article is for personal learning notes only and does not constitute any investment advice.</span>
</div>

]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>00487 The Truth About Investing: Maximizing the Probability of Success, Not Returns; How to Navigate Market Volatility: Strategies to Avoid Interrupting Compound Growth</title>
      <link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1728777529388/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1728777529388/</guid>
      <description>James announces the discontinuation of short video updates, with content to be condensed into a Saturday briefing format. This session emphasizes the importance of risk control and how to maximize the success probability of an investment portfolio. James addresses audience questions on stock pledging, asset allocation, individual stock investments, and reiterates warnings about pump-and-dump schemes and scams. He also shares insights on market volatility, A-share market fluctuations, and investment psychology.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<lite-youtube videoid="ThLEX-IsszE" playlabel="ThLEX-IsszE" params=""></lite-youtube>



<h2 class="relative group">I. Main Topic 
    <div id="i-main-topic" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-main-topic" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>The most important thing in investing is <strong>maximizing the probability of success</strong>, not maximizing returns. Investors should <strong>control risks</strong>, <strong>avoid being forced to interrupt compounding due to market fluctuations</strong>, and choose investment portfolios that can be <strong>held for the long term</strong>. James emphasizes the importance of asset allocation, especially the role of cash, and the need to choose appropriate investment strategies based on different individuals (retired/not retired, different asset sizes).</p>


<h2 class="relative group">II. Briefing Content 
    <div id="ii-briefing-content" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii-briefing-content" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<ol>
<li><strong>The Most Important Thing in Investing:</strong>
<ul>
<li>The goal of investing is to maximize the probability of success, not to maximize the rate of return.</li>
<li>Risk management is to maximize the success of the investment portfolio and avoid interrupting compound growth due to being forced to sell because of market fluctuations.</li>
<li>Good investment assets must be able to withstand fear and panic. The best investment strategies are those that do not create fear and panic.</li>
<li>Sufficient cash is the best asset to help you sleep well and survive a sharp market decline.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Risks of Stock Pledging:</strong>
<ul>
<li>Stock pledging can easily lead to bankruptcy if asset allocation is not done properly.</li>
<li>Do not try stock pledging lightly if you do not understand the operating principles of stock pledging, otherwise, you will most likely go bankrupt.</li>
<li>Most people do not need to do stock pledging. Good asset allocation can make you rich without pledging.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Asset Allocation for Different Individuals:</strong>
<ul>
<li><strong>Individuals who are not retired and have salary income:</strong> Refer to the article &ldquo;Asset Allocation for Those Who Are Still Some Time Away from Retirement&rdquo;, with QQQ as the main investment.</li>
<li><strong>Individuals who are retired and have no income:</strong> Refer to the article &ldquo;Asset Allocation for Those Who Are Retired and Have No Income&rdquo;, and choose QQQ, SPY, or high-dividend ETFs for allocation based on asset size, and consider the withdrawal rate.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Investment and Life Philosophy:</strong>
<ul>
<li>Investing is like life. It requires continuous learning and experiencing different stages to find an investment strategy that suits you.</li>
<li>Resist temptation, avoid chasing short-term hotspots, and adhere to long-term investment.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>A-share Market Volatility:</strong>
<ul>
<li>The A-share market has recently experienced a surge and a plunge, with many investors being trapped due to chasing hotspots.</li>
<li>Market fluctuations are normal, especially in emerging markets. Investors need to be rational and adhere to long-term investment strategies.</li>
<li>The Chinese government&rsquo;s cooling measures are aimed at preventing further expansion of the bubble and protecting the interests of investors.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Beware of Pump and Dump Schemes:</strong>
<ul>
<li>Some online groups and &ldquo;teachers&rdquo; use market forecasts and insider information to induce investors to make trades and profit from them. Be wary of these pump and dump schemes.</li>
<li>The futures market, due to its smaller scale, is more susceptible to manipulation. Be wary of pump and dump schemes in the futures market as well.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>CLEC Investment and Financial Management Channel Update Plan:</strong>
<ul>
<li>Due to the time-consuming nature of producing short videos and the low viewership, we plan to stop updating short videos.</li>
<li>The content of the produced short videos will be condensed into a briefing format and shared with you on Saturdays for discussion.</li>
<li>It is recommended that you listen to long videos several times or listen to them in segments to achieve the same learning effect.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ol>


<h2 class="relative group">III. Q&amp;A Session 
    <div id="iii-qa-session" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii-qa-session" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p><strong>Ethan:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing:</strong> In China, a similar effect to stock pledging can be achieved through the margin financing function of securities firms.</li>
<li><strong>Sharing:</strong> The A-share market has recently experienced drastic fluctuations, and many investors have been influenced by the media to chase hotspots, resulting in heavy losses.</li>
<li><strong>Viewpoint:</strong> If you don&rsquo;t have the right understanding of the stock market, you are the victim.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Jackie:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing:</strong>  Her personal journey of investing in the Nasdaq, from skepticism to firm holding, and finally overcoming psychological barriers to achieve &ldquo;buy whenever you have money&rdquo;.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>H:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing:</strong>  Followed recommendations for meme stocks in 2021, resulting in heavy losses. Started gradually transferring funds to QQQ in 2023 and using leverage.</li>
<li><strong>Question:</strong>  The current proportions of QQQ, QLD, and SGOV have deviated from the initial 70%, 20%, and 10%. Is rebalancing needed? How should it be rebalanced?</li>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Reply:</strong>  It is recommended to adopt a smart rebalancing strategy. Transfer 30% of the QLD profits to SGOV. When the market falls, transfer 2% of the total assets in cash to QLD.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Im:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing:</strong>  Uses the mural story of Journey to the West as an analogy for the different stages of investment, reminding investors not to chase short-term gains and to adhere to long-term investment and continuous learning.</li>
<li><strong>Question:</strong>  How to persuade people who spend extravagantly to develop the habit of saving?</li>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Reply:</strong>  You can introduce them to the concept of long-term investment in index funds and the power of compound growth. Provide help within your means.</li>
<li><strong>Question:</strong>  If you also have the habit of spending extravagantly, how do you control it?</li>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Reply:</strong>  Live within your means. As your wealth grows, it is normal for your living standards to gradually improve within the scope of risk control, but avoid excessive consumption and spending beyond your means.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Sunny:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing:</strong>  The CLEC course not only teaches investment knowledge but also conveys life philosophy, helping everyone maintain a stable mindset in life and work.</li>
<li><strong>Viewpoint:</strong>  People with stable emotions are the most valuable. Investing in QQQ also brings peace of mind.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Beisen:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Background:</strong>  Assets of 70 million, monthly mortgage payment of 125,000.</li>
<li><strong>Question:</strong>  How to allocate assets to achieve early retirement?</li>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Reply:</strong>  Based on the current assets and expenses, immediate retirement is not possible. It is recommended to try the SPY asset allocation strategy, or use part of the funds to invest in high-dividend ETFs, and control the withdrawal rate.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Kevin:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Question:</strong>  Why has Tesla fallen so much?</li>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Reply:</strong>  Investing in individual stocks requires understanding the company better than the CEO to grasp the ups and downs of the stock price. If you don&rsquo;t understand Tesla&rsquo;s business model, you shouldn&rsquo;t invest in it.</li>
<li><strong>Question:</strong>  If you are very confident in Tesla, can you hold it for the long term?</li>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Reply:</strong>  If you truly understand and are optimistic about Tesla, you can hold it for the long term, but you must manage risks well.</li>
<li><strong>Question:</strong>  Does the teacher think the stock market will fall to zero?</li>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Reply:</strong>  &ldquo;Falling to zero&rdquo; is a figure of speech, which means that even if the stock does not completely fall to zero, it will not be able to be realized if it falls to a certain level, and cash is needed to maintain life.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Ming:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing:</strong>  I have invested in individual stocks before, and they all ended up going to zero in the end, so now I want to learn how to invest in index ETFs.</li>
<li><strong>Background:</strong>  Total assets of 3.3 million, of which 2 million are in a brokerage account, 300,000 are in a Roth account, and 1 million are in a traditional IRA account.  About to retire.</li>
<li><strong>Question:</strong>  How to allocate cash and index ETFs?</li>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Reply:</strong>  It is recommended to fully invest the brokerage account in SPY, the Roth account in TQQQ, and 60% of the traditional IRA account in money market funds and 40% in SPY.</li>
<li><strong>Question:</strong>  How to withdraw funds after retirement? Do you sell even in a loss state?</li>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Reply:</strong>  After retirement, you can withdraw 3% of your total assets for living expenses. You can sell SPY or obtain funds through stock pledging loans. You have to sell even in a loss state because you need cash to maintain your life.</li>
<li><strong>Question:</strong>  Is the risk of investing in TQQQ in a Roth account too high?</li>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Reply:</strong>  It is to maintain a certain cash ratio while obtaining relatively high returns. In extreme cases, you can transfer cash from the traditional IRA to the brokerage account or sell TQQQ to supplement cash.</li>
<li><strong>Question:</strong>  How to transfer funds from a traditional IRA to a Roth account?</li>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Reply:</strong>  Transfer out a portion of the money every year and use loans or salary to pay taxes.</li>
<li><strong>Question:</strong>  Why is the borrowing interest rate 5% and the cash interest rate only 2.5% when calculating interest in SPACE?</li>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Reply:</strong>  This is just a conservative estimate. The yield of money market funds is usually lower than the borrowing interest rate.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Sara:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing:</strong>  I have been investing in QQQ for three years and recently also invested in meme stocks.</li>
<li><strong>Question:</strong>  I plan to borrow money to invest. Should I buy QLD? How should cash be allocated?</li>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Reply:</strong>  Based on Sara&rsquo;s questions, it can be seen that she does not understand the concepts of stock pledging, leveraged ETFs, and asset allocation. Borrowing money to invest is not recommended. It is recommended to continue holding the 80% QQQ + 20% cash portfolio, and cash can be invested in BOXS.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Tom:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Question:</strong>  How to maintain the cash ratio and avoid excessive tax rates in the case of long-term borrowing to live?</li>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Reply:</strong>
<ul>
<li>Leveraged ETFs and cash should be placed in retirement accounts as much as possible.</li>
<li>Borrowing from a brokerage account should not exceed 70% of the account assets.</li>
<li>Invest Roth IRA in TQQQ and hold cash in a traditional IRA.</li>
<li>In extreme cases, the cash in the traditional IRA can be transferred to the brokerage account or TQQQ can be sold to supplement cash.</li>
<li>The borrowing amount should be controlled within a certain range, for example, not exceeding 2% of the total assets per year.</li>
<li>Taxes incurred by transferring a traditional IRA to a Roth IRA can be paid with loans or salary.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question:</strong>  Why is the borrowing interest rate 5% while the cash interest rate is only calculated as 2.5% in SPACE?</li>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Reply:</strong>  This is just a conservative estimate. Money market fund yields are usually lower than borrowing rates.</li>
<li><strong>Question:</strong>  How to handle it if funds in the Brokerage account need to be used before retirement?</li>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Reply:</strong>  You can use the funds in the Brokerage account for a pledge loan, but you need sufficient cash as a guarantee.</li>
<li><strong>Question:</strong>  What if the cash in the Brokerage account is insufficient to cover the loan in the event of an extreme stock market decline?</li>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Reply:</strong>  In extreme cases, you can transfer the cash in the Roth or Traditional IRA account to the Brokerage account, but this is an emergency measure and will incur penalties.</li>
<li><strong>Question:</strong>  Is investing TQQQ in a Roth IRA too risky?</li>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Reply:</strong>  Investing Roth IRA in TQQQ is to obtain higher returns while ensuring a certain cash ratio. If you are concerned about risks, you can appropriately reduce the proportion of TQQQ and increase the proportion of money market funds.</li>
<li><strong>Question:</strong>  In the long run, will borrowing from a Brokerage account lead to paying high taxes?</li>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Reply:</strong>  Borrowing itself does not increase the tax burden, but it can avoid the tax burden caused by selling stocks. However, if you transfer funds from a Traditional IRA to a Roth IRA, it will increase your taxable income for the year and you will need to pay additional taxes.</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">IV. Highlights 
    <div id="iv-highlights" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv-highlights" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p><strong>The most important thing in investing is maximizing the probability of success, not maximizing the rate of return.</strong>
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>To achieve long-term stable returns, control risks, avoid being forced to interrupt compound growth due to market fluctuations, and choose investment portfolios that can be held for the long term.</p>
<blockquote>
<p><strong>Don&rsquo;t try stock pledging lightly if you don&rsquo;t understand it.</strong>
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Stock pledging is very risky if not done properly and can lead to bankruptcy.</p>
<blockquote>
<p><strong>Most people don&rsquo;t need to do stock pledging and can still become wealthy without it.</strong>
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Good asset allocation and long-term investment can lead to financial freedom even without stock pledging.</p>
<blockquote>
<p><strong>If you don&rsquo;t have the right understanding of the stock market, you are the victim.</strong>
&ndash; Ethan</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Learn investment knowledge, understand market rules, and avoid becoming a韭菜 (leek, a metaphor for someone easily exploited in the stock market).</p>
<blockquote>
<p><strong>Investing is like life. You need to keep learning to find an investment strategy that suits you.</strong>
&ndash; Im</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Investing is a continuous learning process. You need to constantly improve your cognitive level to succeed in the market.</p>
<blockquote>
<p><strong>People with stable emotions are the most valuable. Investing in QQQ also brings peace of mind.</strong>
&ndash; Sunny</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Investing requires rationality and avoiding emotional trading to succeed in market volatility.</p>
<blockquote>
<p><strong>Rotten apples don&rsquo;t get better, and broken elevators don&rsquo;t fix themselves.</strong>
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>If the individual stocks you hold are not performing well, cut your losses in time and switch to more potential investment targets.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">V. Summary 
    <div id="v-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#v-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This episode emphasizes the importance of risk management and asset allocation and gives specific investment advice for different groups of people. James answers the audience&rsquo;s questions about stock pledging, asset allocation, individual stock selection, market fluctuations, pump and dump schemes, etc., to help everyone better understand the concept and methods of long-term investment. At the same time, James also announced the future update plan of the CLEC Investment and Financial Management Channel, which will stop updating short videos and condense the content of the short videos into a briefing format for sharing on Saturdays.</p>

  



<div
  
    class="flex px-4 py-3 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900"
  >

  <span
    
      class="text-primary-400 ltr:pr-3 rtl:pl-3 flex items-center"
    >

    

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M506.3 417l-213.3-364c-16.33-28-57.54-28-73.98 0l-213.2 364C-10.59 444.9 9.849 480 42.74 480h426.6C502.1 480 522.6 445 506.3 417zM232 168c0-13.25 10.75-24 24-24S280 154.8 280 168v128c0 13.25-10.75 24-23.1 24S232 309.3 232 296V168zM256 416c-17.36 0-31.44-14.08-31.44-31.44c0-17.36 14.07-31.44 31.44-31.44s31.44 14.08 31.44 31.44C287.4 401.9 273.4 416 256 416z"/></svg>

  </span>


  </span>

  <span
    
      class="dark:text-neutral-300"
    ><strong>Disclaimer:</strong> This article is for personal learning notes only and does not constitute any investment advice.</span>
</div>

]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
