<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Investment Psychology on QQQ Investor</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/tags/investment-psychology/</link><description>Recent content in Investment Psychology on QQQ Investor</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jomonylw.github.io/en/tags/investment-psychology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>00487 The Truth About Investing：Maximizing the Probability of Success, Not Returns; How to Navigate Market Volatility：Strategies to Avoid Interrupting Compound Growth</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1728777529388/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1728777529388/</guid><description>James announces the discontinuation of short video updates, with content to be condensed into a Saturday briefing format. This session emphasizes the importance of risk control and how to maximize the success probability of an investment portfolio. James addresses audience questions on stock pledging, asset allocation, individual stock investments, and reiterates warnings about pump-and-dump schemes and scams. He also shares insights on market volatility, A-share market fluctuations, and investment psychology.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<lite-youtube videoid="ThLEX-IsszE" playlabel="ThLEX-IsszE" params=""></lite-youtube>



<h2 class="relative group">I. Session Topic 
    <div id="i-session-topic" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-session-topic" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This session revolves around risk control and investment strategies, with the core message being that investment success lies not in maximizing returns, but in maximizing the probability of success. It emphasizes avoiding forced interruption of compound growth due to market fluctuations, choosing an investment portfolio that can be held for the long term, and highlights the importance of cash. James announces the discontinuation of short video updates, with future sharing of investment philosophies and case studies through long videos and Saturday briefings.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">II. Briefing Content 
    <div id="ii-briefing-content" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii-briefing-content" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<ul>
<li><strong>Discontinuation of Short Videos:</strong> James announces the end of short video updates, with content to be streamlined and condensed into a briefing format, shared and discussed on Saturdays, covering case studies and life philosophies. Short videos have been produced up to March 27th of next year, at which point updates will cease.</li>
<li><strong>Prioritizing Risk Control:</strong> The most important aspect of investing is maximizing the probability of success, not maximizing returns. Risk control aims to safeguard the long-term success of an investment portfolio, avoiding forced exits due to market volatility. It&rsquo;s better to earn less and ensure long-term holding.</li>
<li><strong>Importance of Cash:</strong> Sufficient cash is a crucial asset for ensuring the safety of an investment portfolio, allowing investors  to weather periods of significant market decline with peace of mind. It&rsquo;s the key to &ldquo;sleeping well at night.&rdquo;</li>
<li><strong>Risks of Stock Pledging:</strong> Stock pledging, if not accompanied by proper asset allocation, carries a substantial risk of bankruptcy. Without adequate financial literacy, it should not be attempted lightly. Especially in Taiwan, borrowing 3 million against 5 million in assets is close to the pledging limit and extremely risky. James emphasizes understanding &ldquo;Scenario 1&rdquo; through &ldquo;Scenario 9&rdquo; and how to respond to different situations.</li>
<li><strong>Importance of Asset Allocation:</strong> Proper asset allocation is crucial, tailored to individual circumstances.  Those who don&rsquo;t understand stock pledging should avoid it. Recommendations are provided for different asset levels and retirement statuses:
<ul>
<li><strong>Not retired and with income:</strong> QQQ 60% + QLD 20% + Cash 20%. This is an aggressive investment strategy, with most funds allocated to Nasdaq 100 index funds.</li>
<li><strong>Retired and with sufficient assets (50x annual expenses and above):</strong> QQQ 80% + Cash 20%. Retirees with ample assets can adopt this allocation.</li>
<li><strong>Retired with assets between 20-50x annual expenses:</strong> SPY or High Dividend + Cash 20% (SPY/High Dividend ratio can be adjusted based on specific circumstances). Those who are retired but with insufficient assets can utilize an SPY or High Dividend strategy with a 20% cash allocation.</li>
<li><strong>Retired with assets below 20x annual expenses:</strong> 0056 or SPHD + 5% Cash (conservative strategy).  Individuals with even fewer assets should not engage in stock pledging due to the higher risk, and should adopt a more conservative strategy.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Beware of Pump-and-Dump Schemes and Scams:</strong>  Listeners are warned to be vigilant against pump-and-dump schemes and scams in the market, not to blindly trust so-called &ldquo;gurus&rdquo; and &ldquo;experts,&rdquo; and to avoid sending money to unknown websites. CLEC does not charge any fees, and all groups are open and transparent.</li>
<li><strong>Market Volatility is Normal:</strong> The market will eventually rise and continually reach new highs. Investors should remain optimistic and patiently await the growth of their wealth. &ldquo;Investors are always optimistic, always looking towards the sun.&rdquo;</li>
<li><strong>A-Share Market Volatility:</strong> The A-share market is highly volatile, reminding investors to remain rational and avoid impulsive buying and selling. The government&rsquo;s cooling measures are aimed at the long-term healthy development of the market, not at specific stocks or investors.</li>
<li><strong>Investing is Like Life&rsquo;s Cultivation:</strong> The example of Journey to the West is used to illustrate that both investing and life require continuous learning and progress. Making mistakes is not terrible; the important thing is to learn from them.</li>
<li><strong>Recommended Reading:</strong> Recommends Professor Zhou Guannan&rsquo;s book &ldquo;Long-Term Investing&rdquo; to learn about investment psychology.</li>
<li><strong>Guidance for Newcomers:</strong> Newcomers are advised to watch YouTube channel videos 00451, 00398 or 00288, as well as videos from 2023 to the present, to understand CLEC&rsquo;s investment philosophy and system.</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">III. Q&amp;A Session 
    <div id="iii-qa-session" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii-qa-session" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p><strong>Ethan:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Although stock pledging is not available in mainland China, a similar effect can be achieved through the margin financing function of brokerage firms, utilizing the transfer of collateral between margin accounts and regular accounts.</li>
<li>Sharing: The A-share market has experienced significant volatility recently, reminding everyone not to be swayed by market sentiment and to adhere to a long-term investment strategy. Many investors are easily influenced by market emotions, leading to buying high and selling low.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Jackie:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Describes her journey from initial skepticism to fully understanding and embracing the concept of long-term Nasdaq investing, including overcoming psychological barriers to finally going all-in on QQQ. This sharing mentions two psychological obstacles overcome: 1. Fear of buying at the highest point; 2. Comparison between investing in real estate and investing in QQQ.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>H:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Recounts her personal experience of investing in popular stocks, and the eventual process of cutting losses and switching to QQQ, emphasizing the importance of cutting losses. Shares her experience of listening to recommendations for popular stocks in 2021, which led to losses, and finally switching to QQQ in 2023.</li>
<li>Question: The ratio of QQQ and QLD is out of balance, how to rebalance?</li>
<li>James&rsquo;s reply: Suggests using the Smart Rebalancing strategy, transferring 30% of the profits from QLD to SGOV. When the market falls, transfer 2% of the total assets in cash to QLD.  Also recommends that H read articles about Smart Rebalancing.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Kevin:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>Questions:</p>
<ul>
<li>I&rsquo;d like to understand why Tesla has dropped so much.</li>
<li>Also, could the stock market ever really fall to zero?</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p>James&rsquo; responses:</p>
<ul>
<li>Tesla&rsquo;s Decline: James stated that he doesn&rsquo;t have a specific opinion on this. Daily fluctuations are unpredictable, and jokingly suggested asking a deity (&ldquo;Third Prince&rdquo;) for a more accurate prediction. He emphasized that investing in individual stocks requires an understanding of the company&rsquo;s business model that surpasses even the CEO&rsquo;s. If you don&rsquo;t have a stronger vision and ability than Elon Musk, you shouldn&rsquo;t be investing in Tesla. Market ups and downs are not the primary concern; understanding the company&rsquo;s value and long-term plan is crucial.</li>
<li>Stock Market Crashing to Zero: James explained that &ldquo;the market falling to zero&rdquo; is a figure of speech. It refers to a situation where the market might not literally hit zero, but it falls to a point where selling is impractical or impossible. There&rsquo;s a possibility of market closures, like what happened during 911. Closure is equivalent to zero in that context. He highlighted the importance of cash reserves, as they are essential for sustaining living expenses during market downturns.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>IM:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Uses the mural story from Journey to the West as an analogy for the investment journey, from the initial excitement of entering the market to the pain of being trapped, and finally to the enlightenment of finding the correct investment method.</li>
<li>Question: How to persuade friends who spend money lavishly?</li>
<li>James&rsquo;s reply: Explain the concept of long-term investing and show them the long-term upward trend of the market, illustrating that even small investments can accumulate wealth over time. If they still can&rsquo;t understand, then there&rsquo;s nothing more that can be done.</li>
<li>Question: How to control one&rsquo;s own lavish spending?</li>
<li>James&rsquo;s reply: Within the scope of risk control, it&rsquo;s normal for living standards to improve as wealth grows. The key is not to exceed one&rsquo;s own capabilities and to avoid selling stocks as much as possible. Spending money is a form of self-cultivation; it&rsquo;s important to live within one&rsquo;s means.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Ming:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Question: A series of questions about retirement accounts, stock pledging, cash allocation, etc. Ming has 3.3 million in assets, of which 2 million are in brokerage, 300,000 in Roth, and 1 million in a traditional account, with a monthly mortgage payment of 125,000.</li>
<li>James&rsquo;s reply: Provides detailed answers to Ming&rsquo;s questions and offers specific asset allocation advice based on her situation, including the allocation of brokerage, Roth, and traditional accounts, and how to utilize stock pledging and borrowing to reduce tax burden. Recommends brokerage 100% SPY, Roth 100% TQQQ, traditional 60% cash + 40% SPY.  Also suggests that Ming engage in stock pledging and use borrowed funds to cover living expenses and taxes.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Sara:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Question: As a 1099 worker nearing retirement, how to carry out asset allocation and borrow for investment?</li>
<li>James&rsquo;s reply: Since Sara lacks sufficient understanding of concepts like stock pledging, it&rsquo;s recommended that she not borrow money and adopt a simple allocation of 80% QQQ + 20% cash, with the cash portion allocated to BOXS. Also advises Sara to rebalance annually.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Tom:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Question: Questions about borrowing for investment, cash allocation, tax optimization, etc. Tom is concerned about the interest expenses and high tax rates associated with long-term borrowing, and how to maintain sufficient cash in brokerage accounts.</li>
<li>James&rsquo;s reply: Suggests that Tom keep leveraged funds and cash primarily in retirement accounts and engage in pledging operations based on specific circumstances. Emphasizes the flexibility of Roth accounts and the ability to transfer funds to brokerage accounts in emergencies. Explains that the interest calculation method is an estimate and doesn&rsquo;t need to be overly precise. Also recommends that Tom use Roth account funds for investing in TQQQ, traditional accounts for holding cash, and brokerage accounts for investing in QQQ and engaging in pledging.</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">IV. Key Insights 
    <div id="iv-key-insights" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv-key-insights" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>Don&rsquo;t make getting rich your goal, but rather strive not to die impoverished.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Investing is for a better life, not for becoming a billionaire. A sound investment strategy is more important than pursuing high returns.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>If you don&rsquo;t have the right understanding of the stock market, you&rsquo;ll become a victim. The stock market is a scam.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Emphasizes the importance of investor education and the risks present in the market.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>A rotten apple won&rsquo;t get better, and a broken elevator won&rsquo;t fix itself.
&mdash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Uses an analogy to illustrate the risk of individual stock investing and the importance of cutting losses in a timely manner.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Market fluctuations can sometimes exceed your imagination. If, midway, due to a sharp decline caused by fluctuations, you exit the market out of fear, or are forced to exit, the initially projected performance of your investment portfolio, no matter how good, will be useless.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Highlights the importance of risk control. Even if the expected return is high, if you can&rsquo;t withstand the risk, you may ultimately end up losing everything.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Human nature is what it is, but you must learn to control it.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Points out the importance of controlling human nature and emotions in investing.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">V. Summary 
    <div id="v-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#v-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This session underscores the importance of risk control and long-term investing. Avoid blindly chasing high returns while ignoring risks. The most important aspect of investing is long-term holding, avoiding forced exits due to market fluctuations. James announces the discontinuation of short video updates and addresses audience questions on stock pledging, asset allocation, individual stock investing (Tesla), and A-share market volatility. He reminds everyone again to be wary of pump-and-dump schemes and scams in the market, emphasizing that CLEC does not charge any fees. He encourages everyone to read Professor Zhou Guannan&rsquo;s book &ldquo;Long-Term Investing&rdquo; to gain knowledge about investment psychology. Based on the situations of different listeners, James provides specific asset allocation advice and explains in detail how to conduct stock pledging and rebalancing operations.</p>

  



<div
  
    class="flex px-4 py-3 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900"
  >

  <span
    
      class="text-primary-400 ltr:pr-3 rtl:pl-3 flex items-center"
    >

    

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M506.3 417l-213.3-364c-16.33-28-57.54-28-73.98 0l-213.2 364C-10.59 444.9 9.849 480 42.74 480h426.6C502.1 480 522.6 445 506.3 417zM232 168c0-13.25 10.75-24 24-24S280 154.8 280 168v128c0 13.25-10.75 24-23.1 24S232 309.3 232 296V168zM256 416c-17.36 0-31.44-14.08-31.44-31.44c0-17.36 14.07-31.44 31.44-31.44s31.44 14.08 31.44 31.44C287.4 401.9 273.4 416 256 416z"/></svg>

  </span>


  </span>

  <span
    
      class="dark:text-neutral-300"
    ><strong>Disclaimer:</strong> This article is for personal learning notes only and does not constitute any investment advice.</span>
</div>

]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>00483 Rock-solid asset allocation,Investment strategies based on asset allocation and risk management</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1728265687577/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1728265687577/</guid><description>This live stream focuses on the core concept of &amp;#34;wealth is a gift&amp;#34;. James explains the importance of investing and financial management, the advantages of index investing, the relationship between risk tolerance and investment returns, and how to allocate your assets reasonably. During the Q&amp;amp;A session, students raised questions about TQQQ investment, Beta calculation, asset allocation strategies, and the investment market in mainland China. James answered these questions in detail and shared numerous experiences and cases to help students overcome psychological barriers in investment and solidify their long-term investment philosophy.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<lite-youtube videoid="eSkubAhBlhE" playlabel="eSkubAhBlhE" params=""></lite-youtube>



<h2 class="relative group">I. Theme of the Episode 
    <div id="i-theme-of-the-episode" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-theme-of-the-episode" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>The theme of this episode is &ldquo;Investing and Financial Management, Wealth is a Gift.&rdquo; The core viewpoints  are: <strong>Wealth is innate, but one must be informed to realize it; investing and financial management is an important way to accumulate wealth; index investing is an effective method to achieve long-term stable growth; rational asset allocation and risk control are the keys to investment success; and overcoming psychological barriers in investment and solidifying the long-term investment philosophy are crucial to ultimately achieving financial freedom.</strong></p>


<h2 class="relative group">II. Summary of the Briefing 
    <div id="ii-summary-of-the-briefing" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii-summary-of-the-briefing" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<ul>
<li><strong>Wealth is a Gift:</strong> Wealth is innate, and being informed of this fact makes a huge difference. While successful entrepreneurs like Elon Musk are a minority, most people need to be told that &ldquo;wealth is a gift,&rdquo; and they need to learn how to invest and manage their finances to achieve wealth growth.</li>
<li><strong>The Power of Index Investing and Compound Interest:</strong> Index investing is an effective way to achieve long-term stable returns, and its compounding effect is astonishing. For example, investing $1,500 per month for 40 years with a 14% annualized return will yield $2.6 million. <strong>Even small amounts of money can accumulate considerable wealth through consistent long-term investment.</strong></li>
<li><strong>High Risk, High Return?</strong>: High risk doesn&rsquo;t necessarily lead to high returns. Whether you can bear the risk determines whether you can ultimately achieve high returns. Don&rsquo;t overestimate your risk tolerance. Your risk appetite should be determined by an asset allocation that you can withstand even if your investment goes to zero. <strong>For example, if you cannot afford the risk of TQQQ going to zero, you should not invest in TQQQ.</strong></li>
<li><strong>Choosing Investment Targets</strong>: It is recommended to invest in the global Nasdaq 100 index fund (QQQ). Those with insufficient funds or who are already retired can consider investing in SPY or high-dividend ETFs. Avoid investing in individual stocks because they tend to disappear over the long term, while index funds can continue to exist. <strong>The half-life of individual stocks is 10 years; out of 100 stocks, there may be less than three left after 50 years.</strong></li>
<li><strong>Investment Mindset</strong>: The market will eventually rise, and investment requires patience. Always stay optimistic, even if the investment goes to zero. Learning about investing and financial management requires continuous thinking, like peeling an onion, layer by layer, to elevate the energy of the spiritual level. <strong>Investing is like the Yellow Mountain, eternally unchanging, yet different every day; every learning experience will bring new insights.</strong></li>
<li><strong>Asset Allocation</strong>: Asset allocation is like building a house; it is a big project that requires comprehensive planning, not something simple. It is necessary to consider many factors, such as whether you are retired, your age, income, debt, and cash flow, to formulate a reasonable asset allocation plan. <strong>You need to carefully study the articles and videos on asset allocation provided by James to develop a plan that suits you.</strong></li>
<li><strong>Do Not  Blindly Trust External Information</strong>: Financial professionals often only consider their interests, so do not easily believe their advice. Think independently, study carefully, and do not be swayed by external information and noise. <strong>Most of the outside information is garbage; do not be affected by it, focus on learning James&rsquo; investment philosophy.</strong></li>
<li><strong>Balancing Risk and Reward</strong>: Do not excessively pursue high returns or completely risk-free investments; balance risk and reward. Avoid changing investment strategies easily to prevent additional costs due to frequent trading. <strong>James&rsquo; investment methods can guarantee asset appreciation and relative safety, avoiding extreme situations.</strong></li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">III. Q&amp;A Session 
    <div id="iii-qa-session" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii-qa-session" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p><strong>IM:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>Sharing: Learning about investment is like peeling an onion; at first, the amount of information is overwhelming, but as you learn more, you will gradually understand the core idea and ultimately reach the realm of &ldquo;the great Dao is simple.&rdquo;</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Question 1: What do you think about the idea that &ldquo;investing is simple&rdquo;?</p>
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo; Response: Such views often mistake ignorance for inaction and do not truly understand the complexity and risks of investment.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p>Question 2: How should we communicate with friends who don&rsquo;t understand index investing?</p>
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo; Response: You can start by briefly introducing the concept and advantages of index investing and suggest that they watch related videos to learn. Don&rsquo;t force them to accept it, everyone has their own choices. <strong>Just like preaching, we can only try our best to spread the message; whether it&rsquo;s ultimately accepted depends on the individual.</strong></li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>LAN:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>Question 1: How to calculate Beta? What is the actual Beta value of a leveraged ETF?</p>
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo; Response: You can refer to the link to the article on Beta calculation on the message board. The actual Beta value of a leveraged ETF may deviate from the theoretical value due to factors such as market volatility and friction costs. <strong>When market volatility is large, the wear and tear of leveraged ETFs will be more serious, resulting in an actual Beta value lower than the theoretical value.</strong></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p>Question 2: Why is there a huge difference in final return between scenario 3 and scenario 4.1 in the 005 topic?</p>
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo; Response: Scenario 4.1 is where no money is withdrawn from the investment, so the final return will be higher.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p>Question 3: How to adjust Beta in a rising market?</p>
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo; Response:  The adjustment of Beta should be determined by your own risk tolerance, not by the market trend. <strong>Do not try to predict the market, just keep a fixed Beta value.</strong></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p>Question 4:  For investments in Taiwan, should I choose Q2D or 00670L?</p>
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo; Response: 00670L is recommended because it includes New Taiwan dollar hedging, which can reduce the risk caused by exchange rate fluctuations. <strong>Don&rsquo;t change investment targets frequently, choose one that suits you and hold it for the long term.</strong></li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Nai Xin:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Wealth is a gift, just as self-confidence is a gift; everyone has potential, but it needs to be stimulated. The key to investing and financial management lies in learning. Once you have mastered the correct investment method, you can focus on your own career and life and let wealth grow naturally over time. <strong>Overcome fear, build confidence, and you can realize your potential, gain wealth, and achieve success.</strong></li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Jason:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Understanding &ldquo;buy whenever you have money,&rdquo; but still finding it difficult to overcome psychological fluctuations when the market rises or falls sharply.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo; Response:  Overcoming psychological fluctuations takes time and experience. You can try to make a small number of trades, experience the impact of market fluctuations, and gradually adapt to market changes.</li>
<li>IM Supplement: You can overcome psychological barriers by imagining starting to invest two years later and understanding that &ldquo;money arrives at different points in time.&rdquo;<strong>Don&rsquo;t worry about buying at the lowest point; as long as you stick to long-term investment, you can get good returns.</strong></li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Hai Rui Ji:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>Sharing:</p>
<ol>
<li>Thank you James for selflessly sharing your investment philosophy; students learn from each other and make progress together.</li>
<li>James&rsquo; investment philosophy requires continuous learning and understanding to grasp it fully. &ldquo;Never sell&rdquo; does not mean you cannot sell, but that you should develop a reasonable investment strategy based on your own situation. ** &ldquo;Never sell&rdquo; refers to mentally ignoring market fluctuations and adhering to a long-term investment philosophy.**</li>
<li>Investment philosophy needs to keep pace with the times and adjust investment strategies according to changes in the environment.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<p>Question: Already answered in the video.</p>
</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Li Zi:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: To overcome psychological barriers to investment, manage accounts separately, using one part for long-term investment and the other for tentative operations, such as selling covered calls. This satisfies the desire to trade and avoids losses due to frequent trading.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo; Response: You only know what is best after you have experienced it. Experience in trading can lead to a firmer commitment to a long-term investment strategy. <strong>Trying different trading strategies can help you understand the advantages of long-term investment and ultimately achieve the state of &ldquo;daily reduction for the Dao.&rdquo;</strong></li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>T:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>Question 1: Why has the capital market in mainland China performed poorly for a long time?</p>
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo; Response: Emerging markets take time to mature. The Chinese market is like the Taiwanese market 50 years ago. It has the potential to rise in the long term, but its return may be lower than that of the US market. <strong>Investment should focus on sustainable development markets. The US market has advantages in terms of systems and industries.</strong></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p>Question 2: Under foreign exchange control, how do I invest in US index funds? Are there any risks?</p>
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo; Response: You can invest by purchasing ETFs listed in China that track US index funds, such as 513100. Foreign exchange controls mainly restrict the physical flow of funds, and buying ETFs is not restricted. The current scale of such investment is small and will not trigger a quota limit. <strong>Even with foreign exchange control, it is still possible to allocate global assets through legal channels.</strong></li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">IV. Key Takeaways 
    <div id="iv-key-takeaways" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv-key-takeaways" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>Wealth is a Gift
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Everyone has the potential for wealth, but they must be informed to realize it and learn how to invest and manage their finances to achieve wealth growth.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Learning Increases Daily, the Dao Decreases Daily
&ndash; IM</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Learning about investing and financial management is a process of continuous improvement. At first, you will be exposed to a large amount of information, but as your understanding deepens, you will gradually simplify your investment strategy and eventually reach the state of &ldquo;the great Dao is simple.&rdquo;</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The Difficult to Return to After Seeing a Vast Ocean
&ndash; Li Zi &amp; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Only after experiencing something can you know what is best. In investing, only after actually operating and experiencing market fluctuations and the impact of different investment strategies can you more firmly choose the long-term investment strategy that suits you.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The More Money You Borrow, the More Money You Have
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Understand and control risk, not avoid it. Understanding how to use leverage can accelerate wealth growth, but only with proper risk management, such as building a solid asset allocation.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Cash is Air
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Cash is very important and you must keep enough cash to deal with market fluctuations and emergencies.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">V. Summary 
    <div id="v-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#v-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This live stream focused on the theme of &ldquo;Wealth is a gift.&rdquo; James explained the importance of investing and financial management, the advantages of index investing, the relationship between risk tolerance and investment returns, and how to conduct reasonable asset allocation in a simple and profound way. During the Q&amp;A session, students actively questioned their own issues and confusions. James patiently and meticulously answered them by combining practical cases and his own experience, helping the students better understand and master the knowledge and methods of investing and financial management. He also guided the students to overcome psychological barriers in investments, establish a firm long-term investment philosophy, and ultimately achieve financial freedom.</p>

  



<div
  
    class="flex px-4 py-3 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900"
  >

  <span
    
      class="text-primary-400 ltr:pr-3 rtl:pl-3 flex items-center"
    >

    

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M506.3 417l-213.3-364c-16.33-28-57.54-28-73.98 0l-213.2 364C-10.59 444.9 9.849 480 42.74 480h426.6C502.1 480 522.6 445 506.3 417zM232 168c0-13.25 10.75-24 24-24S280 154.8 280 168v128c0 13.25-10.75 24-23.1 24S232 309.3 232 296V168zM256 416c-17.36 0-31.44-14.08-31.44-31.44c0-17.36 14.07-31.44 31.44-31.44s31.44 14.08 31.44 31.44C287.4 401.9 273.4 416 256 416z"/></svg>

  </span>


  </span>

  <span
    
      class="dark:text-neutral-300"
    ><strong>Disclaimer:</strong> This article is a personal learning summary and does not constitute any investment advice.</span>
</div>

]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>00481 Asset Allocation Strategies to Avoid Market Pitfalls; How to Achieve Steady Wealth through Proper Investment Strategies</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1728285792652/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1728285792652/</guid><description>In this session, James emphasizes the crucial role of mental strength in investment success. He discusses asset allocation, the use and rebalancing of leveraged ETFs, provides supplementary explanations of 401(k) and IRA accounts, and touches upon choosing the right brokerage. The Q&amp;amp;A session addresses audience questions concerning investing with mortgage loans, market crash risks, the risks associated with single brokerage accounts, and how to cope with the psychological pressure stemming from market fluctuations. Furthermore, the discussion includes insights on investment target selection, the purpose of holding cash, and life planning.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<lite-youtube videoid="ZvTM4--CaKw" playlabel="ZvTM4--CaKw" params=""></lite-youtube>



<h2 class="relative group">I. Main Theme 
    <div id="i-main-theme" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-main-theme" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This session centers around the importance of psychological resilience in investing. James&rsquo;s core message is that mental strength is the key to investment success, while other skills and calculations are secondary. Investors need to maintain a highly optimistic mindset, viewing market fluctuations as opportunities rather than crises in the long run. Long-term investing, rational analysis, and maintaining a healthy mindset are more crucial than striving for precise calculations.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">II. Briefing Content 
    <div id="ii-briefing-content" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii-briefing-content" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<ul>
<li><strong>Correction on 401(k) and IRA:</strong> James corrects a statement from the previous session regarding 401(k) and IRA contribution limits, clarifying that the limits for each are independent, but that IRAs have income restrictions. He provides further explanations about the Backdoor Roth IRA conversion, advising listeners to manage pre-tax and after-tax funds carefully to avoid account confusion and complications during tax filing.</li>
<li><strong>Asset Allocation Strategy:</strong> He emphasizes the significance of asset allocation and suggests listeners refer to existing articles and Excel spreadsheets for simulations, discouraging impulsive decision-making. He offers various asset allocation plans catering to different risk tolerances and retirement stages, stressing the concept of &ldquo;fuzzy accuracy&rdquo; – that it is not necessary to pursue overly precise ratios, but ensuring sufficient cash reserves is crucial. Example: A listener proposes an allocation of 60% QQQ and 40% cash, which James believes carries a risk of bankruptcy and advises them to consult the provided asset allocation plans.</li>
<li><strong>Leveraged ETFs and Rebalancing:</strong> Using QQQ&rsquo;s beta value of 1.0 as a benchmark, he simplifies beta calculations for leveraged ETFs, for instance, QLD is considered 2.0. He recommends a gradual approach when adjusting beta during rebalancing, advising against drastic changes. For investors with earned income, the frequency and ratio of rebalancing can be more flexible. Example: He suggests that young investors can rotate investments among QQQ, QLD, and TQQQ every six months, then rebalance at the end of the year.</li>
<li><strong>Long-Term Investing and Market Volatility:</strong> James reiterates the importance of long-term investing, using the dot-com bubble of 2000 as an example to demonstrate that long-term investors ultimately profit, even after enduring prolonged market downturns. Market dips are opportunities, and investors should remain optimistic, buying whenever they have funds available. He refutes the notion that &ldquo;investments in 2000 took 15 years to break even,&rdquo; emphasizing that the market always recovers in the long run. Example: An investment of $5 million at the peak of the market in 2000, despite experiencing the burst of the internet bubble, would still have grown to $32.375 million by 2024.</li>
<li><strong>Brokerage Selection:</strong> He advises choosing brokerages with physical branch offices and understanding how stocks and cash are held in custody to ensure asset security. Example: He explains the risks of nominee accounts and recommends selecting brokerages that allow for direct ownership of stocks, encouraging listeners to inquire about the brokerage&rsquo;s custodian banks for stocks and cash.</li>
<li><strong>Purpose of Holding Cash:</strong> He underlines that cash holdings are meant for emergencies and to seize buying opportunities during market downturns, not for pursuing interest income. Example: He suggests maintaining a 20% cash position, a portion of which can be utilized for adding to leveraged ETFs during dips.</li>
<li><strong>Investment Target Selection:</strong> He recommends selecting suitable investment targets based on individual circumstances. For instance, retirees or individuals with limited funds may consider high-dividend ETFs, while younger individuals or those with ample funds should focus on growth-oriented ETFs like QQQ. Example: Addressing a listener holding SCH, James advises them to assess whether high-dividend ETFs are appropriate based on their asset level and annual expenses.</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">III. Q&amp;A Session 
    <div id="iii-qa-session" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii-qa-session" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p><strong>Danny:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Shares: He has been following James&rsquo;s investment strategy for three years and achieved a return of approximately 35%.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Chang&rsquo;an:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Question: Brokerage security and recommendations in Hong Kong.</li>
<li>James&rsquo;s Response: Choose brokerages with physical branch offices in the region, understand the custodian banks for stocks and cash, and avoid easily dissolved online brokerages.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Eric:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Shares: He began investing during the pandemic, experienced the hardships of short-term trading, and eventually recognized the importance of long-term investing and psychological control. He uses the example of Jesse Livermore to illustrate the risks of trading.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Jessie:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Shares: Both she and her husband are nearing 60 years old, and a portion of their investment funds comes from a mortgage loan. She expresses concerns about a potential market crash and the risk of USD devaluation.</li>
<li>Questions:</li>
</ul>
<ol>
<li>How to cope with a possible future market crash, especially with a mortgage due before retirement?</li>
<li>What about USD devaluation?</li>
<li>Are there risks associated with concentrating large sums of money in a single brokerage account?</li>
<li>Is it feasible to refinance the mortgage in five years or repay it early with funds from the investment account?</li>
</ol>
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Response:</li>
</ul>
<ol>
<li>The market is unlikely to experience losses within a 15-year timeframe. Ensure you can comfortably handle mortgage payments for the next 13 years; the most secure approach is to sell the house and repay the loan.</li>
<li>He declines to answer hypothetical questions.</li>
<li>Stocks are registered under the investor&rsquo;s name, hence the risk of brokerage failure is manageable.</li>
<li>Refinancing or early repayment is not recommended. Excessive focus on short-term interest gains is akin to &ldquo;penny wise, pound foolish,&rdquo; and ultimately increases risk.</li>
</ol>
<p><strong>Sam:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Shares: He went all-in on QQQ, but after some short-term trading, realized it wasn&rsquo;t suitable for him and experienced psychological pressure due to large position fluctuations.</li>
<li>Question: How to overcome the psychological pressure brought about by fluctuations in a large portfolio?</li>
<li>James&rsquo;s Response:</li>
</ul>
<ol>
<li>Focus on realized gains rather than unrealized gains.</li>
<li>Maintain 20% cash and 20% leveraged ETFs to stabilize your mindset.</li>
<li>Exercise caution with short-term trading, as it may not be sustainable in the long run.</li>
</ol>
<p><strong>Haoqing:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Shares: He uses examples of friends gambling and raising children to illustrate the importance of moderate expectations and nurturing interests. He compares and contrasts education philosophies and Nobel Prize achievements between China and the US, emphasizing the significance of financial freedom for the next generation.</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">IV. Highlights 
    <div id="iv-highlights" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv-highlights" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>Mental fortitude is the equipment for investing, it determines whether you will succeed.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Investment skills and calculations are undoubtedly important, but psychological resilience is the ultimate factor that decides investment success. Even for simple index fund investing, a sound mental state is needed to navigate market volatility.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>A market downturn is not a disaster, it&rsquo;s an opportunity.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>From a long-term investment perspective, market downturns provide excellent opportunities to acquire high-quality assets.  Maintain a long-term outlook and don&rsquo;t be intimidated by short-term fluctuations.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>There should be a limit to human pessimism.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Excessive pessimism and worry are detrimental to investments. One should rationally analyze risks and develop sensible coping strategies. Do not let extreme scenarios or low-probability events unduly influence investment decisions.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Parents sometimes have these expectations for their children, don&rsquo;t impose your unfulfilled aspirations on them.
&ndash; Haoqing</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Parents should respect their children&rsquo;s individuality and interests and refrain from forcing their own unaccomplished goals onto them. Allowing children to have a joyful childhood and the autonomy to choose their own paths in life is more important than chasing conventional success.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">V. Summary 
    <div id="v-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#v-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>In this session, James reiterates the importance of mental fortitude in investing and the effectiveness of long-term investment and asset allocation strategies. By addressing listeners&rsquo; practical concerns, such as retirement planning, market volatility, and capital security, he helps them better understand and apply these investment principles. James also provides advice on choosing appropriate investment targets and the purpose of holding cash, aiding listeners in constructing more comprehensive investment strategies. Haoqing&rsquo;s sharing sparked reflection on educational philosophies and life values, advocating for a focus on children&rsquo;s overall development and mental well-being.</p>

  



<div
  
    class="flex px-4 py-3 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900"
  >

  <span
    
      class="text-primary-400 ltr:pr-3 rtl:pl-3 flex items-center"
    >

    

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M506.3 417l-213.3-364c-16.33-28-57.54-28-73.98 0l-213.2 364C-10.59 444.9 9.849 480 42.74 480h426.6C502.1 480 522.6 445 506.3 417zM232 168c0-13.25 10.75-24 24-24S280 154.8 280 168v128c0 13.25-10.75 24-23.1 24S232 309.3 232 296V168zM256 416c-17.36 0-31.44-14.08-31.44-31.44c0-17.36 14.07-31.44 31.44-31.44s31.44 14.08 31.44 31.44C287.4 401.9 273.4 416 256 416z"/></svg>

  </span>


  </span>

  <span
    
      class="dark:text-neutral-300"
    ><strong>Disclaimer:</strong> This document is only for personal learning and note-taking purposes and does not constitute any investment advice.</span>
</div>

]]></content:encoded></item></channel></rss>