<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Investment Psychology on QQQ Investor</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/tags/investment-psychology/</link><description>Recent content in Investment Psychology on QQQ Investor</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 28 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jomonylw.github.io/en/tags/investment-psychology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>00520 [Stop Being a Sucker! The Truth About Investment Scams and the Right Mindset for Financial Management</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1751158103958/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1751158103958/</guid><description>In this session, Teacher James emphasizes that market volatility is irrelevant to long-term investors and that the biggest risk is being out of the market. He reiterates the core philosophy of &amp;#39;buy whenever you have money, and never sell,&amp;#39; and delves into asset allocation, the use of leveraged funds, the principles of borrowing to invest, and how to debunk common investment myths like the Buffett Indicator. He also shares his unique perspective on capitalism and warns everyone to be vigilant against investment scams.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<lite-youtube videoid="GbkfZwvjqkU" playlabel="GbkfZwvjqkU" params=""></lite-youtube>



<h2 class="relative group">I. Topic of the Session 
    <div id="i-topic-of-the-session" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-topic-of-the-session" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>The core theme of this session is to emphasize that long-term investors should ignore short-term market volatility and firmly believe in the market&rsquo;s perpetual upward trend. Teacher James points out that having funds out of the market is the biggest risk, and investors should enter the market as soon as possible, adopting a &ldquo;buy whenever you have money, and never sell&rdquo; strategy. By debunking common market prediction indicators (like the Buffett Indicator) and analyzing asset allocation, he aims to help investors build a solid investment mindset to achieve long-term wealth growth.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">II. Briefing Content 
    <div id="ii-briefing-content" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii-briefing-content" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Core Investment Philosophy and Market Attitude 
    <div id="core-investment-philosophy-and-market-attitude" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#core-investment-philosophy-and-market-attitude" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Market Volatility Doesn&rsquo;t Concern Me</strong>: For long-term investors, daily market fluctuations, global situations, tariff wars, etc., should not influence investment decisions. The market hitting new highs for three consecutive days proves the importance of staying in the market.</li>
<li><strong>Being Out of the Market is the Biggest Risk</strong>: Many people exit the market fearing a downturn, but waiting for a correction might mean never getting back in. Keeping funds out of the market and missing out on gains is a far greater risk than a short-term decline.</li>
<li><strong>Predictions are Useless, Making Money is What Matters</strong>: There are many who make correct market predictions, but the ones who actually make money are those who ignore the predictions and stay invested.</li>
<li><strong>The Market Always Goes Up</strong>: This is the core belief a long-term investor must have. Historical data proves that in the long run, the market only goes up and will always reach new highs. Investors should always be extremely optimistic and face the sun.</li>
<li><strong>Review the Past, Preview the Future</strong>: The teacher advises students, especially new ones, to watch videos from the market crashes at the end of 2018, March 2020, and in 2022 to learn how to react correctly during times of panic and to mentally prepare for future market volatility.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Investment Discipline and Risk Management 
    <div id="investment-discipline-and-risk-management" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#investment-discipline-and-risk-management" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>No Risk in Long-Term Investing</strong>: Looking at a century of history, buying at any point and holding for the long term has always been profitable. However, short-term volatility can be immense, with potential drops of 50% or even 80%, so one must focus on long-term returns.</li>
<li><strong>The Nature of Your Funds Dictates Your Investment</strong>: Money needed for the short term (like tuition or a down payment for a house) must absolutely not be invested in the stock market; it should be kept as cash. Only long-term funds that you won&rsquo;t touch for 10-20 years are suitable for investment.</li>
<li><strong>The Importance of Asset Allocation</strong>:
<ul>
<li><strong>Seek Stability Before Returns</strong>: Investment allocation should prioritize psychological stability. It is inadvisable for people to switch from an aggressive allocation (e.g., 442) to a conservative one (e.g., 433) when they can&rsquo;t handle the pressure during a market drop (like in April of this year).</li>
<li><strong>A Conservative Beta Value</strong>: It is recommended that an investor&rsquo;s Beta value not exceed 1.0. If you think you can handle 1.0, it&rsquo;s better to subtract 0.2 and adopt a Beta of 0.8, which might be more suitable.</li>
<li><strong>Keep Sufficient Cash</strong>: It&rsquo;s advisable to keep at least 30% in cash. For example, a portfolio of 70% QQQ + 30% Cash.</li>
<li><strong>Gradual Increase in Leverage</strong>: Newcomers to the market can start without using leveraged funds. During a market dip, you can use a small amount of cash (e.g., 2% of assets) to buy a 2x leveraged fund, thereby gradually building a leveraged position and allowing the Beta value to increase naturally as the market rises. This is like riding a smooth, high-class train rather than a bumpy race car.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Specific Cases and Myth Debunking 
    <div id="specific-cases-and-myth-debunking" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#specific-cases-and-myth-debunking" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Case: Currency Exchange Impact on 00662 vs. QLD</strong>
<ul>
<li>A student asked if the performance of 00662 (Fubon NASDAQ-100) lagged behind QLD due to the appreciation of the Taiwan Dollar (TWD).</li>
<li><strong>Teacher&rsquo;s Analysis</strong>: Comparisons must be made in the same currency. Assuming the exchange rate was 33 when investing in QQQ and is now 29, the exchange loss is 12%. Over the past 5 years, QLD&rsquo;s performance was about 128%, and 00662&rsquo;s was about 114%. However, after deducting the 12% currency exchange loss from QLD&rsquo;s 128%, its performance becomes about 112%, which is actually lower than 00662&rsquo;s 114%. The conclusion is that their performances are essentially the same; don&rsquo;t be misled by nominal figures in different currencies.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Debunking the &ldquo;Buffett Indicator&rdquo; Myth</strong>:
<ul>
<li>Many people use the &ldquo;Total Stock Market Capitalization / GDP&rdquo; ratio to judge if the market is overheated, which is wrong.</li>
<li><strong>GDP is a flow concept</strong>: It only measures the new value added in the current year.</li>
<li><strong>Market Cap is a stock concept</strong>: It includes the value of all of a company&rsquo;s historical investments and accumulated value.</li>
<li>Comparing a changing flow metric to a cumulative stock metric is like comparing apples and oranges; it&rsquo;s completely illogical.</li>
<li>Warren Buffett himself rarely mentions this indicator and emphasizes not to use a single indicator to judge the market. Many &ldquo;pundits&rdquo; and bloggers on the market abuse this concept just to get attention, like mindless &ldquo;parrots.&rdquo;</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Scam Alert and Life Philosophy 
    <div id="scam-alert-and-life-philosophy" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#scam-alert-and-life-philosophy" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Beware of Investment Scams</strong>:
<ul>
<li>Teacher James <strong>solemnly declares</strong> that he provides <strong>completely free</strong> and <strong>voluntary teaching</strong>. He will never contact students privately, let alone offer financial services for a 1% fee or any other charge.</li>
<li>Anyone who uses his name on platforms like LINE or WeChat to contact you, claiming they can manage your finances for a fee, is a <strong>scammer</strong>.</li>
<li>In the US, it is illegal for an uncertified financial advisor to charge fees. The teacher stresses that no one cares more about your assets than you do; you must manage your investments yourself.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Awakening to Capitalism</strong>: Teacher James puts forward a sharp point: laborers who go to work in modern society are, in essence, &ldquo;slaves&rdquo; of capitalism. The purpose of his teaching is to awaken everyone&rsquo;s &ldquo;capitalist consciousness,&rdquo; to learn to use capitalism to become capitalists, rather than being enslaved by it. (Refer to video <code>00315</code>)</li>
<li><strong>Ultimate Goals in Life</strong>:
<ol>
<li><strong>Health and Longevity are Fundamental</strong>: Longevity is the path to wealth, and health is the mother of happiness. He reminds everyone to get health check-ups (like CT scans).</li>
<li><strong>Happiness is the purpose of life</strong>.</li>
<li><strong>Wealth is just the icing on the cake</strong>.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li><strong>The Principle of Borrowing to Invest</strong>:
<ul>
<li>For money borrowed according to proper principles, <strong>never think about paying it back</strong>.</li>
<li>Once you repay the loan, your risk (Beta value) will immediately increase. For example, an investor with 50% cash and 50% QQQ (Beta=0.5) who uses cash to repay a loan will see their Beta value skyrocket, greatly increasing their risk.</li>
<li>Having cash on hand gives you the confidence to face risks.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">III. Q&amp;A Session 
    <div id="iii-qa-session" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii-qa-session" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Zhao 
    <div id="zhao" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#zhao" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing</strong>: He is a 65-year-old veteran investor who lost tens of millions in the stock market twice. After starting to learn Teacher James&rsquo;s philosophy after the Chinese New Year, although he had doubts about some points (about 10-15%), he found through deeper study that the teacher&rsquo;s philosophy is continuously refined and has deep logic.</li>
<li><strong>Question 1</strong>: The market often says, &ldquo;If you miss the best few days of gains, your annualized return will drop significantly.&rdquo; What is the specific definition of this &ldquo;best time for gains&rdquo;?</li>
<li><strong>Question 2</strong>: Regarding &ldquo;smart rebalancing&rdquo; versus &ldquo;mindless rebalancing,&rdquo; if the market is still rising at the end of the year, will rebalancing then cause one to miss out on subsequent gains?
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s Reply</strong>:
<ol>
<li><strong>On Missing Up Days</strong>: This is precisely why it&rsquo;s important &ldquo;not to leave the market.&rdquo; Attempting to time the market will very likely cause you to miss the days with the biggest gains, leading to long-term returns far worse than those of an investor who &ldquo;never sells.&rdquo;</li>
<li><strong>On Rebalancing</strong>: Attempting &ldquo;smart,&rdquo; irregular rebalancing based on market movements is <strong>active investing</strong>, which cannot be taught because everyone&rsquo;s judgment criteria are different (add at a 10% drop? or 20%?). This approach can deplete your cash in an extreme market (like a three-year decline), leading to bankruptcy. Therefore, the simplest, safest, and most replicable method is to <strong>rebalance once a year</strong>. It doesn&rsquo;t matter that you didn&rsquo;t add more at the low point in April this year, because by the end of the year, your entire portfolio will still have appreciated significantly.</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Niu Ba 
    <div id="niu-ba" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#niu-ba" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing</strong>: Praised the NotebookLM system created by student &ldquo;Chen Feng&rdquo; and the teacher&rsquo;s ChatGPT tool as being very useful.</li>
<li><strong>Question 1</strong>: For a portfolio of 60% QQQ, 10% QLD, and 30% cash, what is the Beta value? (Teacher&rsquo;s reply: 0.6 + 0.1*2 = 0.8)</li>
<li><strong>Question 2</strong>: Can one use technical indicators (like the 200-day moving average) to assist in decision-making—becoming conservative when the price is below the average and aggressive when it&rsquo;s above?</li>
<li><strong>Question 3</strong>: Are people like Apple CEO Tim Cook considered capitalists or laborers?
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s Reply</strong>:
<ol>
<li><strong>On Technical Indicators</strong>: Completely unnecessary. In the recent V-shaped recovery, using a 200-day moving average strategy would have had you sell and buy back at roughly the same point. Not only would you not have made a profit, you might have lost money on transaction fees, underperforming a &ldquo;do nothing&rdquo; strategy.</li>
<li><strong>On Tim Cook</strong>: He is a <strong>laborer</strong>, a very highly paid &ldquo;slave.&rdquo; His wealth comes from his salary (including stock options), not from returns on his own invested capital. True capitalists do not have to go to work.</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Inny 
    <div id="inny" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#inny" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing</strong>:
<ol>
<li>Influenced by family, she previously invested in real estate. Her property in Japan yielded poor returns due to the yen&rsquo;s major depreciation over the last decade.</li>
<li>Shared a success story: she took out a home loan of 8 million TWD four or five years ago and didn&rsquo;t pay it off early. Instead, she invested the funds in ETFs and made a profit of four to five million, deeply understanding the benefits of investing with borrowed money.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li><strong>Question 1</strong>: What should she do with the Japanese Yen she holds?</li>
<li><strong>Question 2</strong>: She has about $200,000 USD in cash (cost basis ~32 TWD/USD) and has already invested $100,000 in US stocks (QQQ/SPY/VT). Now she doesn&rsquo;t know what to do with the remaining cash because she heard the teacher say there are tax issues for Taiwanese people buying US stocks.
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s Reply</strong>:
<ol>
<li><strong>Handling the Yen</strong>: Immediately, right now, exchange it for TWD and buy 00662. Don&rsquo;t worry about the exchange rate loss, because the potential return from the stock market is far greater than currency fluctuations.</li>
<li><strong>Handling the USD Assets</strong>: Again, ignore the exchange rate. For Taiwanese investors, the best approach is to sell the holdings in the US brokerage, transfer the funds back to Taiwan, and buy 00662 with all of it to avoid future estate tax issues. In the long run, the exchange rates for entering and exiting the market will average out, so there&rsquo;s no need for excessive worry.</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Grace 
    <div id="grace" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#grace" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Question</strong>: She is in her 30s, and about 30-40% of her assets are in Bitcoin, with the rest in QQQ. How should she handle the Bitcoin?
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s Reply</strong>: Because you are still very young, you can continue to hold the Bitcoin. But <strong>do not add any more</strong>. All new funds in the future should be invested in QQQ. In the future, Bitcoin might be used as collateral like gold, so you may not need to sell it. At your age, if you persist for the long term, it&rsquo;s possible to have assets worth tens of billions or even hundreds of billions.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Ola 
    <div id="ola" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ola" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing</strong>: He is 65 and retired. During the recent downturn, his allocation was too aggressive (Beta 1.1), and he had no cash to add at the bottom. He has now adjusted to a Beta of 0.9 (70% QQQ, 10% QLD, 20% Cash).</li>
<li><strong>Question</strong>: Is there a mechanical rule for deploying cash during a major market drop? For example, investing one-third of the cash when the market drops 20%?
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s Reply</strong>: This falls under active management. If you must do it, you could consider this: when the market drops 10% (happens almost every year), you can add more once; when it drops 20% (happens every few years), you can add more again. If it continues to fall, you must be very cautious, as it could be a major bear market. At that point, you should switch to a defensive posture, not continue to add. The key is to <strong>never run out of cash</strong>, and the goal of adding to your position is to <strong>maintain your original Beta value (0.9)</strong>, not to raise it.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Wasi 
    <div id="wasi" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#wasi" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Question</strong>: QQQ has hit a new high, but her TQQQ position (about 10% of her portfolio) is still far from its high point. Why is that?
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s Reply</strong>: This is due to the <strong>volatility decay</strong> characteristic of leveraged ETFs. In volatile and declining markets, the drop in leveraged ETFs will be more than a multiple of the index&rsquo;s drop, and their recovery is also slower. This is why a full position in leveraged funds is not recommended. For those holding leveraged funds, adding to your position during a major market drop can help you break even faster. For those with a salary, you should normally buy QQQ and use your salary to buy TQQQ during major market dips.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Lu 
    <div id="lu" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#lu" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing</strong>:
<ol>
<li>She shared her observation of the debate in Taiwan between &ldquo;high-dividend ETFs&rdquo; and &ldquo;market-cap ETFs,&rdquo; believing that both are good as long as they attract people to participate in the capital market.</li>
<li>She shared her learning journey: after diligently listening to the teacher&rsquo;s past courses (especially the videos from the 2022 bear market), her conviction was established, many questions resolved themselves, and she became confident in managing minor &ldquo;variations&rdquo; in her portfolio without needing to ask the teacher about everything.</li>
<li>She shared her experience visiting relatives in Thailand and the joy of spending money on experiences. This was because after investing according to the teacher&rsquo;s method, she felt like she had more than enough money, leading to a more relaxed mindset.</li>
</ol>
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s Comment</strong>: I completely agree. There is no absolute right or wrong in investing and opinions; there&rsquo;s no need to debate. He himself has learned that it&rsquo;s better to understand the reasons behind the other person&rsquo;s viewpoint than to argue. He won&rsquo;t &ldquo;burn himself out&rdquo; trying to convince others but rather act as a light, allowing those who are destined to find it themselves.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Yao Nian 
    <div id="yao-nian" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#yao-nian" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Question</strong>: Regarding children&rsquo;s education, a friend&rsquo;s Chinese-American child was beaten at school for stopping a black classmate from cutting in line. The school handled it poorly due to &ldquo;political correctness.&rdquo; How should we teach our children to protect themselves when facing bullying and injustice, without losing faith in justice?
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s Reply</strong>: <strong>Safety is always the number one priority</strong>. He quoted a police officer&rsquo;s advice: when faced with a violent attack, the first reaction is to <strong>run</strong>, not to fight back. We must teach our children that defending justice cannot come at the cost of their own physical well-being; we are not martyrs. One can verbally intervene, but if the other person ignores it or shows violent tendencies, one must leave immediately and protect oneself. Society will teach them their lesson; our children don&rsquo;t need to take that risk.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">IV. Insightful Quotes 
    <div id="iv-insightful-quotes" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv-insightful-quotes" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>Being out of the market is actually the biggest risk.
&ndash; Teacher James</p></blockquote>
<p>This point was central to the entire session. The teacher repeatedly emphasized that compared to the risk of a short-term market decline, the risk of investors exiting out of fear and thereby missing out on huge long-term returns is far greater.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Today&rsquo;s laborers who go to work are like the cotton pickers brought from Africa to America in the past. All who work in factories today are slaves to capitalism.
&ndash; Teacher James</p></blockquote>
<p>This is a very sharp and thought-provoking view from the teacher, aimed at awakening people to the nature of capitalism and encouraging them to become capitalists through investment, thereby escaping the status of a &ldquo;laborer.&rdquo;</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Longevity is the path to wealth, happiness is the purpose of life, health is the mother of happiness, and wealth is just the icing on the cake.
&ndash; Teacher James</p></blockquote>
<p>The teacher shared his philosophy of life, emphasizing what is truly important. Wealth is meant to serve a better life, not be the ultimate goal.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>If someone says, &ldquo;Pay me 1% and I can be your investment advisor&rdquo;&hellip; that is a scam.
&ndash; Teacher James</p></blockquote>
<p>The teacher directly used the language of scammers as an example to strongly remind all students that anyone impersonating him and offering paid financial advice is a scam, urging everyone to protect their assets.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>You shouldn&rsquo;t defend justice with your own body; we are not martyrs.
&ndash; Teacher James</p></blockquote>
<p>This was the core advice given in response to the question about how a child should face school bullying. He stressed that under any circumstances, personal safety is the highest priority, teaching children to uphold their sense of justice while also learning to protect themselves wisely.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">V. Summary 
    <div id="v-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#v-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This session once again stressed the core discipline of long-term investing: ignore short-term market volatility and firmly believe in the market&rsquo;s long-term upward trend. By analyzing asset allocation, the use of leveraged funds, and debunking common myths like the Buffett Indicator, Teacher James pointed out a simple yet effective path to wealth growth. The Q&amp;A session was rich in content, covering profound discussions from specific investment strategies (like rebalancing timing and leveraged fund allocation) to life philosophies (such as dealing with bullying and the nature of capitalism). The central idea of the entire session is that investors should build a strong psychological foundation, focus on controllable investment principles, and simultaneously pursue a life of health, happiness, and longevity, viewing wealth as a tool for a better life, not the ultimate goal.</p>

  



<div
  
    class="flex px-4 py-3 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900"
  >

  <span
    
      class="text-primary-400 ltr:pr-3 rtl:pl-3 flex items-center"
    >

    

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M506.3 417l-213.3-364c-16.33-28-57.54-28-73.98 0l-213.2 364C-10.59 444.9 9.849 480 42.74 480h426.6C502.1 480 522.6 445 506.3 417zM232 168c0-13.25 10.75-24 24-24S280 154.8 280 168v128c0 13.25-10.75 24-23.1 24S232 309.3 232 296V168zM256 416c-17.36 0-31.44-14.08-31.44-31.44c0-17.36 14.07-31.44 31.44-31.44s31.44 14.08 31.44 31.44C287.4 401.9 273.4 416 256 416z"/></svg>

  </span>


  </span>

  <span
    
      class="dark:text-neutral-300"
    ><strong>Disclaimer:</strong> This article is for personal study notes only and does not constitute any investment advice.</span>
</div>

]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>00518 From Houses to Bonds: Asset Allocation is a Master Strategy, Avoid Scams, Understand Risks, and Return to the Index</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1749950529180/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1749950529180/</guid><description>Teacher James shares his philosophy of long-term investment in the Nasdaq 100 index fund, emphasizing risk control, asset allocation (especially the importance of cash), and a positive investment mindset. The content covers his views on current market volatility, bond investments, financial products, individual stocks versus ETFs, as well as practical sharing and Q&amp;amp;A with students, supplemented by the teacher&amp;#39;s profound reflections on personal experiences, educational philosophy, and social responsibility.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<lite-youtube videoid="JlFNunk6brQ" playlabel="JlFNunk6brQ" params=""></lite-youtube>



<h2 class="relative group">I. Theme of the Session 
    <div id="i-theme-of-the-session" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-theme-of-the-session" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>The core of this lecture is to emphasize <strong>persisting in long-term investment in the Nasdaq 100 index fund, prioritizing risk control and reasonable asset allocation, and maintaining an extremely optimistic investment mindset</strong>. Teacher James points out that market volatility is normal; investors should ignore short-term fluctuations, focus on long-term growth, recognize the critical role of cash in asset allocation, and ultimately achieve financial freedom and life&rsquo;s purpose.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">II. Briefing Content 
    <div id="ii-briefing-content" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii-briefing-content" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Opening and Investment Mindset 
    <div id="opening-and-investment-mindset" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#opening-and-investment-mindset" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>The Market&rsquo;s Normal State</strong>: Global situations and market turmoil are normal. Investors should remain calm and not be disturbed by short-term volatility, international affairs, market analysis, financial statements, or economic conditions.</li>
<li><strong>Disclaimer</strong>: This channel is a pro bono sharing platform and does not constitute investment advice. There are no fees, no alternate accounts, and be wary of scams. Investing involves risk, which you must manage yourself. Relevant links are pinned in the YouTube comments section.</li>
<li><strong>Learning Path</strong>: Newcomers are advised to start with &ldquo;00451 The One-Dollar Investment Lecture,&rdquo; think independently, and find a method that suits them. Quiet study improves the quality of thought more than joining too many groups.</li>
<li><strong>Core Investment Vehicle</strong>: Focus on the Nasdaq 100 index fund (like QQQ). Page 10 of the handout provides a selection of related funds worldwide. The videos started in 2018, and there is a complete 2022 course playlist available.</li>
<li><strong>Investment Mentality</strong>: Always be extremely optimistic, always face the sun; the market will eventually go up. Investing requires patience (ignoring market fluctuations), and financial freedom is worth the wait. Please like, comment, and subscribe on all platforms.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Macroeconomics and the Bond Myth 
    <div id="macroeconomics-and-the-bond-myth" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#macroeconomics-and-the-bond-myth" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Stablecoins and Short-Term Treasuries</strong>: A student asked if the issuance of stablecoins would increase demand for short-term treasuries and lower their interest rates. Teacher James believes short-term treasury rates are tied to the central bank&rsquo;s rates and won&rsquo;t fall significantly because of this. Short-term treasuries are similar to money market funds with low volatility. The central bank&rsquo;s rate is the benchmark; no one would buy a bond with a lower rate.</li>
<li><strong>The Trap of Long-Term Bonds</strong>: Long-term bond interest is linked to inflation expectations for many years to come, and the interest is fixed.
<ul>
<li><strong>Example</strong>: For a 30-year Treasury bond with a 5% coupon rate, if inflation is 3%, the real annualized rate of return (Real IRR) is only 1.94%. In contrast, if short-term rates are 4%, it is far superior to the real return of long-term bonds. The $5 in interest you receive after 30 years will have long been devalued.</li>
<li><strong>Conclusion</strong>: It is not recommended for individual investors to buy long-term government bonds. Issuing long-term bonds is advantageous for the U.S. Treasury because the long-term interest is close to zero for the issuer (after considering inflation). Even if the central bank&rsquo;s rate is below 2%, buying long-term bonds is not necessarily a good deal. The Treasury has its own issuance plan and won&rsquo;t easily change it due to shifts in the central bank&rsquo;s rates. The idea of issuing 100-year bonds is impractical and tantamount to default.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Risk Control and Asset Allocation 
    <div id="risk-control-and-asset-allocation" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#risk-control-and-asset-allocation" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Risk Awareness</strong>: The first priority in investing is risk control; the world is full of uncertainties (like the conflict in Israel).</li>
<li><strong>The Importance of Asset Allocation</strong>: Good asset allocation is a &ldquo;master strategy&rdquo; (奇门遁甲), a powerful &ldquo;Army, Navy, and Air Force&rdquo; deployment.
<ul>
<li><strong>Cash</strong>: The &ldquo;food and air&rdquo; of asset allocation, the most important part. Sufficient cash prevents market panic.</li>
<li><strong>Index Fund</strong>: The &ldquo;aircraft carrier&rdquo; of asset allocation.</li>
<li><strong>Leveraged Fund</strong>: Like the &ldquo;missile force.&rdquo;</li>
<li><strong>Stock Pledging</strong>: The &ldquo;Transformer&rdquo; of asset allocation.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>The Courage to Sell a House for Investment</strong>: Selling your primary residence to rent and investing the funds in an index is an excellent financial strategy, but it requires a strong mind and the courage to face social judgment (e.g., fear of being told you&rsquo;re &ldquo;not doing well&rdquo;). In reality, this is a sign of &ldquo;doing exceptionally well.&rdquo;</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Investment Concepts and Behavioral Psychology 
    <div id="investment-concepts-and-behavioral-psychology" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#investment-concepts-and-behavioral-psychology" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>The Difficulty of Educating Family and Friends</strong>: Family and friends would rather trust the annuities and savings insurance (1% return) recommended by bank advisors than accept advice about index funds (10% long-term return), even when presented with spreadsheets. The main reason is the fear of &ldquo;what if it drops?&rdquo;
<ul>
<li><strong>Counter-strategy</strong>: First, become a &ldquo;big tree&rdquo; yourself and influence them with your own success. Your words carry little weight when you&rsquo;re insignificant; &ldquo;familiarity breeds contempt&rdquo; (近庙欺神). It&rsquo;s hard to distinguish &ldquo;saints&rdquo; from &ldquo;demons&rdquo; in society.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Cognitive Roots of the Wealth Gap</strong>: Poverty is often caused by a lack of awareness, not systemic issues. CLEC aims to &ldquo;cure&rdquo; this &ldquo;disease of poverty,&rdquo; but it&rsquo;s very difficult; even family members may not accept it. Some people can&rsquo;t accept good medicine and instead buy things like long-term bonds.</li>
<li><strong>The Challenges of Individual Stock Investing</strong>:
<ul>
<li><strong>Example</strong>: NVIDIA&rsquo;s stock price fluctuates wildly. It was once sold off due to poor sales and excess inventory, then soared because of AI. It&rsquo;s difficult for individual investors to grasp; even if you bought it, you might not have held on for the entire ride.</li>
<li><strong>Conclusion</strong>: Individual stocks are volatile, information is asymmetric, and they can suddenly be cut in half or go to zero. ETFs provide a more stable way to share in market growth. It&rsquo;s also very hard to stick with a portfolio of mixed-quality individual stocks.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>The Dangers of Short-Term Trading</strong>: Short-term trading is like &ldquo;gambling + drug addiction.&rdquo; It&rsquo;s addictive and leads not only to financial loss but also the loss of family, health, and self, potentially ruining one&rsquo;s entire life. There&rsquo;s no need to become a &ldquo;boy wonder trader.&rdquo;</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Critique of Chaos in the Financial Industry 
    <div id="critique-of-chaos-in-the-financial-industry" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#critique-of-chaos-in-the-financial-industry" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Profit Motives of Banks and Insurance Companies</strong>: Criticizes post offices and banks for persuading depositors (especially the elderly) to buy annuity insurance, structured notes, and similar products. This is a failure of financial regulators.</li>
<li><strong>Regulatory Issues</strong>: Believes financial regulators should ensure the separation of savings, insurance, wealth management, and lending to avoid conflicts of interest. American commercial banks (like BofA) don&rsquo;t proactively sell insurance. Taiwan&rsquo;s &ldquo;Financial Holding Company&rdquo; model is described as an &ldquo;all-encompassing, one-stop-shop scam.&rdquo; Charles Schwab only mentions loan options when a client has a large funding need.</li>
<li><strong>The Goal of the Insurance Industry</strong>: To convert large amounts of fixed deposits into insurance policies, which is the main objective of the insurance industry, given the huge amount of fixed deposits in Taiwan.</li>
<li><strong>The Risk of Mortgaging Property to Buy Insurance</strong>: There have been cases where the property mortgage remains, but the insurance policy&rsquo;s value drops to zero, leaving people homeless. These institutions &ldquo;will go as far as making people homeless.&rdquo;</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Responses to Chat Comments and Additional Remarks (Teacher James&rsquo;s collective response to student comments and personal reflections) 
    <div id="responses-to-chat-comments-and-additional-remarks-teacher-jamess-collective-response-to-student-comments-and-personal-reflections" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#responses-to-chat-comments-and-additional-remarks-teacher-jamess-collective-response-to-student-comments-and-personal-reflections" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>On Publishing a Book/Media Exposure</strong>: Teacher James frankly states that if he were to publicly promote his ideas like &ldquo;investing with loans&rdquo; and &ldquo;not buying a house,&rdquo; he could violate financial regulations (practicing without a license), offend powerful interest groups (real estate, insurance, finance), and even face cyberbullying and political pressure (being labeled &ldquo;pro-Taiwan independence&rdquo; or &ldquo;pro-CCP&rdquo;). He could be &ldquo;torn to shreds&rdquo; or even &ldquo;end up in jail.&rdquo; If he doesn&rsquo;t discuss many of these topics, the teaching loses its meaning. The very people you help might turn around and curse you.</li>
<li><strong>Insurance</strong>: An insurance policy with a 1.06% annual return is acceptable if it includes protection, but it&rsquo;s generally not recommended.</li>
<li><strong>Caring for Parents</strong>: Re-emphasizes the loneliness and health risks of elderly people living alone (not taking medicine on time, not measuring blood sugar/pressure, leading to complications like worsening COPD, minor strokes, brain atrophy, mental disorders). Advises children to pay attention and provide companionship early. Even if parents seem self-sufficient, consider arranging for a caregiver early to prevent accidents and ensure a regular routine (medication, diet, avoiding falls). Shares his regret of not returning to Taiwan in time to accompany his mother, who, despite having other children in Taiwan, was not adequately cared for while living alone. Emphasizes that parents&rsquo; health is the children&rsquo;s happiness.</li>
<li><strong>A Partner&rsquo;s Investment Philosophy</strong>: Accept individual differences. Due to different upbringings and personal experiences (like living through the dot-com and 2008 bubbles), security levels and cognitions vary. Lead by example and influence them gradually with long-term results; don&rsquo;t force it. It&rsquo;s normal for them not to listen to you, just as you may not listen to them.</li>
<li><strong>00662 (Taiwan ETF) Currency Impact</strong>: Short-term currency fluctuations are normal. For instance, when the Taiwan dollar depreciated in the previous two years, 00662 outperformed QQQ. In the long run, currency effects tend to cancel each other out.</li>
<li><strong>Credit Loans vs. Stock Pledges</strong>: Credit loans are relatively independent and safe. Stock pledges are high-risk; a sharp market downturn could trigger a margin call, making it like a &ldquo;loan shark&rdquo; — you have to pay back when they demand it, or you&rsquo;re &ldquo;shot dead with one bullet.&rdquo;</li>
<li><strong>Brokerage Firms Raising Pledge Rates and Risks</strong>: Brokerages like Capital Securities in Taiwan might raise interest rates after a client has borrowed, or even restrict withdrawals (due to limited funding pools), &ldquo;luring you into a trap.&rdquo; It&rsquo;s advisable to prioritize more stable brokerages like Yuanta Securities.</li>
<li><strong>Apply for Credit Loans Early</strong>: Bank credit policies can change. When you qualify (e.g., with an interest rate below 2%), you should apply early. Seize the opportunity when a bank proactively offers you a loan.</li>
<li><strong>Stock Pledging in Hong Kong</strong>: HSBC is a good choice, especially for VIP clients with large capital (e.g., over 1 million HKD). HSBC&rsquo;s pledge interest rates are currently low. Friends from Malaysia, Singapore, Australia, etc., who successfully open an account and get a pledge loan from HSBC are welcome to share their experiences.</li>
<li><strong>QQQ Compounding</strong>: The annualized rate of return (CAGR), according to Teacher James&rsquo;s research, is around 18% (including dividend reinvestment).</li>
<li><strong>Repayment of Investment Mortgage</strong>: Typically, it&rsquo;s a lump-sum repayment at maturity (10-15 years). By then, you can sell some stocks or use another pledged loan to repay it. You need more than 15 years to ensure profitability.</li>
<li><strong>Compound Frequency</strong>: Refers to capital gains and dividend reinvestment.</li>
<li><strong>Philosophy of Helping Others</strong>: There are different levels of helping others. The lowest is for others (hoping for their well-being). The next is for oneself (deriving happiness or meaning from it). The highest is selflessness (helping is a natural act, regardless of for whom, or whether it brings happiness, like the Buddha or Jesus; it&rsquo;s natural ethics). Using helping others to add meaning and happiness to one&rsquo;s own life is actually &ldquo;not right.&rdquo; The highest state is &ldquo;like water flowing without a trace&rdquo; (传过水无痕).</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">III. Q&amp;A Session 
    <div id="iii-qa-session" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii-qa-session" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Kacy 
    <div id="kacy" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#kacy" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing</strong>: An elderly friend, who was once very influential in the market, agrees with Teacher James&rsquo;s index investing philosophy. This elder confessed that his past outsized returns were due to information asymmetry and his influence (manipulating small-cap stocks), which is not replicable for ordinary investors. He believes it&rsquo;s not easy for ordinary people to make money in the market, and index investing is the most correct path.
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s Comment</strong>: Index investing not only makes you money but also gives you a &ldquo;life&rdquo; (improves quality of life). Even if you make money from short-term trading, you might lose your life due to constant anxiety (e.g., being unable to take a 15-day vacation with peace of mind).</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Sharing (Follow-up)</strong>:
<ol>
<li>Reflecting on her family life, she emphasizes love and companionship for her parents to avoid regrets. She sees Teacher James&rsquo;s actions as &ldquo;dedication&rdquo; rather than &ldquo;charity&rdquo; with a sense of superiority and feels for the misunderstandings he might face.</li>
<li>Shares her future plans: to establish a women&rsquo;s financial academy (focusing on female financial awareness, as Chinese women are relatively disadvantaged, and financial independence provides more confidence), volunteer in hospice care (to learn about &ldquo;fasting until death&rdquo; and euthanasia), travel, read, and set up scholarships, reflecting a desire for &ldquo;altruism&rdquo; (influenced by Kazuo Inamori&rsquo;s philosophy of &ldquo;altruism&rdquo;).</li>
</ol>
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s Comment</strong>:
<ol>
<li>Commends Kacy&rsquo;s practice of accompanying her parents. Shares the joy of his own father, in his 90s, still planning a trip to Korea. Advises that for elderly parents, even if they appear healthy, one should consider arranging for a caregiver early to prevent accidents and ensure a regular routine (medication, diet). Parents&rsquo; health is the children&rsquo;s happiness. If parents have medical needs, like follow-up visits every three months or low-dose lung cancer screenings, they should be supported.</li>
<li>Greatly admires Kacy&rsquo;s &ldquo;altruistic&rdquo; plans, believing that from a women&rsquo;s financial academy to educating disadvantaged groups, it&rsquo;s all very meaningful. It&rsquo;s right to start planning now.</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">C 
    <div id="c" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#c" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing</strong>: His mother noticed his mood has become calmer and happier recently. He explained it&rsquo;s because through investing (practicing the teacher&rsquo;s teachings), he has found meaning in life and is confident about his future wealth, no longer worrying about finances. This has led to an internal change from external influences.
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s Comment</strong>: Shares his own longing and regrets regarding his mother, how in his youth he failed to fully grasp the loneliness and hardship of an elderly person living alone (e.g., his mother falling while going to the doctor alone, and his own failure to return to Taiwan to be with her). Reminds everyone to care for their parents, especially those living alone, after achieving financial freedom early, to avoid life&rsquo;s regrets. Advises young people to learn from wise elders (like Warren Buffett) to avoid many pitfalls and find a &ldquo;mental coach.&rdquo;</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question</strong>: Following the teacher&rsquo;s guidance, he used an investment mortgage to invest in 00662. After using a portion of the funds from high-dividend ETFs to pay the monthly interest, there&rsquo;s still a surplus each month. Should he invest this in 00865 (short-term bond/cash-like ETF) or continue buying fractional shares of 00662?
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s Response</strong>: Continue buying 00662. The emergency fund (00865) only needs to be built up to a certain level (e.g., 2-3 years of living expenses for someone employed). Any excess funds should be invested in growth assets.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">IM 
    <div id="im" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#im" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing 1</strong>: Recalls entering the market in 2018, with emotions fluctuating with the market, having once lost 50%. A wise friend enlightened her (&ldquo;Save money when you&rsquo;re making it, and just wait it out when it&rsquo;s down&rdquo;), teaching her to remain calm through ups and downs and become numb to the market. Mentions how wealthy people view money (a piece of clothing costs 500-600k; money is like trash to them). Grateful for the teacher&rsquo;s guidance that has &ldquo;filled her head.&rdquo;</li>
<li><strong>Sharing 2</strong>: Has come to understand the teacher&rsquo;s mindset that &ldquo;all sharing is for self-fulfillment, not for rewards.&rdquo; When sharing investment ideas with others, she encounters different reactions: some (who have worked for 20-30 years and are set in their ways) cling to old concepts, while others, despite living in hardship (a single mother working two jobs), are willing to listen. Through sharing, she has also gained a sense of value by giving back the knowledge she has learned.
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s Comment</strong>: (Regarding Sharing 2) Helping others can bring happiness, but the highest state is to be &ldquo;unaffected by helping,&rdquo; meaning helping others is a natural act, not for happiness, not for self. The lowest level is &ldquo;for others,&rdquo; i.e., for their benefit; the second level is &ldquo;for oneself,&rdquo; i.e., achieving self-actualization through helping (the teacher admits his own teaching is to find value in retirement); the highest is &ldquo;selflessness,&rdquo; where even the thought of &ldquo;for myself&rdquo; is gone.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question</strong>: After sharing investment concepts with friends, how can she determine if they truly understand? Are there any questions to ask to test them? (Friends listen and think it&rsquo;s logical but can&rsquo;t articulate it themselves.)
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s Response</strong>: It&rsquo;s hard to judge with simple questions. True understanding is reflected in action (like opening an account to invest). A more effective way is like how Frank guided him back in the day (meeting for dinner every week, hand-holding him through opening an account, starting with a $200 Mutual Fund), guiding them step-by-step to open an account, make their first investment, and follow up continuously. This is a process of &ldquo;sowing seeds&rdquo;; whether and when they sprout is unknown. He himself was &ldquo;led by the hand&rdquo; by Frank to get started. Now, he is willing to be such a guide, with the Bodhisattva spirit of &ldquo;If I don&rsquo;t descend into hell, who will?&rdquo;</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Man 
    <div id="man" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#man" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing</strong>: Gained insights from gardening.
<ol>
<li><strong>Individual Differences</strong>: The same seeds planted result in different flowers, just as people receive information differently. Their internal &ldquo;genes&rdquo; determine their level of acceptance and reaction (some &ldquo;get it,&rdquo; others &ldquo;laugh it off&rdquo;). The gardener (the sharer) cannot change the seed&rsquo;s nature.</li>
<li><strong>Patient Guidance</strong>: A good gardener will loosen the soil and water, helping it grow, just as a mentor guides students to open accounts and invest.</li>
<li><strong>Inner Joy</strong>: The pleasure derived from tilling the soil and weeding surpasses the rewards of all fame and fortune. This effort is not for a return but for self-actualization.</li>
<li><strong>Practical Example</strong>: She once guided a friend to buy QQQ. The friend sold during a dip and missed the subsequent 45% gain. She only sent a screenshot and said no more, believing it was also &ldquo;fate.&rdquo;</li>
<li><strong>Translating for the Elderly at a Doctor&rsquo;s Visit</strong>: Shares her experience as a volunteer translator for the elderly, realizing their immense need in medical communication. Such small acts can bring great help and a ray of light into their lives.</li>
</ol>
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s Comment</strong>: Agrees with the views on &ldquo;destiny&rdquo; and intrinsic motivation. Shares his own experience of planting tomatoes, where three seeds grew very differently; one was a &ldquo;chosen seedling&rdquo; and very robust, while others were &ldquo;sickly.&rdquo; Cites Dr. Yang Ding-I&rsquo;s view to &ldquo;look inward.&rdquo; For people you can&rsquo;t change, don&rsquo;t force it. Be yourself, don&rsquo;t be discouraged by it; giving up is an option. Affirms the value of her volunteer work.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Sifei 
    <div id="sifei" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#sifei" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing</strong>: Came into contact with CLEC in 2024 through a friend (who had mentioned it 5 years ago, but she was indifferent at the time). In her 50s, she has been interested in investing since graduating from college and has been exploring on her own for years. She was deeply moved after listening to the lectures and has invested a lot of time in studying (finished the 2021-2022 courses and is now re-listening). She shared it with a hundred people, and only two took action, but she still feels gratified.</li>
<li><strong>Question</strong>: Regarding the choice between a credit loan and a stock pledge in Taiwan. She leans towards using the stock pledge first (2.56% interest, no principal repayment, only interest), because of its convenience. She thinks she can use a credit loan (already approved for a 3 million TWD limit, but requires installment repayments) as a backup if the stock market crashes. She believes her job is stable (banks are always begging her to take out loans), so she&rsquo;s not afraid of unemployment and can access the credit loan anytime.
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s Response</strong>: (In a firm tone, repeatedly emphasizing) <strong>Absolutely do not do this!</strong>
<ol>
<li><strong>Core Principle</strong>: Money borrowed from a stock pledge <strong>must not be reinvested in the stock market</strong>. It can only be used for living expenses or to repay other loans. This is &ldquo;the first thing.&rdquo;</li>
<li><strong>Huge Risk</strong>: When the market crashes, banks may tighten credit (&ldquo;take away the umbrella in the rain&rdquo;), and you might not be able to borrow money then. If you lose your job at the same time, it&rsquo;s even more impossible. A credit loan is not something you can just &ldquo;hold there&rdquo; forever.</li>
<li><strong>Deploy All Troops (韩信点兵)</strong>: All available &ldquo;forces&rdquo; (including the credit loan) should be deployed to the &ldquo;battlefield&rdquo; (investment) as early as possible.</li>
<li><strong>The Correct Approach</strong>: You should first take out the credit loan (e.g., 3 million TWD) and invest it in the market. The monthly loan repayments can be paid using funds from a low-interest stock pledge. This way, the principal continues to work in the market, and your personal salary can also be invested. Don&rsquo;t take a huge risk just because you&rsquo;re &ldquo;too lazy to repay the principal&rdquo; or tempted by the short-term convenience of a pledge.</li>
<li><strong>Safety of Credit Loans</strong>: A credit loan is a relatively safe form of leverage, not directly linked to market fluctuations, and you won&rsquo;t get a margin call. With a stock pledge, even if you only borrow 10% (e.g., pledging 1 million from a 10 million asset portfolio—the teacher thinks 10% is already a huge risk, let alone the 2-3 million she wants to borrow), you could face risks in an extreme market downturn.</li>
<li><strong>Brokerage Risk</strong>: Some brokerages in Taiwan (like Capital Securities) may change their pledge interest rates, and their limited funding pools might prevent you from withdrawing funds as needed.
(Kacy and other students also chimed in, emphasizing the risk of banks &ldquo;taking away the umbrella in the rain&rdquo; and the fundamental difference between credit loans and pledges, and that pledged money cannot be used to buy more stocks).</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Xiao Zhang 
    <div id="xiao-zhang" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#xiao-zhang" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Did not speak or content was not recorded.</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">IV. Highlighted Quotes 
    <div id="iv-highlighted-quotes" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv-highlighted-quotes" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>Market fluctuations have nothing to do with me, international affairs have nothing to do with me, market analysis has nothing to do with me, financial statements have nothing to do with us, and the economic situation doesn&rsquo;t matter at all. Don&rsquo;t pay attention to it. The more you pay attention, the more mistakes you&rsquo;ll make.
&ndash; Teacher James</p></blockquote>
<p>Background: Teacher James emphasized at the beginning the composure investors should have, not letting external noise affect their investment decisions.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Investing requires patience, and financial freedom is worth the wait. What is patience? It is to be unconcerned with market fluctuations.
&ndash; Teacher James</p></blockquote>
<p>Background: Explaining that the core of long-term investing lies in the psychological tolerance for market volatility.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Cash is the food and air of asset allocation.
&ndash; Teacher James</p></blockquote>
<p>Background: Emphasizing the extreme importance of holding sufficient cash for risk management and psychological stability in asset allocation.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>You are poor because of a lack of awareness, not because the system made you poor.
&ndash; Teacher James</p></blockquote>
<p>Background: When discussing the difficulty of teaching family about investing, pointing out that the wealth gap often stems from cognitive differences.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Short-term trading doesn&rsquo;t just want your money; it will want your life and your lifelong happiness.
&ndash; Teacher James</p></blockquote>
<p>Background: A stern warning about the immense dangers of short-term trading, comparing it to gambling and drug addiction.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>In investing, we first seek safety, then profit. First, seek safety; do what is foolproof first.
&ndash; Teacher James</p></blockquote>
<p>Background: Emphasizing that the primary principle of investing is safety, in response to a student&rsquo;s question about credit loans versus stock pledges.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>When you are making money, you should also be humble and look at everything with humility. Just as Teacher James taught me, whether the market goes up or down, OK, be numb to it. It doesn&rsquo;t have a big impact on our daily lives.
&ndash; IM</p></blockquote>
<p>Background: Student IM sharing her transformation from anxiously watching the market to maintaining a calm composure towards market fluctuations.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The things we invest in others, when we invest, it&rsquo;s not for a return. It&rsquo;s because you have to do this thing. You have to do what is meaningful to you; this is the value of your being.
&ndash; Man</p></blockquote>
<p>Background: Student Man drawing an analogy from gardening to the intrinsic value of sharing knowledge and helping others, without seeking external rewards.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Life is really not just about money&hellip; Wealth is about having enough.
&ndash; Kacy</p></blockquote>
<p>Background: Student Kacy sharing her pursuit of quality of life, believing that more wealth is not necessarily better; having enough is sufficient.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The highest level is helping others without any sense of happiness, without feeling&hellip; Even the &lsquo;for myself&rsquo; is gone. This is what I have learned, that even the &lsquo;for myself&rsquo; is gone.
&ndash; Teacher James</p></blockquote>
<p>Background: When responding to IM&rsquo;s question about the motivation for sharing, he explains the three levels of helping behavior, the highest of which is selfless altruism, a natural act.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">V. Summary 
    <div id="v-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#v-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>In this session, Teacher James systematically re-emphasized his core investment philosophy: consistently buy and hold the Nasdaq 100 index fund, fearless of short-term market volatility. He focused on analyzing the extreme importance of risk control, viewing reasonable asset allocation (especially an adequate cash reserve) as the cornerstone of investment success. Through specific examples, the teacher revealed the investment value trap of long-term bonds and severely criticized certain misleading and detrimental practices in the financial industry, especially warning investors against low-return products like annuities and savings insurance. At the same time, he pointed out the huge uncertainty of individual stock investing and the destructive nature of short-term trading. During the Q&amp;A session, students actively shared their insights and confusions from their investment practices, family communication, and personal growth. Teacher James not only provided specific investment advice (such as the correct use and risk perception of credit loans versus stock pledges) but also guided students from a life philosophy perspective to reflect on the meaning of wealth, work, family, and personal value, encouraging everyone on the path to financial freedom to continuously enhance their cognition, maintain a positive mindset, pay attention to family and social responsibilities, and ultimately give back to society.</p>

  



<div
  
    class="flex px-4 py-3 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900"
  >

  <span
    
      class="text-primary-400 ltr:pr-3 rtl:pl-3 flex items-center"
    >

    

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M506.3 417l-213.3-364c-16.33-28-57.54-28-73.98 0l-213.2 364C-10.59 444.9 9.849 480 42.74 480h426.6C502.1 480 522.6 445 506.3 417zM232 168c0-13.25 10.75-24 24-24S280 154.8 280 168v128c0 13.25-10.75 24-23.1 24S232 309.3 232 296V168zM256 416c-17.36 0-31.44-14.08-31.44-31.44c0-17.36 14.07-31.44 31.44-31.44s31.44 14.08 31.44 31.44C287.4 401.9 273.4 416 256 416z"/></svg>

  </span>


  </span>

  <span
    
      class="dark:text-neutral-300"
    ><strong>Disclaimer:</strong> This article is for personal study notes only and does not constitute any investment advice.</span>
</div>

]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>00512 Asset Allocation Simulation Full Guide: Practical Exercises in Leverage, Rebalancing, and Cash Conversion</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1745130594222/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1745130594222/</guid><description>James discusses the investment mindset in volatile markets, updates the Excel tool for retirement withdrawals and leverage management, emphasizes the importance of long-term holding and early Roth conversion, and explores the operation of the financial system, coping with external pressure, and perspectives on the future of US technology.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<lite-youtube videoid="Wrcv9WKvu4s" playlabel="Wrcv9WKvu4s" params=""></lite-youtube>



<h2 class="relative group">I. Current Theme 
    <div id="i-current-theme" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-current-theme" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This episode focuses on the mindset and strategies that investors should adopt in the context of current market volatility and volatile international situations. James emphasizes that for long-term investors, short-term market fluctuations, macroeconomic conditions, and even wars should not be of excessive concern. The core strategy should be to insist on buying high-quality index funds (such as Nasdaq 100 QQQ) and holding them for the long term, never selling. At the same time, he shares an updated Excel financial simulation tool, discusses pre-retirement withdrawal strategies, leverage management, the significant advantages of early Roth conversion, and how to build a strong investment psychology to cope with external pressure and complex information.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">II. Briefing Content 
    <div id="ii-briefing-content" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii-briefing-content" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Core Investment Philosophy and Market Views 
    <div id="core-investment-philosophy-and-market-views" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#core-investment-philosophy-and-market-views" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Ignore the Noise, Keep Buying:</strong> Macro factors such as market volatility, international situations, tariff wars, trade wars, hot wars, and cold wars have little to do with long-term investing. Investors cannot and do not need to predict or respond to them. Just keep buying index funds (QQQ) and holding them for the long term.</li>
<li><strong>Halving is Inevitable:</strong> In the long-term investment process, a 50% or even greater reduction in assets is an inevitable event, not a matter of probability, but a certainty. Investors need to be psychologically prepared and ensure that they can still &ldquo;survive&rdquo; in this situation. Ask yourself every day: &ldquo;If the market halves again, can I still hold on?&rdquo;</li>
<li><strong>Long-Termism and Optimistic Mindset:</strong> Investing requires patience, and wealth is worth waiting for. The market always goes up in the long run. Investors should always be extremely optimistic, even if the market drops 80%, because the decline is part of the investment process, and the future is always bright. Buying is for future gains, not for leaving the market out of fear of future declines.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Excel Tool Updates and Applications (Refer to Lecture Notes from Page 18) 
    <div id="excel-tool-updates-and-applications-refer-to-lecture-notes-from-page-18" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#excel-tool-updates-and-applications-refer-to-lecture-notes-from-page-18" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Origin and Background of the Problem:</strong>
<ul>
<li>Some students reported problems with the old Excel version: 1) Increasing the spending ratio may actually reduce the final assets; 2) After a significant increase in assets (such as from 1 million to 4 million), spending directly at 2% of the new assets (i.e., 80,000) failed the stress test when simulating the 2000 tech bubble burst.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Main Updates and Usage Suggestions:</strong>
<ol>
<li><strong>Separating Spending and Rebalancing Ratios:</strong> Corrected the error of linking the spending ratio with the smart rebalancing ratio. The new version allows independent settings. It is recommended that the smart rebalancing ratio remain at 2% or be adjusted according to individual risk tolerance.</li>
<li><strong>New Strategy for Increasing Spending After Asset Growth (0.8% Rule):</strong>
<ul>
<li><strong>Simulation Conclusion:</strong> If assets increase significantly (such as from 1 million to 4.6 million, net worth 3.8 million, and borrowing 780,000 accounting for 17% of total assets), spending directly at 2% of the new assets (80,000/year) is too risky.</li>
<li><strong>Safety Recommendation:</strong> When assets have increased by more than <strong>2.5 times</strong> and the pledged loan ratio is controlled within <strong>20%</strong>, consider increasing the annual spending to <strong>0.7% or 0.8% of the new total assets</strong>. For example, assets of 4.6 million can spend about 36,800/year (4.6 million * 0.8%). After this adjustment, even if you encounter a market shock similar to 2000, you can maintain a sufficient margin of safety. This means that if assets grow 2.5 times, the annual spending can safely increase by about 2.2 times.</li>
<li><strong>Operation Guide (Using the &ldquo;Practice Version&rdquo; Excel):</strong>
<ul>
<li>Enter &ldquo;Scenario Nine&rdquo; (applicable to situations where you have started pledged borrowing and spending).</li>
<li>Modify the &ldquo;Amount Already Borrowed&rdquo; in the &ldquo;Personal Information&rdquo; or &ldquo;Scenario Eight Nine Information&rdquo; area in the front of the table (<strong>do not directly change the S2 cell inside Excel, go to the overview page in front to change it</strong>).</li>
<li>Return to the scenario nine simulation page and modify the initial asset allocation ratio (such as QQQ 33%, QLD/Leverage 45%, Cash 22%).</li>
<li>Adjust the &ldquo;Borrowing Expenses&rdquo; percentage (located in column T, such as changing to 0.8 or 0.7).</li>
<li>Adjust the &ldquo;Borrowing Interest&rdquo; according to the actual situation (cell S5, such as setting it to 3% for Taiwan).</li>
<li>Observe the &ldquo;Minimum Maintenance Rate&rdquo; (or &ldquo;Minimum Equity Ratio&rdquo;) in the results and ensure that it is higher than your set safety threshold (such as 150% or 160%).</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Cash Interest Assumption:</strong> When calculating the compound interest on the Cash portion in Excel, the interest rate used is half of the borrowing rate (S5) (i.e., <code>S5/2/12</code> calculated monthly). This is based on the conservative assumption that the deposit rate is usually lower than the borrowing rate and does not need to be modified.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li><strong>Version Description:</strong> Provides &ldquo;Easy Version&rdquo; (only needs to fill in the initial total assets, smart rebalancing %, and annual spending %) and &ldquo;Practice Version&rdquo; (allows you to modify more detailed parameters inside Excel, such as initial allocation ratio, profit transfer ratio, initial borrowing ratio/amount, withholding cash ratio, etc.). To perform detailed simulations and parameter adjustments, you need to use the &ldquo;Practice Version.&rdquo;</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Early Retirement and Roth Conversion (Refer to Lecture Notes on Page 20) 
    <div id="early-retirement-and-roth-conversion-refer-to-lecture-notes-on-page-20" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#early-retirement-and-roth-conversion-refer-to-lecture-notes-on-page-20" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Scenario Analysis:</strong> Compare a couple aged 50 with 2 million in Traditional IRA, expected return of 14%, and tax rate of 24%, under three different Roth conversion strategies for the long term (to age 100).
<ul>
<li>Scenario 1: No conversion, relying on RMD. The final assets are approximately <strong>330 million</strong>.</li>
<li>Scenario 2: Work until age 56 and then start converting. The final assets are approximately <strong>350 million</strong>.</li>
<li>Scenario 3: Retire immediately at age 50 and start converting. The final assets are as high as <strong>780 million</strong>.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Core Conclusion:</strong> Retiring 6 years early to perform Roth conversion, utilizing the low tax bracket window in the early stage of retirement, can bring more than <strong>300 million USD</strong> in additional wealth. Even for high-income earners (assuming a conversion tax rate of 40%), it takes an additional 9-10 years of work to make up for the huge opportunity cost of not converting early. <strong>It is strongly recommended that those who meet the conditions plan and execute Roth conversion as soon as possible.</strong></li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Financial System Operation and Personal Financial Wisdom 
    <div id="financial-system-operation-and-personal-financial-wisdom" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#financial-system-operation-and-personal-financial-wisdom" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Make Good Use of Financial Tools (Transmissive Power):</strong> Specifically pointed out that Taiwan&rsquo;s low interest rate environment provides investors with favorable conditions to use borrowing (pledged loans, etc.) to amplify investment returns (transmissive power).</li>
<li><strong>Bank Perspective and Customer Relationships:</strong> Banks view deposits as liabilities and loans as assets. They are happy to see customers borrow and pay interest on time. Large borrowing customers are VIPs of the bank and enjoy preferential treatment; ordinary depositors need to go through regular procedures.</li>
<li><strong>Wealth Circulation Mechanism:</strong> Commercial banks play an intermediary role in the capitalist system, transferring the idle funds (deposits) of risk-averse/non-investors to investors (borrowers) who are willing to take risks and know how to use funds, and earn interest spreads from them. Understanding this mechanism helps investors use leverage more confidently.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Investment Psychological Construction and Philosophy of Life 
    <div id="investment-psychological-construction-and-philosophy-of-life" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#investment-psychological-construction-and-philosophy-of-life" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Coping with External Pressure:</strong> When facing the worries or doubts of family and friends when the market falls, you need to build a strong inner self:
<ul>
<li><strong>Self-Belief:</strong> First of all, you must be firm in your investment philosophy and understand that volatility is a normal process.</li>
<li><strong>Shielding and Transcendence:</strong> Practice from the realm of &ldquo;not listening, not seeing, does not exist&rdquo; to &ldquo;both seeing and listening but also does not exist,&rdquo; that is, the inner self is not disturbed by external words.</li>
<li><strong>Positive Attitude:</strong> Show confidence and a good state to the outside world (&ldquo;I&rsquo;m fine, no problem, the market will rise&rdquo;).</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Decluttering and Value Ordering (Refer to Video 00351 &ldquo;Enlightenment&rdquo;):</strong>
<ul>
<li>Life should be simplified, and clarifying what you &ldquo;don&rsquo;t want&rdquo; is more important than what you &ldquo;want.&rdquo; Reducing unnecessary material pursuits and social relationships can bring more freedom and focus.</li>
<li>Reflect on the core values of life, such as &ldquo;relationships,&rdquo; &ldquo;sense of contribution,&rdquo; &ldquo;health,&rdquo; and &ldquo;soul&rdquo; shared by students, and work is only a part of it.</li>
<li>Get rid of the shackles of seeking external recognition (refer to &ldquo;The Courage to be Disliked&rdquo;).</li>
<li>Love and responsibility for children are the fundamental values that many people find difficult to give up.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Beware of Information Cocoons (Refer to Video 00420 Logic Class):</strong>
<ul>
<li>Realize that we may all be trapped in &ldquo;information cocoons&rdquo; by network algorithms, only accessing homogeneous information, resulting in a narrow vision and loss of independent thinking ability, like &ldquo;parrots&rdquo; repeating views.</li>
<li>Actively seek different information sources, use <strong>critical thinking</strong>, especially the ability to <strong>falsify</strong>, and maintain skepticism about the information received (first assume that 99% is wrong).</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">III. Q&amp;A Session 
    <div id="iii-qa-session" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii-qa-session" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Lily 
    <div id="lily" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#lily" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Share:</strong> Taiwanese firefighter, 40 years old, new investor (started in February), adopting a 442 allocation (40% QQQ, 40% leverage, 20% cash), investing approximately 6 million. Recently experienced a large single-day drop of 28% in the leveraged portion, but stated that they could withstand it. Few friends shared the same philosophy. Believes that never selling can achieve financial freedom.
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Comments:</strong> Thank you for sharing. The 442 allocation is more aggressive, and this decline is a good stress test. Reminded that firefighting work is physically demanding, and investment should focus more on stability. Suggested adjusting the allocation according to their own comfort level, such as 433 or more conservative 424 or even 505. The primary goal of asset allocation is to make yourself &ldquo;comfortable&rdquo; and able to hold it for the long term. Cash is the key to &ldquo;surviving.&rdquo; When facing external doubts, maintaining a strong inner self and confidence is the most important.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Rui 
    <div id="rui" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#rui" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Share:</strong>
<ol>
<li><strong>Life Reflections:</strong> Reviewing last week&rsquo;s homework, combined with &ldquo;How Will You Measure Your Life?&rdquo; and Brian Dyson&rsquo;s five-ball theory, clarified that the second value of life is &ldquo;relationships,&rdquo; &ldquo;sense of contribution,&rdquo; and &ldquo;treating nature well&rdquo;; emphasized the irreplaceability of health, family, friendship, and soul; the current most wanted to get rid of is &ldquo;seeking recognition from others&rdquo;; believed that life regrets often stem from &ldquo;things not done.&rdquo;</li>
<li><strong>Origin of Excel Questions:</strong> Deeply studied Excel and discovered problems due to concerns about smart rebalancing causing Beta to continue to rise (such as &gt;1.2) and wanting to increase living expenses (at 2% of new assets) after asset growth.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li><strong>Question:</strong> Can leveraged ETFs (such as 00670L) commonly used by Taiwanese investors be included in the Excel model to calculate the maintenance rate (market value)? If included, even with a higher Beta (such as 1.24), it seems that a 433 allocation can pass the test.
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response:</strong>
<ul>
<li><strong>Philosophy of Life:</strong> Appreciated the in-depth thinking. Emphasized the importance of &ldquo;decluttering&rdquo; and clarifying &ldquo;what not to want.&rdquo; Agreed that there is no need for others to recognize, and shared that they value their relationship with their children the most. Recommended video 00351 &ldquo;Enlightenment.&rdquo;</li>
<li><strong>Excel and Taiwan Applications:</strong> Theoretically, the market value of leveraged ETFs can be included in the maintenance rate calculation. The existing model is based on the US situation and is conservative (high interest rate assumptions, not explicitly including the market value of leverage), aimed at being universal and safe. Taiwanese investors can take advantage of the no capital gains tax (easy to reduce leverage) and lower interest rates, and modify Excel themselves (such as changing the interest rate and adjusting the maintenance rate formula) to better fit reality. If the model can pass, it is usually easier in Taiwan. Thanked them for their question, which prompted the optimization of the &ldquo;how to increase spending after asset growth&rdquo; strategy (0.7%-0.8% rule or reducing leverage).</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Yaowen 
    <div id="yaowen" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#yaowen" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Question:</strong> Observed that the recovery time of historical bear markets seems to be shortening. Combined with the evolution of US financial policies (QE, pandemic response, etc.), does it mean that the government&rsquo;s control efficiency has improved and the market recovery is accelerating?
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response:</strong> Agreed with the observation. With the accumulation of financial theory and practical experience, policy tools are more effective, and the ability to respond to known crises has indeed increased, shortening the recovery period. But the real risk lies in <strong>unknown, unprecedented crises</strong>. There is no need to worry too much about known patterns, and be optimistic about the future but have risk awareness.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Weijun 
    <div id="weijun" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#weijun" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Share:</strong> 433 allocation is already All in. Although they thought they were prepared, when actually facing the decline, it was difficult to bear the pressure from their parents&rsquo; &ldquo;caring&rdquo; worries, and they were even afraid to tell them about the losses. Glad that this decline occurred when the invested proportion was not yet high.</li>
<li><strong>Question:</strong> How to cope with this kind of caring pressure from relatives and friends (especially parents)? (Especially for office workers who cannot physically avoid it like retirees).
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response:</strong> Cannot control others, only cultivate the inner self. From shielding information (&ldquo;not listening, not seeing, does not exist&rdquo;) to the inner self not being disturbed (&ldquo;both seeing and listening but also does not exist&rdquo;). The key is to have firm self-belief, understand the current situation, and show confidence to the outside world (&ldquo;I&rsquo;m fine&rdquo;). The decline is the norm for investing, or a good opportunity to rebalance. When the inner self is strong enough to realize a certain illusion of the external world, its influence can be reduced.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">JJ 
    <div id="jj" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#jj" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Question:</strong> Expressed concerns about the US&rsquo;s leading position in technology, listed multiple negative information (loss of scientists, tightening of visas, damage to funding/independence of research institutions, anti-vaccine stance of the Minister of Health and public health incidents), and asked about the impact of the US losing its position as a technology center on QQQ investment and whether it is necessary to adjust the strategy.
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response:</strong>
<ul>
<li><strong>Macro Level:</strong> Refer to video 00430C. Admitted that global competition is intensifying, but the US has not declined, and the foundation of technological strength remains. The US democratic system has resilience and self-correcting ability, and there is no need to be overly pessimistic due to short-term policies or personnel changes.</li>
<li><strong>Investment Indicators:</strong> The criteria for judgment is the composition of the top ten technology companies in the world by market value. If it is still dominated by the United States, then there is no need to change the strategy. If the future pattern changes significantly (such as non-US companies accounting for more than half), consider adjusting the proportion accordingly. Unlikely to happen within 50 years.</li>
<li><strong>Specific Concerns:</strong> Much information may be amplified or biased (information cocoon effect). Believe in the basic integrity system and institutional resilience of American society. Individual incidents (such as anti-vaccine rhetoric, measles outbreaks), while worrying, are unlikely to subvert the entire system. Stay focused, but don&rsquo;t panic, and focus on verifiable facts.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">David 
    <div id="david" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#david" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Share and Response:</strong>
<ol>
<li>Questioned the information mentioned by JJ, emphasizing the need to verify the source and scientific nature of the information (such as the measles vaccine issue), and compared the different practices of China and the United States in areas such as autonomous driving, pointing out the prudence and regulatory constraints in the US system.</li>
<li>Questioned the authenticity of reports about cuts in social welfare (lack of examples).</li>
<li>Cited historical data from the 2018 trade war to prove that the US market and economic regulation are more resilient than China.</li>
<li>Suggested actively searching for reverse information and historical data to overcome fear.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Comments:</strong> Highly praised David&rsquo;s emphasis on information discrimination. Further elaborated on the dangers of <strong>information cocoons</strong>, which deprive people of independent thinking ability and turn them into <strong>parrots</strong>. Called on everyone to be vigilant, actively break down information barriers, and use <strong>critical thinking</strong> and <strong>falsification</strong> methods (refer to video 00420 Logic Class) to examine information.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Tony 
    <div id="tony" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#tony" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Question:</strong> Why is the annual borrowing rate (S5) divided by 2 in the monthly compound interest calculation of the cash portion in the Excel practice version?
<ul>
<li><strong>James/慶 (Qing) Response:</strong> This is the design assumption of the model: The <strong>deposit rate</strong> (cash yield) is set to half of the <strong>borrowing rate</strong>. This is a simplified, conservative estimate that reflects the reality of the bank&rsquo;s deposit and loan interest rate spread. The formula <code>principal * (1 + S5/2/12)</code> is correct, reflecting this safety margin, and does not need to be modified.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">IV. Wonderful Views 
    <div id="iv-wonderful-views" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv-wonderful-views" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>Market volatility, international situations, trade wars, hot and cold wars&hellip; have nothing to do with our investment, just buy, don&rsquo;t sell. Long-term is investment.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>Background: Emphasizes that long-term investment should focus on holding high-quality assets, ignoring short-term market noise and macro events.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>You will definitely encounter several opportunities for asset depreciation of 50% in the market, this is not a probability problem, this is a certainty.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>Background: Reminds investors that a significant market correction is an inevitable part of long-term investment and that they need to be psychologically and financially prepared for it.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Asset allocation is not done for performance, asset allocation is done for your comfort.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>Background: Explains that the primary goal of asset allocation (especially the proportion of cash holdings) is to ensure that investors can hold it with peace of mind and get through the cycle, rather than simply pursuing the highest returns.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Commercial banks are intermediaries that transfer the money of the poor to the rich for use, and this revolving door takes place in banks. This is the reason why the capitalist system makes the poor poorer and the rich richer.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>Background: Reveals the core role of the modern banking system in capital flow and its impact on the wealth distribution pattern.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>People who borrow money are VIPs&hellip; those who don&rsquo;t have much money and don&rsquo;t borrow money, please go to the counter to draw a number and line up.
&ndash; James (quoting student Benson&rsquo;s observation)</p></blockquote>
<p>Background: Vividly compares the vast difference in the way banks treat large borrowing customers and ordinary depositors.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>You push out all the things you don&rsquo;t want first&hellip; then what are the things you have left that you want? It&rsquo;s very little&hellip; the less you want, the less homework you have.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>Background: Applies the concept of &ldquo;decluttering&rdquo; to life planning, advocating that by reducing desires and unnecessary pursuits, inner freedom and focus can be achieved.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>We are besieged by the network and locked in an information prison, you can&rsquo;t break out&hellip; all our thoughts are not our thoughts&hellip; we are all parrots.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>Background: Deeply warns of the erosion of individual cognition and independent thinking ability by &ldquo;information cocoons,&rdquo; calling for vigilance.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Both seeing and listening but also does not exist.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>Background: Describes an advanced state of psychological practice, where even when exposed to negative or disturbing information, the inner self can remain calm and unaffected.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Things that have happened in the past are less worried about, we are worried about things that have never happened before.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>Background: Distinguishes between known and unknown risks, pointing out that historical experience helps to deal with recurring crises, but the real challenge lies in dealing with new, unknown shocks.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>If you retire six years early (to perform Roth conversion), you will be short of 300 million (USD).
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>Background: Based on simulation calculation results, strongly emphasizes the huge long-term wealth effect that can be brought about by using the low tax rate window to convert Roth IRA/401k as early as possible.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">V. Summary 
    <div id="v-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#v-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This lecture, against the background of increased market volatility, strengthened the core concept of long-term investment: ignore the noise and insist on holding high-quality index funds (QQQ). James not only updated and explained in detail the important financial planning tool Excel model (especially the adjustment of withdrawal strategies after asset growth), but also persuasively demonstrated the amazing value of doing Roth conversion as early as possible. At a deeper level, the course focused on the construction of investment psychology, discussed how to understand and use financial system rules, how to cope with external pressure (worries from relatives and friends, social information) with a strong inner self, and especially emphasized the extreme importance of maintaining independent thinking and being wary of &ldquo;information cocoons&rdquo; in the era of information explosion. The ultimate goal is to help investors cultivate both their inner skills and achieve a double improvement in cognition and mindset on the road to pursuing financial freedom.</p>

  



<div
  
    class="flex px-4 py-3 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900"
  >

  <span
    
      class="text-primary-400 ltr:pr-3 rtl:pl-3 flex items-center"
    >

    

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M506.3 417l-213.3-364c-16.33-28-57.54-28-73.98 0l-213.2 364C-10.59 444.9 9.849 480 42.74 480h426.6C502.1 480 522.6 445 506.3 417zM232 168c0-13.25 10.75-24 24-24S280 154.8 280 168v128c0 13.25-10.75 24-23.1 24S232 309.3 232 296V168zM256 416c-17.36 0-31.44-14.08-31.44-31.44c0-17.36 14.07-31.44 31.44-31.44s31.44 14.08 31.44 31.44C287.4 401.9 273.4 416 256 416z"/></svg>

  </span>


  </span>

  <span
    
      class="dark:text-neutral-300"
    ><strong>Disclaimer:</strong> This article is only a personal study note and does not constitute any investment advice.</span>
</div>

]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>00509 Don't Let Greed and Fear Ruin Your Investment Life: Investing Isn't About Being the Fastest, But About Who Laughs Last</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1743323578617/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1743323578617/</guid><description>In this episode, James discusses the normalcy of market fluctuations, emphasizes the importance of long-term holding of index funds, analyzes the actual situation of U.S. Treasury bonds, and shares insights on asset allocation, leverage use, investment psychology, real estate, children&amp;#39;s education, and consumption concepts.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<lite-youtube videoid="p6vRBnH2VqA" playlabel="p6vRBnH2VqA" params=""></lite-youtube>



<h2 class="relative group">I. Current Theme 
    <div id="i-current-theme" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-current-theme" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>The market is always fluctuating; this is normal. Investors should have a long-term perspective, ignoring short-term volatility and market noise (such as international situations, economic analysis, financial reports, etc.). The core strategy is to hold high-quality index funds (such as QQQ) for the long term, and to make reasonable asset allocation (including cash reserves) based on individual risk tolerance, while overcoming the greed and fear of human nature. Learning and building a firm belief are essential.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">II. Briefing Content 
    <div id="ii-briefing-content" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii-briefing-content" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Market Volatility and Long-Term Investing 
    <div id="market-volatility-and-long-term-investing" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#market-volatility-and-long-term-investing" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Market volatility is normal</strong>: A 10% market drop is normal, 20% happens about every two or three years, and 50% may happen every five to ten years. This is like the tides, wind, rain, and earthquakes in nature; it&rsquo;s an inevitable natural phenomenon. Don&rsquo;t think &ldquo;this year is different&rdquo;; every year is the same.</li>
<li><strong>Importance of a long-term perspective</strong>: As long as you stay in the market long enough, you will understand that there is nothing new in the market. The core laws of the market are &ldquo;always rising&rdquo; and &ldquo;always fluctuating.&rdquo;</li>
<li><strong>Ignore the noise</strong>: Market fluctuations, international situations, market analysis, financial reports, and economic situations are all irrelevant to the decisions of long-term investors.</li>
<li><strong>Recommended strategy</strong>: Hold the Nasdaq 100 index fund (QQQ) for the long term; it can be bought worldwide. This is the simplest and most effective strategy.</li>
<li><strong>Interactive request</strong>: Hope everyone likes, leaves comments, and most importantly, subscribes on various platforms (Podcast, Bilibili, YouTube).</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Learning and Mindset 
    <div id="learning-and-mindset" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#learning-and-mindset" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Learning to build belief</strong>: Investing is simple (buy index funds), but there are many external distractions (monsters and ghosts). You need to build firm belief and willpower through learning, so that you will not be easily swayed by other people&rsquo;s opinions.</li>
<li><strong>Overcoming human weaknesses</strong>: Greed and fear are the biggest enemies of investment.
<ul>
<li><strong>Manifestations of greed</strong>: Chasing high when the market rises, thinking that the opportunity to &ldquo;buy the dip&rdquo; has come when the market falls, and using up all cash too early (e.g., constantly adding positions when the market has just fallen 5%-13%).</li>
<li><strong>Manifestations of fear</strong>: Not daring to buy when the market rises, only FOMOing (fear of missing out) All-in when it has risen too much; panicking when the market falls and selling at a loss at the bottom.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Importance of cash</strong>: Ample cash is a magic weapon to overcome human nature (especially fear), as important as air. It makes you feel comfortable and secure when the market falls. Don&rsquo;t exhaust your cash when the market just starts to fall.</li>
<li><strong>Living in the present</strong>: Don&rsquo;t dwell on past mistakes (such as losses in real estate investment), don&rsquo;t worry too much about future uncertainties, focus on the present, and do your current investment and learning well.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Asset Allocation and Leverage 
    <div id="asset-allocation-and-leverage" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#asset-allocation-and-leverage" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Finding the comfort zone</strong>: Everyone has a different risk tolerance. You need to find your comfortable asset allocation ratio through market fluctuations (such as 442, 433, 523, 514, 505, etc.), and the cash ratio is very important. If you feel uncomfortable when the market falls, you should adjust to a configuration that you can hold with peace of mind during rebounds.</li>
<li><strong>Leverage risk</strong>: Few people can withstand fluctuations of more than 1.2 times Beta. When the market falls, many people will not be able to stand it and reduce leverage. Don&rsquo;t be overconfident in adding leverage when the market is good.
<ul>
<li><strong>Example</strong>: Some people went from 442 to 0.9x leverage or even lower.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Rebalancing</strong>: It is recommended to do rebalancing once a year. Only use a small amount of cash (e.g., 2% per year) to buy if the market is down at the end of the year. Don&rsquo;t operate frequently or exhaust your cash due to monthly or short-term declines.</li>
<li><strong>About full-position leverage</strong>: It is not recommended for young people to use &ldquo;full-position two-times leverage,&rdquo; because there will always be a big bubble in life. High leverage may lead to a significant asset drawdown (e.g., falling to 0.1), which is difficult to recover, and you may reach your goal later than with a stable investment.</li>
<li><strong>Tortoise and hare</strong>: A stable configuration (tortoise) will outperform an aggressive high-leverage strategy (hare) in the long run. Even if the Beta is lower than 1, it doesn&rsquo;t matter.</li>
<li><strong>Purpose of secured borrowing</strong>: The purpose of secured borrowing is not to pursue extreme returns, but to meet living needs or make better configurations while holding high-quality assets for the long term. The risk lies in the ability to repay the principal, not the interest burden.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">U.S. Treasury Bonds and the Economy 
    <div id="us-treasury-bonds-and-the-economy" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#us-treasury-bonds-and-the-economy" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>US Debt Clock Update</strong>: The website has been updated, adding data such as DoJ Waste Recovery of federal wasted funds and U.S. Hidden Wealth Assets (including gold, minerals, real estate, land, stocks, Recaptured Assets, etc.).</li>
<li><strong>U.S. Balance Sheet</strong> (as of March 27, 2025, approximate numbers):
<ul>
<li>Total Assets: Approximately 168 Trillion (T)</li>
<li>Federal Government Debt (in bond form): Approximately 36 T</li>
<li>Total Liabilities (including credit represented by cash M1/M2, etc.): Approximately 102 T</li>
<li>Annual Income (GDP): Approximately 28 T</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Interpretation</strong>: It&rsquo;s like a person having 1.68 million in assets (and the assets are growing at a rate of about 10%), 1.02 million in debt (of which 360,000 is core debt), and an annual salary of 280,000 (which is also growing). The debt is controllable, and the risk of bankruptcy is very low. U.S. dollar cash itself is also a liability, but it will depreciate with inflation, reducing the actual repayment pressure.</li>
<li><strong>Interest problem</strong>: Federal debt interest expenditure is about 1T, which is controllable relative to federal tax revenue (about 4.9T + state tax) and GDP (28T). There is no need to worry too much about the so-called interest exceeding defense spending (about 0.9T), as this comparison is not meaningful.</li>
<li><strong>Clarification of Musk&rsquo;s views</strong>: Musk mainly criticized the <strong>inefficiency and waste</strong> of the U.S. government&rsquo;s spending, rather than the debt itself being unsustainable.</li>
<li><strong>Impact of tariffs</strong>: Raising tariffs essentially shifts costs to consumers, leading to rising prices, which is equivalent to a disguised tax. This is just a different form from directly collecting federal taxes (paying in installments in daily consumption vs. paying once a year). The impact on the overall economy is complex, but for individuals, it may just be &ldquo;shifting from the left pocket to the right pocket.&rdquo;</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Other Sharing 
    <div id="other-sharing" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#other-sharing" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>HSBC Hong Kong Account Opening Experience (Student Sharing)</strong>:
<ul>
<li>Threshold: May require assets equivalent to HK$1 million to avoid monthly fees (approximately HK$380).</li>
<li>Transaction fee: Relatively high, but has little impact on long-term holders.</li>
<li>Stock pledge interest rate: HIBOR + 1.2%, currently about 4.92%, which is acceptable.</li>
<li>Suggestion: It is more convenient to sell stocks in other brokerages for cash and transfer them in than to perform complex cross-system transfers. Don&rsquo;t delay important matters for small fees.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Canadian Real Estate Investment Issues (Student Sharing)</strong>:
<ul>
<li>Non-tax residents face high withholding tax on selling property (35% of the selling price, not the profit), and transaction costs are high (brokerage fees, prepayment penalties, lawyer and accounting fees).</li>
<li>Conclusion: Houses are &ldquo;invisible cages&rdquo; and tools for governments, the financial industry, and capitalism to bind labor. Don&rsquo;t hesitate to sell the house; past investments are sunk costs. James also shared his experience of losing money selling a house in Longtan, Taiwan.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Retirement Planning Case (Student Question)</strong>:
<ul>
<li>NT$15 million in funds + NT$5 million in financial-type mortgage.</li>
<li>Suggestion: For the part that needs cash flow, consider buying ETFs such as 0050/0056 that provide dividends, but be aware that their dividends may include principal (selling component stocks).</li>
<li>Investment of NT$15 million: If you don&rsquo;t need to withdraw money from it, you can consider leveraged allocation (such as 433); if you need to withdraw money, you cannot use leverage. Choose the allocation based on the withdrawal rate (the amount needed after deducting Social Security benefits) (e.g., 2% withdrawal with 80/20 QQQ/cash; 3% withdrawal with SPY). The withdrawal rate is key, not the traditional 4% rule.</li>
<li>Core: Any configuration must consider whether you can withstand a 50% market drop.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Tesla FSD Experience (Student and Teacher Sharing)</strong>:
<ul>
<li>FSD V12 is amazing, close to fully autonomous driving, able to handle complex road conditions (such as San Francisco), and significantly reduces driving stress and fatigue.</li>
<li>FSD has a certain &ldquo;perception&rdquo; ability and can judge the intentions of other vehicles/pedestrians and make intelligent reactions.</li>
<li>Value: The teacher believes that FSD is worth the money (willing to spend $100,000 to buy it), improves safety (saves lives), improves the driving experience (reduces family quarrels), and may even reduce insurance premiums (using Tesla Insurance). Strongly recommends buying a Tesla car with FSD (the new Model Y comes standard). Use the teacher&rsquo;s referral code for discounts.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Consumption Concepts and Family (Student Question)</strong>:
<ul>
<li>Problem: Family members (such as spouses, parents) continue to demand new car replacements and other consumption due to &ldquo;laborer thinking&rdquo; or material needs, which conflicts with their own goals of accumulating wealth, and they feel annoyed.</li>
<li>Teacher&rsquo;s suggestion:
<ul>
<li>Understand the needs and feelings of family members (love what they love).</li>
<li>Learn to &ldquo;consume smartly,&rdquo; using financial tools (such as secured loans, adjusting allocation ratios) to meet some reasonable needs without excessively affecting the growth of core investments. For example, sell 100,000 QQQ, exchange it for 50,000 QLD (keeping some exposure) + 50,000 cash to buy a car.</li>
<li>The goal of capitalists is to make money generate money and ultimately use it to improve the quality of life, not just to save money. Find a balance between accumulation and consumption.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Technology Product Consumption</strong>: The teacher shared that buying high-quality displays (Nano-texture display) and AirPods Pro 2 (with hearing aid function, about $249) is to protect health and improve the quality of life. These investments are worthwhile, and financial operations (such as secured loans, credit card rebates reinvestment) can be used to make them feel like &ldquo;no money is spent.&rdquo;</li>
<li><strong>Defining Purchasing Power</strong>: True purchasing power means that when the purchased items (such as houses and cars) are accidentally damaged, you have the ability to easily buy another one without feeling financial pressure or heartache. Otherwise, you are exceeding your consumption capacity.</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">III. Q&amp;A Session 
    <div id="iii-qa-session" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii-qa-session" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">K 
    <div id="k" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#k" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Often explains to friends that market fluctuations are normal and not to panic. Also dissuaded friends from borrowing too much to invest just because their income could afford the interest.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s comment: Agreed. The main risk of secured borrowing is not the ability to pay interest, but the ability to repay the principal (Margin Call) when the market falls. Adjusting leverage to a comfortable level during market rebounds is important.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">C 
    <div id="c" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#c" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Thanks for the teacher&rsquo;s inspiration, sharing that he and a friend were deeply touched and started taking action, but also lamented that many people would rather eat, drink, and have fun than squeeze out a small amount of money to invest each month. Cognition determines wealth.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s comment: Glad to see students agree and execute, eventually becoming wealthy. Shared the example of an early student (2006) who persisted and has achieved financial freedom. Becoming a capitalist requires cognition and persistence, and it is indeed a minority of people.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Tommy 
    <div id="tommy" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#tommy" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Reviewed his 16-year investment journey: early purchases of 0050/0056 -&gt; chasing biotech stocks (heavy losses) -&gt; starting to invest in U.S. stocks (VOO/VTI/bonds, diversified) after the pandemic -&gt; epiphany after listening to the course, and is now concentrating assets into QQQ. Realized that dividends (0056) are not as good as total return (0050), paying off the mortgage too early was a wrong decision, and the cost of time is terrible.</li>
<li>Question 1: Should asset allocation (such as 442/433) be achieved on all accounts (Taiwan, US Brokerage, IRA, Roth 401k, etc.) as a whole, or should each account follow?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s reply: All accounts should be regarded as a whole for allocation. Leveraged funds (such as QLD) can only be placed in tax-free growth Roth accounts. Cash can be placed in Brokerage or Traditional IRA/401k (doing so can slow down the growth of pre-tax accounts, which is beneficial for future taxes). The final Beta value will be limited by the size of the Roth account. Even if the Beta is lower than 1, it doesn&rsquo;t matter. Stability (tortoise) may outperform aggression (hare).</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2: There are historical contributions in Traditional 401k (mutual funds have been converted to QQQ), and now it is a mix of Roth and Traditional. Should the Traditional portion be converted to Roth?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s reply: Whether to convert depends on the amount and current tax rate. If the amount is not large, you can convert it all at once. If the amount is large (e.g., 500,000), in order to avoid high tax burdens, it should be converted over many years. You can use the Investment Calculator to calculate how much amount to convert each year to reduce the Traditional balance to zero within a set period (e.g., 10 years) while controlling the annual tax burden. Fidelity clearly distinguishes the shares of Roth and Traditional internally.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">MMA 
    <div id="mma" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#mma" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Experienced Tesla FSD V12 and felt it was very good. 99% of the journey can be driven automatically, including handling cut-ins, traffic jams, and complex slopes in San Francisco, which greatly improves driving efficiency and comfort. Admired Tesla&rsquo;s technology and efficiency (the AI ​​department has few people but significant results).
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s comment: Very much agree. FSD is not just mechanical execution, but can also &ldquo;feel&rdquo; the intentions of other vehicles and pedestrians and make intelligent judgments. FSD greatly reduces driving pressure and improves safety (saves lives). Using FSD also helps reduce the insurance premium for Tesla Insurance. Strongly recommends buying a Tesla with FSD, and stocks can be held through QQQ.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Iam 
    <div id="iam" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iam" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Encountered a brokerage that promoted an IPO and realized that it was an interference from &ldquo;monsters and ghosts.&rdquo;</li>
<li>Question: How to deal with close people (parents, spouses, children) who continue to hold &ldquo;laborer thinking&rdquo; and constantly demand material consumption (such as changing to a new car), which conflicts with their own wealth accumulation philosophy and feels annoyed and pressured? Is there a good way to deal with it?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s reply:
<ol>
<li><strong>Understanding and love</strong>: Understand the needs of family members and love them (love what they love). Meeting reasonable needs is part of maintaining family harmony.</li>
<li><strong>Smart consumption</strong>: Capitalists don&rsquo;t not consume, but consume smartly. Use financial tools (secured loans, adjusting investment portfolios such as selling QQQ for QLD + cash) to meet consumption needs as much as possible without affecting the compound growth of core assets.</li>
<li><strong>Balance</strong>: Find a balance between wealth accumulation and enjoyment of life. It is not necessary to meet all requirements, but it is not possible to completely reject them. It is necessary to meet one or two needs that family members value every year or every few years.</li>
<li><strong>No need to explain too much</strong>: Actions speak louder than words. Express love through practical actions (such as buying a car), but there is no need to argue too much about concepts.</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Ling 
    <div id="ling" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ling" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Describes a complex arbitrage strategy: Using secured borrowing (leverage may exceed 1.5 times), puts some funds into a digital account in Taiwan (about 2% interest), and buys 00864B (USD money market fund) to try to cover the 2.8% borrowing cost. Also shared how to use credit card payments to get 0% interest installments and then use the money to buy 00864B for arbitrage.</li>
<li>Question: Is this operation feasible? Does it conform to the 442 configuration idea?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s reply:
<ol>
<li><strong>Not 442</strong>: What you described is an arbitrage strategy, not the 442 asset allocation based on long-term growth that we discussed.</li>
<li><strong>Arbitrage efficiency</strong>: Putting borrowed money (cost 2.8%) into a NTD account with 2% interest is losing money. All of it should be put into 00864B with higher returns (about 4.5%) and matching currencies (USD) for arbitrage. Exchange rate fluctuations are not important.</li>
<li><strong>Credit card arbitrage</strong>: It is feasible to use 0% interest installments for arbitrage, but it is a &ldquo;sesame green bean&rdquo; small trick and should not be distracted too much.</li>
<li><strong>Risk</strong>: As long as the target (00864B) itself does not fall, this pure arbitrage strategy has low risk and will not be margin called.</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Sandy 
    <div id="sandy" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#sandy" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Experienced the 2008 financial crisis, assets were halved, and since then has attached importance to cash, maintaining 30-40% cash all year round. Dared to buy in when the market fell sharply in 2022 and made a profit at the end of the year.</li>
<li>Question 1: Made considerable profits last year and early this year and wanted to sell some at a high level to avoid a callback, but her husband prevented it because of concerns about high taxes (believing that it would push the tax bracket to 50%). How to deal with it?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s reply: Her husband&rsquo;s understanding of tax law is wrong. Long-term Capital Gain Tax is calculated separately from ordinary income tax. Its tax rate is tiered (usually 0%, 15%, 20%), and the highest is 20% (plus a possible 3.8% NIIT). Selling capital gains will not push ordinary income to an extremely high tax bracket (such as 50%). The tax rate for selling a lot of LTCG is basically fixed (it is 20% after reaching a certain amount). However, it is not recommended to time the market to sell. If you really want to operate, you should prioritize doing so in retirement accounts (such as IRA/401k). Selling has no immediate tax impact, and you can even buy reverse ETFs (such as SQQQ) for hedging in retirement accounts (advanced operation, not recommended).</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2: Is it better to buy dividend-paying stocks or other things with the cash (Money Market) held? Worried about the tax on dividend-paying stocks.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s reply: Don&rsquo;t use dividend-paying stocks to hold cash, the tax efficiency is low. You should use money market funds. If you want to avoid both federal and state taxes, you can consider municipal bond funds (Muni Bond Fund, such as Vanguard&rsquo;s VOOX). If you only consider federal tax, you can use U.S. Treasury money market funds (such as SGOV, BIL). There is a capital gains tax problem only when selling.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 3: I want to anonymously sponsor a talented child (a friend&rsquo;s child, with decent family conditions), but I don&rsquo;t want the other party to know now, how to operate? Worried about tax issues.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s reply: Anonymous operation is difficult, especially involving opening an account. And the other party&rsquo;s family may not need sponsorship. A safer way is to write this child (providing name, address, and other information) into your own trust file as a beneficiary of future inheritance. This operation is simple and usually tax-free.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">CL 
    <div id="cl" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#cl" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question 1: In the United States, in addition to mortgage loans and stock pledges, what other similar low-cost sources of funds can be used like &ldquo;Han Xin counting soldiers&rdquo;?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s reply: The U.S. financial market is highly efficient and has a lot of &ldquo;smart money,&rdquo; so the interest rate on unsecured personal loans is usually higher (such as 8% +). Unlike Taiwan, which has a large amount of low-cost funds (due to export-oriented currency abundance), there are indeed not many other low-cost, flexible sources of funds besides stock pledges (Pledge Loan). If you have channels in Taiwan to borrow low-interest NTD funds, you can consider it.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2: Regarding children&rsquo;s college tuition fees, is it better for them to apply for student loans themselves (and we will use the pledged money to pay them back after graduation), or to pay directly with the pledged money? Which is better?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s reply: There is no absolute right or wrong, it depends on the child&rsquo;s personality and feelings. If the child feels stressed about debt, pay directly. If the child understands financial leverage and the student loan conditions are favorable (such as interest only after graduation), you can let them take out the loan and the parents will pay it back later. The key is to communicate well with the child. The teacher shared his experience of paying his daughter&rsquo;s tuition fees directly.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Sharing: Fortunate to have followed the teacher&rsquo;s advice to sell the expensive house in Los Angeles and exchange it for a cheaper one and use a pledge loan. Now I feel relaxed, unlike some friends who are trapped in expensive houses and facing difficulties under the wave of layoffs.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s comment: Yes, real estate has poor liquidity, especially when bought at a high price, which easily limits life choices and financial flexibility. Young people should be especially cautious.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Hao Qing (浩清) 
    <div id="hao-qing-%E6%B5%A9%E6%B8%85" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#hao-qing-%E6%B5%A9%E6%B8%85" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Told about his difficult experiences in the United States in the early stages of immigration: meager salary (less than 30,000 USD/year), relying on friends to introduce jobs, being questioned by the boss for his ability, saving money, working long hours and studying every day to support his family. Shared the process and feelings of raising three children: Children are motivation and will find their own way out. Responded to the teacher&rsquo;s video case about hesitating whether to have a third child, encouraged having children, and believed that children have their own future.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s comment: Shared his own experience of being poor when he first came to the United States (borrowing money to come to the United States, living in Motel 6, cooking by himself). Emphasized that the hardship of life is a process and also a valuable wealth and memory. Encouraged everyone to face life challenges bravely. Marriage and childbirth are not that terrible, love is the key, and money is usually not the biggest problem.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Terry 
    <div id="terry" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#terry" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question 1: Concerns about U.S. Treasury bonds (such as the debt-to-GDP ratio, interest burden), is it possible that the world will stop buying U.S. bonds?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s reply: U.S. assets (168T) far exceed debt (federal debt 36T). The interest burden is controllable relative to fiscal revenue and GDP. Countries around the world hold a large amount of USD reserves and must purchase USD assets (government bonds, treasury bills, money market funds, etc.) to store them. There are no other large-scale options to replace them. Therefore, the world will not stop buying U.S. bonds. A strong U.S. dollar is in the best interest of the United States.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2: The price of SGOV (short-term treasury bond ETF) is rising slightly every day, while the price of TLT (long-term treasury bond ETF) has been falling recently, why?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s reply: SGOV tracks short-term interest rates. Its mechanism is to accrue interest accumulation daily and the net value returns after dividends, showing a step-like slight oscillation. TLT represents long-term treasury bonds, and its price (yield) mainly reflects the market&rsquo;s <strong>expectations for future long-term inflation</strong>. If the market expects inflation to rise in the future (for example, worrying about tariffs leading to inflation), the yield on long-term treasury bonds will rise and the price of TLT will fall. This has little to do with the Fed&rsquo;s current short-term interest rate policy.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">IV. Highlighted Quotes 
    <div id="iv-highlighted-quotes" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv-highlighted-quotes" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>The market is always fluctuating&hellip; There is nothing new in the market, that is, as long as you stay in the market long enough.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>(Emphasizes the normalcy of market volatility and the importance of a long-term perspective)</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Cash is a magic weapon to overcome human nature.
&ndash; James (Cookie student also mentioned &ldquo;Cash is King&rdquo;)</p></blockquote>
<p>(Emphasizes the key role of cash in dealing with market fluctuations and psychological biases)</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Even if you are a god, you have many magic weapons. If you run out of magic weapons, you are not a god.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>(Uses metaphor to illustrate the importance of cash reserves, which cannot be easily exhausted)</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The purpose of capitalists is to spend money. Money is a tool, so what do we earn so much money for? It&rsquo;s to spend&hellip; We need to know how to spend money without reducing assets, killing other people&rsquo;s chickens, and our own chickens are still full of pits. This is our capitalist&rsquo;s philosophy, not saving money.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>(Explains a capitalist mindset that uses financial tools to achieve &ldquo;smart consumption&rdquo; and balance wealth growth and quality of life)</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Good individual stocks don&rsquo;t mean you can&rsquo;t get rich, they mean you can&rsquo;t get rich.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>(Explains the difficulty of holding a single stock with huge fluctuations, it&rsquo;s better to invest in index funds)</p>
<blockquote>
<p>When you can afford to buy two houses, you go buy one&hellip; You can buy something that, if it breaks, you&rsquo;re not sad at all, and you&rsquo;re even happy that you can buy a new one. That means you have the ability to consume.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>(Defines true &ldquo;purchasing power&rdquo; as the ability to afford losses without affecting life, advising young people to be cautious about buying houses)</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Long-term (capital gains) has nothing to do with income&hellip; Long-term capital gain is a fixed tax rate, it&rsquo;s either 15% or 20% and that&rsquo;s it, it won&rsquo;t be higher than 20%&hellip; You sell 10 million and it&rsquo;s still 20%.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>(Clarifies the calculation of U.S. long-term capital gains tax, it is not mixed with ordinary income and progressively increases)</p>
<blockquote>
<p>A strong dollar is in the best interest of the United States.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>(Points out the core interest orientation of the United States in monetary policy)</p>
<blockquote>
<p>TLT&hellip; Its interest is linked to inflation, linked to inflation expectations. So it has nothing to do with the central bank&rsquo;s interest rate.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>(Explains the core drivers of long-term treasury bond yields)</p>


<h2 class="relative group">V. Summary 
    <div id="v-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#v-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>In this CLEC investment and financial management sharing session, James reiterated the core philosophy of long-term investment: embrace market volatility, adhere to holding index funds represented by QQQ, and build firm belief through continuous learning. The teacher analyzed the real situation of U.S. Treasury bonds in detail, believing that there is no need to worry too much, and clarified the misunderstanding about its interest burden and Musk&rsquo;s criticism. At the same time, it discussed the rational use of leverage, the importance of cash reserves (like air and magic weapons), and how to overcome psychological biases in investment. The Q&amp;A session involved asset allocation across accounts, Roth conversion, real estate processing (including Canadian non-resident tax issues and personal experience), children&rsquo;s education funding planning, the excellent value and experience of Tesla FSD, consumption concept balance (smart consumption vs. laborer thinking), the limited sources of low-cost funds in the United States, the driving factor differences between long-term and short-term treasury bond ETFs, and the correct understanding of U.S. long-term capital gains tax and other practical issues, providing specific operational suggestions and thinking frameworks. The core message is to maintain a long-term perspective, make rational decisions, use financial tools to achieve a balance between wealth growth and quality of life, while understanding and respecting the needs of the people around you.</p>

  



<div
  
    class="flex px-4 py-3 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900"
  >

  <span
    
      class="text-primary-400 ltr:pr-3 rtl:pl-3 flex items-center"
    >

    

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M506.3 417l-213.3-364c-16.33-28-57.54-28-73.98 0l-213.2 364C-10.59 444.9 9.849 480 42.74 480h426.6C502.1 480 522.6 445 506.3 417zM232 168c0-13.25 10.75-24 24-24S280 154.8 280 168v128c0 13.25-10.75 24-23.1 24S232 309.3 232 296V168zM256 416c-17.36 0-31.44-14.08-31.44-31.44c0-17.36 14.07-31.44 31.44-31.44s31.44 14.08 31.44 31.44C287.4 401.9 273.4 416 256 416z"/></svg>

  </span>


  </span>

  <span
    
      class="dark:text-neutral-300"
    ><strong>Disclaimer:</strong> This article is for personal study notes only and does not constitute any investment advice.</span>
</div>

]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>00483 Rock-solid asset allocation,Investment strategies based on asset allocation and risk management</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1728265687577/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1728265687577/</guid><description>This live stream focuses on the core concept of &amp;#39;wealth is a gift&amp;#39;. James explains the importance of investing and financial management, the advantages of index investing, the relationship between risk tolerance and investment returns, and how to allocate your assets reasonably. During the Q&amp;amp;A session, students raised questions about TQQQ investment, Beta calculation, asset allocation strategies, and the investment market in mainland China. James answered these questions in detail and shared numerous experiences and cases to help students overcome psychological barriers in investment and solidify their long-term investment philosophy.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<lite-youtube videoid="eSkubAhBlhE" playlabel="eSkubAhBlhE" params=""></lite-youtube>



<h2 class="relative group">I. Theme of the Episode 
    <div id="i-theme-of-the-episode" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-theme-of-the-episode" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>The theme of this episode is &ldquo;Investing and Financial Management, Wealth is a Gift.&rdquo; The core viewpoints  are: <strong>Wealth is innate, but one must be informed to realize it; investing and financial management is an important way to accumulate wealth; index investing is an effective method to achieve long-term stable growth; rational asset allocation and risk control are the keys to investment success; and overcoming psychological barriers in investment and solidifying the long-term investment philosophy are crucial to ultimately achieving financial freedom.</strong></p>


<h2 class="relative group">II. Summary of the Briefing 
    <div id="ii-summary-of-the-briefing" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii-summary-of-the-briefing" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<ul>
<li><strong>Wealth is a Gift:</strong> Wealth is innate, and being informed of this fact makes a huge difference. While successful entrepreneurs like Elon Musk are a minority, most people need to be told that &ldquo;wealth is a gift,&rdquo; and they need to learn how to invest and manage their finances to achieve wealth growth.</li>
<li><strong>The Power of Index Investing and Compound Interest:</strong> Index investing is an effective way to achieve long-term stable returns, and its compounding effect is astonishing. For example, investing $1,500 per month for 40 years with a 14% annualized return will yield $2.6 million. <strong>Even small amounts of money can accumulate considerable wealth through consistent long-term investment.</strong></li>
<li><strong>High Risk, High Return?</strong>: High risk doesn&rsquo;t necessarily lead to high returns. Whether you can bear the risk determines whether you can ultimately achieve high returns. Don&rsquo;t overestimate your risk tolerance. Your risk appetite should be determined by an asset allocation that you can withstand even if your investment goes to zero. <strong>For example, if you cannot afford the risk of TQQQ going to zero, you should not invest in TQQQ.</strong></li>
<li><strong>Choosing Investment Targets</strong>: It is recommended to invest in the global Nasdaq 100 index fund (QQQ). Those with insufficient funds or who are already retired can consider investing in SPY or high-dividend ETFs. Avoid investing in individual stocks because they tend to disappear over the long term, while index funds can continue to exist. <strong>The half-life of individual stocks is 10 years; out of 100 stocks, there may be less than three left after 50 years.</strong></li>
<li><strong>Investment Mindset</strong>: The market will eventually rise, and investment requires patience. Always stay optimistic, even if the investment goes to zero. Learning about investing and financial management requires continuous thinking, like peeling an onion, layer by layer, to elevate the energy of the spiritual level. <strong>Investing is like the Yellow Mountain, eternally unchanging, yet different every day; every learning experience will bring new insights.</strong></li>
<li><strong>Asset Allocation</strong>: Asset allocation is like building a house; it is a big project that requires comprehensive planning, not something simple. It is necessary to consider many factors, such as whether you are retired, your age, income, debt, and cash flow, to formulate a reasonable asset allocation plan. <strong>You need to carefully study the articles and videos on asset allocation provided by James to develop a plan that suits you.</strong></li>
<li><strong>Do Not  Blindly Trust External Information</strong>: Financial professionals often only consider their interests, so do not easily believe their advice. Think independently, study carefully, and do not be swayed by external information and noise. <strong>Most of the outside information is garbage; do not be affected by it, focus on learning James&rsquo; investment philosophy.</strong></li>
<li><strong>Balancing Risk and Reward</strong>: Do not excessively pursue high returns or completely risk-free investments; balance risk and reward. Avoid changing investment strategies easily to prevent additional costs due to frequent trading. <strong>James&rsquo; investment methods can guarantee asset appreciation and relative safety, avoiding extreme situations.</strong></li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">III. Q&amp;A Session 
    <div id="iii-qa-session" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii-qa-session" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p><strong>IM:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>Sharing: Learning about investment is like peeling an onion; at first, the amount of information is overwhelming, but as you learn more, you will gradually understand the core idea and ultimately reach the realm of &ldquo;the great Dao is simple.&rdquo;</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Question 1: What do you think about the idea that &ldquo;investing is simple&rdquo;?</p>
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo; Response: Such views often mistake ignorance for inaction and do not truly understand the complexity and risks of investment.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p>Question 2: How should we communicate with friends who don&rsquo;t understand index investing?</p>
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo; Response: You can start by briefly introducing the concept and advantages of index investing and suggest that they watch related videos to learn. Don&rsquo;t force them to accept it, everyone has their own choices. <strong>Just like preaching, we can only try our best to spread the message; whether it&rsquo;s ultimately accepted depends on the individual.</strong></li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>LAN:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>Question 1: How to calculate Beta? What is the actual Beta value of a leveraged ETF?</p>
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo; Response: You can refer to the link to the article on Beta calculation on the message board. The actual Beta value of a leveraged ETF may deviate from the theoretical value due to factors such as market volatility and friction costs. <strong>When market volatility is large, the wear and tear of leveraged ETFs will be more serious, resulting in an actual Beta value lower than the theoretical value.</strong></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p>Question 2: Why is there a huge difference in final return between scenario 3 and scenario 4.1 in the 005 topic?</p>
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo; Response: Scenario 4.1 is where no money is withdrawn from the investment, so the final return will be higher.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p>Question 3: How to adjust Beta in a rising market?</p>
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo; Response:  The adjustment of Beta should be determined by your own risk tolerance, not by the market trend. <strong>Do not try to predict the market, just keep a fixed Beta value.</strong></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p>Question 4:  For investments in Taiwan, should I choose Q2D or 00670L?</p>
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo; Response: 00670L is recommended because it includes New Taiwan dollar hedging, which can reduce the risk caused by exchange rate fluctuations. <strong>Don&rsquo;t change investment targets frequently, choose one that suits you and hold it for the long term.</strong></li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Nai Xin:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Wealth is a gift, just as self-confidence is a gift; everyone has potential, but it needs to be stimulated. The key to investing and financial management lies in learning. Once you have mastered the correct investment method, you can focus on your own career and life and let wealth grow naturally over time. <strong>Overcome fear, build confidence, and you can realize your potential, gain wealth, and achieve success.</strong></li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Jason:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Understanding &ldquo;buy whenever you have money,&rdquo; but still finding it difficult to overcome psychological fluctuations when the market rises or falls sharply.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo; Response:  Overcoming psychological fluctuations takes time and experience. You can try to make a small number of trades, experience the impact of market fluctuations, and gradually adapt to market changes.</li>
<li>IM Supplement: You can overcome psychological barriers by imagining starting to invest two years later and understanding that &ldquo;money arrives at different points in time.&rdquo;<strong>Don&rsquo;t worry about buying at the lowest point; as long as you stick to long-term investment, you can get good returns.</strong></li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Hai Rui Ji:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>Sharing:</p>
<ol>
<li>Thank you James for selflessly sharing your investment philosophy; students learn from each other and make progress together.</li>
<li>James&rsquo; investment philosophy requires continuous learning and understanding to grasp it fully. &ldquo;Never sell&rdquo; does not mean you cannot sell, but that you should develop a reasonable investment strategy based on your own situation. ** &ldquo;Never sell&rdquo; refers to mentally ignoring market fluctuations and adhering to a long-term investment philosophy.**</li>
<li>Investment philosophy needs to keep pace with the times and adjust investment strategies according to changes in the environment.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<p>Question: Already answered in the video.</p>
</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Li Zi:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: To overcome psychological barriers to investment, manage accounts separately, using one part for long-term investment and the other for tentative operations, such as selling covered calls. This satisfies the desire to trade and avoids losses due to frequent trading.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo; Response: You only know what is best after you have experienced it. Experience in trading can lead to a firmer commitment to a long-term investment strategy. <strong>Trying different trading strategies can help you understand the advantages of long-term investment and ultimately achieve the state of &ldquo;daily reduction for the Dao.&rdquo;</strong></li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>T:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>Question 1: Why has the capital market in mainland China performed poorly for a long time?</p>
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo; Response: Emerging markets take time to mature. The Chinese market is like the Taiwanese market 50 years ago. It has the potential to rise in the long term, but its return may be lower than that of the US market. <strong>Investment should focus on sustainable development markets. The US market has advantages in terms of systems and industries.</strong></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p>Question 2: Under foreign exchange control, how do I invest in US index funds? Are there any risks?</p>
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo; Response: You can invest by purchasing ETFs listed in China that track US index funds, such as 513100. Foreign exchange controls mainly restrict the physical flow of funds, and buying ETFs is not restricted. The current scale of such investment is small and will not trigger a quota limit. <strong>Even with foreign exchange control, it is still possible to allocate global assets through legal channels.</strong></li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">IV. Key Takeaways 
    <div id="iv-key-takeaways" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv-key-takeaways" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>Wealth is a Gift
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>Everyone has the potential for wealth, but they must be informed to realize it and learn how to invest and manage their finances to achieve wealth growth.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Learning Increases Daily, the Dao Decreases Daily
&ndash; IM</p></blockquote>
<p>Learning about investing and financial management is a process of continuous improvement. At first, you will be exposed to a large amount of information, but as your understanding deepens, you will gradually simplify your investment strategy and eventually reach the state of &ldquo;the great Dao is simple.&rdquo;</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The Difficult to Return to After Seeing a Vast Ocean
&ndash; Li Zi &amp; James</p></blockquote>
<p>Only after experiencing something can you know what is best. In investing, only after actually operating and experiencing market fluctuations and the impact of different investment strategies can you more firmly choose the long-term investment strategy that suits you.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The More Money You Borrow, the More Money You Have
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>Understand and control risk, not avoid it. Understanding how to use leverage can accelerate wealth growth, but only with proper risk management, such as building a solid asset allocation.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Cash is Air
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>Cash is very important and you must keep enough cash to deal with market fluctuations and emergencies.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">V. Summary 
    <div id="v-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#v-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This live stream focused on the theme of &ldquo;Wealth is a gift.&rdquo; James explained the importance of investing and financial management, the advantages of index investing, the relationship between risk tolerance and investment returns, and how to conduct reasonable asset allocation in a simple and profound way. During the Q&amp;A session, students actively questioned their own issues and confusions. James patiently and meticulously answered them by combining practical cases and his own experience, helping the students better understand and master the knowledge and methods of investing and financial management. He also guided the students to overcome psychological barriers in investments, establish a firm long-term investment philosophy, and ultimately achieve financial freedom.</p>

  



<div
  
    class="flex px-4 py-3 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900"
  >

  <span
    
      class="text-primary-400 ltr:pr-3 rtl:pl-3 flex items-center"
    >

    

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M506.3 417l-213.3-364c-16.33-28-57.54-28-73.98 0l-213.2 364C-10.59 444.9 9.849 480 42.74 480h426.6C502.1 480 522.6 445 506.3 417zM232 168c0-13.25 10.75-24 24-24S280 154.8 280 168v128c0 13.25-10.75 24-23.1 24S232 309.3 232 296V168zM256 416c-17.36 0-31.44-14.08-31.44-31.44c0-17.36 14.07-31.44 31.44-31.44s31.44 14.08 31.44 31.44C287.4 401.9 273.4 416 256 416z"/></svg>

  </span>


  </span>

  <span
    
      class="dark:text-neutral-300"
    ><strong>Disclaimer:</strong> This article is a personal learning summary and does not constitute any investment advice.</span>
</div>

]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>00481 Asset Allocation Strategies to Avoid Market Pitfalls; How to Achieve Steady Wealth through Proper Investment Strategies</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1728285792652/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1728285792652/</guid><description>In this session, James emphasizes the crucial role of mental strength in investment success. He discusses asset allocation, the use and rebalancing of leveraged ETFs, provides supplementary explanations of 401(k) and IRA accounts, and touches upon choosing the right brokerage. The Q&amp;amp;A session addresses audience questions concerning investing with mortgage loans, market crash risks, the risks associated with single brokerage accounts, and how to cope with the psychological pressure stemming from market fluctuations. Furthermore, the discussion includes insights on investment target selection, the purpose of holding cash, and life planning.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<lite-youtube videoid="ZvTM4--CaKw" playlabel="ZvTM4--CaKw" params=""></lite-youtube>



<h2 class="relative group">I. Main Theme 
    <div id="i-main-theme" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-main-theme" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This session centers around the importance of psychological resilience in investing. James&rsquo;s core message is that mental strength is the key to investment success, while other skills and calculations are secondary. Investors need to maintain a highly optimistic mindset, viewing market fluctuations as opportunities rather than crises in the long run. Long-term investing, rational analysis, and maintaining a healthy mindset are more crucial than striving for precise calculations.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">II. Briefing Content 
    <div id="ii-briefing-content" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii-briefing-content" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<ul>
<li><strong>Correction on 401(k) and IRA:</strong> James corrects a statement from the previous session regarding 401(k) and IRA contribution limits, clarifying that the limits for each are independent, but that IRAs have income restrictions. He provides further explanations about the Backdoor Roth IRA conversion, advising listeners to manage pre-tax and after-tax funds carefully to avoid account confusion and complications during tax filing.</li>
<li><strong>Asset Allocation Strategy:</strong> He emphasizes the significance of asset allocation and suggests listeners refer to existing articles and Excel spreadsheets for simulations, discouraging impulsive decision-making. He offers various asset allocation plans catering to different risk tolerances and retirement stages, stressing the concept of &ldquo;fuzzy accuracy&rdquo; – that it is not necessary to pursue overly precise ratios, but ensuring sufficient cash reserves is crucial. Example: A listener proposes an allocation of 60% QQQ and 40% cash, which James believes carries a risk of bankruptcy and advises them to consult the provided asset allocation plans.</li>
<li><strong>Leveraged ETFs and Rebalancing:</strong> Using QQQ&rsquo;s beta value of 1.0 as a benchmark, he simplifies beta calculations for leveraged ETFs, for instance, QLD is considered 2.0. He recommends a gradual approach when adjusting beta during rebalancing, advising against drastic changes. For investors with earned income, the frequency and ratio of rebalancing can be more flexible. Example: He suggests that young investors can rotate investments among QQQ, QLD, and TQQQ every six months, then rebalance at the end of the year.</li>
<li><strong>Long-Term Investing and Market Volatility:</strong> James reiterates the importance of long-term investing, using the dot-com bubble of 2000 as an example to demonstrate that long-term investors ultimately profit, even after enduring prolonged market downturns. Market dips are opportunities, and investors should remain optimistic, buying whenever they have funds available. He refutes the notion that &ldquo;investments in 2000 took 15 years to break even,&rdquo; emphasizing that the market always recovers in the long run. Example: An investment of $5 million at the peak of the market in 2000, despite experiencing the burst of the internet bubble, would still have grown to $32.375 million by 2024.</li>
<li><strong>Brokerage Selection:</strong> He advises choosing brokerages with physical branch offices and understanding how stocks and cash are held in custody to ensure asset security. Example: He explains the risks of nominee accounts and recommends selecting brokerages that allow for direct ownership of stocks, encouraging listeners to inquire about the brokerage&rsquo;s custodian banks for stocks and cash.</li>
<li><strong>Purpose of Holding Cash:</strong> He underlines that cash holdings are meant for emergencies and to seize buying opportunities during market downturns, not for pursuing interest income. Example: He suggests maintaining a 20% cash position, a portion of which can be utilized for adding to leveraged ETFs during dips.</li>
<li><strong>Investment Target Selection:</strong> He recommends selecting suitable investment targets based on individual circumstances. For instance, retirees or individuals with limited funds may consider high-dividend ETFs, while younger individuals or those with ample funds should focus on growth-oriented ETFs like QQQ. Example: Addressing a listener holding SCH, James advises them to assess whether high-dividend ETFs are appropriate based on their asset level and annual expenses.</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">III. Q&amp;A Session 
    <div id="iii-qa-session" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii-qa-session" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p><strong>Danny:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Shares: He has been following James&rsquo;s investment strategy for three years and achieved a return of approximately 35%.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Chang&rsquo;an:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Question: Brokerage security and recommendations in Hong Kong.</li>
<li>James&rsquo;s Response: Choose brokerages with physical branch offices in the region, understand the custodian banks for stocks and cash, and avoid easily dissolved online brokerages.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Eric:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Shares: He began investing during the pandemic, experienced the hardships of short-term trading, and eventually recognized the importance of long-term investing and psychological control. He uses the example of Jesse Livermore to illustrate the risks of trading.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Jessie:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Shares: Both she and her husband are nearing 60 years old, and a portion of their investment funds comes from a mortgage loan. She expresses concerns about a potential market crash and the risk of USD devaluation.</li>
<li>Questions:</li>
</ul>
<ol>
<li>How to cope with a possible future market crash, especially with a mortgage due before retirement?</li>
<li>What about USD devaluation?</li>
<li>Are there risks associated with concentrating large sums of money in a single brokerage account?</li>
<li>Is it feasible to refinance the mortgage in five years or repay it early with funds from the investment account?</li>
</ol>
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Response:</li>
</ul>
<ol>
<li>The market is unlikely to experience losses within a 15-year timeframe. Ensure you can comfortably handle mortgage payments for the next 13 years; the most secure approach is to sell the house and repay the loan.</li>
<li>He declines to answer hypothetical questions.</li>
<li>Stocks are registered under the investor&rsquo;s name, hence the risk of brokerage failure is manageable.</li>
<li>Refinancing or early repayment is not recommended. Excessive focus on short-term interest gains is akin to &ldquo;penny wise, pound foolish,&rdquo; and ultimately increases risk.</li>
</ol>
<p><strong>Sam:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Shares: He went all-in on QQQ, but after some short-term trading, realized it wasn&rsquo;t suitable for him and experienced psychological pressure due to large position fluctuations.</li>
<li>Question: How to overcome the psychological pressure brought about by fluctuations in a large portfolio?</li>
<li>James&rsquo;s Response:</li>
</ul>
<ol>
<li>Focus on realized gains rather than unrealized gains.</li>
<li>Maintain 20% cash and 20% leveraged ETFs to stabilize your mindset.</li>
<li>Exercise caution with short-term trading, as it may not be sustainable in the long run.</li>
</ol>
<p><strong>Haoqing:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Shares: He uses examples of friends gambling and raising children to illustrate the importance of moderate expectations and nurturing interests. He compares and contrasts education philosophies and Nobel Prize achievements between China and the US, emphasizing the significance of financial freedom for the next generation.</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">IV. Highlights 
    <div id="iv-highlights" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv-highlights" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>Mental fortitude is the equipment for investing, it determines whether you will succeed.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>Investment skills and calculations are undoubtedly important, but psychological resilience is the ultimate factor that decides investment success. Even for simple index fund investing, a sound mental state is needed to navigate market volatility.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>A market downturn is not a disaster, it&rsquo;s an opportunity.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>From a long-term investment perspective, market downturns provide excellent opportunities to acquire high-quality assets.  Maintain a long-term outlook and don&rsquo;t be intimidated by short-term fluctuations.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>There should be a limit to human pessimism.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>Excessive pessimism and worry are detrimental to investments. One should rationally analyze risks and develop sensible coping strategies. Do not let extreme scenarios or low-probability events unduly influence investment decisions.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Parents sometimes have these expectations for their children, don&rsquo;t impose your unfulfilled aspirations on them.
&ndash; Haoqing</p></blockquote>
<p>Parents should respect their children&rsquo;s individuality and interests and refrain from forcing their own unaccomplished goals onto them. Allowing children to have a joyful childhood and the autonomy to choose their own paths in life is more important than chasing conventional success.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">V. Summary 
    <div id="v-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#v-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>In this session, James reiterates the importance of mental fortitude in investing and the effectiveness of long-term investment and asset allocation strategies. By addressing listeners&rsquo; practical concerns, such as retirement planning, market volatility, and capital security, he helps them better understand and apply these investment principles. James also provides advice on choosing appropriate investment targets and the purpose of holding cash, aiding listeners in constructing more comprehensive investment strategies. Haoqing&rsquo;s sharing sparked reflection on educational philosophies and life values, advocating for a focus on children&rsquo;s overall development and mental well-being.</p>

  



<div
  
    class="flex px-4 py-3 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900"
  >

  <span
    
      class="text-primary-400 ltr:pr-3 rtl:pl-3 flex items-center"
    >

    

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M506.3 417l-213.3-364c-16.33-28-57.54-28-73.98 0l-213.2 364C-10.59 444.9 9.849 480 42.74 480h426.6C502.1 480 522.6 445 506.3 417zM232 168c0-13.25 10.75-24 24-24S280 154.8 280 168v128c0 13.25-10.75 24-23.1 24S232 309.3 232 296V168zM256 416c-17.36 0-31.44-14.08-31.44-31.44c0-17.36 14.07-31.44 31.44-31.44s31.44 14.08 31.44 31.44C287.4 401.9 273.4 416 256 416z"/></svg>

  </span>


  </span>

  <span
    
      class="dark:text-neutral-300"
    ><strong>Disclaimer:</strong> This document is only for personal learning and note-taking purposes and does not constitute any investment advice.</span>
</div>

]]></content:encoded></item></channel></rss>