<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Wealth on QQQ Investor</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/tags/wealth/</link><description>Recent content in Wealth on QQQ Investor</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jomonylw.github.io/en/tags/wealth/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Personal Investment Bible - Investment Iron Law XIII</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1731056005972/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1731056005972/</guid><description>This article explores the key to financial success, emphasizing that taking action is more important than knowledge. Through several stories, it illustrates that even with financial knowledge, wealth growth cannot be achieved without action. The article encourages readers to overcome fear, dare to try, start with small investments, and learn from failures to ultimately achieve financial freedom.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[

<h2 class="relative group">Investment Iron Law XIII: Act Now 
    <div id="investment-iron-law-xiii-act-now" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#investment-iron-law-xiii-act-now" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>Those who require a fully justified reason for every action are never practitioners.</p>
</blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">Taking Action is Better Than Just Researching 
    <div id="taking-action-is-better-than-just-researching" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#taking-action-is-better-than-just-researching" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>A group of friends worked hard from sunrise to sunset, but their income remained meager.  They envied others who invested in stocks, real estate, or other ventures and became wealthy. They lamented, &ldquo;We toil all day, earning so little, while those investors make easy money.&rdquo;  Finally, they decided to seek guidance from an investment guru.</p>
<p><strong>Knowledge Without Action is Useless</strong></p>
<p>Touched by their sincerity, the guru agreed to teach them. The first lesson was &ldquo;Investment Principles,&rdquo; covering compound interest, returns, and risk management. The second lesson was &ldquo;Investment Practice,&rdquo; where the guru demonstrated how to invest in stocks, real estate, and other assets.  He then asked, &ldquo;Do you understand?&rdquo; They all replied, &ldquo;Yes!&rdquo; The guru said, &ldquo;Congratulations, you&rsquo;ve graduated!&rdquo;  The group rejoiced and returned to their jobs.</p>
<p>Decades later, at a reunion, they complained, &ldquo;Is there any way to make good money? Why do we always have to work so hard?&rdquo; They revisited the guru, who asked, &ldquo;Where did you put your earnings?&rdquo;  They answered, &ldquo;In bank savings accounts.&rdquo;</p>
<p>This story illustrates that education can change thinking but not necessarily behavior. <strong>Possessing knowledge and wisdom without action is no different from lacking them; you&rsquo;ll still rely on physical labor and skills for a living.</strong>  Wisdom without action is useless; one must be willing to act.</p>
<p>A survey of wealthy Americans revealed that one of their key traits is &ldquo;proactive action.&rdquo; In other words, financial success depends on what we do, not what we know.</p>
<p>Investment professors sometimes face student skepticism: &ldquo;If you know so much, why aren&rsquo;t you rich from investing?&rdquo;  A common response is, &ldquo;A teacher&rsquo;s duty is to impart knowledge, not necessarily to practice it. Just like the best coach isn&rsquo;t always the best athlete.&rdquo;</p>
<p>I often ponder this: Many teachers desire wealth.  Wealth accumulation and educating the next generation aren&rsquo;t mutually exclusive.  Why don&rsquo;t most investment professors, armed with financial knowledge, become wealthy?</p>
<p>Another common question is: &ldquo;Some uneducated, idle speculators get rich through investing without ever taking an investment course. How?&rdquo; The difference between professors and these speculators is simple: some professors know but don&rsquo;t act, while speculators act but don&rsquo;t necessarily know.  Financial knowledge alone doesn&rsquo;t guarantee wealth; action is key.</p>
<p><strong>Action is the Key to Investment Success</strong></p>
<p>Can investment skills be taught? No.  True skill comes from practice.  I often compare investing to ice skating, swimming, or cycling.  Can reading books on &ldquo;How to Ice Skate&rdquo; make you a skater? The best teacher is experience – falling hundreds of times, getting back up, and persevering.</p>
<p>Fear is the biggest obstacle to learning about investing.  A student once asked, &ldquo;What if I lose all my money before I learn how to invest?&rdquo;  I countered, &ldquo;Did you study fluid dynamics before learning to ride a bike, fearing you&rsquo;d crash before mastering it?&rdquo; Investors must understand that even extensive reading won&rsquo;t prevent losses; just like a perfect score in fluid dynamics doesn&rsquo;t guarantee perfect cycling.</p>
<p>Practice and experience are essential for practical skills.  Investing can&rsquo;t be taught. The key is to step away from books, enter the market, experiment, make mistakes, and learn from them.  Start small with a limited amount of money.</p>
<p>Achieving wealth through investing involves two stages: 1) acquiring correct investment knowledge, and 2) continuous practice and action. Both are essential.  Reading this book and understanding the principles is just the first step.</p>
<p><strong>Knowledge Becomes Power Through Action</strong></p>
<p>Knowledge is potential power.  Only through absorption, internalization, and action does it become real power.  &ldquo;Knowledge is power&rdquo; needs amending.</p>
<p>Correct understanding alone is insufficient.  Achieving wealth requires consistent action and practice. Otherwise, knowledge remains theoretical.  Investing is a skill honed through constant practice, like entrepreneur Wang Yung-ching, who continued massive investments in his 70s.</p>
<p><strong>We instinctively avoid risk; it&rsquo;s uncomfortable.  But investing for wealth requires calculated risks, learned through experience.</strong> Dear reader, action is paramount. Initial fear and anxiety are natural. The best way to overcome them is to act.</p>
<p><em>1. Those who put ideas and methods into action possess a competitive edge and grasp the opportunity for success.</em></p>
<p><em>2. In today&rsquo;s knowledge-rich world, the biggest obstacle to success is not knowing what to do, but doing what we know.</em></p>
<p><em>3. Many excel at thinking, analyzing, and identifying opportunities, but few act upon them.</em></p>
<p><strong>A Farmer Outperforms Market Veterans</strong></p>
<p>In early 1996, amid cross-strait tensions, Taiwan&rsquo;s stock market slumped. A farmer walked into a brokerage, placed a bag of cash (around 3-4 million NTD) on the counter, and said, &ldquo;I want to buy San Shang Yin.&rdquo;</p>
<p>The clerk, baffled, asked for his account number, which stock he wanted (San Shang Yin refers to three different bank stocks), and his desired price. He knew none of this, saying only, &ldquo;My friend said San Shang Yin is good. Here&rsquo;s the money.&rdquo;</p>
<p>The clerk explained the situation, helped him open an account, and bought 10 shares of each bank stock at around 90 NTD. Two months later, the prices rose to 160 NTD.</p>
<p>This farmer, lacking knowledge but daring to act, profited.  Meanwhile, market experts who thoroughly analyzed San Shang Yin missed out because they hesitated to act.</p>
<p>Does knowledge or action bring wealth? The farmer&rsquo;s lack of knowledge might have been his advantage, while overthinking paralyzed the experts. How much do analysis and knowledge truly contribute to wealth creation? It&rsquo;s worth pondering.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Active action makes dreams come true.  A strong desire for wealth fuels action.</p>
</blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">Your Future Wealth is in Your Hands 
    <div id="your-future-wealth-is-in-your-hands" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#your-future-wealth-is-in-your-hands" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>Many attendees at my seminars nod in agreement but fail to act. Remember, action, not knowledge, determines your future.  This book is useless unless you act upon it.</p>
<p><strong>Dreams Alone Won&rsquo;t Make You Rich</strong></p>
<p>Many dream of wealth, but few succeed.  It&rsquo;s not luck or intelligence, but the unity of thought and action. Success and wealth are earned through planning, action, and consistent effort.</p>
<p>For most, wealth is a fantasy. They think and talk, but don&rsquo;t act. Some lack the know-how, which is understandable.  Sadly, others know but don&rsquo;t act.  &ldquo;Knowing and not doing is not knowing.&rdquo;  Wealth won&rsquo;t come to those who only dream or accumulate knowledge without action.  People attribute wealth to luck, but does luck favor those dreaming at home or those actively seeking opportunities?</p>
<p>Reading this book won&rsquo;t magically make you rich.  Financial success depends on what we do.  We&rsquo;ve all seen seemingly unintelligent, not particularly hard-working, or frugal people who are wealthy.</p>
<p>The difference between self-made millionaires and us isn&rsquo;t intellect, effort, frugality, or knowledge, but where our money is placed.  They invest in high-return assets, while we often settle for low returns.  Most make excuses: not enough money, time, knowledge, or opportunity, or blaming age.  These are merely excuses preventing wealth accumulation.</p>
<p><em>1. The principles of financial management are simple; the difficulty lies in overcoming fear, greed, and laziness to do what we know we should.</em></p>
<p><em>2. Investing is an art and a science, but more art.  The best way to learn is by doing.</em></p>
<p><em>3. Without putting money to work, you&rsquo;ll rely on physical labor and skills your entire life.</em></p>
<p><strong>The First Step: Open a Brokerage Account and Buy Stocks</strong></p>
<p>An elderly British writer lamented, &ldquo;I&rsquo;ve seen many talented young people remain obscure, their potential unfulfilled because they lacked the courage to try.  Guidance and encouragement to take risks could have unleashed their talents and benefited society.&rdquo;</p>
<p>Over 13% of seniors in Taiwan rely on continued work or family support.  Many ended up this way because they didn&rsquo;t invest in risky assets like stocks or real estate in their youth.  Had they been guided to invest wisely, they could be enjoying retirement, reducing social inequality and promoting harmony.</p>
<p>Inspired by this writer, I now encourage my students to open brokerage accounts and buy stocks (or closed-end funds if unsure) on the first day of my investment courses.  I advise them to hold long-term, regardless of price fluctuations, aiming for practical experience over theoretical knowledge.</p>
<p><strong>Paying for Experience</strong></p>
<p>In 1983, while pursuing my PhD at UC Berkeley, a Wall Street analyst lectured at the university.  I asked him for book recommendations on stock investing.  He advised, &ldquo;The best way to learn is to invest. You&rsquo;ll learn more from one real investment than from several books.&rdquo; I followed his advice, lost money, and learned valuable lessons that shaped my future investment approach.</p>
<p>Financial management can&rsquo;t be learned solely in the classroom. Can attending ten lectures on swimming theory and reading ten books on &ldquo;Swimming Secrets&rdquo; make you a swimmer?  The first step is to get in the water.  Taiwan&rsquo;s education system overemphasizes book learning and neglects practical experience.</p>
<p>What&rsquo;s the first step in learning to invest?  Some suggest reading books, subscribing to financial magazines, or taking courses.  My advice: after reading this book, invest a small amount in stocks or mutual funds (especially index funds) if unsure.</p>
<p>Mutual funds offer diversification and professional management, generally performing close to market averages, minimizing potential losses and discouraging fear.</p>
<p>Outperforming mutual funds through individual stock picking is challenging.  Fund managers have experience, expertise, and research teams.  Consider mutual funds, especially index funds like CTBC Harmony Fund or China 100 Fund, in the initial stages.  &ldquo;Beating the index&rdquo; is every fund manager&rsquo;s dream, but most admit it&rsquo;s incredibly difficult.  If so, mirroring the market through index funds is a viable strategy.</p>
<p><strong>If you have savings and don&rsquo;t own property, consider buying a home as your first investment.</strong></p>
<blockquote>
<p>We learn more from failure than from success.  Success is built upon countless failures.</p>
</blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">Learning from Mistakes 
    <div id="learning-from-mistakes" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#learning-from-mistakes" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>Successful American investors share two traits: 1) they don&rsquo;t strive for perfection, and 2) they don&rsquo;t dwell on failures, focusing instead on future challenges.  High returns come with high risks.  Failure is inevitable and part of the learning process. Most successful investors have experienced multiple failures.</p>
<p><strong>No Success Without Failure</strong></p>
<p>Anyone claiming to have never lost money in investing is either lying or has never invested.  It&rsquo;s like a baseball player claiming to have never missed a swing.  Even the best hitters don&rsquo;t have a 100% batting average.</p>
<p>A top baseball player once attributed his success to &ldquo;missing more swings than others.&rdquo; To achieve a high batting average, he must have swung and missed more times than others.  Biographies of successful people often reveal that they&rsquo;ve experienced more failures than those less successful.  Failure is the mother of success, especially in investing.</p>
<p>Aspiring investors must withstand losses.  <strong>Those who haven&rsquo;t failed can&rsquo;t achieve greatness; those who haven&rsquo;t experienced losses can&rsquo;t expect to make a fortune.</strong>  Demanding a perfect track record leads to extreme conservatism and eliminates opportunities for success.</p>
<p><strong>The biggest failure is to never fail.</strong>  Avoiding mistakes eliminates chances for success. The best path to success is through failure and learning from it.  Never forget your losses; they are the keys to victory.  Successful investors analyze failures, learn from them, and improve their strategies.</p>
<p><strong>Reflect and Restart</strong></p>
<p>My failures have led to reflection, reassessment, and improved investment strategies.  Most failures bring unexpected benefits.  Treat failure as a necessary lesson, and your courage will grow.</p>
<p>Failure can&rsquo;t be learned secondhand.  You won&rsquo;t find books on &ldquo;How to Lose 10 Million in Investments.&rdquo;  People brag about successes, not failures.  Therefore, lessons from failure must come from personal experience.</p>
<p>Everyone makes mistakes in investing.  Even correct decisions can lead to losses.  Since losses and failures are inevitable, accepting them and learning from them is crucial.  Failure is not shameful or terrifying.  Face it, overcome it, and success will follow.</p>
<p><em>1. Take calculated risks for high rewards, be prepared for losses, and avoid undue self-blame.</em></p>
<p><em>2. Learn from every failure, identify flawed decision-making habits, and avoid repeating them.</em></p>
<p><em>3. Study valuable lessons from failures and discover opportunities for wealth creation.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Personal Investment Bible: Investment Iron Law V</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1731056005964/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1731056005964/</guid><description>This article explores the relationship between risk and return in investment and financial management, emphasizing the importance of risk management. It points out that all high-return investments come with high risks, and while risk aversion is human nature, excessive risk aversion can lead to missed opportunities. Using Forbes&amp;#39; philosophy on risk as an example, the author illustrates how to assess risks and rewards, advocating for calculated risks with adequate preparation. The article also cautions readers against being seduced by high-risk, low-return speculative activities, encouraging them to start with small investments to gain experience, gradually overcome their fear of risk, and ultimately master risk to achieve wealth growth.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[

<h2 class="relative group">Investment Iron Law V: Mitigating Investment Risk 
    <div id="investment-iron-law-v-mitigating-investment-risk" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#investment-iron-law-v-mitigating-investment-risk" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>Investment and financial management should never prioritize returns while neglecting risks.</p>
</blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">Analyzing Risk, Minimizing Damage 
    <div id="analyzing-risk-minimizing-damage" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#analyzing-risk-minimizing-damage" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>In 1987, while working at Merrill Lynch in the United States, I met a seasoned investment veteran with decades of Wall Street experience. He once said, &ldquo;I can teach you how to pick stocks in an hour, but it would take me more than five years to teach you how to manage investment risk.&rdquo;</p>
<p><strong>Risk is Unavoidable</strong></p>
<p>In the ever-changing and unpredictable world of investment, uncertainties abound. We call these uncertainties risks. How you face these risks when they materialize is a question every investor must confront. <strong>Risk is called risk precisely because future outcomes are uncertain and unavoidable.</strong> Therefore, investment and financial management should never solely focus on returns while ignoring risks. In fact, managing risk is even more crucial. <strong>The purpose of risk management is not to eliminate risk entirely, but to acknowledge its inherent existence and impossibility of complete eradication.  It&rsquo;s about analyzing risk and subsequently mitigating it.</strong></p>
<p>While engaging in risk management, investors must understand that &ldquo;you can never be fully prepared for every risk.&rdquo;  You can strive to reduce risk, but don&rsquo;t attempt to eliminate it completely. Many try to avoid risk through predictions or expert advice.  However, no matter how accurate your forecasting techniques or how insightful the expert predictions, risk can never be fully avoided. <strong>The greatest danger of predictions is not their frequent inaccuracy, but the tendency for investors to blindly trust them, losing their risk awareness. They focus solely on whether the prediction comes true, neglecting the potential magnitude of the underlying risks.</strong>  Relying solely on predictions without thorough risk analysis is extremely dangerous. Any sound investment decision inherently involves unknowns, uncertainties, and risks.  Furthermore, investments without uncertainties and a degree of risk are unlikely to be good investments.</p>
<p><strong>All High-Return Investments Carry High Risks</strong></p>
<p>The key to successful investment and financial management lies in learning to grasp high returns while effectively managing the accompanying risks.</p>
<p>The investment environment is constantly changing and unpredictable. The only constant is change. Some external factors (such as interest rates, exchange rates, economic conditions, and inflation rates) are bound to change, although the nature of these changes remains unknown.  Additionally, unforeseen events (such as wars, political events, and natural disasters) are uncontrollable variables.  To succeed in this volatile investment world, the most important thing is not to lament change but to accept it as inevitable. <strong>Prepare for various changes and even anticipate them, because only through change can wealth be redistributed.</strong> Change is both a threat and an opportunity, depending on how you respond.  Skilled investors often find profitable opportunities amidst change.</p>
<p>People often assume investors love risk.  This is not true.  Successful investors possess a unique ability to manage risk. They don&rsquo;t see &ldquo;risk-taking&rdquo; as a source of amusement, nor do they find the act of taking risks thrilling or exciting. They take risks solely for the potential of high investment returns.  Since all high-return investments inherently carry high risks, risk-taking is an unavoidable part of the journey to financial success.</p>
<p>Many perceive stock investment as extremely risky, believing stock investors to be risk-seekers. In reality, investing in stocks is not about loving the risk associated with stocks. It&rsquo;s about understanding that all high-return investments carry high risks. To build wealth, you must take the risk of investing in high-return assets and bear the associated risks.  Savvy investors understand how to take calculated risks and mitigate them.  In fact, if risk mitigation measures are implemented effectively, the actual risks of investment and financial management are relatively small.</p>
<p><strong>Stocks and real estate offer high returns precisely because of their inherent volatility and risk.</strong> Because most people are risk-averse and avoid investing in risky assets like stocks and real estate, those who can tolerate risk are better positioned to reap higher returns.</p>
<p>Many shy away from stocks and real estate primarily because they fear losses, are intimidated by future uncertainties, or can&rsquo;t handle price fluctuations. <strong>In fact, short-term price fluctuations are perfectly normal and highlight the high-risk nature of high-return investments.</strong> Therefore, to achieve high returns, one must possess a spirit of adventure and be able to withstand significant volatility.</p>
<p><em>1. Unpredictable risks allow risk-takers to earn a risk premium.</em></p>
<p><em>2. We miss opportunities because we are afraid to take risks, not because the world doesn&rsquo;t offer them.</em></p>
<p><em>3. To achieve financial success through investment, you must take risks, because high returns always come with high risks.</em></p>
<blockquote>
<p>I dislike taking unnecessary risks, so before every activity, I do my best to take necessary precautions to mitigate risk.</p>
</blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">The Forbes Philosophy on Risk 
    <div id="the-forbes-philosophy-on-risk" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#the-forbes-philosophy-on-risk" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>Malcolm Forbes was a legendary figure in the American business world.  He amassed a fortune by founding Forbes magazine, possessed a priceless collection, and was listed among the 400 wealthiest Americans. He not only ran a high-risk magazine business but was also a renowned hot air balloonist and motorcycle enthusiast.  He once rode a motorcycle across Eurasia from Paris to Beijing.  He traveled the world, flying hot air balloons across the United States, and even ventured to Turkey and China, setting multiple world records and attracting widespread media attention, making him a household name.</p>
<p><strong>Averting Danger Before it Happens, Ensuring Safety</strong></p>
<p>Some labeled him an &ldquo;adventurer.&rdquo;  He offered an insightful explanation of this label, saying, &ldquo;Many people think I&rsquo;m a risk-lover.  I&rsquo;m not. Like most people, I strongly dislike risk. The reason I take risks today, despite my aversion to them, is simple: all good things in life come with risks. I take risks purely to live a rich and fulfilling life.”  &ldquo;Riding in a hot air balloon or on a motorcycle across different lands broadens one&rsquo;s horizons and exposes one to the world&rsquo;s beauty, enriching life. However, many people, despite yearning for these experiences, hesitate to engage in them because they perceive them as high-risk activities. But, once you actually try them, you&rsquo;ll find that if you take adequate precautions beforehand, the risks involved are quite small.” &ldquo;I dislike taking unnecessary risks, so before every activity, I strive to take the necessary preventative measures to mitigate risk.&rdquo;</p>
<p>Malcolm Forbes was risk-averse, but he took risks to experience the good things in life, and after taking those risks, he sought ways to mitigate them.</p>
<p><strong>Assess the Rewards and Risks, If It&rsquo;s Worth It – Take the Risk</strong></p>
<p>Are you afraid of taking risks? If so, you are not alone.  Most people are afraid of taking risks; very few are natural risk-takers.  But why are some people so composed in the face of risk, and even achieve success through it?  It&rsquo;s because they understand the principles of &ldquo;nothing ventured, nothing gained&rdquo; and &ldquo;no high risk, no high return.&rdquo;  Indeed, the correct perspective on risk should be: take risks worth taking, and then find ways to mitigate them.</p>
<p>Successful investors are driven by the pursuit of &ldquo;wealth.&rdquo; Although they must be prepared to withstand the pressure of price fluctuations, as long as the expected return is high and there&rsquo;s a risk premium, risk-taking will ultimately lead to success.</p>
<p>Before every investment, it&rsquo;s essential to understand the potential risks and develop contingency plans for every possible scenario. Analyze the degree of blind risk-taking, estimate the probability of success, and continuously re-evaluate throughout the process. I recommend investors create a risk-reward assessment table before making any investment, weighing all factors.  Ask yourself, &ldquo;Can I bear the consequences if the worst-case scenario unfolds?&rdquo; and &ldquo;Is the potential return of this investment attractive enough?&rdquo;</p>
<p>Always plan for the worst and prepare for the best. This is especially true for investment and financial management.  <strong>Before making any investment, no matter how confident you are, you should ask yourself, &ldquo;What is the worst possible outcome?&rdquo; Then ask, &ldquo;Can I bear the consequences if the worst happens?&rdquo; If the answer to both questions is yes, and the expected return is high enough, then you should invest. If the worst-case scenario is unbearable, then no matter how alluring the potential reward, you should categorically refuse to invest.</strong></p>
<p><strong>Don&rsquo;t Take Unnecessary Risks</strong></p>
<p>If you ever visit Las Vegas or Atlantic City, observe the lavishly decorated casinos carefully. You&rsquo;ll notice the absence of clocks and windows, and the ever-present bright lights.  &ldquo;There&rsquo;s no time in the mountains, and no time in casinos.&rdquo; Why are there no clocks or windows in casinos?  It&rsquo;s because casinos leverage the law of large numbers to win your money.  The lack of clocks and windows is designed to blur the lines between day and night, encouraging gamblers to play endlessly until they lose track of time. The longer you play, the more times you play, the higher the probability of the casino winning.  As the number of games increases, the expected value gradually reveals itself.  Gambling inevitably leads to losses because its expected value is negative.  This might not be apparent in a few instances, but over time, the expected value becomes increasingly evident. Therefore, prolonged gambling inevitably leads to losses.  This explains the saying &ldquo;nine out of ten gamblers lose&rdquo; and &ldquo;long-term gambling leads to certain loss,&rdquo; which aligns perfectly with the principle of the law of large numbers. The law of large numbers states that the more times a game is played, the closer the return gets to the expected value of that game.</p>
<p>I had a classmate in the doctoral program at UC Berkeley who excelled in mathematics and frequented Las Vegas casinos on weekends.  Curious, I asked him, &ldquo;You&rsquo;re so smart and you know that gambling is designed against the players. Are you trying to win money?&rdquo;  He replied, &ldquo;I never go there to win money. I gamble to relieve stress.&rdquo;  He explained that after a heartbreak in college, he tried various methods to cope, such as drinking, speeding, and traveling, but none were effective.  He eventually found that only gambling could allow him to truly escape. Gambling can be a form of entertainment, but it&rsquo;s certainly not a way to make money. Its expected average return is lower than bank deposits, making it impossible to build wealth through such activities.</p>
<p>Many people hold the misconception that &ldquo;high risk always equates to high return.&rdquo; This misunderstanding stems from a misinterpretation of the definition of &ldquo;return.&rdquo; High risk might indeed offer high potential returns, but this represents the maximum possible return, which has a very low probability.  However, in the context of &ldquo;high risk, high return,&rdquo; the &ldquo;return&rdquo; refers to the expected return (long-term average return), not the maximum possible return.  Indeed, gambling boasts incredibly high maximum potential returns, but its average, or expected, return is negative. Taking such risks is not only unprofitable but also detrimental.</p>
<p><strong>There are No High-Return, Zero-Risk Investments</strong></p>
<p>Success requires risk-taking, but risk-taking doesn&rsquo;t guarantee success.  One must take calculated risks. A calculated risk is one that, on average, offers high returns over the long term.</p>
<p>Some people&rsquo;s problem isn&rsquo;t a lack of risk-taking spirit but a tendency to take unnecessary risks. They don&rsquo;t know what risks to take to achieve financial success. As detailed in previous chapters, the cornerstone of investment success is the power of compounding, which only works effectively with high returns.  Over the long term, stocks and real estate are asset classes that offer high expected returns.  Therefore, taking calculated risks means investing in assets with high expected returns and bravely bearing the associated risks.</p>
<p>Consider a game where participants must pay $100. There&rsquo;s a 99.9% chance of losing $100 and a 0.1% chance of winning $95,000. Would you play?  In a survey I conducted with hundreds of students, over 65% chose to play this high-risk game.  Their reasoning was simple: while the risk was high, the potential loss was capped at $100, while the potential gain was a whopping $95,000.  However, the expected return of this game is negative.  Even if you get lucky and win once, in the long run, you&rsquo;re bound to lose.  This is a classic example of a risk not worth taking.</p>
<p>Avoid risks that don&rsquo;t offer high returns. Activities like futures trading, margin trading in foreign exchange and bonds, lotteries, and short-term stock trading all carry high risks and often have negative returns.  In other words, these are high-risk, negative-return activities.  You can engage in these activities for entertainment, but never delude yourself into believing they will bring you wealth.</p>
<p><strong>There are no high-return, zero-risk investment opportunities.</strong> In a society filled with intelligent individuals, such opportunities are impossible. If someone offers you a high-return, risk-free investment opportunity, they are undoubtedly trying to scam you.</p>
<p>I remind readers again: don&rsquo;t blindly chase high returns and jump into risky ventures.  Speculative activities like those mentioned above are not truly high-return investment tools, but they are definitely high-risk endeavors.  These risks are not worth taking.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Absolute safety is a myth. The real danger is not taking any risks. In a volatile environment, the biggest risk is not taking any risks.</p>
</blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">Don&rsquo;t Shy Away from Risk Entirely 
    <div id="dont-shy-away-from-risk-entirely" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#dont-shy-away-from-risk-entirely" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>The future world is changing rapidly.  Changes will accelerate across all aspects of business, economics, finance, politics, and society, creating a more complex financial landscape.  <strong>It&rsquo;s foreseeable that wealth redistribution will also accelerate.</strong> Risk aversion is human nature.  In the past, you could live a stable life without taking risks.  However, <strong>in the face of the volatile investment environment of the future, not taking risks becomes the biggest risk of all.</strong></p>
<p><strong>Fear of Falling Will Keep You from Running Fast</strong></p>
<p>Fear of risk prevents many from investing, causing them to miss out on the opportunity to build wealth.  Keeping money in a bank seems safe and risk-free. However, as previously analyzed, inflation severely erodes the real value of money.  From a financial management perspective, keeping money in a bank carries the greatest risk.  Decades later, when those around you who invested wisely become millionaires, those who kept their money in banks may face financial hardship.  My point is: don&rsquo;t shy away from risk entirely. Risk isn&rsquo;t as terrifying as it seems.  Taking calculated risks with high potential returns is absolutely worthwhile.</p>
<p>I&rsquo;m often asked, &ldquo;Teacher, will the stock market fall again?&rdquo; My answer is, &ldquo;I don&rsquo;t know.&rdquo;  Then they ask, &ldquo;When will it start rising?&rdquo; My answer remains, &ldquo;I don&rsquo;t know.&rdquo;  They further inquire, &ldquo;Which stock should I buy?  Can you give me a hot tip?&rdquo; My answer is still, &ldquo;I don&rsquo;t know.&rdquo;  Then they question skeptically, &ldquo;How can you invest when you don&rsquo;t know anything? Isn&rsquo;t that too risky?&rdquo; My response is, &ldquo;You must invest and manage your finances without knowing the answers to these questions to succeed.&rdquo;</p>
<p>Why invest when the answers are unknown and the future is uncertain? The reason is simple: While the future is full of risks, one thing is certain: as long as the economy continues to grow and corporate profitability rises, the long-term return on investment in the stock market will inevitably surpass bank deposits, and by a significant margin.  Repeatedly avoiding worthwhile risks will prevent you from building wealth.</p>
<p><strong>How to Cultivate a Risk-Taking Spirit</strong></p>
<p><em>A courageous risk-taker is not someone without fear, but someone with the power to overcome it.</em></p>
<p>The spirit of adventure isn&rsquo;t innate; it&rsquo;s developed through practice, through taking risks, failing, taking risks again, failing again… step by step.</p>
<p>Everyone is capable of taking risks, and everyone has had the experience of taking bold risks.  As toddlers, we dared to stand and learn to walk, falling and getting back up countless times.  Learning to ride a bicycle involved numerous falls, followed by getting back up, falling again, and getting back up again, until we finally mastered it. Most life skills, such as swimming, skating, driving, public speaking, and so on, are not innate instincts.  Learning these skills requires going through a phase of risk-taking, embracing the spirit of perseverance, and trying repeatedly.  Learning investment and financial management is no exception; it requires this standard process of risk-taking.  To become a successful investor, you must first discard the habit of risk aversion, rediscover your lost instinct for adventure, and cultivate a healthy risk-taking spirit.</p>
<p>Does investing have to be extremely risky?  In reality, the risks involved in investment and financial management are no greater than the examples mentioned above.  It&rsquo;s just that as we reach an age where we believe we are qualified to manage finances, our risk-taking spirit has diminished significantly. As children, almost everyone learns to walk.  A little older, most learn to ride a bicycle.  But as we grow older, the number of people who learn more adventurous activities like swimming and skating decreases considerably.  In adulthood, the number of people comfortable with public speaking dwindles even further.</p>
<p><strong>Our risk-taking spirit seems to fade with age.  This is partly because experiencing failures and mistakes naturally leads to frustration and discouragement. Without sufficient motivation, we tend to avoid taking risks to minimize the blow of failure.  Another contributing factor is traditional education.  Out of a desire to protect children, adults often reprimand them for any risky behavior, instilling a habit of prioritizing safety and avoiding mistakes.  Children then strive to be &ldquo;good kids&rdquo; who never do anything wrong.  As we age, this risk aversion becomes ingrained. While avoiding risk isn&rsquo;t inherently bad, excessive risk aversion becomes a significant obstacle to successful investment and financial management.</strong></p>
<p><strong>The First Priority of Financial Management: Overcoming Fear</strong></p>
<p>When individuals can control their fear, they can control their thoughts and actions.  Self-control enables them to remain calm in chaotic environments, make necessary decisions without being paralyzed by the uncertainty of the outcomes, and be prepared to bear the consequences of failure when things don&rsquo;t go as planned. This courage and risk-taking spirit in the face of danger are essential qualities for investors.</p>
<p><strong>Courageous risk-takers are not fearless; they simply recognize risk and overcome their fear of it.</strong> Courage stems from controlling fear, and cultivating a risk-taking spirit begins with understanding risk.</p>
<p>To become a successful investor, you must first discard the habit of avoiding risk.  Admittedly, changing long-held risk-averse habits is no easy feat.  However, since risk-taking is an indispensable element of successful financial management, the first priority in learning to manage your finances is to overcome fear and force yourself to take risks.  Cultivate a healthy risk-taking spirit, invest bravely in assets with high expected returns, and bear the associated risks.</p>
<p><strong>Top performers in any field achieve success by bravely facing their fears and taking calculated risks.</strong> Those who achieve financial success and fulfill their dreams through investment share this same spirit of adventure. <strong>Remember: excessive caution hinders success.  Without a spirit of adventure, dreams will forever remain dreams.</strong></p>
<blockquote>
<p>Mastering risk is the foundation of successful financial management.</p>
</blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">Overcoming Risk – Start Small 
    <div id="overcoming-risk--start-small" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#overcoming-risk--start-small" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>Skilled risk-takers never test the depth of the water by stepping in with both feet. They extend one foot first, and if the situation seems unfavorable, they quickly withdraw.  An African proverb states, &ldquo;Only a fool tests the depth of the water with both feet.&rdquo;  Similarly, only a fool would go all-in without any investment experience.</p>
<p><strong>Gain Experience with Small Amounts of Money</strong></p>
<p>When faced with unfamiliar investment opportunities, don&rsquo;t put all your eggs in one basket. Start small.  Skilled generals don&rsquo;t expose their main forces to unnecessary danger.  To gather intelligence and gain an advantage, they deploy small reconnaissance units deep into enemy territory to identify low-risk, high-impact attack strategies.</p>
<p>The same principle applies to investment risk-taking strategies.  When dealing with unfamiliar investments, unclear situations, or a lack of confidence, avoid going all-in.  Start small, using small amounts of money to gain experience and familiarize yourself with the situation. Once you have sufficient experience and confidence, then you can invest larger sums.</p>
<p>As the saying goes, &ldquo;All things are difficult before they are easy.&rdquo; The best way to overcome fear is to confront what you fear head-on.  Since risk-taking is an essential part of building wealth through investment, don&rsquo;t shy away from it.  Start with small investments to build your risk tolerance.  With experience, the feeling of fear will gradually dissipate.  By progressively overcoming small fears, you can then face larger risks. You&rsquo;ll soon discover that the experience gained through risk-taking is helping you steadily approach your dreams.</p>
<p><strong>Once You&rsquo;re Used to Risk, You&rsquo;ll Find It&rsquo;s Not So Scary</strong></p>
<p>Risk aversion is human nature, but don&rsquo;t let a single investment failure shatter your confidence and prevent you from investing again, turning you into a perpetual loser.  Conversely, don&rsquo;t let a stroke of good luck make you forget the existence of risk, leading you to borrow heavily and invest recklessly, resulting in irreparable losses.  Successful and unsuccessful investors alike fear risk; they simply react to it differently.</p>
<p>Dear readers, if you haven&rsquo;t tried investing yet, take the plunge for the sake of building wealth!  If you take appropriate risk mitigation measures after investing, I can assure you from experience: &ldquo;The risks of investing are actually quite small, even smaller than the risk of riding a bicycle.  After 10 or 20 years of investing, when you see your wealth growing rapidly, the feeling will be hundreds of times better than riding a bicycle.&rdquo;</p>
<p><strong>The first element of investing is a strong adventurous spirit, seeking to generate substantial risk premiums between risk and safety.</strong> No matter what investment you choose, as long as it offers high expected returns, risk is inevitable. Investors should embrace calculated risks and accumulate financial knowledge and experience along the way. Risk naturally decreases with accumulated knowledge, and wealth grows at an increasing pace.</p>
<p>This book dedicates significant space to discussing risk because the biggest challenge people face in financial management is their inability to confront risk directly.  They don&rsquo;t know how to face or manage risk, and some are even afraid to take any risks.  They don&rsquo;t realize that the biggest obstacle to successful investment and financial management is the fear of risk. This mindset is understandable, as most investment and financial management decisions are made amidst uncertainty and change. In short, to achieve financial success through investment, you must be willing to take calculated risks. Currently, many people suffer significant losses due to blind risk-taking and involvement in high-risk speculative activities.</p>
<p>If you are unwilling to take risks and prefer a conservative approach, be prepared for a life of mediocrity, as this is unavoidable. Of course, there&rsquo;s nothing wrong with a conservative and mediocre life if it brings you happiness. The choice is yours. <strong>People usually regret the things they didn&rsquo;t do, not the things they tried.</strong> Therefore, my advice is: <strong>Take risks, but be cautious and learn how to manage them.</strong></p>
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Personal Investment Bible: Investment Iron Law II</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1731056005961/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1731056005961/</guid><description>This article explains that the key to wealth accumulation through personal finance is patience. Using Li Ka-shing&amp;#39;s wealth accumulation as an example, it explains the power of compound interest and emphasizes the importance of long-term investment and time. At the same time, the article also points out the pitfalls of getting rich quickly and advises readers to choose entrepreneurship rather than speculation.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[

<h2 class="relative group">Investment Iron Law II: Patience is Key to Wealth Accumulation 
    <div id="investment-iron-law-ii-patience-is-key-to-wealth-accumulation" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#investment-iron-law-ii-patience-is-key-to-wealth-accumulation" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>Working hard is not about making more money,<br>
but about maintaining a state of mind<br>
— challenge, goals, struggle, and success.</p>
</blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">How Did Li Ka-shing Accumulate His Wealth? 
    <div id="how-did-li-ka-shing-accumulate-his-wealth" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#how-did-li-ka-shing-accumulate-his-wealth" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>Li Ka-shing, ranked among the top ten wealthiest Chinese in the world with a fortune of nearly $7 billion, is the chairman of Cheung Kong Holdings and Hutchison Whampoa Limited in Hong Kong. His legendary journey to wealth and his influence in Hong Kong&rsquo;s political and business circles have earned him another nickname — &ldquo;Superman Li.&rdquo;</p>
<p><strong>Capitalizing on the Plunging Property Market</strong></p>
<p>In 1939, 12-year-old Li Ka-shing moved to Hong Kong from his hometown of Chao&rsquo;an, Guangdong, with his father. After two years of schooling, Hong Kong fell due to the Pacific War. The following year, his father died of a serious illness, forcing Li Ka-shing, the eldest son, to drop out of school and support his family. After Hong Kong&rsquo;s liberation in 1945, he ended his odd-job career and became a salesman at a plastics factory, working over 16 hours a day. Three years later, at the age of 20, he was promoted to general manager. Two years after that, he used all his savings of HK$7,000 to start his own small plastics factory, &ldquo;Cheung Kong Industries,&rdquo; the predecessor of today&rsquo;s largest conglomerate in Hong Kong, Cheung Kong Holdings.</p>
<p>How did Li Ka-shing, without even a primary school diploma, take his first step toward becoming the richest man by producing plastic flowers? In 1958, due to a rent increase by the landlord of his factory, Li Ka-shing bought a piece of land in North Point and built his own factory. In the early 1960s, the plastic flower industry declined, and in 1967, Hong Kong property prices plummeted. Li Ka-shing seized the opportunity to acquire land at low prices. In 1972, the Hong Kong stock market soared, and Cheung Kong Industries went public, taking advantage of the opportunity to raise capital from the public to purchase more land. In the 10 years following the completion of his first factory in 1958, his real estate holdings increased 50-fold. Cheung Kong now holds approximately 1.48 million square meters of floor space. Li Ka-shing has been investing in real estate for over 40 years, and long-term investment has accumulated his enormous wealth.</p>
<p>Having strived for 50 years and achieved success in wealth accumulation, Li Ka-shing has unique insights into success. He said: &ldquo;Before the age of 20, 100% of career success comes from hard work; between 20 and 30, when a career has some foundation, 10% of success depends on good luck, and 90% still comes from diligence; after 30, the proportion of opportunity gradually increases; now, luck accounts for about 30% to 40%.&rdquo;</p>
<p>The same applies to wealth accumulation. Before 20, all money comes from hard work; between 20 and 30 is the time to work hard to earn and save money; after 30, the importance of investment and financial management gradually increases. By middle age, the money earned is less important, and how to manage money becomes more critical. Li Ka-shing has been fighting for his wealth all his life. To become rich, one must have enough patience.</p>
<p><strong>The Power of Compound Interest Takes Time</strong></p>
<p>Many people who have heard my lectures often ask the same questions: &ldquo;Saving 14,000 yuan a year to become a billionaire is indeed impressive, but according to your method, it takes 40 years, which is really discouraging!&rdquo; &ldquo;It takes 40 years to become a billionaire. By then, I might be dead. What&rsquo;s the point of having billions then?&rdquo; &ldquo;Can you teach some secrets to getting rich quickly?&rdquo;</p>
<p>Even I feel that 40 years is too long. At the repeated requests of the audience, I did spend some time studying this issue in depth. The result of the research is: <strong>Financial management requires a long time, and the effect is not visible in the short term.  It is impossible to get rich quickly through financial management.</strong></p>
<p>If someone starts now and saves 14,000 yuan at the end of each year, and if the money saved each year can be invested in stocks or real estate with an average annual return of 20%, we know that the wealth will grow to 102.81 million yuan after 40 years. Now, let&rsquo;s ask: How much wealth can he accumulate after 10 years? Most people think that with such a high return, even with a shorter time, after 10 years of compounding, it should be at least 5 million yuan, some even guess 10 million, and the most conservative guess is 1 million.  Similarly, this is a surprising answer: 360,000 yuan! The following calculation formula should be familiar to readers, but they will be surprised that the amount is so small.</p>
<p><math xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" display="block"><mtable displaystyle="true" columnalign="right center left" columnspacing="0 thickmathspace" rowspacing="3pt"><mtr><mtd><mn>14,000</mn><mo>×</mo><mfrac><mrow><msup><mrow><mo stretchy="false">(</mo><mn>1</mn><mo>+</mo><mn>0.20</mn><mo stretchy="false">)</mo></mrow><mrow><mn>10</mn></mrow></msup><mo>−</mo><mn>1</mn></mrow><mn>0.20</mn></mfrac></mtd><mtd><mi></mi><mo>=</mo></mtd><mtd><mn>360,000</mn></mtd></mtr><mtr><mtd><mn>14,000</mn><mo>×</mo><mfrac><mrow><msup><mrow><mo stretchy="false">(</mo><mn>1</mn><mo>+</mo><mn>0.20</mn><mo stretchy="false">)</mo></mrow><mrow><mn>40</mn></mrow></msup><mo>−</mo><mn>1</mn></mrow><mn>0.20</mn></mfrac></mtd><mtd><mi></mi><mo>=</mo></mtd><mtd><mn>102,810,000</mn></mtd></mtr></mtable></math></p>
<p>With the same 20% return, 14,000 yuan per year results in 102.81 million yuan after 40 years of financial management, but only 360,000 yuan after 10 years, which is unbelievable! The difference is more than 300 times! Fortunately, this concept is presented to readers in a timely manner. Otherwise, if readers use the methods mentioned in this book, save 14,000 yuan every year, and invest all of it in stocks, thinking that they can become billionaires, they would be shocked to find that after ten years of hard work, with an average annual return of 20%, they have only accumulated 360,000 yuan! They might feel cheated.  After struggling for 10 years, they can&rsquo;t even afford a car, let alone become billionaires!</p>
<p>What is 10 years? Ten years is a long time. After 10 years of struggle, there&rsquo;s only a little over 300,000 yuan. How discouraging! This is the frustration one inevitably encounters in the process of accumulating wealth through investment and financial management.  Investors must understand that financial management is a &ldquo;marathon&rdquo; rather than a &ldquo;sprint.&rdquo; It&rsquo;s about endurance, not explosive power.</p>
<p>The prerequisite for getting rich through investment and financial management is time, and a long time. You must go through a very long waiting period before you can see the results. If the invested capital is small, no results will be seen after 10 years.</p>
<p><strong>Earning Your Second 10 Million is Easier Than the First 1 Million</strong></p>
<p>Saving 14,000 yuan at the end of each year with an average investment return of 20%, even after 20 years, the assets will only accumulate to 2.61 million yuan.  At this point, one is still far from being a billionaire. It takes 30 years to accumulate 16.55 million yuan, barely reaching the millionaire level.  Only after 40 years of continuous struggle can one become a billionaire with 102.81 million yuan.</p>
<p><em>Annual Investment of 14,000 Yuan, Wealth Accumulation (20% Return, Unit/10,000 Yuan)</em></p>
<table>
  <thead>
      <tr>
          <th>Year</th>
          <th>Accumulated Amount at Year End</th>
          <th>Amount Increased in the Last Five Years</th>
      </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
      <tr>
          <td>5</td>
          <td>10</td>
          <td>10</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>10</td>
          <td>36</td>
          <td>26</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>15</td>
          <td>101</td>
          <td>65</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>20</td>
          <td>261</td>
          <td>160</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>25</td>
          <td>661</td>
          <td>400</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>30</td>
          <td>1655</td>
          <td>994</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>35</td>
          <td>4128</td>
          <td>2473</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>40</td>
          <td>10281</td>
          <td>6153</td>
      </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>
<p>From the table above, we can see: by saving 14,000 yuan annually with a 20% investment return, the wealth increased by 360,000 yuan in the first decade, 2.25 million yuan in the second decade, 13.94 million yuan in the third decade, and 86.26 million yuan in the fourth decade. This is the characteristic of geometric progression, and it is also the principle that people engaged in investment and financial management should understand.  Therefore, three important characteristics of investment and financial management can be summarized here:</p>
<ul>
<li>
<ol>
<li>Most wealth is created in the later stages. From the above example, we can see that only 41.28 million yuan was accumulated in the first 35 years, while 61.53 million yuan was created in the last 5 years.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol start="2">
<li>In terms of amount, your ability to make money through financial management increases over time. From the table above, it can be seen that doing the same thing, the amount of money earned increases, the only thing needed is patience.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol start="3">
<li>Earning the second 10 million yuan is often easier than the first 1 million yuan.</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>Wealth accumulation doesn&rsquo;t happen overnight.</p>
</blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">Patience Pays Off 
    <div id="patience-pays-off" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#patience-pays-off" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>A self-made man who got rich by investing in stocks once told me: &ldquo;Now that I&rsquo;ve made it, a stock price increase can easily bring in millions of yuan. Making money has suddenly become so easy, it&rsquo;s unstoppable. Thinking back to the days when I first entered the stock market 30 years ago, it took a lot of hard work to earn tens of thousands of yuan. I really don&rsquo;t know where the money went back then.&rdquo;</p>
<p>This experience is not unfamiliar to many who have struggled to build their fortunes from scratch.  Everything is difficult at the beginning.  During the initial struggle, money is hard to earn.  It takes a lot of effort to earn just tens of thousands of yuan. It&rsquo;s puzzling why money is so hard to earn.  Until success is achieved, and money comes rolling in, one wonders why making money has become so easy.</p>
<p><strong>Time is the Stepping Stone to Wealth Accumulation</strong></p>
<p>Everyone desires the ability to effortlessly earn their second million or ten million, reaching a state of abundant wealth.  The problem is, before earning the second million, you need to have the first million. But how can you earn the first million?  If you want to accumulate 1 million through investment and financial management, you need &ldquo;time.&rdquo; You have to go through a long period of hardship. If you can endure the difficult period of earning the first million, you can naturally enjoy the ease of earning the second million.</p>
<p>From the compound interest formula, we can see that time is an indispensable factor for compound interest to take effect.  Patient waiting is a prerequisite for investment and financial management.  Especially for wealth accumulation through financial management, the required patience is not a few months or years, but at least two or three decades, or even four or five decades.</p>
<p>The vast majority of wealthy people accumulate their huge fortunes gradually from small amounts of money over a long period. In the beginning, most people have very little capital, even negligible. However, success is woven from a series of small achievements. Great wealth is the accumulation of small wealth, coupled with the effect of compound interest.</p>
<p>The importance of time in investment and financial management is evident. Patience is essential for financial management. The more patient you are in enduring the long waiting period, the greater the power of wealth creation will be. This is the characteristic of &ldquo;compound interest.&rdquo; However, today we live in a &ldquo;fast food&rdquo; culture where everything emphasizes speed and efficiency: fast food restaurants for meals, express delivery for mail, highways for driving, one-hour photo processing, and crash courses for learning. People have become increasingly impatient and short-sighted, lacking patience.  In investment and financial management, they are also impatient and lack patience, wanting to see results immediately.  It may be more efficient to pursue speed in other matters, but investment and financial management cannot be rushed. Time is a necessary condition for financial management. The more you rush, the less you achieve.  Based on my observations, a common mistake among investors is giving up halfway. They get easily discouraged during bear markets and simply sell their stocks and real estate, completely leaving the stock and property markets, not knowing that lack of patience and perseverance makes it difficult to achieve anything.</p>
<ul>
<li>
<ol>
<li>Time is an indispensable factor in achieving wealth through financial management.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol start="2">
<li>The patience required for wealth accumulation is not a few months or years, but at least two or three decades.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol start="3">
<li>Patient waiting allows compound interest to take effect.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol start="4">
<li>How can investors achieve a state of abundant and unstoppable wealth? Long-term holding and patient waiting.</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>The Real Estate Investment Experience of Madam Chang Yao-Hung-Ying, Chairperson of Grand Pacific Construction</strong></p>
<p><em>&ldquo;Land I bought for hundreds of thousands in the past is now worth hundreds of millions.&rdquo;</em></p>
<p>Madam Chang Yao-Hung-Ying, chairperson of Grand Pacific Construction, pointed out: In the 1930s, a mainlander investing in land in Taiwan was often ridiculed. But it was with this small capital and perseverance that Madam Chang Yao-Hung-Ying, who left Shanghai for Taiwan in 1947, when her husband became disillusioned with his business, saw the development potential of Taiwan. She picked up their real estate business skills from Shanghai and started buying land.</p>
<p>After more than 40 years, her long-term investment in real estate finally paid off.  Her family&rsquo;s business is growing bigger and bigger, and they now own two listed companies: ASE Technology Holding and Grand Pacific Construction. ASE Technology Holding is now the second largest packaging factory in the world. As for Grand Pacific Construction, it launched the Earl&rsquo;s Court project in Xizhi in 1987, which boosted the real estate market in Xizhi and rapidly accumulated their family&rsquo;s wealth, making them one of the richest families in Taiwan.</p>
<p>Madam Chang Yao-Hung-Ying has now passed the baton to her son, Jason Chang. Jason Chang, chairman of ASE Technology Holding, seems to have inherited his mother&rsquo;s investment acumen. He&rsquo;s the kind of person who buys land wherever he goes, whether it&rsquo;s in Taiwan, Hong Kong, mainland China, or the United States. Perhaps in another two or three decades, Jason Chang will also say: &ldquo;I didn&rsquo;t expect that the land I bought for a few million back then would now be worth tens of billions.&rdquo;  However, Jason Chang&rsquo;s wealth accumulation speed will be much faster than his mother&rsquo;s because he has already laid a good foundation.  All he needs to do is go with the flow, and his wealth will increase geometrically, with money rolling in, unstoppable.</p>
<p><strong>Withstanding the Test of Time is the True Measure</strong></p>
<p><em>It&rsquo;s not your judgment that makes you a lot of money, but your patience.</em></p>
<p>A crucial factor in financial management is time. Without a correct understanding of it, impatience will naturally arise.  Impatience leads to taking significant risks, turning potential success into failure.</p>
<p>Whether it&rsquo;s the accumulation of wealth or experience, it&rsquo;s not something that can be accomplished overnight. It takes time. Fortunately, God is very fair in this regard. Regardless of whether one is born rich or poor, noble or humble, everyone has only 24 hours a day and an average lifespan of about 75 years. Time is the greatest wealth in life, and a person&rsquo;s honor, status, wealth, and happiness all depend on how they use this wealth.</p>
<p>To accumulate wealth through investment and financial management, time is an indispensable factor. It cannot be rushed.  Investment and financial management can lead to slow and steady wealth accumulation, but investing small amounts of money and wanting to earn billions of wealth in a short period is, I can say with certainty, &ldquo;impossible!&rdquo; Just imagine, can a mother give birth without going through ten months of pregnancy? Can a farmer shorten the growth period of rice seedlings?</p>
<p>The growth of wealth is like the growth of life.  It&rsquo;s formed bit by bit, day by day, month by month, year by year, under the effect of compound interest.  It cannot be achieved overnight. This is the law of nature, and God never changes his natural laws.</p>
<p><strong>Luck is Not a Long-Term Strategy</strong></p>
<p>Many investors make a fortune overnight and go bankrupt overnight. Their success is due to luck, and their failure is because &ldquo;you may be lucky for a while, but you cannot always be lucky.&rdquo; <strong>Any investment opportunity that promises overnight riches must hide a greater risk of overnight poverty.</strong> This is why most of those who fantasize about getting rich quickly through financial management end up losing everything.</p>
<p>As long as you are patient and invest your assets in the right investment vehicles, you don&rsquo;t need to actively manage or worry. Compound interest will naturally lead to wealth growth, and becoming a billionaire over time is almost a certainty. In investment and financial management, haste makes waste. &ldquo;Fast&rdquo; is definitely not good!</p>
<p>If you really want to get rich quickly, I suggest you try entrepreneurship instead of investment and financial management. If any of the readers want to get rich quickly, what should they do?  My sincere suggestion is to choose the path of entrepreneurship. I have studied the wealth accumulation process of many rich people throughout history and found that there are many examples of getting rich quickly through entrepreneurship. Bill Gates, the richest man in the United States, dropped out of college in his freshman year to found Microsoft and became the richest man in the United States in just 20 years.</p>
<p>However, the probability of success in getting rich through entrepreneurship is extremely low.  According to statistics from the Taiwan Entrepreneurship Association, the success rate of a person&rsquo;s first business venture is only about 7%, and entrepreneurial success does not necessarily mean getting rich. In other words, for every successful entrepreneur we see, there are at least dozens of unknown failures behind them.  Moreover, the entrepreneurial process is very arduous. Working more than ten hours a day seems to be a prerequisite for successful entrepreneurs.</p>
<p>On the contrary, as long as the method is correct, investing money in the stock market and property market, and waiting patiently for decades, the probability of getting rich through investment and financial management is very high. It&rsquo;s hard not to get rich, and the process is relatively easy and enjoyable!  Which method you choose to get rich is up to you. I must emphasize again that there is a possibility of getting rich quickly through entrepreneurship, but it is absolutely impossible to get rich quickly through financial management.</p>
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>The Millionaire Next Door: Book Notes</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1728996298300/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1728996298300/</guid><description>This book reveals the true portrait of American millionaires through a survey, debunking myths about them and showcasing their common characteristics：frugality, diligence, self-discipline, and skillful investment. It also explores the definition of wealth, how to accumulate it, how to educate children, and how to distribute inheritance, providing a life textbook for readers.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[

<h2 class="relative group">I. Summary 
    <div id="i-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This book unveils the real lives of American millionaires through a comprehensive survey, shattering the mystique surrounding them. The authors discovered that most American millionaires were not born with a silver spoon but built their wealth from scratch through frugality, hard work, self-discipline, and smart investing. The book also explores the definition of wealth, how to accumulate it, how to raise children, and how to distribute inheritance, offering a practical guide for those who aspire to build wealth.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">II. Chapter Summaries 
    <div id="ii-chapter-summaries" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii-chapter-summaries" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Chapter 1: Meet the Millionaire Next Door 
    <div id="chapter-1-meet-the-millionaire-next-door" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chapter-1-meet-the-millionaire-next-door" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>This chapter introduces the authors&rsquo; motivation and methodology for surveying millionaires and paints a typical picture of an American millionaire: they are mostly self-made entrepreneurs who live frugally and focus on investment rather than conspicuous consumption.</li>
<li>Through analyzing affluent individuals from diverse racial backgrounds and professions, the authors reveal the relationship between wealth accumulation and factors like racial origin and career choices, emphasizing the crucial role of &ldquo;frugality&rdquo; in wealth building.</li>
<li>The authors introduce the concept of &ldquo;Big Hat, No Cattle,&rdquo; referring to the phenomenon that many who appear to be millionaires are not truly wealthy, while many genuine millionaires live modest, frugal lives.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chapter 2: Frugality: The Cornerstone of Wealth Building 
    <div id="chapter-2-frugality-the-cornerstone-of-wealth-building" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chapter-2-frugality-the-cornerstone-of-wealth-building" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>This chapter delves into the theme of &ldquo;frugality,&rdquo; highlighting it as the foundation of wealth accumulation.</li>
<li>By comparing the lifestyles and consumption habits of &ldquo;Prodigious Accumulators of Wealth (PAWs)&rdquo; and &ldquo;Under Accumulators of Wealth (UAWs),&rdquo; the authors demonstrate the decisive impact of frugality on wealth accumulation. For instance, the contrasting cases of Mr. Ford, a lawyer with high spending habits, and Mr. Richards, a mobile home dealer who lived frugally, ultimately show that Mr. Richards accumulated almost five times the wealth of Mr. Ford.</li>
<li>This chapter points out that most American millionaires are first-generation affluent individuals who practice a lifestyle of saving more than they spend, refraining from splurging on luxury items like expensive clothing, watches, and cars. They accumulate wealth but maintain a moderately frugal lifestyle.</li>
<li>This chapter also introduces a crucial wealth formula: <em>Age multiplied by realized pretax annual household income, divided by 10, minus inherited wealth, equals your expected net worth.</em> Using this formula, readers can calculate their expected net worth and assess whether they are PAWs, UAWs, or &ldquo;Average Accumulators of Wealth (AAWs).&rdquo;</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chapter 3: Time, Energy, and Money 
    <div id="chapter-3-time-energy-and-money" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chapter-3-time-energy-and-money" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>This chapter explores the importance of efficiently allocating &ldquo;time, energy, and money&rdquo; for wealth accumulation.</li>
<li>By comparing how PAWs and UAWs allocate these three resources, the chapter illustrates that PAWs prioritize long-term planning, investment strategies, and risk management, while UAWs tend towards instant gratification, impulsive spending, and a lack of financial planning.</li>
<li>This chapter emphasizes the importance of household budgeting, stating that even high earners need to meticulously plan and control expenses to accumulate wealth.</li>
<li>The authors point out that PAWs spend significantly more time on financial planning than UAWs, and PAWs prefer to invest in appreciating assets like stocks and real estate, while UAWs tend to spend their money on consumer goods.</li>
<li>The authors advise readers to manage their household finances like a business, creating a budget, controlling expenses, and regularly reviewing investment plans.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chapter 4: You Aren&rsquo;t What You Drive 
    <div id="chapter-4-you-arent-what-you-drive" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chapter-4-you-arent-what-you-drive" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>This chapter uses the car-buying habits of millionaires as an example to further illustrate the principle that &ldquo;being financially independent is more important than displaying high social status.&rdquo;</li>
<li>The authors categorize millionaire car buyers into four types: &ldquo;New-Car Dealers&rsquo; Conservatives,&rdquo; &ldquo;New-Car Shoppers,&rdquo; &ldquo;Used-Car Dealers&rsquo; Conservatives,&rdquo; and &ldquo;Used-Car Shoppers.&rdquo;</li>
<li>By analyzing the purchasing behaviors of these four types, the authors find that &ldquo;Used-Car Shoppers&rdquo; are the most frugal, highly price-sensitive, and adept at leveraging various channels to find the best deals. This group is also the most likely to become PAWs.</li>
<li>This chapter also notes that most millionaires buy American-made cars, and many buy used cars. They believe that cars are depreciating assets and there&rsquo;s no need to spend excessively on new ones.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chapter 5: Economic Outpatient Care 
    <div id="chapter-5-economic-outpatient-care" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chapter-5-economic-outpatient-care" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>This chapter explores the phenomenon of &ldquo;Economic Outpatient Care,&rdquo; where parents provide substantial financial assistance to their adult children, often leading to the children&rsquo;s lack of financial independence and drive, ultimately hindering their ability to accumulate wealth.</li>
<li>By comparing the wealth accumulation of children who receive &ldquo;Economic Outpatient Care&rdquo; with those who don&rsquo;t, the authors illustrate the negative impact of this practice. For example, the case of Rama and Mary, a couple who received long-term financial support from Mary&rsquo;s parents, ultimately developed high spending habits and failed to accumulate wealth.</li>
<li>This chapter analyzes the causes of &ldquo;Economic Outpatient Care&rdquo; and offers suggestions to help affluent parents avoid the tragedy of &ldquo;shirtsleeves to shirtsleeves in three generations.&rdquo; For instance, parents should teach their children frugality and financial management instead of solely providing financial aid.</li>
<li>This chapter points out that adult children who receive gifts from their parents generally perform worse in wealth accumulation compared to those who don&rsquo;t. This is because receiving gifts can foster dependence and a tendency to spend the money on consumption rather than investment.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chapter 6: Rules of Thumb 
    <div id="chapter-6-rules-of-thumb" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chapter-6-rules-of-thumb" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>This chapter discusses how affluent parents distribute wealth to their adult children and how they choose heirs.</li>
<li>The authors note that affluent parents often distribute wealth based on their children&rsquo;s professions, gender, and contributions to the family, tending to leave more to children who need financial assistance. For instance, homemakers often receive more inheritance than working children.</li>
<li>This chapter also emphasizes the importance of choosing executors and suggests that affluent parents select an experienced professional as a co-executor to prevent inheritance disputes among children.</li>
<li>This chapter offers advice to help affluent parents avoid family conflicts when distributing inheritance. For example, affluent parents should establish estate plans early and communicate with their children to ensure their wishes are understood.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chapter 7: Affirmative Action, Family Style 
    <div id="chapter-7-affirmative-action-family-style" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chapter-7-affirmative-action-family-style" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>This chapter explores the business opportunities in providing products and services to the wealthy, noting that these opportunities will continue to grow with the increasing affluent population.</li>
<li>The authors list several businesses and professions that can benefit from serving the wealthy, including specialized lawyers, healthcare and dental specialists, estate liquidators, educational institutions and professionals, and real estate experts.</li>
<li>The authors also analyze the spending habits of the wealthy and point out that they are willing to spend on certain aspects, such as investment consulting, healthcare, and education, which provides significant business opportunities for many industries.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chapter 8: The Perfect Investment 
    <div id="chapter-8-the-perfect-investment" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chapter-8-the-perfect-investment" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>This chapter discusses the relationship between career choice and wealth accumulation, pointing out that self-employed business owners and professionals are more likely to build wealth.</li>
<li>By comparing the profitability and risks of different professions, the authors illustrate why self-employed business owners and professionals are more likely to accumulate wealth. For example, the average profit margin of a doctor&rsquo;s office is higher than that of a coal mining operation.</li>
<li>This chapter also analyzes why affluent parents often discourage their children from taking over family businesses and instead recommend pursuing careers as self-employed professionals. This is because self-employed professionals can leverage their knowledge and skills to generate sustainable income, and their careers tend to be more stable and less risky.</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">III. Key Quotes 
    <div id="iii-key-quotes" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii-key-quotes" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;Wealth is not the same as income. If you make a good income each year and spend it all, you are not getting wealthier. You are just living high. Wealth is what you accumulate, not what you spend.&rdquo;</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Analysis: This quote highlights the book&rsquo;s core message: wealth accumulation is not solely based on high income but also relies on frugal habits and smart investment skills. High income doesn&rsquo;t equate to wealth; only by converting income into assets can one achieve true financial freedom.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;Frugality is the cornerstone of wealth building.&rdquo;</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Analysis: This quote emphasizes the crucial role of frugality in wealth accumulation. Only by controlling consumption can one free up more funds for investment, leading to wealth growth. Frugality doesn&rsquo;t mean living an austere life but rather being a rational consumer and avoiding unnecessary waste.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;To build wealth, minimize your realized (taxable) income and maximize your unrealized income (wealth that is not taxed until it is converted to cash).&rdquo;</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Analysis: This quote reveals a vital strategy for wealthy individuals to accumulate wealth, namely, achieving wealth growth through investment rather than solely relying on salary income. One must skillfully utilize tax policies to convert income into tax-advantaged assets like stocks and real estate.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;If you&rsquo;re not yet wealthy but want to be someday, never purchase a home that requires a mortgage that is more than twice your household&rsquo;s total annual realized income.&rdquo;</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Analysis: This quote offers practical advice for those in the early stages of wealth accumulation: avoid excessive mortgage burdens and allocate more funds towards investment. When funds are limited, prioritize investment over consumption.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;Those who are financially independent are considerably happier than those in the same income/age cohort who are not financially secure.&rdquo;</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Analysis: This quote illustrates the importance of financial security for personal happiness. Possessing sufficient wealth allows individuals to face life&rsquo;s challenges with greater confidence. Economic independence is the foundation of personal freedom and a crucial guarantee of happiness.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;Never tell children that their parents are wealthy.&rdquo;</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Analysis: This quote provides valuable educational advice for affluent parents: avoid letting children know about the family&rsquo;s wealth too early to prevent them from developing dependence and a lack of initiative. Children need to understand that wealth is created through their own efforts.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;No matter how wealthy you are, teach your children to be self-sufficient and frugal.&rdquo;</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Analysis: This quote emphasizes the importance of frugality and self-discipline. Even children from affluent families should develop good habits to better adapt to future challenges. Children need to understand that frugality is a virtue and a prerequisite for success.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">IV. Significance 
    <div id="iv-significance" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv-significance" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<ol>
<li><strong>Importance of Frugality and Financial Management:</strong> This book highlights the importance of frugality and investment, helping readers establish a correct perspective on wealth and offering practical financial advice. There are no shortcuts to wealth creation; only through diligent saving and rational investment can one steadily accumulate wealth.</li>
<li><strong>Wisdom in Raising Children:</strong> This book explores how to raise children to be financially responsible individuals, providing insights into the educational experiences and methods of affluent parents and inspiring readers to reflect on their own parenting styles. Affluent parents should focus on cultivating their children&rsquo;s independence, responsibility, and financial management skills instead of solely providing financial assistance.</li>
<li><strong>Career Choices and Wealth Accumulation:</strong> This book analyzes the profitability and risks of different professions, helping readers better understand the relationship between career choices and wealth accumulation and providing guidance for individual career planning. Choosing a career with development potential that aligns with one&rsquo;s interests and abilities is a crucial prerequisite for achieving wealth accumulation.</li>
<li><strong>Business Opportunities in Serving the Wealthy:</strong> This book reveals the vast business opportunities in providing products and services to the wealthy, offering insights and inspiration for aspiring entrepreneurs. To succeed in this market, one must be adept at identifying the needs of the wealthy and providing high-quality products and services.</li>
<li><strong>Debunking Stereotypes about the Wealthy:</strong> This book debunks the myths surrounding millionaires through its survey of American affluent individuals, presenting a realistic portrait of their lives and prompting readers to contemplate the true meaning of wealth. True wealth encompasses more than just money; it also includes health, happiness, family, and a sense of accomplishment.</li>
</ol>
<p>In conclusion, &ldquo;The Millionaire Next Door&rdquo; is a timeless classic worth revisiting. It not only unveils the secrets to the success of the wealthy but also provides valuable insights and methods for ordinary readers to accumulate wealth, raise children, and plan their lives.</p>
<hr>

<section class="space-y-10 w-full">
    
    
        
            






















  <a class="flex flex-wrap article " href="/en/posts/1728295490690-book-list/">
    
        
        <div class="w-full md:w-auto h-full thumbnail nozoom thumbnailshadow md:mr-7" style="background-image:url(/posts/1728295490690-book-list/featured_hu4424409690304057825.jpg);"></div>
        
      <div class=" mt-3 md:mt-0">
      <div class="items-center text-left text-xl font-semibold">
        
        <div class="font-bold text-xl text-neutral-800 decoration-primary-500 hover:underline hover:underline-offset-2 dark:text-neutral"
          href="/en/posts/1728295490690-book-list/">Recommended Reading List</div>
        
        
        
      </div>
      <div class="text-sm text-neutral-500 dark:text-neutral-400">
        











  









  



  









<div class="flex flex-row flex-wrap items-center">
  
  
  <time datetime="2024-10-01T00:00:00&#43;00:00">1 October 2024</time><span class="px-2 text-primary-500">&middot;</span><span>
  
  
    
    
      
      
        
        
      
        
        
      
      
    
  
  <span id="views_posts/1728295490690-book-list/index.md" class="animate-pulse inline-block text-transparent max-h-3 rounded-full mt-[-2px] align-middle bg-neutral-300 dark:bg-neutral-400" title="views">loading</span>
  <span class="inline-block align-text-bottom">

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 576 512">
<path fill="currentColor" d="M288 32c-80.8 0-145.5 36.8-192.6 80.6C48.6 156 17.3 208 2.5 243.7c-3.3 7.9-3.3 16.7 0 24.6C17.3 304 48.6 356 95.4 399.4C142.5 443.2 207.2 480 288 480s145.5-36.8 192.6-80.6c46.8-43.5 78.1-95.4 93-131.1c3.3-7.9 3.3-16.7 0-24.6c-14.9-35.7-46.2-87.7-93-131.1C433.5 68.8 368.8 32 288 32zM432 256c0 79.5-64.5 144-144 144s-144-64.5-144-144s64.5-144 144-144s144 64.5 144 144zM288 192c0 35.3-28.7 64-64 64c-11.5 0-22.3-3-31.6-8.4c-.2 2.8-.4 5.5-.4 8.4c0 53 43 96 96 96s96-43 96-96s-43-96-96-96c-2.8 0-5.6 .1-8.4 .4c5.3 9.3 8.4 20.1 8.4 31.6z"/></svg>
  </span>

</span>
</span><span class="px-2 text-primary-500">&middot;</span><span>
  
  
    
    
      
      
        
        
      
        
        
      
      
    
  
  <span id="likes_posts/1728295490690-book-list/index.md"
    class="animate-pulse inline-block text-transparent max-h-3 rounded-full mt-[-2px] align-middle bg-neutral-300 dark:bg-neutral-400"
    title="likes">loading</span>
  <span class="inline-block align-text-bottom">

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512">
<path fill="currentColor" d="M47.6 300.4L228.3 469.1c7.5 7 17.4 10.9 27.7 10.9s20.2-3.9 27.7-10.9L464.4 300.4c30.4-28.3 47.6-68 47.6-109.5v-5.8c0-69.9-50.5-129.5-119.4-141C347 36.5 300.6 51.4 268 84L256 96 244 84c-32.6-32.6-79-47.5-124.6-39.9C50.5 55.6 0 115.2 0 185.1v5.8c0 41.5 17.2 81.2 47.6 109.5z"/></svg>
  </span>

</span>
</span>
  

  
  
</div>





<div class="flex flex-row flex-wrap items-center">
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  <span style="margin-top:0.5rem" class="mr-2" onclick="window.open(&#34;/en/tags/recommended/&#34;,'_self');">
    <span class="flex" style="cursor: pointer;">
  <span class="rounded-md border border-primary-400 px-1 py-[1px] text-xs font-normal text-primary-700 dark:border-primary-600 dark:text-primary-400">
    Recommended
  </span>
</span>
  </span>
  
  <span style="margin-top:0.5rem" class="mr-2" onclick="window.open(&#34;/en/tags/book/&#34;,'_self');">
    <span class="flex" style="cursor: pointer;">
  <span class="rounded-md border border-primary-400 px-1 py-[1px] text-xs font-normal text-primary-700 dark:border-primary-600 dark:text-primary-400">
    Book
  </span>
</span>
  </span>
  
  
  
  
</div>




      </div>
      
    </div>
  </a>

        
    
</section>
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Just Keep Buying: Book Notes</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1728914740948/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1728914740948/</guid><description>This book answers the most common questions in the field of personal finance and investing. From saving to investing, it provides practical tips to teach you how to increase your income, invest in income-producing assets, manage your finances more wisely, and live a richer life.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[

<h2 class="relative group">I. Content Summary 
    <div id="i-content-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-content-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This book is divided into two parts: saving and investing. The <strong>saving</strong> section covers all aspects of saving money, including how much to save, how to save more, and how to spend money without guilt. The <strong>investing</strong> section covers many aspects of making money with money, including why you should invest, what you should invest in, and how often you should invest. The author answers the most common questions in the field of personal finance and investing, with each chapter exploring a topic in depth and providing practical tips.  Using a large amount of data and empirical research as evidence, the author arrives at reliable ways to save money and build wealth.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">II. Chapter Summary 
    <div id="ii-chapter-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii-chapter-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Chapter 1. Where Should You Start? 
    <div id="chapter-1-where-should-you-start" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chapter-1-where-should-you-start" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>The poor should focus on saving, and the rich should focus on investing.</p>
<ul>
<li>Recent graduates should focus on increasing their income and savings rate, rather than obsessing over investment decisions, because the growth rate of savings far exceeds the growth rate of investment.</li>
<li>People who have accumulated a certain amount of wealth should spend more time thinking about the details of their investment plan.</li>
<li>The author proposes a &ldquo;Save-Invest continuum&rdquo; concept to help you determine your current financial focus: calculate your expected savings and expected investment growth. Focus on whichever is greater.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chapter 2. How Much Should You Save? 
    <div id="chapter-2-how-much-should-you-save" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chapter-2-how-much-should-you-save" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>You probably need to save less than you think.</p>
<ul>
<li>Many saving recommendations are based on false assumptions: that people&rsquo;s incomes are stable and that everyone has the ability to achieve the same savings rate.</li>
<li>In fact, incomes become more unstable over time, and the biggest determinant of an individual&rsquo;s savings rate is their income level.</li>
<li>The best saving advice is: <strong>save what you can save.</strong></li>
<li>A large body of evidence suggests that retirees generally don&rsquo;t spend enough, with many even increasing their financial assets after retirement.</li>
<li>Today&rsquo;s younger generation is not creating wealth any slower than previous generations, so there is no need to worry too much about running out of money after retirement.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chapter 3. How to Save More Money? 
    <div id="chapter-3-how-to-save-more-money" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chapter-3-how-to-save-more-money" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>The biggest lie in personal finance: you can get rich just by saving.</p>
<ul>
<li>The effectiveness of reducing spending is limited. For low-income people, spending is already at its lowest level, making it difficult to reduce further. The author uses data from the U.S. Bureau of Labor Statistics Consumer Expenditure Survey to support this point.</li>
<li>Increasing income is more effective than reducing spending because as income increases, spending does not necessarily increase proportionately (diminishing marginal utility). The author calls this the &ldquo;law of the stomach.&rdquo;</li>
<li>Five ways to increase your income:
<ul>
<li>Sell your time/expertise: easy to do, but not scalable.</li>
<li>Sell a skill/service: higher income, but takes time to develop skills.</li>
<li>Teach: easy to scale, but highly competitive.</li>
<li>Sell a product: scalable, but requires a lot of upfront investment and ongoing marketing efforts.</li>
<li>Climb the career ladder: traditional but effective, can gain skills, experience and stable income growth.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>The most reliable way to get rich is: <strong>Increase your income and invest in income-producing assets.</strong></li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chapter 4. How to Spend Money Without Guilt? 
    <div id="chapter-4-how-to-spend-money-without-guilt" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chapter-4-how-to-spend-money-without-guilt" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Most financial advice uses guilt to make you question your spending decisions, causing you to be overly nervous about spending money.</li>
<li>Two tips to help you make financial decisions without worry and spend money without guilt:
<ul>
<li>The 2x rule: When you splurge, invest the same amount of money in income-producing assets or donate it to charity. For example, if you want to buy a pair of $400 shoes, buy $400 worth of stock at the same time.</li>
<li>Focus on maximizing satisfaction: Think about whether your purchase can bring autonomy, mastery, and purpose, thereby increasing your long-term satisfaction. For example, a daily latte might allow you to do your job better.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>The only right way to spend money is: <strong>the way that works for you</strong>. Think about what you want to get out of life, and make spending decisions accordingly. Research from the University of Cambridge shows that the more your spending patterns match your psychological state, the higher your life satisfaction, and this effect is greater than the happiness brought by your total income.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chapter 5. How Much Lifestyle Inflation Is Harmless? 
    <div id="chapter-5-how-much-lifestyle-inflation-is-harmless" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chapter-5-how-much-lifestyle-inflation-is-harmless" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Lifestyle inflation refers to the increase in spending that follows an increase in one&rsquo;s income.</li>
<li>Some lifestyle inflation is enjoyable, but too much lifestyle inflation will lead to having to delay retirement.</li>
<li>The author simulates the retirement plans of two investors with different savings rates after salary increases to arrive at these conclusions:
<ul>
<li>The lower your current savings rate, the higher your lifestyle inflation can be without affecting your original retirement plan.</li>
<li>The author recommends saving at least 50% of your future raises, a rule that is simple, practical, and suitable for most people.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chapter 6. Should You Go Into Debt? 
    <div id="chapter-6-should-you-go-into-debt" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chapter-6-should-you-go-into-debt" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>Debt is not necessarily good or bad, it depends on how you use it.</p>
<ul>
<li>Debt as a form of risk mitigation: Some people, even with savings, keep credit card debt as a strategy to reduce the risk of future funding shortages.</li>
<li>Debt as a behavioral pillar of forced savings: Some people use debt as a behavioral pillar to force themselves to save.</li>
<li>The two most useful types of debt:
<ul>
<li>To reduce risk: for example, keeping cash on hand for emergencies or fixing housing costs.</li>
<li>To earn a return higher than the cost of borrowing: for example, by taking out education loans, business loans, or mortgages to generate higher returns. The author uses data to demonstrate that getting a college degree is often worthwhile.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Debt can also have non-financial costs, such as psychological stress and health problems, so non-mortgage financial debt should be avoided as much as possible.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chapter 7. Should You Rent or Buy? 
    <div id="chapter-7-should-you-rent-or-buy" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chapter-7-should-you-rent-or-buy" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>The point of buying a home is not whether to buy it, but when to buy it.</p>
<ul>
<li>In addition to the mortgage, there are a number of one-time and ongoing costs associated with buying a home, such as down payment, closing costs, taxes, maintenance, and insurance. The author details these costs, concluding that buying a home is only cost-effective if the buyer intends to live in it for the long term.</li>
<li>In the short term, buying a home is riskier than renting, but in the long term, renters face greater long-term risks such as rent fluctuations, housing instability, and moving costs.</li>
<li>In the United States, the long-term return on  homeownership as an investment is not ideal, far lower than the stock market. The author uses the example of his grandparents buying a home to illustrate this point.</li>
<li>The right time to buy a home is when you:
<ul>
<li>plan to stay in that location for at least ten years;</li>
<li>have a stable personal and professional life;</li>
<li>can afford a 20% down payment and keep your debt-to-income ratio below 43%. The author recommends, if possible, to make a 20% down payment and buy a larger home in one step, because the transaction costs are lower in the long run.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chapter 8. How to Save For a Down Payment (and Other Big Purchases)? 
    <div id="chapter-8-how-to-save-for-a-down-payment-and-other-big-purchases" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chapter-8-how-to-save-for-a-down-payment-and-other-big-purchases" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>Why the length of time you save matters?</p>
<ul>
<li>Short-term saving for less than two years: Holding <strong>cash</strong> is the best option, as it has the lowest risk.</li>
<li>Long-term saving for more than two years: Investing in <strong>bonds</strong> is preferable to holding cash because bond returns can offset the effects of inflation. The author compares cash and bonds using two examples: &ldquo;Save $1,000 per month with a goal of $24,000&rdquo; and &ldquo;Save $1,000 per month with a goal of $60,000&rdquo;.</li>
<li>Longer-term saving for more than three years: You can choose to invest in <strong>stocks</strong>, but the risk is higher and you need to choose an appropriate portfolio based on your own risk tolerance. The author uses data to show that stocks have much higher long-term returns than bonds, but also greater volatility.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chapter 9. When Can You Retire? 
    <div id="chapter-9-when-can-you-retire" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chapter-9-when-can-you-retire" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>There&rsquo;s more to consider than just money when it comes to retirement.</p>
<ul>
<li>The 4% rule: When your retirement savings reach 25 times your expected annual expenses, you can retire.
<ul>
<li>You can withdraw 4% of your investment assets (half bonds and half stocks) in the first year of retirement, and increase the amount withdrawn by 3% each year to keep up with inflation.</li>
<li>If you have a pension or other guaranteed income, you only need to save 25 times your &ldquo;annual excess spending&rdquo; (expected annual expenses less future guaranteed income).</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>The crossover point rule: The point at which your monthly investment income is greater than your monthly expenses, you have reached the &ldquo;crossover point&rdquo; and achieved financial freedom.
<ul>
<li>&ldquo;Crossover Assets&rdquo; = Monthly Expenses / Monthly Investment Return.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Retirement is much more than just a financial decision, it&rsquo;s a lifestyle decision. You need to think about what you want to do and how you want to live after retirement. The author uses the examples of several celebrities to illustrate the confusion and emptiness that can exist after early retirement.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chapter 10. Why You Should Invest? 
    <div id="chapter-10-why-you-should-invest" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chapter-10-why-you-should-invest" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>Three reasons to make your money grow.</p>
<ul>
<li>Save for your future self: Investing allows you to have a pool of resources to draw from as you age. Human lifespans are increasing, and the concept of &ldquo;retirement&rdquo; has emerged accordingly. To ensure quality of life after retirement, it is necessary to invest in advance.</li>
<li>Fight inflation and maintain the purchasing power of your wealth: Investing can offset the impact of inflation and maintain or increase your purchasing power. The author uses data to show that investing can effectively combat the effects of inflation.</li>
<li>Replace your human capital with financial capital: Investing can turn your diminishing human capital into financial capital that can continue to generate returns. The author illustrates this with the example of professional athletes.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chapter 11. What Should You Invest In? 
    <div id="chapter-11-what-should-you-invest-in" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chapter-11-what-should-you-invest-in" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>There is no single right way to get rich.</p>
<ul>
<li>The author lists a variety of income-producing assets, including:
<ul>
<li>Stocks: One of the most reliable ways to build wealth over the long term, easy to own and trade, with low maintenance costs, but highly volatile and valuations easily influenced by market sentiment.</li>
<li>Bonds: Low volatility, safe principal, and helpful in rebalancing portfolios, but returns are generally lower than stocks, especially in a low interest rate environment.</li>
<li>Investment real estate: Returns are higher than stocks or bonds, especially when using leverage, but require more effort to manage and are difficult to diversify.</li>
<li>Real Estate Investment Trusts (REITs): Provide access to real estate investment income without needing to manage it yourself, but are more volatile and highly correlated with stocks and other risky assets during stock market crashes.</li>
<li>Farmland: Low correlation with stocks and bonds, low volatility, inflation-resistant, but low liquidity, higher fees, and requires &ldquo;accredited investor&rdquo; status to participate.</li>
<li>Small businesses/franchises/angel investing: Potential for high returns and the more effort you put in, the greater the return, but requires a significant time commitment and has a high failure rate.</li>
<li>Royalties: Can generate stable income that is uncorrelated with traditional financial assets, but sellers incur high fees and public taste changes are unpredictable.</li>
<li>Your own products: 100% ownership, personal satisfaction and achievement, can create a valuable brand, but very labor-intensive and no guarantee of return.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>The author also contrasts the characteristics of income-producing and non-income-producing assets (e.g., gold, cryptocurrency, art, etc.) and their respective advantages and disadvantages.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chapter 12. Why You Shouldn&rsquo;t Buy Individual Stocks? 
    <div id="chapter-12-why-you-shouldnt-buy-individual-stocks" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chapter-12-why-you-shouldnt-buy-individual-stocks" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>Why underperforming the market is the least of your worries?</p>
<ul>
<li>Most people (even professionals) can&rsquo;t beat the market. Data from the SPIVA report shows that active funds tend to underperform index funds over the long term.</li>
<li>Only a very small percentage of individual stocks outperform in the long run. Bessembinder&rsquo;s research indicates that since 1926, only 4% of stocks have generated returns that exceed U.S. Treasury bonds.</li>
<li>Even stocks that outperform are not always winners. West&rsquo;s statistical analysis suggests that many companies will disappear within a decade.</li>
<li>Choosing individual stocks is emotionally draining and stressful. The author uses the example of his friend Darren investing in GameStop stock to detail the emotional rollercoaster of stock trading.</li>
<li>It&rsquo;s hard to tell if you&rsquo;re really good at picking stocks. The link between stock picking decisions and outcomes is not significant, making it difficult to assess your stock picking skills. Even if you have performed well in the past, there is no guarantee that you will continue to do so in the future.</li>
<li>The risk of holding a concentrated position in a single stock is that the return is lower than the market. The author uses data on U.S. stock performance since 1963 to show that the median return of individual stocks is lower than that of index funds.</li>
<li>The author suggests buying index funds or ETFs to earn market average returns, which can lead to higher returns and less stress during the investment process.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chapter 13. How Early Should You Start Investing? 
    <div id="chapter-13-how-early-should-you-start-investing" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chapter-13-how-early-should-you-start-investing" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>Why buying early is better than buying late?</p>
<ul>
<li>Most markets tend to go up most of the time, so investing early allows for a longer period of compounding growth.</li>
<li>The author compares two investment strategies:
<ul>
<li>Buy now: Put all the money you can invest in immediately.</li>
<li>Average in: Invest the money you can invest in batches.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Conclusion: The <strong>buy now</strong> strategy is generally better than the average-in strategy. The author uses U.S. stock market data from 1997 to 2020, as well as U.S. stock market data from 1920 to 2020, to respectively prove this conclusion. The same results hold when testing other types of assets.</li>
<li>For risk-averse investors, you can choose to invest in a lower risk portfolio. For example, change an 80% stock / 20% bond portfolio to a 60% stock / 40% bond portfolio.</li>
<li>Even if market valuations are high, the buy now strategy is still better than the average in strategy. The author compares the two strategies using CAPE percentile categories, and the results show that the buy now strategy is still superior even during periods of high valuations.</li>
<li>For investors concerned about the risk of a lump sum investment, you can take a longer time to gradually adjust to your target asset allocation.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chapter 14. Why You Shouldn&rsquo;t Wait to Buy the Dip? 
    <div id="chapter-14-why-you-shouldnt-wait-to-buy-the-dip" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chapter-14-why-you-shouldnt-wait-to-buy-the-dip" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>Even God can&rsquo;t beat dollar-cost averaging.</p>
<ul>
<li>The buy the dip strategy only works if the market is about to have a big drop and you can accurately predict when it will happen.</li>
<li>Big market drops don&rsquo;t happen that often, so the buy the dip strategy has a small chance of beating dollar-cost averaging. The author simulates the two strategies using U.S. stock market data from between 1920 and 1980. The results show that in all forty-year investment periods, the buy-the-dip strategy underperformed dollar-cost averaging more than 70% of the time.</li>
<li>Even with perfect information, the buy the dip strategy often loses to dollar-cost averaging because the market may continue to rise while you miss out on compounding growth. The author simulates the two strategies using U.S. stock market data from 1975 onward, again proving this conclusion.</li>
<li>Even if the predicted time of the market bottom is off by only two months, the long-term investment performance of the buy-the-dip strategy still loses to dollar-cost averaging.</li>
<li>Conclusion: <strong>you should invest as early as possible and as often as possible</strong>.</li>
<li>Investment returns are heavily influenced by time, and the power of strategy is far less than the power of market change.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chapter 15. Why Does Investing Involve Luck? 
    <div id="chapter-15-why-does-investing-involve-luck" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chapter-15-why-does-investing-involve-luck" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>And why you shouldn&rsquo;t care.</p>
<ul>
<li>The year you were born influences your investment returns because markets fluctuate unpredictably. The author illustrates this with data on 10-, 20-, and 30-year investment returns in the U.S. stock market since 1910.</li>
<li>The sequence of investment returns also affects your final return because you invest more money in the later stages of your investment, so later returns are more important. The author illustrates the impact of return sequence with two cases of 20-year investment horizons with the same annualized return but in reverse order.</li>
<li>How to mitigate bad luck:
<ul>
<li>Hold low-risk assets (such as bonds) for the long term to diversify risk.</li>
<li>Withdraw less money during market downturns.</li>
<li>Consider getting a part-time job to supplement your income.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chapter 16. Why You Shouldn&rsquo;t Fear Market Volatility? 
    <div id="chapter-16-why-you-shouldnt-fear-market-volatility" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chapter-16-why-you-shouldnt-fear-market-volatility" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>The price of admission for successful investing.</p>
<ul>
<li>Avoiding too many market declines can limit your upside.</li>
<li>Using the analogy of a &ldquo;market genie&rdquo; that tells you the maximum intra-year drawdown for the coming year, the author simulates different risk aversion strategies. The conclusion is that if you want to maximize long-term wealth, you should accept some degree of intra-year market decline (0% to 15%) and avoid large intra-year market declines (greater than 15%).</li>
<li>Buying a diversified portfolio of income-producing assets over the long term is one of the best ways to combat market volatility as it rears its ugly head.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chapter 17. How to Buy During a Crisis? 
    <div id="chapter-17-how-to-buy-during-a-crisis" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chapter-17-how-to-buy-during-a-crisis" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>Why you should keep your cool when the market panics?</p>
<ul>
<li>Market crashes are opportunities to buy because every dollar you invest at this point will earn a higher return after the market recovers. The author uses the 1929 U.S. stock market crash as an example to illustrate the excess returns of investing at the bottom of the market.</li>
<li>The more the market falls, the higher the return you need to make up for the loss. The author illustrates this with a simple mathematical formula and chart.</li>
<li>Even if the market takes a long time to recover, buying during a crisis is still a good decision because you can earn a decent annualized return while you wait. The author proves this conclusion using examples of the U.S. stock market falling 30% and 50% between 1920 and 2020.</li>
<li>Most stock markets trend upwards most of the time, and even if a prolonged downturn occurs, the likelihood of losing money is significantly reduced if you make regular investments as most investors do, rather than a single lump sum investment. The author illustrates this with the example of the Japanese stock market.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chapter 18. When Should You Sell? 
    <div id="chapter-18-when-should-you-sell" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chapter-18-when-should-you-sell" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>About rebalancing, concentrated positions, and the purpose of investing.</p>
<ul>
<li>Three situations where you should consider selling an investment asset:
<ul>
<li>Rebalancing your portfolio.</li>
<li>Getting rid of a concentrated (or consistently losing) investment position.</li>
<li>Meeting your financial needs.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>You should have a plan in place before you consider selling investment assets to avoid emotional decisions.</li>
<li>Selling gradually (or selling later) is generally better than selling immediately, because in the long run, the market tends to go up.</li>
<li>Regularly rebalancing your portfolio can reduce risk, but it generally reduces returns. The author simulates two strategies, annual rebalancing and never rebalancing, using a portfolio of 60% stocks/40% bonds, and compares the returns and maximum drawdowns after 30 years.</li>
<li>Accumulative rebalancing is a better way to rebalance by buying asset classes that are underweight over time to avoid incurring tax liabilities. The author uses the same portfolio to simulate a strategy of adding investments each month, demonstrating that this strategy can effectively reduce the maximum drawdown.</li>
<li>For investors holding large concentrated positions, it is advisable to sell some of the assets to reduce risk and meet their own living needs. Selling strategies can range from selling a portion on a regular basis to selling based on price levels, as long as it is decided in advance.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chapter 19. Where Should Your Investments Be Held? 
    <div id="chapter-19-where-should-your-investments-be-held" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chapter-19-where-should-your-investments-be-held" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>On taxes, traditional 401(k) vs. Roth 401(k), and why you might not want to maximize your 401(k).</p>
<ul>
<li>Tax policy in the United States is constantly changing, and financial management should also be adjusted according to tax policy. The author reviews the history of income tax in the United States to illustrate this point.</li>
<li>When choosing between a traditional 401(k) and a Roth 401(k), the most important factor is whether your effective income tax rate is higher now (during your working years) or later (in retirement).</li>
<li>The author favors traditional 401(k)s because they offer more flexibility and allow you to convert funds to a Roth IRA when tax rates are lower, such as when you are in business school or on maternity leave.</li>
<li>Roth 401(k)s may be a better option for high savers because they can enjoy greater total tax deferral benefits. The author illustrates this with the example of Sally and Sam.</li>
<li>Using a retirement savings account to invest can avoid capital gains taxes, which can lead to significant long-term gains. The author uses simulated data to compare the returns of three approaches: tax-free accounts, accounts taxed once on capital gains, and accounts taxed annually on capital gains. The author also explains the impact of compounding on investment returns.</li>
<li>Maximizing your 401(k) may not be the best option because 401(k) plan fees may offset the tax benefits. The author suggests that you should at least increase your personal contributions to the point where you can receive the maximum employer match. For any contributions beyond that, you need to take into account the 401(k)&rsquo;s expense ratio and your own need for liquidity.</li>
<li>When allocating assets, it is advisable to place high-growth assets (e.g. stocks) in tax-advantaged accounts and low-growth assets (e.g. bonds) in taxable accounts.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chapter 20. Why Will You Never Feel Rich? 
    <div id="chapter-20-why-will-you-never-feel-rich" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chapter-20-why-will-you-never-feel-rich" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>You might already be rich, so why not?</p>
<ul>
<li>People can always find someone richer than themselves, so it&rsquo;s hard to feel content. The author illustrates people&rsquo;s sense of relative wealth by telling the story of Powerball lottery winner Jack Whittaker, and the story of his friend John.</li>
<li>If you compare yourself to people around the world, you may find that you are much richer than you think. For example, if your net worth is over $4,210, you are wealthier than half the world; if your net worth is over $93,170, you are in the top 10% of the world&rsquo;s wealth.</li>
<li>Don&rsquo;t let feelings of relative wealth affect your happiness and appreciate the wealth you have.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chapter 21. The Most Important Asset 
    <div id="chapter-21-the-most-important-asset" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chapter-21-the-most-important-asset" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>Why you can never get more of this asset.</p>
<ul>
<li>Time is your most important asset, and how you use your time will have a huge impact on your future life. The author tells the story of Dashrath Manjhi, an Indian villager who carved a road through a mountain, to illustrate the power of time.</li>
<li>In your younger years, you should prioritize career development because that&rsquo;s when your income grows the fastest. The author uses his own experience to illustrate the importance of making the right career choices early on.</li>
<li>Don&rsquo;t sacrifice your time in pursuit of money, because you can never buy more time with money.</li>
<li>People&rsquo;s happiness tends to follow a U-shaped curve as they age, overestimating their future happiness in their youth, being more pessimistic in middle age, and feeling pleasantly surprised in old age.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Conclusion. The Just Keep Buying Rules 
    <div id="conclusion-the-just-keep-buying-rules" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#conclusion-the-just-keep-buying-rules" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>How to win the time traveler&rsquo;s game?</p>
<ul>
<li>The author summarizes 21 financial guidelines to help you succeed on your financial journey, these guidelines are called the &ldquo;Just Keep Buying Rules&rdquo;:
<ol>
<li>The poor should focus on saving, and the rich should focus on investing.</li>
<li>Save what you can save.</li>
<li>Focus on income, not expenses.</li>
<li>Use the &ldquo;2x rule&rdquo; to eliminate spending guilt.</li>
<li>Save at least 50% of your future raises and bonuses.</li>
<li>Debt is not necessarily a good thing or a bad thing, it depends on how you use it.</li>
<li>Only buy a house when the timing is right.</li>
<li>Use cash when saving for large purchases.</li>
<li>There&rsquo;s more to retirement than just money.</li>
<li>Invest to accumulate financial capital to replace your diminishing human capital.</li>
<li>Think like an owner and buy income-producing assets.</li>
<li>Don&rsquo;t buy individual stocks.</li>
<li>Buy fast, sell slow.</li>
<li>Invest as early and as often as possible.</li>
<li>Investing is not just about the cards you have, it&rsquo;s also about how you play them.</li>
<li>Don&rsquo;t be afraid when volatility inevitably comes.</li>
<li>Market crashes are usually opportunities to buy.</li>
<li>Use your money for the life you need before risking it for the life you want.</li>
<li>Think twice before maximizing your 401(k).</li>
<li>You&rsquo;ll never feel rich, and that&rsquo;s okay.</li>
<li>Time is your most important asset.</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">III. Quotes 
    <div id="iii-quotes" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii-quotes" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>The surest way to get rich is to increase your income and invest in income-producing assets.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Analysis: Instead of blindly pursuing saving, it is better to focus your energy on increasing your income and investing in assets that can generate income; this is a more reliable path to financial freedom.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The only right way to spend money is the way that works for you.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Analysis: Everyone&rsquo;s values, life goals, and preferences are different, so their financial management style should also be personalized. Don&rsquo;t blindly follow the crowd; find a spending pattern that suits you in order to achieve true happiness.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Time is your most important asset.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Analysis: Time is a non-renewable resource. We should cherish time and spend it on the most valuable things. Investing early is not only about accumulating wealth, but also about buying back more time and freedom.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">IV. Guiding Significance 
    <div id="iv-guiding-significance" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv-guiding-significance" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<ul>
<li><strong>Establishing the right financial mindset:</strong> This book helps us understand the essence of personal finance and how to develop a sound savings and investment plan, avoiding common financial pitfalls.</li>
<li><strong>Enhancing personal competitiveness:</strong> The book emphasizes the importance of increasing income and encourages us to continuously learn and improve our personal skills to gain greater career development space.</li>
<li><strong>Balancing life and wealth:</strong> The author reminds us that wealth is not the only goal in life. We should focus on the quality of life and the realization of personal values while pursuing wealth.</li>
<li><strong>Viewing investment rationally:</strong> This book emphasizes the importance of long-term investing and warns investors not to blindly chase short-term gains or be intimidated by market volatility. Only rationality and patience can ultimately lead to success.</li>
</ul>

  



<div
  
    class="flex px-4 py-3 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900"
  >

  <span
    
      class="text-primary-400 ltr:pr-3 rtl:pl-3 flex items-center"
    >

    

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 640 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M172.5 131.1C228.1 75.51 320.5 75.51 376.1 131.1C426.1 181.1 433.5 260.8 392.4 318.3L391.3 319.9C381 334.2 361 337.6 346.7 327.3C332.3 317 328.9 297 339.2 282.7L340.3 281.1C363.2 249 359.6 205.1 331.7 177.2C300.3 145.8 249.2 145.8 217.7 177.2L105.5 289.5C73.99 320.1 73.99 372 105.5 403.5C133.3 431.4 177.3 435 209.3 412.1L210.9 410.1C225.3 400.7 245.3 404 255.5 418.4C265.8 432.8 262.5 452.8 248.1 463.1L246.5 464.2C188.1 505.3 110.2 498.7 60.21 448.8C3.741 392.3 3.741 300.7 60.21 244.3L172.5 131.1zM467.5 380C411 436.5 319.5 436.5 263 380C213 330 206.5 251.2 247.6 193.7L248.7 192.1C258.1 177.8 278.1 174.4 293.3 184.7C307.7 194.1 311.1 214.1 300.8 229.3L299.7 230.9C276.8 262.1 280.4 306.9 308.3 334.8C339.7 366.2 390.8 366.2 422.3 334.8L534.5 222.5C566 191 566 139.1 534.5 108.5C506.7 80.63 462.7 76.99 430.7 99.9L429.1 101C414.7 111.3 394.7 107.1 384.5 93.58C374.2 79.2 377.5 59.21 391.9 48.94L393.5 47.82C451 6.731 529.8 13.25 579.8 63.24C636.3 119.7 636.3 211.3 579.8 267.7L467.5 380z"/></svg>

  </span>


  </span>

  <span
    
      class="dark:text-neutral-300"
    ><strong>Further Reading</strong>: Check out the author, <strong>Nick Maggiulli</strong>&rsquo;s blog: <a href="https://ofdollarsanddata.com/" target="_blank"><strong>Of Dollars And Data</strong></a></span>
</div>

<hr>

<section class="space-y-10 w-full">
    
    
        
            






















  <a class="flex flex-wrap article " href="/en/posts/1728295490690-book-list/">
    
        
        <div class="w-full md:w-auto h-full thumbnail nozoom thumbnailshadow md:mr-7" style="background-image:url(/posts/1728295490690-book-list/featured_hu4424409690304057825.jpg);"></div>
        
      <div class=" mt-3 md:mt-0">
      <div class="items-center text-left text-xl font-semibold">
        
        <div class="font-bold text-xl text-neutral-800 decoration-primary-500 hover:underline hover:underline-offset-2 dark:text-neutral"
          href="/en/posts/1728295490690-book-list/">Recommended Reading List</div>
        
        
        
      </div>
      <div class="text-sm text-neutral-500 dark:text-neutral-400">
        











  









  



  









<div class="flex flex-row flex-wrap items-center">
  
  
  <time datetime="2024-10-01T00:00:00&#43;00:00">1 October 2024</time><span class="px-2 text-primary-500">&middot;</span><span>
  
  
    
    
      
      
        
        
      
        
        
      
      
    
  
  <span id="views_posts/1728295490690-book-list/index.md" class="animate-pulse inline-block text-transparent max-h-3 rounded-full mt-[-2px] align-middle bg-neutral-300 dark:bg-neutral-400" title="views">loading</span>
  <span class="inline-block align-text-bottom">

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 576 512">
<path fill="currentColor" d="M288 32c-80.8 0-145.5 36.8-192.6 80.6C48.6 156 17.3 208 2.5 243.7c-3.3 7.9-3.3 16.7 0 24.6C17.3 304 48.6 356 95.4 399.4C142.5 443.2 207.2 480 288 480s145.5-36.8 192.6-80.6c46.8-43.5 78.1-95.4 93-131.1c3.3-7.9 3.3-16.7 0-24.6c-14.9-35.7-46.2-87.7-93-131.1C433.5 68.8 368.8 32 288 32zM432 256c0 79.5-64.5 144-144 144s-144-64.5-144-144s64.5-144 144-144s144 64.5 144 144zM288 192c0 35.3-28.7 64-64 64c-11.5 0-22.3-3-31.6-8.4c-.2 2.8-.4 5.5-.4 8.4c0 53 43 96 96 96s96-43 96-96s-43-96-96-96c-2.8 0-5.6 .1-8.4 .4c5.3 9.3 8.4 20.1 8.4 31.6z"/></svg>
  </span>

</span>
</span><span class="px-2 text-primary-500">&middot;</span><span>
  
  
    
    
      
      
        
        
      
        
        
      
      
    
  
  <span id="likes_posts/1728295490690-book-list/index.md"
    class="animate-pulse inline-block text-transparent max-h-3 rounded-full mt-[-2px] align-middle bg-neutral-300 dark:bg-neutral-400"
    title="likes">loading</span>
  <span class="inline-block align-text-bottom">

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512">
<path fill="currentColor" d="M47.6 300.4L228.3 469.1c7.5 7 17.4 10.9 27.7 10.9s20.2-3.9 27.7-10.9L464.4 300.4c30.4-28.3 47.6-68 47.6-109.5v-5.8c0-69.9-50.5-129.5-119.4-141C347 36.5 300.6 51.4 268 84L256 96 244 84c-32.6-32.6-79-47.5-124.6-39.9C50.5 55.6 0 115.2 0 185.1v5.8c0 41.5 17.2 81.2 47.6 109.5z"/></svg>
  </span>

</span>
</span>
  

  
  
</div>





<div class="flex flex-row flex-wrap items-center">
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  <span style="margin-top:0.5rem" class="mr-2" onclick="window.open(&#34;/en/tags/recommended/&#34;,'_self');">
    <span class="flex" style="cursor: pointer;">
  <span class="rounded-md border border-primary-400 px-1 py-[1px] text-xs font-normal text-primary-700 dark:border-primary-600 dark:text-primary-400">
    Recommended
  </span>
</span>
  </span>
  
  <span style="margin-top:0.5rem" class="mr-2" onclick="window.open(&#34;/en/tags/book/&#34;,'_self');">
    <span class="flex" style="cursor: pointer;">
  <span class="rounded-md border border-primary-400 px-1 py-[1px] text-xs font-normal text-primary-700 dark:border-primary-600 dark:text-primary-400">
    Book
  </span>
</span>
  </span>
  
  
  
  
</div>




      </div>
      
    </div>
  </a>

        
    
</section>
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Property of Money: Book Notes</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1728564107112/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1728564107112/</guid><description>Korean entrepreneur Kim Seung-ho shares his personal journey from poverty to wealth, providing practical guidance on wealth accumulation, management, and the pursuit of financial freedom.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[

<h2 class="relative group">I. Summary 
    <div id="i-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>&ldquo;Property of Money&rdquo; is Korean entrepreneur Kim Seung-ho&rsquo;s insightful account of his path to financial success. Starting from humble beginnings, he climbed the economic ladder, gaining profound insights into the multifaceted nature of money.  Driven by a desire to share his valuable experiences, the book explores five key attributes of money and outlines four essential skills necessary for achieving wealth. Through compelling stories and real-life examples, Kim Seung-ho demystifies complex economic concepts and investment principles, offering readers a practical guide towards financial freedom.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">II.  Chapter Summary 
    <div id="ii--chapter-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii--chapter-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Part 1: The Essence of Money 
    <div id="part-1-the-essence-of-money" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#part-1-the-essence-of-money" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>
<p><strong>Money is Personified:</strong> Kim personifies money, suggesting it possesses emotions and will. Your attitude towards money influences how it behaves towards you. Respect and treat it like a friend to earn its favor.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Investing in Superior Entrepreneurs:</strong>  Investing in companies and entrepreneurs more competent than oneself is a wise move, akin to partnering with them and reaping the rewards of their success. The author shares how he invested in successful companies like Microsoft, Amazon, and Nike, effectively becoming their &ldquo;partner.&rdquo;</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>The Secret of Compound Interest:</strong>  Compound interest is a fundamental principle in investment, capable of multiplying wealth. However, one must also be wary of its power when applied to debt. The author uses Warren Buffett&rsquo;s &ldquo;Mona Lisa&rdquo; analogy to illustrate the impact of compound interest.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>The Strength of Fixed Income:</strong> Stable cash flow surpasses inconsistent income, attracting and accumulating wealth. Kim compares fixed income to a well-trained army, capable of efficiently managing a large-scale organization despite smaller numbers.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Money&rsquo;s Gravitational Force:</strong> Substantial wealth attracts more wealth. Starting with small accumulations, compound interest propels wealth multiplication, much like the Earth formed from the gradual attraction of minuscule particles. The author illustrates this concept with the Han River and the Amazon River, demonstrating how small streams can converge to form vast rivers.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Highest Risk, Lowest Risk:</strong> The stock market is riskiest when everyone is bullish and chasing the latest hot stock; conversely, it&rsquo;s least risky when fear grips the market and everyone is selling.  Maintain a balanced perspective on fear and greed, embracing opportunity during widespread fear and exercising caution when greed prevails. Warren Buffet&rsquo;s famous quote, &ldquo;Be fearful when others are greedy, and greedy when others are fearful,&rdquo; encapsulates this wisdom.  The author uses the example of increased airline safety a week after an accident to illustrate this point.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Treat Others&rsquo; Money as You Treat Your Own:</strong> Treating others&rsquo; money with respect safeguards your own from similar disrespect.  Respect for others&rsquo; money is reciprocated. The author uses his attitude towards shopping carts at supermarkets to emphasize the importance of respecting others&rsquo; money.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Inheriting Millions with a &ldquo;No Loss&rdquo; Clause:</strong>  Through a hypothetical scenario, Kim highlights that preserving wealth is not straightforward. It requires learning, accumulating experience, and recognizing the significance of consistent income. The protagonist in the story inherits a substantial sum with the stipulation of no loss, ultimately realizing that maintaining wealth&rsquo;s value is no easy feat.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Rejecting Quick Riches:</strong>  The pursuit of quick wealth often leads to speculative traps and the perils of greed, ultimately ending in failure.  Building wealth demands a steady and gradual approach.  The author uses the analogy of constructing a house to demonstrate the importance of gradual wealth accumulation.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Can Economists Predict the Future?:</strong>  No one can accurately predict the macroeconomic future, especially in the long term, due to inherent uncertainties. Resist blindly following expert predictions; cultivate independent thinking and continuous learning.  Kim quotes economist John Kenneth Galbraith: &ldquo;There are two kinds of people in the world: those who don&rsquo;t know and those who don&rsquo;t know they don&rsquo;t know.&rdquo;</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Buying Samsung Stock at Samsung Securities:</strong> This anecdote illustrates the need for knowledge before venturing into investments. Avoid assumptions; understand market rules and investment tools. Kim compares the stock market to a ruthless jungle, where knowledge is essential for survival.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Changing Your Destiny Through Respectful Address:</strong> A personal experience highlights the importance of respecting others and showing genuine interest in their affairs, leading to trust, goodwill, and ultimately, good fortune.  The entrepreneur in the story habitually addresses everyone as &ldquo;that person,&rdquo; ultimately losing friends and connections.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Repeated Luck is Skill, Repeated Failure is Habit:</strong> Lucky individuals often possess greater astuteness and intelligence. They excel at observation, learning, and accumulating experience.  Conversely, repeated failure calls for introspection and addressing personal shortcomings.  The author uses examples like lottery tickets, rock-paper-scissors, and parking spots to illustrate the interplay of luck and skill.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Discerning Fact from Investment Hype in News:</strong> Using the COVID-19 pandemic as an example, Kim underlines the importance of focusing on facts and data, rather than blindly trusting media reports and expert predictions. He reached a more accurate assessment by comparing the total number of infections with the infection rate.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Each Dollar Experiences Time Differently:</strong> Borrowing Einstein&rsquo;s theory of relativity, the author suggests that money is also subject to the influence of time. Different sources of money experience time differently; always invest with money that has ample time.  Kim compares &ldquo;time-rich&rdquo; money to individuals who have more time to build relationships, fall in love, and raise children.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Diversification Isn&rsquo;t Enough:</strong> Kim critiques the misinterpretation of the saying &ldquo;Don&rsquo;t put all your eggs in one basket.&rdquo; Diversifying within a single market is merely using multiple baskets on the same shelf, still exposed to risk. He recommends spreading investments across diverse markets such as stocks, bonds, and real estate.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Three Paths to Wealth:</strong>  The author outlines three ways to become wealthy: inheritance, winning the lottery, and business success. He encourages young people to pursue entrepreneurship or engage in long-term investment. Kim elaborates on two paths to business success: starting a business or investing in successful companies.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Why Savings Don&rsquo;t Grow:</strong>  The root causes of stagnant savings lie in spending future income, neglecting asset management, undervaluing small amounts of money, and lacking investment knowledge. The author advises readers to ditch credit cards, use debit cards, and appreciate the power of accumulating small amounts of money.</p>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Part 2: The Wisdom of Investment 
    <div id="part-2-the-wisdom-of-investment" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#part-2-the-wisdom-of-investment" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>
<p><strong>Identifying Financial Illiteracy:</strong>  Kim presents a list of 90+ economic and financial terms, encouraging readers to study and master this foundational knowledge, enhancing their financial literacy. He believes financial literacy is a vital survival skill for modern individuals.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Traits of Successful Stock Market Investors:</strong> These individuals perceive themselves as business owners, hold high-quality money, and excel at buying at low prices. The author emphasizes selecting quality company stocks for long-term holding, engaging with the company&rsquo;s progress as if they were owners.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Defining True Wealth:</strong>  Genuine wealth encompasses owning a mortgage-free home, a steady stream of passive income, and the mentality of &ldquo;not needing to work.&rdquo; Kim recognizes that the standard of wealth is relative, and true wealth lies in inner freedom.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Daily Habits for Wealth Protection:</strong>  The author shares his routine of diligently reading news, scanning economic websites, and collecting information. He believes continuous learning and market awareness are crucial for maintaining investment sensitivity and making informed decisions.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>The Harsh Realities of Poverty:</strong> Drawing from personal experience, Kim paints a grim picture of poverty, encouraging readers to believe in their potential for wealth. He underscores poverty&rsquo;s power to strip dignity and even dismantle family relationships.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Three Responses to Financial Panic:</strong>  The author categorizes people&rsquo;s responses to financial panics: those who suffer losses, those unaffected, and those who capitalize and profit. He analyzes the characteristics of each group, noting that individuals with no debt and stable income weather the storm while those who seize opportunities emerge wealthier.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Rewinding Time for Wealth:</strong>  Reflecting on his experience, Kim encourages young people to start investing early and highlights the limitations of relying solely on bank savings. He suggests young people focus on long-term investments in quality company stocks instead of traditional bank savings.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>The Foundation of Wisdom:</strong> Learning fundamental knowledge is a prerequisite for gaining wisdom.  The author encourages young people to study languages and mathematics, cultivating logical thinking abilities.  He believes learning new languages broadens horizons while studying mathematics sharpens logical reasoning.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Immediate Action for Wealth:</strong>  Drawing inspiration from Marie Kondo&rsquo;s organizational methods, Kim recommends readers declutter their homes, fostering respect for possessions, and reflecting on their spending habits. He suggests that the way we treat possessions reflects our attitude towards money; respecting belongings leads to cherishing wealth.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Will the Stock Market Rise?:</strong>  Don&rsquo;t obsess over short-term market fluctuations. Focus on long-term investment, select quality companies, and patiently wait for value to return. He advises readers to identify quality companies that warrant long-term investment and maintain unwavering confidence.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Unlocking the Value of Rent Payments:</strong>  Entrepreneurs consistently paying rent possess the capacity to purchase property. The author encourages them to become property owners and capitalize on the potential for greater returns.  He emphasizes that rental income can translate into property appreciation, while property ownership offers greater security and returns.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Real Estate vs. Stock Market:</strong>  Instead of fixating on which market is superior, choose an investment approach aligned with your style and risk tolerance. Kim provides a comparative analysis of real estate and stock market investments, highlighting their unique features and potential risks.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>My Independence Day:</strong>   Using the concept of a personal &ldquo;independence day&rdquo; marked by financial independence, the author emphasizes the significance of economic self-reliance. He encourages readers to develop financial strategies and strive for early financial freedom, recognizing its role as a foundation for personal liberty.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Four Skills of Money Management:</strong>  Kim outlines four essential skills for managing money: earning, saving, preserving, and spending. He provides insights into the characteristics of each skill and recommends learning methods. He emphasizes that these are interconnected skills that need to be mastered for effective wealth management.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Investing with Values:</strong> The author shares his investment principles, avoiding industries that profit from misfortunes. He believes such money carries negative consequences and clashes with his values. He exemplifies this with businesses centered around firearms, cigarettes, and drugs.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Insurance is not Savings:</strong>  Kim criticizes the practice of insurance companies selling high-commission, low-return products disguised as savings. He advises readers to choose insurance primarily for its protection function, not as investment vehicles, and to select suitable products based on their individual needs.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Beautiful Junk:</strong>  Drawing from a luxurious travel experience, Kim conveys that experiences and memories are more valuable than material possessions.  He urges readers to avoid accumulating &ldquo;beautiful junk,&rdquo; recognizing that many purchases become unused clutter, wasting both money and space.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Separating Economics from Political Bias:</strong>  Readers are urged to approach economic news with a critical eye, avoiding interpretation solely from a political standpoint. Refer to factual data to form judgments.  Kim suggests that many media reports are politically charged, encouraging independent thinking and caution against being swayed by media biases.</p>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Part 4: The Mindset and Responsibilities of the Wealthy 
    <div id="part-4-the-mindset-and-responsibilities-of-the-wealthy" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#part-4-the-mindset-and-responsibilities-of-the-wealthy" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>The Underdog Advantage:</strong>  Using historical and business examples, the author illustrates that underdogs overcoming giants is a recurring theme. He encourages young people to embrace challenges and strive for success. He believes individuals from humble backgrounds often possess greater drive and innovation, enabling them to seize opportunities and achieve upward mobility.</li>
<li><strong>Your Personal PER:</strong>  Kim introduces the concept of Price-to-Earnings Ratio (PER) and applies it to personal careers and businesses, reminding readers to focus on the stability and sustainability of income sources. He emphasizes that high income doesn&rsquo;t equate to wealth; building systems that generate consistent income is crucial.</li>
<li><strong>Wealth Is Not Predestined:</strong> Great wealth arises from a combination of opportunities, hard work, intelligence, and luck, not from predetermined destiny. The author encourages readers to actively seek opportunities and prepare themselves, believing everyone holds the potential for success, provided they believe in themselves and strive diligently.</li>
<li><strong>Start Small, Dream Big:</strong> Young aspiring entrepreneurs are advised to gain experience and build connections by initially working in small companies.  He believes small companies offer more opportunities for learning and practical experience, facilitating rapid growth.</li>
<li><strong>Perseverance is Power:</strong>  The author emphasizes the importance of consistency and perseverance, advising readers to devote 100 days or three months to mastering a skill or forming a good habit. He believes persistence is key to success, as any skill requires continuous effort to achieve mastery.</li>
<li><strong>Limitless Business Opportunities:</strong>  Kim encourages readers to think outside the box and be receptive to business opportunities. He shares his experience of launching a flower shop, demonstrating that opportunities are present in everyday life; a keen eye can unearth suitable ventures.</li>
<li><strong>Entrepreneurship: The Path to Freedom:</strong> Entrepreneurship is championed as the only profession offering genuine control over one&rsquo;s destiny. The author encourages young people to pursue entrepreneurship, breaking free from the limitations of corporate employment. He highlights that entrepreneurship offers greater freedom, a sense of accomplishment, and the potential for significant wealth creation.</li>
<li><strong>Discerning the Nature of Money:</strong> Earn money of good character, avoiding ill-gotten gains from sources like gambling or fraud. Kim believes that good money brings blessings, while bad money carries misfortune, using examples of money obtained through gambling or fraud to illustrate the harmful effects of ill-gotten gains.</li>
<li><strong>Navigating Family Responsibilities as the Wealthiest Sibling:</strong> Kim shares guidance based on his own experience, recommending different strategies for supporting and caring for family members, depending on the scale of wealth.
<ul>
<li><strong>Under 100 Million Won:</strong> Prioritize women in the family who have contributed significantly but are often overlooked, such as sisters-in-law, along with nieces and nephews. Buy them gifts, cover family meal expenses, and provide regular financial support to parents. Avoid lending money to siblings for business ventures or assisting parents in upgrading their homes or cars.</li>
<li><strong>Under 500 Million Won:</strong> You can purchase a house or car for your parents, cover all their living expenses, and assist nieces and nephews with education costs. At this stage, you can offer measured support to siblings.</li>
<li><strong>Over 1 Billion Won:</strong> Actively help siblings escape poverty, select suitable siblings to participate in the management of family businesses, and lead the entire family to prosperity.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>The Right to Fail:</strong>  Young people are encouraged to embrace challenges without fear of failure, viewing failure as a valuable learning opportunity. He believes failure is a precious life experience, making success more appreciated when achieved.</li>
<li><strong>Can Books Create Wealth?:</strong>  Reading alone cannot make one wealthy; the key is to cultivate independent thinking and draw inspiration from books.  He suggests reading with a discerning mind, applying what you learn to your own experiences.</li>
<li><strong>God&rsquo;s Impartiality:</strong>  God&rsquo;s fairness lies in his non-intervention in earthly affairs. The author encourages readers to rely on their own efforts rather than placing their hope in divine intervention. He believes each individual is responsible for their own destiny and shouldn&rsquo;t place their hopes solely on divine intervention.</li>
<li><strong>The Passionate Entrepreneur and His Furious Wife:</strong>  A fictional story emphasizes the vital role of family harmony in business success, condemning the practice of prioritizing investments at the expense of family well-being.  The story features an entrepreneur, Mr. Song, who runs a successful dessert shop and a barbecue restaurant. He pours all the profits back into developing new menu items and his research lab, leading to financial strain at home and his wife&rsquo;s understandable frustration.</li>
<li><strong>Partnerships: A Delicate Dance:</strong>  Kim outlines the conditions and considerations for successful partnerships, emphasizing the importance of respecting partners&rsquo; money and drafting legally sound agreements.  He believes that trust and respect are paramount in any partnership, and all aspects of the agreement should be clearly defined in writing to prevent future disputes.</li>
<li><strong>Stick to the Main Road:</strong>  When investing in unfamiliar sectors, opt for companies that are industry leaders to mitigate risk. He compares investing in a leading company to navigating a well-defined road, reducing the risk of getting lost and generally offering greater security.</li>
<li><strong>The Quarter Rule:</strong>  The author unveils his personal &ldquo;Quarter Rule,&rdquo; advocating for living expenses to be capped at one-quarter of one&rsquo;s financial capacity.  This strategy allows for enjoying life while maintaining a financial safety net.</li>
<li><strong>Prayers Alone Won&rsquo;t Bring Riches:</strong>  True wealth comes through hard work, wisdom, and seizing opportunities, not reliance on divine intervention or supernatural forces. While prayer might offer spiritual solace, it cannot replace action.</li>
<li><strong>Four Habits of Saving:</strong>  Cultivate good habits early in life, starting with simple daily actions that lay a strong foundation for wealth accumulation. These habits are: stretching upon waking, making your bed, drinking a glass of water on an empty stomach each morning, and maintaining consistent sleep and wake times.</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">III. Notable Quotes 
    <div id="iii-notable-quotes" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii-notable-quotes" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;Money is personified.&rdquo;</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Money, like people, has emotions and a will; your attitude towards it influences its behavior towards you.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;Compound interest is the greatest invention of mankind, the eighth wonder of the world.&rdquo;</p>
</blockquote>
<p>The power of compounding is immense, capable of multiplying wealth. It is one of the most important principles in investing.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;Be fearful when others are greedy and greedy when others are fearful.&rdquo;</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Approach market sentiment rationally, seize opportunities during fear, exercise caution during greed.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;Treat others&rsquo; money as you treat your own.&rdquo;</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Respect for other people&rsquo;s money earns respect for yours. It reflects a fundamental principle of human interaction.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;The only way to quickly become rich is to not be in a hurry to become rich.&rdquo;</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Avoid the pitfalls of chasing quick riches, build wealth steadily and gradually.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;Not knowing is the right answer.&rdquo;</p>
</blockquote>
<p>The future is full of uncertainties. No one can accurately predict it. Maintain humility and a willingness to learn.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;An illiterate person might experience inconvenience, but a financially illiterate person cannot survive.&rdquo;</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Financial knowledge is essential for survival. Learn and master financial literacy to effectively manage wealth and avoid scams.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;The person paying rent is the landlord.&rdquo;</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Entrepreneurs capable of consistently paying rent possess the capability to own property. Seize opportunities to become property owners.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;The fastest way to become rich is to slowly become rich.&rdquo;</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Avoid the rush to wealth. Genuine wealth comes through persistent learning and gradual accumulation.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;Working hard doesn&rsquo;t guarantee wealth, acquiring wealth doesn&rsquo;t guarantee you&rsquo;ll be rich, and being rich doesn&rsquo;t guarantee happiness.&rdquo;</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Wealth is not an end but a means to an end. A balanced perspective on money is crucial for true happiness.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;Failure is a right.&rdquo;</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Young people should embrace challenges without fear of failure, viewing failure as a valuable learning experience.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“God will not make you rich.”</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Wealth comes from hard work, intelligence, and opportunity, not divine intervention or supernatural forces.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;Small change is the &ldquo;sprout&rdquo; of big money.&rdquo;</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Don&rsquo;t underestimate the power of accumulating small amounts of money. Start small and gradually build your wealth system.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“Money has different characters.”</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Earn money through ethical means and avoid ill-gotten gains like those from gambling or fraud.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">IV. Guiding Principles 
    <div id="iv-guiding-principles" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv-guiding-principles" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>&ldquo;The Attributes of Money&rdquo; provides practical guidance for finance and life, offering these key takeaways:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Perspective on Money:</strong> Respect money, utilize it wisely, and treat it as a tool to achieve your goals, not as an end in itself.</li>
<li><strong>Financial Management:</strong>  Cultivate strong financial habits, value savings, learn to invest, and protect yourself from scams.</li>
<li><strong>Investment Philosophy:</strong>  Interpret market emotions rationally, pursue long-term investments, choose quality companies, and implement a well-defined asset allocation strategy.</li>
<li><strong>Life Philosophy:</strong>  Embrace challenges, learn from failures, and continuously learn and grow. Strive for financial and spiritual freedom.</li>
<li><strong>Family Values:</strong>  Prioritize family harmony, cherish your loved ones, and fulfill your responsibilities towards them.</li>
<li><strong>Ethics in Action:</strong>  Show respect for others, be willing to help, and cultivate kindness in your interactions.</li>
</ul>
<hr>

<section class="space-y-10 w-full">
    
    
        
            






















  <a class="flex flex-wrap article " href="/en/posts/1728295490690-book-list/">
    
        
        <div class="w-full md:w-auto h-full thumbnail nozoom thumbnailshadow md:mr-7" style="background-image:url(/posts/1728295490690-book-list/featured_hu4424409690304057825.jpg);"></div>
        
      <div class=" mt-3 md:mt-0">
      <div class="items-center text-left text-xl font-semibold">
        
        <div class="font-bold text-xl text-neutral-800 decoration-primary-500 hover:underline hover:underline-offset-2 dark:text-neutral"
          href="/en/posts/1728295490690-book-list/">Recommended Reading List</div>
        
        
        
      </div>
      <div class="text-sm text-neutral-500 dark:text-neutral-400">
        











  









  



  









<div class="flex flex-row flex-wrap items-center">
  
  
  <time datetime="2024-10-01T00:00:00&#43;00:00">1 October 2024</time><span class="px-2 text-primary-500">&middot;</span><span>
  
  
    
    
      
      
        
        
      
        
        
      
      
    
  
  <span id="views_posts/1728295490690-book-list/index.md" class="animate-pulse inline-block text-transparent max-h-3 rounded-full mt-[-2px] align-middle bg-neutral-300 dark:bg-neutral-400" title="views">loading</span>
  <span class="inline-block align-text-bottom">

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 576 512">
<path fill="currentColor" d="M288 32c-80.8 0-145.5 36.8-192.6 80.6C48.6 156 17.3 208 2.5 243.7c-3.3 7.9-3.3 16.7 0 24.6C17.3 304 48.6 356 95.4 399.4C142.5 443.2 207.2 480 288 480s145.5-36.8 192.6-80.6c46.8-43.5 78.1-95.4 93-131.1c3.3-7.9 3.3-16.7 0-24.6c-14.9-35.7-46.2-87.7-93-131.1C433.5 68.8 368.8 32 288 32zM432 256c0 79.5-64.5 144-144 144s-144-64.5-144-144s64.5-144 144-144s144 64.5 144 144zM288 192c0 35.3-28.7 64-64 64c-11.5 0-22.3-3-31.6-8.4c-.2 2.8-.4 5.5-.4 8.4c0 53 43 96 96 96s96-43 96-96s-43-96-96-96c-2.8 0-5.6 .1-8.4 .4c5.3 9.3 8.4 20.1 8.4 31.6z"/></svg>
  </span>

</span>
</span><span class="px-2 text-primary-500">&middot;</span><span>
  
  
    
    
      
      
        
        
      
        
        
      
      
    
  
  <span id="likes_posts/1728295490690-book-list/index.md"
    class="animate-pulse inline-block text-transparent max-h-3 rounded-full mt-[-2px] align-middle bg-neutral-300 dark:bg-neutral-400"
    title="likes">loading</span>
  <span class="inline-block align-text-bottom">

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512">
<path fill="currentColor" d="M47.6 300.4L228.3 469.1c7.5 7 17.4 10.9 27.7 10.9s20.2-3.9 27.7-10.9L464.4 300.4c30.4-28.3 47.6-68 47.6-109.5v-5.8c0-69.9-50.5-129.5-119.4-141C347 36.5 300.6 51.4 268 84L256 96 244 84c-32.6-32.6-79-47.5-124.6-39.9C50.5 55.6 0 115.2 0 185.1v5.8c0 41.5 17.2 81.2 47.6 109.5z"/></svg>
  </span>

</span>
</span>
  

  
  
</div>





<div class="flex flex-row flex-wrap items-center">
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  <span style="margin-top:0.5rem" class="mr-2" onclick="window.open(&#34;/en/tags/recommended/&#34;,'_self');">
    <span class="flex" style="cursor: pointer;">
  <span class="rounded-md border border-primary-400 px-1 py-[1px] text-xs font-normal text-primary-700 dark:border-primary-600 dark:text-primary-400">
    Recommended
  </span>
</span>
  </span>
  
  <span style="margin-top:0.5rem" class="mr-2" onclick="window.open(&#34;/en/tags/book/&#34;,'_self');">
    <span class="flex" style="cursor: pointer;">
  <span class="rounded-md border border-primary-400 px-1 py-[1px] text-xs font-normal text-primary-700 dark:border-primary-600 dark:text-primary-400">
    Book
  </span>
</span>
  </span>
  
  
  
  
</div>




      </div>
      
    </div>
  </a>

        
    
</section>
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>The Psychology of Money: Book Notes</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1728478918602/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1728478918602/</guid><description>This book, focusing on the psychology of money, states that the key to financial success is not intellect but behavior. Through numerous real-life examples and stories, it reveals the psychological weaknesses, biases, and behavioral patterns that influence human financial decisions, proposing strategies for making smarter choices in personal finance.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[

<h2 class="relative group">I. Summary 
    <div id="i-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>The central argument of the book is that financial success is less about IQ and more about how you behave. Author Morgan Housel argues that by understanding the common psychological pitfalls associated with money, we can make better decisions. He illustrates this through a series of compelling stories and case studies, shedding light on our financial decision-making process.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">II. Chapter Summaries 
    <div id="ii-chapter-summaries" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii-chapter-summaries" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p><strong>1. No One&rsquo;s Crazy</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>People’s unique experiences shape their financial perspectives and actions, leading to seemingly irrational yet logically justifiable behaviors.</li>
<li>For example, low-income individuals might be drawn to lotteries as their perceived only shot at a life-altering fortune.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>2. Luck &amp; Risk</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Nothing is as good or as bad as it seems, as luck and risk play crucial roles in personal outcomes.</li>
<li>Bill Gates getting into a high school with a computer was luck. His friend Kent Evans dying in a mountain climbing accident was risk.</li>
<li>Recognizing the influence of luck and risk helps avoid over-attributing success or failure solely to personal effort or poor decisions.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>3. Never Enough</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Contentment is key in finance. The pursuit of &ldquo;never enough&rdquo; leads to a dangerous cycle of insatiable desire that can ultimately lead to ruin.</li>
<li>Former McKinsey CEO Rajat Gupta and Ponzi schemer Bernie Madoff are cited as examples of individuals who lost everything due to greed.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>4. Confounding Compounding</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Compounding’s power lies in long-term accumulation, allowing even small gains to snowball into extraordinary results.</li>
<li>Warren Buffett&rsquo;s immense wealth is attributed not just to skilled investment but to 70 years of consistent investing, highlighting the power of time.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>5. Getting Wealthy vs. Staying Wealthy</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Getting wealthy requires taking risks, while staying wealthy requires humility, frugality, and respecting the fleeting nature of good fortune.</li>
<li>Trading legend Jesse Livermore, despite remarkable success, fell victim to overconfidence and excessive risk-taking, ultimately leading to bankruptcy and suicide.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>6. Tails, You Win</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>In business and investing, &ldquo;tail events&rdquo; (rare, high-impact events) often disproportionately drive overall results.</li>
<li>Walt Disney produced hundreds of films, but the success of a single one, Snow White, propelled his entire enterprise to unimaginable heights.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>7. Freedom</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>The greatest dividend of wealth is the ability to control your time, offering the ultimate flexibility to pursue your passions and spend time with loved ones.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>8. The Ferrari Fallacy</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>People care less about your wealth than you think. Their attention is often directed towards their own desires and comparing themselves to you.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>9. Wealth is What You Don&rsquo;t See</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>True wealth lies not in flashy possessions but in the unseen: financial security, flexibility, and the ability to make choices.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>10. Save Money</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Building wealth hinges on your savings rate, which is driven by lifestyle choices and managing desires.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>11. Reasonable &gt; Rational</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>In financial decisions, making reasonable choices that you can stick with is often more effective than striving for absolute rationality.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>12. Surprise!</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>History is full of surprises, so relying solely on historical patterns to predict the future is unreliable. Recognizing the constant possibility of the unexpected is crucial.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>13. Room for Error</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>The most important part of every plan is planning on your plan not going according to plan: Building in a margin of safety is crucial.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>14. You&rsquo;ll Change</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Our goals, thoughts, and aspirations change over time. Acknowledging this is essential when making long-term financial plans. Avoid extreme financial goals, embracing the fluid nature of life.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>15. Nothing&rsquo;s Free</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Everything has a price. Success in investing comes with costs: volatility, fear, and uncertainty. Viewing these as fees for a valuable service rather than penalties to avoid helps navigate the emotional rollercoaster of investing.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>16. No One&rsquo;s Crazy (Reprise)</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Avoid blindly following financial advice from people with different circumstances and timelines than your own.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>17. The Seduction of Pessimism</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Pessimism often seems more intelligent and gains more attention, even though the world has generally improved significantly over time.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>18. When You Believe Anything</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>The power of narratives shapes our beliefs. The more we want something to be true, the more likely we are to embrace narratives that inflate its likelihood, especially in high-risk, high-reward scenarios like investing.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>19. Summary</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>This chapter provides a recap of the key principles and advice from previous chapters to guide sound financial decision-making.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>20. Confessions</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>The author shares his own personal approach to money management, highlighting the importance of seeking financial independence and emphasizing long-term investing.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Appendix: A Brief History of the American Consumer</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Post-WWII, the US deliberately engineered the American consumer through low-interest rates, consumer credit, and programs like the GI Bill, fostering a culture of consumption and economic growth.</li>
<li>From the 1950s to the 1970s, income distribution remained relatively equitable, the debt was manageable, and confidence in a better future was high.</li>
<li>The 1980s onwards witnessed growing income inequality. The aspirational lifestyles of a small group of prosperous individuals diverged drastically from those of the average person, fostering a culture of keeping up appearances, fueled by debt.</li>
<li>The 2008 financial crisis, a culmination of a debt bubble, exposed the cracks in this system.</li>
<li>Recent years have seen a rise in social unrest tied to income inequality, prompting individuals to question the current economic and social model.</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">III. Memorable Quotes 
    <div id="iii-memorable-quotes" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii-memorable-quotes" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;Nothing is as good or as bad as it seems.&rdquo;</p>
</blockquote>
<ul>
<li>Life’s outcomes are influenced by chance and factors outside our control. This quote urges us to be mindful of the unpredictable nature of events.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;The hardest financial skill is getting the goalpost to stop moving.&rdquo;</p>
</blockquote>
<ul>
<li>Contentment is essential for financial well-being. Constantly shifting financial goals in pursuit of &ldquo;more&rdquo; can become a destructive cycle.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;The greatest dividend of wealth is the ability to control your time.&rdquo;</p>
</blockquote>
<ul>
<li>Wealth allows us to free ourselves from time constraints, enabling us to spend our time as we see fit.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;Wealth is what you don&rsquo;t see.&rdquo;</p>
</blockquote>
<ul>
<li>True wealth resides in our ability to make choices and have options, not in material possessions.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>“Save Money. Just save.”</p>
</blockquote>
<ul>
<li>Saving should be a default behavior, a fundamental habit for financial stability and future flexibility.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>“No One’s Crazy (Reprise).”</p>
</blockquote>
<ul>
<li>Recognize that financial advice must be individualized. Avoid mimicking strategies without considering personal circumstances and goals.</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">IV. Practical Takeaways 
    <div id="iv-practical-takeaways" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv-practical-takeaways" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<ul>
<li><strong>Acknowledge your psychological biases</strong> – Understand your weaknesses related to managing money and avoid impulsive decisions.</li>
<li><strong>View money as a tool, not an end goal</strong> – Strive to use wealth as a means to achieve freedom and happiness, not to pursue material possessions.</li>
<li><strong>Create a financial plan that makes sense to you</strong> – Develop a plan, tailored to your needs and risk tolerance, that fosters financial stability. Incorporate a margin of safety for unforeseen events and market fluctuations.</li>
<li><strong>Invest for the long-term and stay the course</strong> – Compounding works best over long periods. Choose an investment strategy that resonates with your goals and  commit to it, riding out the inevitable market ups and downs.</li>
<li><strong>Pursue time freedom and happiness</strong> –  Remember that the ultimate goal of acquiring wealth is to create a life of greater freedom and happiness.</li>
</ul>
<hr>

<section class="space-y-10 w-full">
    
    
        
            






















  <a class="flex flex-wrap article " href="/en/posts/1728295490690-book-list/">
    
        
        <div class="w-full md:w-auto h-full thumbnail nozoom thumbnailshadow md:mr-7" style="background-image:url(/posts/1728295490690-book-list/featured_hu4424409690304057825.jpg);"></div>
        
      <div class=" mt-3 md:mt-0">
      <div class="items-center text-left text-xl font-semibold">
        
        <div class="font-bold text-xl text-neutral-800 decoration-primary-500 hover:underline hover:underline-offset-2 dark:text-neutral"
          href="/en/posts/1728295490690-book-list/">Recommended Reading List</div>
        
        
        
      </div>
      <div class="text-sm text-neutral-500 dark:text-neutral-400">
        











  









  



  









<div class="flex flex-row flex-wrap items-center">
  
  
  <time datetime="2024-10-01T00:00:00&#43;00:00">1 October 2024</time><span class="px-2 text-primary-500">&middot;</span><span>
  
  
    
    
      
      
        
        
      
        
        
      
      
    
  
  <span id="views_posts/1728295490690-book-list/index.md" class="animate-pulse inline-block text-transparent max-h-3 rounded-full mt-[-2px] align-middle bg-neutral-300 dark:bg-neutral-400" title="views">loading</span>
  <span class="inline-block align-text-bottom">

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 576 512">
<path fill="currentColor" d="M288 32c-80.8 0-145.5 36.8-192.6 80.6C48.6 156 17.3 208 2.5 243.7c-3.3 7.9-3.3 16.7 0 24.6C17.3 304 48.6 356 95.4 399.4C142.5 443.2 207.2 480 288 480s145.5-36.8 192.6-80.6c46.8-43.5 78.1-95.4 93-131.1c3.3-7.9 3.3-16.7 0-24.6c-14.9-35.7-46.2-87.7-93-131.1C433.5 68.8 368.8 32 288 32zM432 256c0 79.5-64.5 144-144 144s-144-64.5-144-144s64.5-144 144-144s144 64.5 144 144zM288 192c0 35.3-28.7 64-64 64c-11.5 0-22.3-3-31.6-8.4c-.2 2.8-.4 5.5-.4 8.4c0 53 43 96 96 96s96-43 96-96s-43-96-96-96c-2.8 0-5.6 .1-8.4 .4c5.3 9.3 8.4 20.1 8.4 31.6z"/></svg>
  </span>

</span>
</span><span class="px-2 text-primary-500">&middot;</span><span>
  
  
    
    
      
      
        
        
      
        
        
      
      
    
  
  <span id="likes_posts/1728295490690-book-list/index.md"
    class="animate-pulse inline-block text-transparent max-h-3 rounded-full mt-[-2px] align-middle bg-neutral-300 dark:bg-neutral-400"
    title="likes">loading</span>
  <span class="inline-block align-text-bottom">

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512">
<path fill="currentColor" d="M47.6 300.4L228.3 469.1c7.5 7 17.4 10.9 27.7 10.9s20.2-3.9 27.7-10.9L464.4 300.4c30.4-28.3 47.6-68 47.6-109.5v-5.8c0-69.9-50.5-129.5-119.4-141C347 36.5 300.6 51.4 268 84L256 96 244 84c-32.6-32.6-79-47.5-124.6-39.9C50.5 55.6 0 115.2 0 185.1v5.8c0 41.5 17.2 81.2 47.6 109.5z"/></svg>
  </span>

</span>
</span>
  

  
  
</div>





<div class="flex flex-row flex-wrap items-center">
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  <span style="margin-top:0.5rem" class="mr-2" onclick="window.open(&#34;/en/tags/recommended/&#34;,'_self');">
    <span class="flex" style="cursor: pointer;">
  <span class="rounded-md border border-primary-400 px-1 py-[1px] text-xs font-normal text-primary-700 dark:border-primary-600 dark:text-primary-400">
    Recommended
  </span>
</span>
  </span>
  
  <span style="margin-top:0.5rem" class="mr-2" onclick="window.open(&#34;/en/tags/book/&#34;,'_self');">
    <span class="flex" style="cursor: pointer;">
  <span class="rounded-md border border-primary-400 px-1 py-[1px] text-xs font-normal text-primary-700 dark:border-primary-600 dark:text-primary-400">
    Book
  </span>
</span>
  </span>
  
  
  
  
</div>




      </div>
      
    </div>
  </a>

        
    
</section>
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>00483 Rock-solid asset allocation,Investment strategies based on asset allocation and risk management</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1728265687577/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1728265687577/</guid><description>This live stream focuses on the core concept of &amp;#39;wealth is a gift&amp;#39;. James explains the importance of investing and financial management, the advantages of index investing, the relationship between risk tolerance and investment returns, and how to allocate your assets reasonably. During the Q&amp;amp;A session, students raised questions about TQQQ investment, Beta calculation, asset allocation strategies, and the investment market in mainland China. James answered these questions in detail and shared numerous experiences and cases to help students overcome psychological barriers in investment and solidify their long-term investment philosophy.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<lite-youtube videoid="eSkubAhBlhE" playlabel="eSkubAhBlhE" params=""></lite-youtube>



<h2 class="relative group">I. Theme of the Episode 
    <div id="i-theme-of-the-episode" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-theme-of-the-episode" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>The theme of this episode is &ldquo;Investing and Financial Management, Wealth is a Gift.&rdquo; The core viewpoints  are: <strong>Wealth is innate, but one must be informed to realize it; investing and financial management is an important way to accumulate wealth; index investing is an effective method to achieve long-term stable growth; rational asset allocation and risk control are the keys to investment success; and overcoming psychological barriers in investment and solidifying the long-term investment philosophy are crucial to ultimately achieving financial freedom.</strong></p>


<h2 class="relative group">II. Summary of the Briefing 
    <div id="ii-summary-of-the-briefing" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii-summary-of-the-briefing" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<ul>
<li><strong>Wealth is a Gift:</strong> Wealth is innate, and being informed of this fact makes a huge difference. While successful entrepreneurs like Elon Musk are a minority, most people need to be told that &ldquo;wealth is a gift,&rdquo; and they need to learn how to invest and manage their finances to achieve wealth growth.</li>
<li><strong>The Power of Index Investing and Compound Interest:</strong> Index investing is an effective way to achieve long-term stable returns, and its compounding effect is astonishing. For example, investing $1,500 per month for 40 years with a 14% annualized return will yield $2.6 million. <strong>Even small amounts of money can accumulate considerable wealth through consistent long-term investment.</strong></li>
<li><strong>High Risk, High Return?</strong>: High risk doesn&rsquo;t necessarily lead to high returns. Whether you can bear the risk determines whether you can ultimately achieve high returns. Don&rsquo;t overestimate your risk tolerance. Your risk appetite should be determined by an asset allocation that you can withstand even if your investment goes to zero. <strong>For example, if you cannot afford the risk of TQQQ going to zero, you should not invest in TQQQ.</strong></li>
<li><strong>Choosing Investment Targets</strong>: It is recommended to invest in the global Nasdaq 100 index fund (QQQ). Those with insufficient funds or who are already retired can consider investing in SPY or high-dividend ETFs. Avoid investing in individual stocks because they tend to disappear over the long term, while index funds can continue to exist. <strong>The half-life of individual stocks is 10 years; out of 100 stocks, there may be less than three left after 50 years.</strong></li>
<li><strong>Investment Mindset</strong>: The market will eventually rise, and investment requires patience. Always stay optimistic, even if the investment goes to zero. Learning about investing and financial management requires continuous thinking, like peeling an onion, layer by layer, to elevate the energy of the spiritual level. <strong>Investing is like the Yellow Mountain, eternally unchanging, yet different every day; every learning experience will bring new insights.</strong></li>
<li><strong>Asset Allocation</strong>: Asset allocation is like building a house; it is a big project that requires comprehensive planning, not something simple. It is necessary to consider many factors, such as whether you are retired, your age, income, debt, and cash flow, to formulate a reasonable asset allocation plan. <strong>You need to carefully study the articles and videos on asset allocation provided by James to develop a plan that suits you.</strong></li>
<li><strong>Do Not  Blindly Trust External Information</strong>: Financial professionals often only consider their interests, so do not easily believe their advice. Think independently, study carefully, and do not be swayed by external information and noise. <strong>Most of the outside information is garbage; do not be affected by it, focus on learning James&rsquo; investment philosophy.</strong></li>
<li><strong>Balancing Risk and Reward</strong>: Do not excessively pursue high returns or completely risk-free investments; balance risk and reward. Avoid changing investment strategies easily to prevent additional costs due to frequent trading. <strong>James&rsquo; investment methods can guarantee asset appreciation and relative safety, avoiding extreme situations.</strong></li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">III. Q&amp;A Session 
    <div id="iii-qa-session" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii-qa-session" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p><strong>IM:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>Sharing: Learning about investment is like peeling an onion; at first, the amount of information is overwhelming, but as you learn more, you will gradually understand the core idea and ultimately reach the realm of &ldquo;the great Dao is simple.&rdquo;</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Question 1: What do you think about the idea that &ldquo;investing is simple&rdquo;?</p>
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo; Response: Such views often mistake ignorance for inaction and do not truly understand the complexity and risks of investment.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p>Question 2: How should we communicate with friends who don&rsquo;t understand index investing?</p>
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo; Response: You can start by briefly introducing the concept and advantages of index investing and suggest that they watch related videos to learn. Don&rsquo;t force them to accept it, everyone has their own choices. <strong>Just like preaching, we can only try our best to spread the message; whether it&rsquo;s ultimately accepted depends on the individual.</strong></li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>LAN:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>Question 1: How to calculate Beta? What is the actual Beta value of a leveraged ETF?</p>
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo; Response: You can refer to the link to the article on Beta calculation on the message board. The actual Beta value of a leveraged ETF may deviate from the theoretical value due to factors such as market volatility and friction costs. <strong>When market volatility is large, the wear and tear of leveraged ETFs will be more serious, resulting in an actual Beta value lower than the theoretical value.</strong></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p>Question 2: Why is there a huge difference in final return between scenario 3 and scenario 4.1 in the 005 topic?</p>
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo; Response: Scenario 4.1 is where no money is withdrawn from the investment, so the final return will be higher.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p>Question 3: How to adjust Beta in a rising market?</p>
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo; Response:  The adjustment of Beta should be determined by your own risk tolerance, not by the market trend. <strong>Do not try to predict the market, just keep a fixed Beta value.</strong></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p>Question 4:  For investments in Taiwan, should I choose Q2D or 00670L?</p>
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo; Response: 00670L is recommended because it includes New Taiwan dollar hedging, which can reduce the risk caused by exchange rate fluctuations. <strong>Don&rsquo;t change investment targets frequently, choose one that suits you and hold it for the long term.</strong></li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Nai Xin:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Wealth is a gift, just as self-confidence is a gift; everyone has potential, but it needs to be stimulated. The key to investing and financial management lies in learning. Once you have mastered the correct investment method, you can focus on your own career and life and let wealth grow naturally over time. <strong>Overcome fear, build confidence, and you can realize your potential, gain wealth, and achieve success.</strong></li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Jason:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Understanding &ldquo;buy whenever you have money,&rdquo; but still finding it difficult to overcome psychological fluctuations when the market rises or falls sharply.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo; Response:  Overcoming psychological fluctuations takes time and experience. You can try to make a small number of trades, experience the impact of market fluctuations, and gradually adapt to market changes.</li>
<li>IM Supplement: You can overcome psychological barriers by imagining starting to invest two years later and understanding that &ldquo;money arrives at different points in time.&rdquo;<strong>Don&rsquo;t worry about buying at the lowest point; as long as you stick to long-term investment, you can get good returns.</strong></li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Hai Rui Ji:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>Sharing:</p>
<ol>
<li>Thank you James for selflessly sharing your investment philosophy; students learn from each other and make progress together.</li>
<li>James&rsquo; investment philosophy requires continuous learning and understanding to grasp it fully. &ldquo;Never sell&rdquo; does not mean you cannot sell, but that you should develop a reasonable investment strategy based on your own situation. ** &ldquo;Never sell&rdquo; refers to mentally ignoring market fluctuations and adhering to a long-term investment philosophy.**</li>
<li>Investment philosophy needs to keep pace with the times and adjust investment strategies according to changes in the environment.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<p>Question: Already answered in the video.</p>
</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Li Zi:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: To overcome psychological barriers to investment, manage accounts separately, using one part for long-term investment and the other for tentative operations, such as selling covered calls. This satisfies the desire to trade and avoids losses due to frequent trading.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo; Response: You only know what is best after you have experienced it. Experience in trading can lead to a firmer commitment to a long-term investment strategy. <strong>Trying different trading strategies can help you understand the advantages of long-term investment and ultimately achieve the state of &ldquo;daily reduction for the Dao.&rdquo;</strong></li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>T:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>Question 1: Why has the capital market in mainland China performed poorly for a long time?</p>
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo; Response: Emerging markets take time to mature. The Chinese market is like the Taiwanese market 50 years ago. It has the potential to rise in the long term, but its return may be lower than that of the US market. <strong>Investment should focus on sustainable development markets. The US market has advantages in terms of systems and industries.</strong></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p>Question 2: Under foreign exchange control, how do I invest in US index funds? Are there any risks?</p>
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo; Response: You can invest by purchasing ETFs listed in China that track US index funds, such as 513100. Foreign exchange controls mainly restrict the physical flow of funds, and buying ETFs is not restricted. The current scale of such investment is small and will not trigger a quota limit. <strong>Even with foreign exchange control, it is still possible to allocate global assets through legal channels.</strong></li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">IV. Key Takeaways 
    <div id="iv-key-takeaways" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv-key-takeaways" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>Wealth is a Gift
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Everyone has the potential for wealth, but they must be informed to realize it and learn how to invest and manage their finances to achieve wealth growth.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Learning Increases Daily, the Dao Decreases Daily
&ndash; IM</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Learning about investing and financial management is a process of continuous improvement. At first, you will be exposed to a large amount of information, but as your understanding deepens, you will gradually simplify your investment strategy and eventually reach the state of &ldquo;the great Dao is simple.&rdquo;</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The Difficult to Return to After Seeing a Vast Ocean
&ndash; Li Zi &amp; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Only after experiencing something can you know what is best. In investing, only after actually operating and experiencing market fluctuations and the impact of different investment strategies can you more firmly choose the long-term investment strategy that suits you.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The More Money You Borrow, the More Money You Have
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Understand and control risk, not avoid it. Understanding how to use leverage can accelerate wealth growth, but only with proper risk management, such as building a solid asset allocation.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Cash is Air
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Cash is very important and you must keep enough cash to deal with market fluctuations and emergencies.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">V. Summary 
    <div id="v-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#v-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This live stream focused on the theme of &ldquo;Wealth is a gift.&rdquo; James explained the importance of investing and financial management, the advantages of index investing, the relationship between risk tolerance and investment returns, and how to conduct reasonable asset allocation in a simple and profound way. During the Q&amp;A session, students actively questioned their own issues and confusions. James patiently and meticulously answered them by combining practical cases and his own experience, helping the students better understand and master the knowledge and methods of investing and financial management. He also guided the students to overcome psychological barriers in investments, establish a firm long-term investment philosophy, and ultimately achieve financial freedom.</p>

  



<div
  
    class="flex px-4 py-3 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900"
  >

  <span
    
      class="text-primary-400 ltr:pr-3 rtl:pl-3 flex items-center"
    >

    

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M506.3 417l-213.3-364c-16.33-28-57.54-28-73.98 0l-213.2 364C-10.59 444.9 9.849 480 42.74 480h426.6C502.1 480 522.6 445 506.3 417zM232 168c0-13.25 10.75-24 24-24S280 154.8 280 168v128c0 13.25-10.75 24-23.1 24S232 309.3 232 296V168zM256 416c-17.36 0-31.44-14.08-31.44-31.44c0-17.36 14.07-31.44 31.44-31.44s31.44 14.08 31.44 31.44C287.4 401.9 273.4 416 256 416z"/></svg>

  </span>


  </span>

  <span
    
      class="dark:text-neutral-300"
    ><strong>Disclaimer:</strong> This article is a personal learning summary and does not constitute any investment advice.</span>
</div>

]]></content:encoded></item></channel></rss>