<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>QQQI on QQQ Investor</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/tags/qqqi/</link><description>Recent content in QQQI on QQQ Investor</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jomonylw.github.io/en/tags/qqqi/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>00547 The Real Risk Is Not the Drop; Only Asset Allocation That Survives Simulation Tests Can Endure</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1766882241086/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1766882241086/</guid><description>This episode marks the first class of 2026. Teacher James first emphasized the importance of positive thinking and positive language for life and investing, believing that human intention combines with cosmic fluctuations to create one&amp;#39;s reality. He then detailed a major update to the backtesting tool, specifically changing the calculation benchmark from &amp;#39;monthly closing price&amp;#39; to &amp;#39;monthly lowest price,&amp;#39; and explained the impact of this on leverage ratios for US market asset allocation. The sharing session covered various topics including investment mindset, asset allocation strategies, retirement planning (retiring with 15x annual expenses), overseas asset selection, and coping with geopolitical risks. The content is rich and practical.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<lite-youtube videoid="jGb4pHUasMM" playlabel="jGb4pHUasMM" params=""></lite-youtube>



<h2 class="relative group">I. Topic of the Episode 
    <div id="i-topic-of-the-episode" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-topic-of-the-episode" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>The core of this episode focuses on two main areas: First, emphasizing <strong>mindset building for investment and life</strong>, specifically shaping one&rsquo;s wealth and happiness through &ldquo;positive affirmations&rdquo; and extreme optimism. Second, sharing <strong>updates on investment tools and strategy optimization</strong>, particularly the algorithm modification of the backtesting tool and its impact on leverage allocation. It also deeply explores the feasibility of achieving early retirement (15x annual expenses) by combining high-dividend products (like QQQI) with growth assets (like QQQ).</p>


<h2 class="relative group">II. Presentation Content 
    <div id="ii-presentation-content" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii-presentation-content" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Mindset Building and Investment Philosophy 
    <div id="mindset-building-and-investment-philosophy" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#mindset-building-and-investment-philosophy" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>The Power of Positive Intention</strong>: Teacher James opened by emphasizing that our lives and the world are created by our thoughts (brainwaves). One must say positive things to oneself daily, such as &ldquo;I am the best,&rdquo; &ldquo;I am rich,&rdquo; and &ldquo;I am happy.&rdquo; By irrigating the subconscious, we attract positive energy, thereby transforming the external environment into what we desire. This applies not only to investing but to life as a whole.</li>
<li><strong>No-Brainer Investing</strong>: Investing in index funds should adopt a &ldquo;no-brainer investment method,&rdquo; ignoring short-term market turbulence, international situations, economic analysis, and financial reports. Admitting one&rsquo;s &ldquo;incompetence&rdquo; in predicting the market allows one to easily obtain long-term market returns.</li>
<li><strong>Information Channels</strong>:
<ul>
<li>Given the excessive ads in some YouTube videos (like 00451), it is suggested that students switch to <strong>Podcast</strong> or <strong>Himalaya</strong> platforms for listening.</li>
<li>A friend from China (Tree Kevin/Da Shu Kevin) has migrated the audio content to Himalaya, making it convenient for students in mainland China to listen.</li>
<li>All important information and links have been summarized in the &ldquo;<strong>Newcomer&rsquo;s Sunflower Bible</strong>&rdquo; for easy reference.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Investment Tool Updates and Asset Allocation Strategy 
    <div id="investment-tool-updates-and-asset-allocation-strategy" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#investment-tool-updates-and-asset-allocation-strategy" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Major Update to Backtesting Tool</strong>:
<ul>
<li><strong>Logic Modification</strong>: When calculating the maintenance ratio, the backtesting tool has changed the data benchmark from the previous &ldquo;<strong>monthly closing price</strong>&rdquo; to the &ldquo;<strong>monthly lowest price</strong>.&rdquo;</li>
<li><strong>Reason for Modification</strong>: In the actual market, asset prices may hit a low point mid-month (e.g., on the 8th or 15th), triggering a Margin Call (liquidation), without waiting for the month-end close. Therefore, using the lowest price for backtesting aligns better with realistic risks.</li>
<li><strong>Impact on Asset Allocation</strong>: This change does not affect the 80/20 allocation in Taiwan, but it impacts <strong>US market asset allocation</strong>. The previous 2.0x leverage (pledge loan accounting for 20% of total assets) would fail in worst-case scenarios and <strong>needs to be lowered to 1.9x</strong> (i.e., borrowing a maximum of $19,000 against $100,000 in assets).</li>
<li><strong>Tool Access and Usage</strong>: New tool instructions, engine explanations, and GitHub source code links have been provided. Users in mainland China who cannot access Vercel can download the source code via GitHub and use it offline in a local Docker environment.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Rebalancing Strategy Details</strong>:
<ul>
<li><strong>Smart Rebalancing</strong>: Switching between Cash and QLD.</li>
<li><strong>Flexible Rebalancing</strong>: Divided into two scenarios.
<ol>
<li><strong>Insufficient Cash</strong>: During a decline, transfer a portion of QQQ to QLD without consuming cash.</li>
<li><strong>Sufficient Cash</strong>: Further divided into two modes:
<ul>
<li><strong>Defensive</strong>: Buy with cash when the market falls; switch between Cash and QLD when the market rises.</li>
<li><strong>Aggressive</strong>: Buy with cash when the market falls; when the market rises, sell QLD and convert directly to QQQ instead of cash.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Cash Management Strategy</strong>:
<ul>
<li>Teacher James personally holds <strong>almost zero cash</strong>. Daily expenses are covered by pledge loans borrowed only when needed (e.g., the day before credit card payments).</li>
<li>Idle cash should be invested in cash-equivalent assets, such as US BOX (BIL/SGOV/SHV) or Taiwan&rsquo;s 00865B, and sold only when money is needed.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Critique of Insurance</strong>:
<ul>
<li>The teacher believes that buying insurance is a form of laziness and inertia, an attempt to transfer risk to insurance companies. He refers to insurance companies as &ldquo;<strong>poverty manufacturing machines</strong>&rdquo; and &ldquo;<strong>viruses of society</strong>,&rdquo; considering the financial industry to be &ldquo;licensed scam groups&rdquo; that investors should not rely on.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Asset and ETF Information</strong>:
<ul>
<li><strong>Non-US Assets</strong>: Provided XNAS, CNDX, EQAC, EQQQ, etc., as references, which may not be subject to US estate tax.</li>
<li><strong>Hong Kong High-Dividend Alternatives</strong>: 3451 or 9451 can serve as alternatives to QQQI; 3416 can also be considered.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">III. Q&amp;A Session 
    <div id="iii-qa-session" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii-qa-session" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Weng 
    <div id="weng" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#weng" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Question</strong>: As a young person in Japan, if I use a Home Equity Line of Credit (HELOC) and credit to invest in a Japanese Nasdaq 100 index fund, what should I do if the Yen appreciates significantly later (e.g., from 157 to 100)?
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo; Reply</strong>: Absolutely no problem. Your income is in Yen, and your loan is in Yen. As long as your salary is sufficient to cover the monthly loan payments, there is no need to worry. Stock and exchange rate fluctuations are irrelevant to you because you do not need to sell stocks to repay the debt. Even if there is a 30% loss in exchange rates, two years of stock market gains will be enough to cover it, so there is no need for concern.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Lulin 
    <div id="lulin" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#lulin" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing</strong>: She began living a retirement life in July 2025 using the method taught by the teacher (about 25x annual expenses), traveling everywhere. She found that the &ldquo;two-track parallel&rdquo; approach (part high-dividend + part growth) she adopted at the time coincides with the teacher&rsquo;s recently shared strategy of &ldquo;retiring with 15-20x annual expenses.&rdquo; She personally verified that this retirement lifestyle is very comfortable and free, and that assets continue to grow while being withdrawn, truly experiencing the feeling of &ldquo;endless money.&rdquo;
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo; Comment</strong>: Excellent! Lulin has reached the highest realm of financial and personal freedom, able to go anywhere she pleases. This proves the feasibility of the 15x annual expense retirement plan.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Huasheng 
    <div id="huasheng" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#huasheng" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Share 1</strong>: Regarding purchasing Nasdaq funds in Hong Kong to avoid US estate tax, he summarized from personal experience that iShares <strong>2834</strong> is the best choice. It is registered in Hong Kong and adopts a dividend reinvestment strategy (has never paid dividends since listing in 2016), effectively avoiding CRS tax issues. In contrast, KQQM carries estate tax risks, and 3086 pays dividends which trigger CRS reporting.</li>
<li><strong>Share 2</strong>: He has helped many Clubhouse students gratuitously by sharing information on Hong Kong investments.</li>
<li><strong>Question</strong>: He has an undeveloped idea: Can he take a portion of assets to buy QQQI to cover all living expenses with its dividends, then put all remaining assets into QQQ (2834), keeping no cash, and handling emergencies via pledge loans?
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo; Reply</strong>: No. This approach is very high risk. Apart from QQQI, the other portion of growth assets <strong>still needs to maintain a cash position</strong> (e.g., a 70% QQQ + 30% Cash allocation). There are two reasons: 1. Psychological stability; having cash prevents panic when the market drops 80%. 2. Dealing with emergencies. If a large sum of money is suddenly needed while the market is falling, taking out a pledge loan at that time is very dangerous. Without a cash buffer, you might be forced to sell assets at a low point or face the risk of liquidation. Keeping 30% cash, whether to use directly or as backing for a pledge, is much safer.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">MM 
    <div id="mm" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#mm" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Question</strong>: She hasn&rsquo;t retired yet and doesn&rsquo;t need cash flow. She found through software backtesting that a 4-3-3 allocation (Beta 1.0) performs better than 8:2. Can she adopt the 4-3-3 allocation and open the pledge function at the bank, but temporarily not borrow money (incurring no interest), solely for use when she retires in the future?
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo; Reply</strong>: Absolutely. This is a very good practice. Opening the pledge function in advance to prepare for rainy days is a wise preparation.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">WW 
    <div id="ww" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ww" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Question</strong>: Plans to move to Las Vegas (no state tax) after retirement. Her current state has a 6.8% state tax. Considering the federal tax rate might rise from 35% to 37% after retirement, should she do a Roth Conversion now or wait until after moving?
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo; Reply</strong>: <strong>Convert as early as possible.</strong> Because money in the IRA will continue to grow; 100k not converted this year might become 120k next year, increasing both the total amount to convert and the tax due in the future. The state tax saved by waiting is far less than the future tax burden brought by asset growth within the account. Additionally, it is suggested she sell her current car, take the cash to Las Vegas, and buy a new Tesla with a loan, allowing the cash to be used for investment.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Qing 
    <div id="qing" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#qing" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Share 1</strong>: Recently re-read &ldquo;The Bible of Wealth Management&rdquo; and found that after nearly 20 years, his understanding improved from 20% to over 80%. The book&rsquo;s views on real estate once prompted him to buy a house, and studying the case of Asian tycoon Tan Yu (Zheng Zhoumin) made him deeply understand the importance of cash flow.</li>
<li><strong>Share 2</strong>: Regarding Tesla FSD (Full Self-Driving), he initially worried it would replace taxi drivers, but later realized human society always progresses, just as cars replaced rickshaw pullers; people will always find new paths.
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo; Comment</strong>: The emergence of Robotaxis will make the lives of taxi drivers <strong>better</strong>. They can transform into fleet owners, buying vehicles to let the cars earn money, while they drink coffee at home, achieving passive income. Humans are not born to work.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Tim 
    <div id="tim" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#tim" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Share 1</strong>: Recommends a book, &ldquo;Activate Your Inner Healing Power,&rdquo; which uses quantum fields, neural networks, and other scientific methods to explain why positive intention is real and effective.</li>
<li><strong>Question</strong>: He has persuaded his father to sell a 47-year-old townhouse (Tou Tian Cuo) that has many problems (severe leaks, tenants not paying rent). However, his father insists on spending money to fix the house completely to sell it for a high price. Should they sell it as-is quickly or follow his father&rsquo;s advice?
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo; Reply</strong>: <strong>You must fix the house up before you can sell it quickly.</strong> Especially for major flaws like leaks; no one wants to buy without repairs. Selling a house is not about selling for a &ldquo;high price,&rdquo; but being able to &ldquo;sell it.&rdquo; The price is determined by the market, not the seller. Repairs should be done immediately, and it should be sold upon receiving the first reasonable offer, because the time cost of delay is high. That money can create more returns once invested in the market sooner.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Hling 
    <div id="hling" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#hling" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing</strong>: As a student who has been learning for over a year, she shared her journey of serious study, note-taking, and strict execution of asset allocation (4-4-2 Beta). She recently completed her first annual rebalancing and confirmed the correctness of her calculations through exchanges with Brother Chen Feng. She encourages new students to systematically watch all of the teacher&rsquo;s videos step-by-step, as many questions will naturally be answered during the learning process.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Haoqing 
    <div id="haoqing" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#haoqing" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Question</strong>: Due to business needs, he borrowed a high-interest (11-12%) Margin Loan from a brokerage. He went to Schwab to switch to a lower-interest Pledge Loan (PAL) but was told he could only choose one. However, the financial specialist helped him significantly lower the Margin rate to &ldquo;Federal Rate + 2.25%&rdquo; (approx. 6%). He asks, in this situation, is it better to use the high-flexibility but high-risk Margin Loan, or apply for PAL?
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo; Reply</strong>: This is correct information. Margin Loans come from brokers, PALs come from Bankers; the risk mechanisms differ. A Margin Call can happen instantly and sell at the lowest point, whereas PAL has a certain buffer time. Money borrowed via Margin can be reinvested in stocks, while PAL funds usually cannot. Therefore, Margin is more flexible but also carries higher risk.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Simple 
    <div id="simple" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#simple" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Question</strong>: He runs his own business and has 100k TWD in monthly passive rental income, basically covering living expenses and mortgage. He just obtained a 5 million TWD credit line (interest approx. 2.5%) in Taiwan and applied for a 200k USD loan in Singapore (also approx. 2.5%, but with the condition of purchasing the bank&rsquo;s wealth management products). How should he use these funds? Put a lump sum into QQQ/QQQI, or invest in his own business?
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo; Reply</strong>: 1. <strong>Do not take the Singapore loan</strong>, avoid any loan that comes with conditions to buy their wealth management products. 2. The 5 million TWD credit should be <strong>fully invested in the stock market (e.g., 00662)</strong> and absolutely not invested in your own business, to diversify risk and avoid putting all eggs in one basket. 3. The prerequisite for borrowing is that repayment must come from stable business cash flow, not the already occupied rental income. 4. As a young person in the asset accumulation phase, you should invest in <strong>growth assets (00662)</strong>, not dividend-paying types like QQQI.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">DY 
    <div id="dy" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#dy" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Question 1</strong>: Does the &ldquo;15-year living expense retirement method&rdquo; (10 years expenses in QQQI, 5 years expenses in 4-3-3 allocation) mentioned by the teacher only apply to retirees? Can those still accumulating assets allocate based on this ratio (e.g., 2/3 QQQI, 1/3 Growth)?
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo; Reply</strong>: <strong>Young people in the asset accumulation phase must absolutely not touch high-dividend products like QQQI.</strong> Your goal is to pursue maximized growth. QQQI is prepared for retirees who need cash flow.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question 2</strong>: Her family is afraid of QQQ volatility and feels safer with QQQI&rsquo;s monthly dividends. What should she do?
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo; Reply</strong>: If the money belongs to the family and investing in QQQI is the only way they can accept, then so be it. At least it&rsquo;s better than not investing, though it&rsquo;s not the optimal strategy. QQQI&rsquo;s own volatility (Beta 1.0) is as high as QQQ.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question 3</strong>: Does QQQI have tax issues in Taiwan?
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo; Reply</strong>: It falls under overseas income. Within 1 million TWD annual income requires no filing; over 1 million requires filing, but the basic exemption is very high (7.5 million), so average people don&rsquo;t need to worry about paying taxes.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Qiming 
    <div id="qiming" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#qiming" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Question</strong>: What is After-hour trading? How does it differ from normal trading hours?
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo; Reply</strong>: After-hour trading is like a night market; there are few participants, liquidity is poor, and the Bid-Ask Spread is very large. Trading risk is high, and you should <strong>absolutely never use Market Orders</strong>. Unless there is an extremely urgent reason, avoid trading after hours. When placing a normal order, the system won&rsquo;t automatically enter after-hour trading; you need to actively check the relevant options.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Meihao 
    <div id="meihao" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#meihao" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Question</strong>: Although she feels financially free, she is recently worried and confused by the geopolitical tensions in the Taiwan Strait, feeling unable to consider it &ldquo;irrelevant to me&rdquo; as the teacher says. She asks how to view this risk from a spiritual level?
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo; Reply</strong>: The probability of such an event is extremely low, like an asteroid hitting the earth. Excessive worry about such low-probability events yields returns disproportionate to the mental effort spent. The only thing we can do, and the most practical preparation, is: <strong>Ensure everyone in the family has a valid passport.</strong></li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chenfeng 
    <div id="chenfeng" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chenfeng" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing</strong>: He created a new personal blog, &ldquo;<strong>Chenfeng Pilot Life Fleet</strong>,&rdquo; integrating all the teacher&rsquo;s course materials (summaries of long and short videos), an AI interactive bot, all his personal documents and spreadsheets, and opened a <strong>forum</strong>. This platform is open globally, aiming to break regional restrictions (like LINE groups) so students worldwide can interact, ask questions, find answers, and grow together.</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">IV. Key Highlights 
    <div id="iv-key-highlights" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv-key-highlights" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>Your world and the people and things you encounter are actually related to your brainwaves. So you must think about what you want and what you like in your head. You must use positive statements, and the universe will become what you want it to be.
&ndash; Teacher James</p></blockquote>
<p>This viewpoint emphasizes the creative power of thought and language, believing that one can actively shape their reality and financial status through positive self-suggestion.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Buying insurance is laziness, it is inertia. You are essentially trying to transfer risk to the insurance company&hellip; Insurance companies are poverty manufacturing machines, viruses of society.
&ndash; Teacher James</p></blockquote>
<p>The teacher criticizes the role of traditional insurance in financial management with very sharp language, believing it is not an effective tool for wealth growth and may instead erode assets.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Living this retirement life with this method for half a year has been truly very comfortable&hellip; The level of relaxation in my life is truly different.
&ndash; Lulin</p></blockquote>
<p>As a retired student, Lulin shared her real feelings after practicing the teacher&rsquo;s investment method, proving that financial freedom brings not just money, but a fundamental change in the state of life.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>After Robotaxis come out, the lives of these taxi drivers will be better&hellip; We humans are not born to work; let the cars go to work and help him earn money.
&ndash; Teacher James</p></blockquote>
<p>Addressing concerns that technological progress might lead to unemployment, the teacher offered a counter-intuitive but visionary perspective: Technology will ultimately liberate humanity, letting assets work for us.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>If (geopolitical war) happens&hellip; should I have overseas assets&hellip; but what the teacher says makes sense&hellip; my effort is not proportional to my return.
&ndash; Meihao &amp; Teacher James</p></blockquote>
<p>This dialogue highlights how individuals should assess their actions when facing macro, uncontrollable risks. Instead of over-planning and agonizing over low-probability events, it is better to make the most basic and practical preparations (such as keeping passports valid).</p>


<h2 class="relative group">V. Summary 
    <div id="v-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#v-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>In the first class of 2026, Teacher James started from the &ldquo;heart,&rdquo; once again emphasizing the decisive role of positive intention in successful investing and a happy life. The course content combined philosophical height with practical depth, not only updating the algorithm of the core weapon—the backtesting tool—and clarifying the safe boundaries of leverage usage, but also providing a clearer, lower-barrier &ldquo;15x annual expense&rdquo; retirement path for students who are about to or aspire to retire. The Q&amp;A session was lively and in-depth; the real experiences shared by students and the profound questions raised collided with the teacher&rsquo;s answers to spark wisdom, covering everything from macro risk management to specific product selection, showcasing the vibrancy of a mutual-aid learning community.</p>

  



<div
  
    class="flex px-4 py-3 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900"
  >

  <span
    
      class="text-primary-400 ltr:pr-3 rtl:pl-3 flex items-center"
    >

    

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M506.3 417l-213.3-364c-16.33-28-57.54-28-73.98 0l-213.2 364C-10.59 444.9 9.849 480 42.74 480h426.6C502.1 480 522.6 445 506.3 417zM232 168c0-13.25 10.75-24 24-24S280 154.8 280 168v128c0 13.25-10.75 24-23.1 24S232 309.3 232 296V168zM256 416c-17.36 0-31.44-14.08-31.44-31.44c0-17.36 14.07-31.44 31.44-31.44s31.44 14.08 31.44 31.44C287.4 401.9 273.4 416 256 416z"/></svg>

  </span>


  </span>

  <span
    
      class="dark:text-neutral-300"
    ><strong>Disclaimer:</strong> This article is solely for personal study notes and does not constitute any investment advice.</span>
</div>

]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>00543 What to Do When the Market Is Fearful? Market Fear and the Mindset for Getting Rich in the Prison of Real Estate!</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1765076605184/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1765076605184/</guid><description>In this session, Teacher James shares his optimistic forecast for the December market, emphasizing that investors should get in as soon as possible. The core idea is &amp;#39;survival first, profit later,&amp;#39; meaning long-term returns are contingent on being able to withstand market volatility without being liquidated. This session highlights QQQI as a retirement cash flow tool and delves into the concept of real estate as a consumer good rather than an investment. Additionally, James provides updates on Canadian tax regulations, market capital flow (end of QT), and reiterates the importance of fraud prevention and the compliance of US stock pledging.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<lite-youtube videoid="cQSeuySP8jk" playlabel="cQSeuySP8jk" params=""></lite-youtube>



<h2 class="relative group">I. Topic of the Session 
    <div id="i-topic-of-the-session" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-topic-of-the-session" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This session focuses on <strong>the mindset and actions investors should adopt amidst optimistic market expectations</strong>. The core idea is that the market is on the verge of a significant rally, and investors should enter decisively without hesitation. Teacher James emphasizes that the key to successful investing is <strong>&ldquo;survival first, profit later.&rdquo;</strong> Only by staying in the market for the long term and enduring all volatility can one ultimately enjoy the rich rewards of compounding. Therefore, constructing an asset allocation that allows you to weather any storm is crucial.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">II. Briefing Content 
    <div id="ii-briefing-content" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii-briefing-content" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Market Views &amp; Investment Mentality 
    <div id="market-views--investment-mentality" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#market-views--investment-mentality" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Market Outlook &amp; Capital Flow</strong>: The market is poised for a breakout to new highs. A strong rally is expected in December. An important backdrop is that QT (Quantitative Tightening) ended on December 1st. The central bank will now inject about $15 billion into the market weekly, totaling around $50 billion per month. This will create a massive capital flow, driving the market upward.</li>
<li><strong>The First Principle of Investing: Survive</strong>:
<ul>
<li>An annualized return of 15% is predicated on being able to stay invested for over 30 years without being liquidated due to fear or excessive leverage. If you exit midway, even the highest returns are irrelevant to you.</li>
<li>It&rsquo;s better to choose a stable asset allocation that can survive any risk, even if the annualized return is only 7%. The key is to survive for 30 years or even longer.</li>
<li>The core of investing is <strong>doing the right thing</strong>. Regardless of the market&rsquo;s current state, you should always be buying. Be happy when it goes up, and don&rsquo;t panic when it goes down.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Coping with Market Sentiment</strong>:
<ul>
<li>The principle of &ldquo;be greedy when others are fearful, and fearful when others are greedy&rdquo; is hard to execute. The simplest way to practice it is to <strong>resolutely not sell</strong>.</li>
<li>Investors need to admit that they &ldquo;know nothing&rdquo; and cannot predict market highs or lows. This allows them to respect the market and hold for the long term.</li>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo;s channel teaches only one thing: buy bravely and consistently, never sell, and you will succeed.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Investment Tools &amp; Strategy Introduction (QQQI) 
    <div id="investment-tools--strategy-introduction-qqqi" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#investment-tools--strategy-introduction-qqqi" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Background</strong>: To provide a new option for retirees who need a stable cash flow.</li>
<li><strong>Ticker Introduction</strong>: QQQI (Nasdaq-100 Enhanced Opt &amp; Growth ETF).</li>
<li><strong>Features &amp; Advantages</strong>:
<ol>
<li><strong>High Dividend</strong>: The dividend yield can reach 12%. For example, an investment of $1 million can generate $120,000 in cash flow per year ($10,000 per month); an investment of $5 million can yield $600,000 per year ($50,000 per month).</li>
<li><strong>Lowers the Retirement Threshold</strong>: For retirees who haven&rsquo;t prepared 25-30 times their annual expenses, investing just 8-10 times their annual expenses in QQQI can generate enough cash flow to cover living costs.</li>
<li><strong>Operational &amp; Tax Advantages</strong>: QQQI distributes dividends derived from a portion of capital gains (from selling appreciated stocks) and income from selling covered call options (about 4-5% annually). For Taiwanese investors using a brokerage with QI (Qualified Intermediary) status (like E.Sun, Yuanta, Cathay, SinoPac, etc.), most of the dividend income, being sourced from capital gains, is eligible for a tax refund. Approximately 96% of the dividends can be refunded.</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Personal Finance &amp; Life Philosophy 
    <div id="personal-finance--life-philosophy" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#personal-finance--life-philosophy" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Act Decisively</strong>: Investors who are still hesitating and haven&rsquo;t entered the market should stop &ldquo;daydreaming.&rdquo; Be &ldquo;ruthless&rdquo; in your actions—immediately sell what you shouldn&rsquo;t hold, buy the correct asset allocation, and then &ldquo;get on the bus and go to sleep.&rdquo; Financial freedom won&rsquo;t be far off.</li>
<li><strong>A House is a Consumer Good, Not an Investment</strong>:
<ul>
<li>If you&rsquo;ve reached a level of wealth where &ldquo;buying a house is like buying a pair of slippers,&rdquo; then buying a luxury home to enjoy life is perfectly fine.</li>
<li>But beware of becoming &ldquo;high-income but exquisitely poor,&rdquo; where your cash flow is extremely tight just to maintain a lavish home. This is akin to buying yourself a giant &ldquo;cage.&rdquo;</li>
<li><strong>The Correct Sequence</strong>: You should invest first and let your money make money. For example, <strong>if you have $1 million now, first invest it to grow into $200 million, and only then take out $100 million to buy a house.</strong> This way, you can truly enjoy the pleasure of living without being shackled by your property.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Subconscious and Manifestation</strong>: It is recommended to watch a video in the presentation notes that teaches how to connect your subconscious with universal energy. The core principle is to &ldquo;believe&rdquo; first, then meditate in a state of peace, happiness, and love, which makes it easier to manifest your desires.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Other Supplements &amp; Reminders 
    <div id="other-supplements--reminders" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#other-supplements--reminders" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Fraud Prevention</strong>: A reminder that there are many impersonators and scams on Clubhouse and other platforms. Scammer IDs (like <code>clecchman</code>) are very similar to the teacher&rsquo;s ID (<code>clecchirman</code>) and use GPT to mimic his tone in private messages. Please be sure to verify by checking follower counts (the teacher has 4.3K followers) and other means.</li>
<li><strong>Book Commentary</strong>: Mentioned that &ldquo;Dr. Huang Pei-Yuan&rsquo;s Bible of Financial Management&rdquo; is a good book, but its sequel, &ldquo;Financial EQ,&rdquo; was likely a cash grab by the publisher with mostly filler content. Reading the first book is sufficient.</li>
<li><strong>Canadian Tax Update</strong>:
<ul>
<li>2025: 50% of capital gains will be included in the year&rsquo;s income.</li>
<li>Starting 2026: For capital gains exceeding C$250,000, 67% of the excess amount will be included in the year&rsquo;s income.</li>
<li>As long as you don&rsquo;t sell, no capital gains tax will be incurred.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">III. Q&amp;A Session 
    <div id="iii-qa-session" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii-qa-session" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Celine 
    <div id="celine" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#celine" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing:
<ol>
<li><strong>Regarding QQQI Tax Refund</strong>: Taiwanese investors need to confirm if their brokerage has &ldquo;QI status.&rdquo; If so, they can get a tax refund on their QQQI investment. The method may vary; some brokerages don&rsquo;t withhold tax upfront, while others withhold and then refund it. Most medium to large brokerages have QI status.</li>
<li><strong>The Ease and Persistence of Investing</strong>: Any diligent investment method can make money, but Teacher James&rsquo;s method is the most effortless and worry-free. However, &ldquo;buy whenever you have money, and never sell&rdquo; is easier said than done. It requires personally experiencing severe market volatility (like in 2022) to truly test one&rsquo;s mentality.</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Haiwai Guzhong 
    <div id="haiwai-guzhong" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#haiwai-guzhong" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question: With the development of AI, will countries like Vietnam and Indonesia lose the opportunity to transition from labor-intensive to tech-based economies, as Taiwan and South Korea did, and thus be permanently locked at the bottom of the value chain?
<ul>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo;s Reply: This issue is more severe than imagined. The impact of AI is global, not just limited to developing countries. Taiwan&rsquo;s semiconductor industry could also be replaced by fully automated AI factories. The future society will be divided into a tiny minority of capitalists (about 0.1%) and a vast majority of ordinary people (99.9%) dependent on social welfare. The only way out is to become a capitalist—get on board (invest) as soon as possible to enjoy the dividends of this technological revolution. Otherwise, everyone could be left behind by the times.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Zhihong 
    <div id="zhihong" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#zhihong" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question: I am 45, my father has cancer. After selling a house, we have NT$8 million in cash, but annual expenses are NT$1.1 million. I want to take out a NT$6 million loan against my mortgage-free house to invest in QQQI, using the cash flow to support my father. I also hope my father will invest, but it&rsquo;s hard to convince him. What is your advice?
<ul>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo;s Reply: You are very filial, but you don&rsquo;t need to worry excessively about your father&rsquo;s finances. Right now, <strong>companionship and care are far more important to your father than investment advice.</strong> You should spend more time with him and cherish this period. You can use the NT$6 million loan to invest for yourself, and the returns can be used to support your mother in the future. You don&rsquo;t need to spend excessively on talent classes for your children; playing with them is the best education.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Yue Feng 
    <div id="yue-feng" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#yue-feng" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question: Fubon in Taiwan recently launched a Nasdaq-100 index fund with an &ldquo;automatic dip-buying&rdquo; feature. Can I buy this instead of 00662?
<ul>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo;s Reply: Don&rsquo;t buy it. It&rsquo;s a mutual fund with extra custodian fees. And you don&rsquo;t need a &ldquo;dip-buying&rdquo; feature; the market is about to rally strongly. If you have money, you should buy 00662 immediately. Don&rsquo;t play around with those complicated, esoteric products.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Sherry 
    <div id="sherry" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#sherry" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question 1: I have initial capital and a monthly salary. Should I DCA monthly, or accumulate for a year and then rebalance according to the 433 strategy?
<ul>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo;s Reply: Buy whenever you have money each month. Don&rsquo;t wait a year.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2: Using the 433 allocation, what should I do with the money borrowed from a stock pledge if I don&rsquo;t need it immediately?
<ul>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo;s Reply: <strong>(Extremely Important Warning!)</strong> If you are in the United States, money borrowed from a pledge <strong>absolutely cannot</strong> be put back into a securities account. The fund flow must be clearly for consumption. A friend has already been asked by Schwab to close their pledge account for this reason, or face a forced sale of stocks to repay the loan. The consequences are severe. If you are not in the US, this amount (at most 2% of assets borrowed annually) is small, so reinvesting it won&rsquo;t have a major impact.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Frank 
    <div id="frank" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#frank" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question: I am 40, with a NT$5.5 million personal loan and NT$7 million in my own funds. Can I use the most aggressive &ldquo;442&rdquo; asset allocation?
<ul>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo;s Reply: Absolutely not recommended. The risk is too high; even I wouldn&rsquo;t do that. Use the &ldquo;433&rdquo; allocation at most. As long as there is debt, there is risk. You cannot be overly aggressive.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Luu 
    <div id="luu" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#luu" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Sending greetings from Bali, complimenting the teacher for looking like Chow Yun-fat with sunglasses on in a group photo, saying he looked very charming.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Lily 
    <div id="lily" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#lily" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing:
<ol>
<li><strong>Stocks vs. Real Estate</strong>: After some thought, she concluded that stocks grow through compounding, while real estate&rsquo;s advantage is leverage. However, due to the growth rate difference between stocks (~10%) and real estate (~6%), plus loan interest, the leverage advantage of real estate is depleted after about 7-8 years. After that, the growth curve of stocks will far surpass that of real estate.</li>
<li><strong>Cash Management in China</strong>: In the Chinese stock market, unused cash can earn interest through &ldquo;government bond reverse repos,&rdquo; which can be selected on a daily basis and are very flexible. The interest rates can sometimes be very high before public holidays.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>Question:
<ol>
<li>Which Nasdaq-100 ETF should I invest in in China?</li>
<li>My personal financial situation is very good, and I hope to maximize long-term returns. How should I allocate my assets?</li>
<li>My current small brokerage in the US charges commissions as high as 1.5-2%. Should I move to Schwab?</li>
<li>How can I join the LINE group?</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo;s Reply:
<ol>
<li>The 159509 she bought before is a technology fund, not a Nasdaq-100 index. It&rsquo;s recommended to choose the tickers we suggest.</li>
<li>Since you can tolerate high volatility, you can use a very aggressive allocation: <strong>85% QQQ + 10% QLD + 5% TQQQ</strong>, and rebalance once a year.</li>
<li><strong>Transfer immediately!</strong> Your brokerage&rsquo;s fees are extremely high and it&rsquo;s not safe. Schwab is the best choice—it&rsquo;s secure and commission-free.</li>
<li>The LINE group has regional restrictions; US numbers might not be able to join, but you can try.</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Susan (AV) 
    <div id="susan-av" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#susan-av" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: She is a Buddhist. After listening to the teacher&rsquo;s class, she felt like the &ldquo;God of Wealth had arrived,&rdquo; and she was finally liberated from the &ldquo;samsara&rdquo; of daily market-watching, chasing highs and lows, and constant anxiety. She converted all her stocks to 00662, feels an unprecedented sense of peace, and has started teaching her children to invest so they can all be wealthy in the future. She also strongly agrees with the teacher&rsquo;s educational philosophy, sharing her own experience of supporting her son&rsquo;s dream to pursue photography instead of going to university, and how he ultimately lived a wonderful life.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Danken 
    <div id="danken" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#danken" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question: I just arrived in the US. The best option in my 401K is an S&amp;P 500 fund. My Roth IRA is allocated to QLD, and I have cash (in BOX) in my personal brokerage account. In the long run, the proportion of the S&amp;P 500 will become too high. How should I adjust?
<ul>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo;s Reply: Your setup is fine. Max out your 401K with the S&amp;P 500 and max out your Roth IRA with QLD. In your personal brokerage account, keep six months of living expenses in BOX (don&rsquo;t buy SGOV, as the dividends are taxable), and invest the rest of the funds <strong>entirely in QQQ</strong>.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chris 
    <div id="chris" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chris" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: He helped his mother get a home equity line of credit for investment purposes. In the process, he discovered that a &ldquo;villa&rdquo; his mother was proud of was actually built on agricultural and pastoral land, which the bank would not appraise, making its value very low. This experience made his mother realize that the value of real estate is not as stable as she thought, and she began to accept the idea of investing in 00662.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Washing, W 
    <div id="washing-w" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#washing-w" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question: I am 62 and a half. Should I start collecting my own Social Security now, or collect half of my ex-husband&rsquo;s first and wait until I&rsquo;m 71 to collect my own?
<ul>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo;s Reply: Don&rsquo;t wait. Compare which amount is higher right now and start collecting that one immediately. The returns from investing the money you receive will far exceed the increase from waiting.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Paiqing 
    <div id="paiqing" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#paiqing" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Responding to a previous member whose family member has lung cancer, she shared her own experience of her father passing away from the same illness 10 years ago. She comforted the member, saying that health insurance covers a lot of the costs, so money is not the biggest issue. What&rsquo;s more important is to cherish the time with your father. Take him out more, because in the later stages of lung cancer, bone metastasis can affect mobility. You will have money in the future, but the time for companionship is finite.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Li Xianhong 
    <div id="li-xianhong" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#li-xianhong" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question: The teacher said not to buy insurance. Does that include term life insurance?
<ul>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo;s Reply: If you still have young children to support, buying term life insurance is acceptable.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">YKY 
    <div id="yky" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#yky" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing and Questions:
<ol>
<li>Sharing: From mainland China, he just discovered the channel last week and felt a sense of &ldquo;sudden enlightenment,&rdquo; with hope for his future. He and his wife had followed the traditional path of buying a house and taking on a mortgage, leading to immense pressure. After listening to the teacher&rsquo;s classes, his mindset completely changed. He no longer frets over grievances at work because he knows he will be wealthy in the future.</li>
<li>Question 1: I have a mortgage (covered by the Housing Provident Fund) and a personal loan. How should I handle them?</li>
<li>Question 2: I have 100,000 RMB available for investment (after setting aside six months of living expenses). Should I allocate it as 80% index / 20% cash?</li>
<li>Question 3: I&rsquo;ve opened a Schwab account and plan to open an account in Hong Kong in the future for pledging. Is this plan feasible?</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo;s Reply:
<ol>
<li>Continue to use the Provident Fund for the mortgage. For the personal loan, don&rsquo;t rush to pay off the principal; just pay the interest and use it as a revolving line of credit.</li>
<li>Yes, apply an 80/20 allocation to all your investable assets. The 20% cash can be put into a money market fund.</li>
<li>The plan is excellent. Start transferring some funds to Hong Kong annually now. Once the capital reaches a certain size, you can start pledging. This is a correct ten-year plan. Also, don&rsquo;t be afraid to have a second child because of financial pressure. You will be very wealthy in the future, and having more children will make your family happier.</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">IV. Insightful Quotes 
    <div id="iv-insightful-quotes" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv-insightful-quotes" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>You only have a tomorrow in the market if you survive; only then can you talk about a rate of return.
&ndash; Teacher James</p></blockquote>
<p>This quote emphasizes that the prerequisite for long-term investment success is the ability to withstand any market fluctuation without being forced out. Survival is the first element of profit.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>If you can buy a house like you buy a pair of slippers—just get another pair if you don&rsquo;t like them—then you can buy one. If you can&rsquo;t be that magnanimous, then a house is just a big cage.
&ndash; Teacher James</p></blockquote>
<p>This quote vividly defines a house as a consumer good rather than an investment, advising people not to be shackled by property and become &ldquo;exquisitely poor.&rdquo;</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Only the capitalists can enjoy the greatest dividends of human transformation&hellip; otherwise, everyone will perish.
&ndash; Teacher James</p></blockquote>
<p>In response to the impact of AI on future social structures, the teacher points out that in the face of disruptive technological change, becoming a capitalist (an investor) is the only way out for ordinary people.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>After I learned about the teacher, I felt as if the God of Wealth had arrived. I am about to escape that cycle of samsara.
&ndash; Susan</p></blockquote>
<p>A student shares her feeling of liberation from the &ldquo;samsara&rdquo; of chasing highs and lows and daily anxiety after learning the investment philosophy, expressing her hope for the future.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>When I saw the teacher&rsquo;s video on Saturday, I had a sudden enlightenment. I feel there is still hope for my future.
&ndash; YKY</p></blockquote>
<p>A young student from mainland China, who was feeling suffocated by the &ldquo;buy a house, pay off the mortgage&rdquo; model, felt his life was illuminated and his hope was renewed after being exposed to the investment philosophy.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Money is actually the least of your worries. What matters is how you accompany your father to the end&hellip; cherish the time you have with him.
&ndash; Paiqing</p></blockquote>
<p>A student uses her personal experience to comfort another member whose family member has cancer, reminding everyone that in the face of life&rsquo;s ultimate challenges, money is far less important than love and companionship.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">V. Summary 
    <div id="v-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#v-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This session began with a very optimistic market forecast (end of QT, influx of capital) and reinforced CLEC&rsquo;s core investment philosophy: <strong>simple, persistent, and brave</strong>. Teacher James not only gave clear instructions—&ldquo;keep buying, don&rsquo;t sell&rdquo;—but also built a solid theoretical foundation from both psychological and strategic standpoints. Whether it was emphasizing the importance of &ldquo;survival,&rdquo; introducing the powerful retirement cash flow tool QQQI, or subverting the traditional concept that &ldquo;a house is a cage,&rdquo; the goal was to help investors establish a correct view of wealth, break free from anxiety, and embark on a relaxed yet firm path to financial freedom. The enthusiastic sharing and questions from the students also provided vivid interpretations and applications of these concepts in real-life situations.</p>

  



<div
  
    class="flex px-4 py-3 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900"
  >

  <span
    
      class="text-primary-400 ltr:pr-3 rtl:pl-3 flex items-center"
    >

    

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M506.3 417l-213.3-364c-16.33-28-57.54-28-73.98 0l-213.2 364C-10.59 444.9 9.849 480 42.74 480h426.6C502.1 480 522.6 445 506.3 417zM232 168c0-13.25 10.75-24 24-24S280 154.8 280 168v128c0 13.25-10.75 24-23.1 24S232 309.3 232 296V168zM256 416c-17.36 0-31.44-14.08-31.44-31.44c0-17.36 14.07-31.44 31.44-31.44s31.44 14.08 31.44 31.44C287.4 401.9 273.4 416 256 416z"/></svg>

  </span>


  </span>

  <span
    
      class="dark:text-neutral-300"
    ><strong>Disclaimer:</strong> This article is for personal study notes only and does not constitute any investment advice.</span>
</div>

]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>00542 A 2.5% retirement withdrawal rate is key; QQQ is not about tech, it's about the strongest companies! The investment focus isn't on industry classification, but on the correct logic for long-term wealth building</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1764465235759/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1764465235759/</guid><description>In this session, Teacher James explains in detail the application scenarios of QQQI as a retirement cash flow tool and provides an in-depth analysis clarifying that QQQ is not purely a high-tech fund, but an investment in the current one hundred strongest companies. The Q&amp;amp;A session was lively, discussing asset allocation and stock pledging operations in different regions like Hong Kong, Canada, and Mainland China. Through long-term data comparison, the immense advantage of the &amp;#39;sell your house, rent, and invest in indexes&amp;#39; strategy was re-emphasized to help students overcome psychological barriers to investing.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<lite-youtube videoid="A65OoUXqteY" playlabel="A65OoUXqteY" params=""></lite-youtube>



<h2 class="relative group">I. Main Topic of the Session 
    <div id="i-main-topic-of-the-session" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-main-topic-of-the-session" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>The core of this class revolved around two key points: first, introducing the proper use of the high-dividend ETF <strong>QQQI</strong> for retirees and investors needing cash flow, emphasizing its role as a supplementary cash flow tool rather than a substitute for cash itself; second, through in-depth analysis, clarifying the common misconception about <strong>QQQ (Nasdaq 100 Index)</strong>, pointing out that its investment logic is to &ldquo;invest in the strongest companies of the moment,&rdquo; not limited to the &ldquo;high-tech&rdquo; sector. Teacher James used examples and a historical perspective to explain the dynamic adaptability of the index and reiterated the core investment philosophy of holding for the long term and ignoring market fluctuations.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">II. Briefing Content 
    <div id="ii-briefing-content" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii-briefing-content" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Reminder: Beware of Scams 
    <div id="reminder-beware-of-scams" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#reminder-beware-of-scams" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Teacher James once again reminded everyone that scam groups are continuously using his name and profile picture to impersonate him.</li>
<li>The teacher emphasized that he has over 4,000 followers, while the scammers only have a few dozen, making them easy to distinguish.</li>
<li>Initially, scammers may imitate the teacher&rsquo;s tone, even using AI tools to answer questions, but their ultimate goal is to defraud people of money or request to manage their accounts. Please be vigilant and do not engage in private chats or send money to any &ldquo;James Chan&rdquo; who actively contacts you offering investment advice.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Investment Philosophy: Simple, Firm, No Forecasting 
    <div id="investment-philosophy-simple-firm-no-forecasting" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#investment-philosophy-simple-firm-no-forecasting" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Market Irrelevance</strong>: Market volatility, international situations, economic data, and company earnings reports are all irrelevant to our investment decisions.</li>
<li><strong>Core Strategy</strong>: The only correct strategy is to &ldquo;buy whenever you have money, hold for the long term, and never sell.&rdquo;</li>
<li><strong>Investment Target</strong>: Do not invest in individual stocks; focus on broad-market index funds to avoid the risks associated with individual company earnings and operations.</li>
<li><strong>Risk Awareness</strong>: The market can drop by 50% or even 80% at any time. Investors must manage their own risk and ensure that the funds invested are for the long term and will not be needed.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">QQQI: A Cash Flow Tool for Retirees 
    <div id="qqqi-a-cash-flow-tool-for-retirees" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#qqqi-a-cash-flow-tool-for-retirees" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Target Audience</strong>: QQQI is suitable for those who are retired or need a stable cash flow, especially when your annual expenses exceed 2.5% of your total assets.</li>
<li><strong>Functional Positioning</strong>: QQQI is a tool to <strong>generate cash flow</strong>, but it <strong>cannot be equated with cash</strong>. Your emergency fund should still be kept in highly liquid assets like money market funds (e.g., 00865B).</li>
<li><strong>Allocation Scenario</strong>: If your retirement assets are less than 40 times your annual expenses (i.e., your withdrawal rate is higher than 2.5%), you can pair it with a portion of QQQI to increase overall cash flow yield to meet living expenses. Young people or investors still in the accumulation phase should continue to invest in growth-oriented index funds like QQQ, 00662, etc.</li>
<li><strong>Practical Application</strong>:
<ul>
<li>In the United States, QQQI can be held in both retirement and individual accounts.</li>
<li>In Taiwan, you can purchase QQQI through a sub-brokerage (such as Yuanta, Fubon, Cathay). Most of the dividends distributed can be reclaimed through tax refunds.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Case Study</strong>: A friend of the teacher followed his advice early on, sold his house, and went all-in on QQQ (00662). His assets grew by 1.5 times in five to six years, achieving financial freedom. He now enjoys a high-quality retired life. This stands in stark contrast to those who work their entire lives for a house, a car, and an insurance company.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Analyzing QQQ: Investing in the Strongest Companies, Not a Pure Tech Fund 
    <div id="analyzing-qqq-investing-in-the-strongest-companies-not-a-pure-tech-fund" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#analyzing-qqq-investing-in-the-strongest-companies-not-a-pure-tech-fund" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Dispelling the Misconception</strong>: Many believe that investing in QQQ is investing in &ldquo;American high-tech.&rdquo; This is not entirely accurate. Truly pure technology sector funds are like XLK or VGT, but we do not recommend investing in any sector-specific funds.</li>
<li><strong>The Essence of QQQ</strong>: QQQ invests in the <strong>100 strongest companies listed on the Nasdaq Stock Exchange</strong>. It is an index without a &ldquo;personality&rdquo;; its only criterion is &ldquo;strength.&rdquo;</li>
<li><strong>Dynamic Adaptability</strong>:
<ul>
<li>In the current era, the strongest companies happen to be mostly high-tech firms.</li>
<li>However, if we went back 40 years, the strongest companies might have been those making radios, televisions, or trains, and they would have been included in the index. The definition of &ldquo;high-tech&rdquo; changes with the times.</li>
<li>The index also includes companies like Costco and Starbucks, which are not high-tech but are extremely powerful.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Core Viewpoint</strong>: We invest in QQQ because we believe that human progress is driven by these strongest companies. We are investing in a <strong>mechanism that dynamically selects the strongest players</strong>, not betting on a specific industry. Obsessing over whether it is a &ldquo;high-tech fund&rdquo; is pointless; what matters is its excellent long-term performance.</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">III. Q&amp;A Session 
    <div id="iii-qa-session" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii-qa-session" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Momo 
    <div id="momo" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#momo" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Discussed the process of stock pledging at HSBC in Hong Kong. She found HSBC&rsquo;s loan-to-value ratios to be relatively conservative (70% for underlying stocks, 90% for cash, leveraged ETFs cannot be pledged), which is lower than in the US or Taiwan.</li>
<li>Question 1: She designed a low-risk allocation of 50% Nasdaq and 50% cash (Beta=0.5), with annual expenses accounting for about 3% of total assets. She wanted to confirm if this approach is safe and whether using the cash portion would create risk. Additionally, she heard that HSBC uses the entire account as collateral, rather than differentiating by asset type, and wanted to verify this.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: The pledging rules at HSBC Hong Kong are identical to those in the US. It&rsquo;s normal for leveraged funds to have no pledge value. She has two options: 1. If taxes are not a concern, she can build a 4-3-3 portfolio within HSBC, buying Hong Kong-listed leveraged ETFs and rebalancing. 2. To avoid domestic capital gains tax, she could, like other students, buy and sell leveraged ETFs through an overseas broker like IBKR, but she must be mindful of potential future US estate tax issues. The teacher emphasized that when you need money, you should &ldquo;borrow&rdquo; from your credit line, not &ldquo;sell assets.&rdquo; A single withdrawal should preferably not exceed 10% of total assets, and always ensure your cash position is greater than your total liabilities; this is very safe.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2: She is helping her mother with financial management and, to give her mother a sense of involvement, is debating whether to open a Joint Account or manage it herself and provide regular updates.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: There are several options, depending on her mother&rsquo;s preference. They could open a joint account; she could open an account in her mother&rsquo;s name, and her mother could sign a Power of Attorney for her to operate it; or she could open it in her name and just share the login details so her mother can view it anytime. The simplest way is to show her the monthly statement and discuss the account&rsquo;s status together.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Zhihua Wang 
    <div id="zhihua-wang" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#zhihua-wang" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question: Is the dividend yield of QQYI fixed? He observed it changed from 12% last week to 13.64% this week.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: The dividend yield is related to market volatility, so the amount paid out each month will vary slightly, but the annual total is generally stable between 10%-13%. It is not fixed. The teacher also demonstrated live how to use ChatGPT to calculate asset allocation ratios: by inputting the expected returns of different portfolios (e.g., 2.5% for a 4-3-3 portfolio, 11% for QQQI), the AI can help you calculate the capital proportions needed to achieve a target return rate (e.g., 4% or 6%).</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Jet 
    <div id="jet" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#jet" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question: Does the teacher have any recommended retirement locations in the US? The requirements are safety, good climate, and few natural disasters.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: (Jokingly) You&rsquo;re welcome to be my neighbor in Cupertino, California. It&rsquo;s next to Apple&rsquo;s headquarters, very safe, our area has no wildfire issues, and there are many excellent hospitals.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Tianluzhixia 
    <div id="tianluzhixia" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#tianluzhixia" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question: He is currently in South Korea and learned that the stock pledging interest rate is around 4.5%, which feels higher than in the US and Taiwan. Is it still worth doing?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: 4.5% is very cheap! The rates in the US are now up to 6%, so 4.5% is a very good rate and completely worth doing. South Korea has a well-developed financial system, and being able to buy 2x leveraged ETFs is also great.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Wendy 
    <div id="wendy" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#wendy" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question: She is a citizen of mainland China but has accounts and funds in mainland China, Hong Kong (Standard Chartered Bank), and IBKR (opened previously in Canada). She feels her asset allocation is chaotic and doesn&rsquo;t know how to distribute it.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: First, as a Chinese tax resident, it is not advisable to keep large assets in IBKR due to the risk of US estate tax; the funds should be consolidated into a Hong Kong account as soon as possible. Second, it&rsquo;s important to distinguish between &ldquo;margin financing&rdquo; at mainland brokers (borrowing money to buy stocks, cash cannot be withdrawn) and &ldquo;stock pledging&rdquo; at Hong Kong banks (collateralizing stocks to borrow cash for spending). He advised her to keep about 1 year of living expenses in China, 2-3 years of cash in Hong Kong, and invest the majority of the remaining funds in the Nasdaq 100 index. She could allocate a small portion (e.g., 10%) to a 2x leveraged ETF since she is still young and not yet retired.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Liang 
    <div id="liang" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#liang" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question 1: An internal staff member from a free tax filing software platform she uses in Canada contacted her, pointing out that her mutual fund fees were high and promoting investment advice to her. She felt this was a violation of her privacy.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: This is most likely because she agreed to the user agreement upon registration, which included a clause allowing the platform to use her data for internal marketing. This kind of investment advice is a &ldquo;scam&rdquo;; just ignore it. He re-emphasized the first rule of investing: stay away from any advice from financial advisors and banks.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2: She shared a news story from Canada where a couple passed away in the same year, leaving their children with a massive tax bill on their RRSP (Registered Retirement Savings Plan) and vacation home. This made her feel that estate planning in Canada is very difficult.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: The teacher expressed sympathy for Canada&rsquo;s high-tax environment and noted this is one reason he does not recommend immigrating there. This sparked a lively discussion about Canadian taxes (such as the deemed disposition at death, capital gains tax, gift tax, etc.), highlighting the complex realities of wealth planning in different countries.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Vicky 
    <div id="vicky" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#vicky" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question: She made an operational error during a trade. She intended to buy 12 shares of 00865B but ended up buying 12 lots (12,000 shares), forcing her to use her stock pledge loan to cover the funds, which raised her debt ratio to 14%. She asked if she should hold these extra bonds and pay back the money later.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: Absolutely not! In investing, once you make an operational mistake, you must correct it immediately and get back on your original planned track. You cannot let a mistake stand. This was an unplanned, passive borrowing act, which is wrong. She should sell the extra bonds as soon as possible and pay off the pledged loan.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Meihao Weilai 
    <div id="meihao-weilai" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#meihao-weilai" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question: She observed that during recent market volatility, her leveraged ETF portion deviated from its target allocation. She had an impulse to rebalance but resisted because it wasn&rsquo;t her scheduled annual rebalancing time (December/January). Now that the market has rebounded, she is wondering if she made a mistake. She wants to confirm if she should strictly adhere to the once-a-year discipline.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: Yes, you must adhere strictly. You absolutely cannot act based on short-term market fluctuations, or you will become a short-term trader. The discipline is to operate only once a year, pick a time (like December or January), get it done, and then you are finished until the next year. The practice of investing is to reach a state where you don&rsquo;t look at your account and are unaffected by market sentiment.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Jenny 
    <div id="jenny" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#jenny" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question 1: She plans to open an account at HSBC Hong Kong for pledging, using a 4-3-3 allocation. She wanted to confirm if she still needs to follow the principle that the &ldquo;total pledged loan amount should be less than the cash portion (30%)&rdquo;?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: Yes, for absolute safety, you should follow this principle.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2: She currently has an IBKR account in Canada. After opening an HSBC account, should she keep both accounts and operate them in parallel?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: Not recommended. She should consolidate all assets into the HSBC Hong Kong account. Keeping the IBKR account will always expose her to the risk of US estate tax. This &ldquo;leg&rdquo; is a &ldquo;lame leg&rdquo; that will need to be &ldquo;amputated&rdquo; sooner or later, so it&rsquo;s better to deal with it now. He suggested selling the assets directly in IBKR and transferring the cash, rather than attempting a complicated asset transfer.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Doris 
    <div id="doris" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#doris" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: No particular questions, just came on to wish the teacher and classmates a Happy Thanksgiving.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: Thank you, glad you came on.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Liuxiaojuan 
    <div id="liuxiaojuan" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#liuxiaojuan" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Accidentally pressed the button to come on stage and said hello to the teacher.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: Hello.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Rosemary 
    <div id="rosemary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#rosemary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Also pressed by accident, wished the teacher a Happy Thanksgiving.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: Okay, thank you.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Qing 
    <div id="qing" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#qing" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: He observed some investment bloggers on YouTube and found that they privately admit their most profitable business is actually &ldquo;teaching&rdquo; and &ldquo;memberships,&rdquo; not their own investment operations. He used this to comment on Teacher James&rsquo;s &ldquo;Buddha-like heart&rdquo; for teaching for free.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: Thanks for sharing.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Evelyn 
    <div id="evelyn" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#evelyn" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question: She has made up her mind to sell her primary residence to invest but is facing a huge psychological barrier. She calculated that the future rent would be about the same as her current mortgage payment, but her living space would shrink to one-third of its original size. This makes her feel like &ldquo;life is going backward,&rdquo; as if she is &ldquo;sacrificing today&rsquo;s quality of life for an imaginary tomorrow.&rdquo;
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: This is a matter of changing your perspective. By selling the house, you gain a large sum of cash to invest, which means your assets start working for you. A smaller living space means a simpler life, less cleaning, and you can spend your time and money on improving experiences. More importantly, this is a short-term &ldquo;sacrifice.&rdquo; Five or ten years from now, when your invested assets have doubled or grown, you can use the returns to rent a much larger and more luxurious place than the one you sold. This isn&rsquo;t &ldquo;enduring hardship&rdquo;; it&rsquo;s &ldquo;taking nourishment&rdquo; for the sake of exponential future freedom.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Suwei 
    <div id="suwei" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#suwei" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question: He saw an AI video on YouTube imitating Charlie Munger, claiming that QQQ and SPY are overvalued because too many people are buying them, and their prices have detached from the actual value of their constituent stocks, with future returns unlikely to exceed 10%. He is confused by this.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: This is typical nonsense. First, the source of the video is questionable; it&rsquo;s likely AI-generated. Second, the &ldquo;price is too high&rdquo; argument has been made every year for the past decade, yet the market keeps hitting new highs. In the long run, QQQ&rsquo;s annualized return will reach 15% or even higher. Investors need to have critical thinking skills. If you can&rsquo;t distinguish the authenticity of information, the safest approach is not to listen or watch, but to simply execute your established investment strategy.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Cherry 
    <div id="cherry" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#cherry" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: She is currently traveling in Barcelona, Spain, and shared her observations of the relaxed, enjoy-the-moment attitude she saw in Europe. She believes that Chinese culture often makes people too tense, only knowing how to work hard without relaxing. She encouraged everyone that money is a tool for improving quality of life and experiencing the world, not just for accumulating numbers. The brand new, high-quality hotel she stayed in locally cost only about $100 USD per night, proving that without being tied down by property, one can live very well all over the world.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: A very good sharing.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Unnamed Student (Singapore) 
    <div id="unnamed-student-singapore" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#unnamed-student-singapore" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question 1: She works in China and lives in Singapore and wanted to confirm her investment strategy. Should she adopt a leveraged strategy of 60% QQQ + 20% pledge + 20% cash, or since she still has an income, should she go all-in on QQQ and invest a fixed amount monthly?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: For an investor who is new to this concept and unfamiliar with stock pledging, it is recommended to use a simpler method: keep one to two years of living expenses as cash, and with the rest of the money, &ldquo;buy whenever you have money&rdquo; in QQQ. Do not engage in pledging.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2: Her child is 6 years old, and in Singapore&rsquo;s highly competitive environment, she feels very anxious. On one hand, she wants her child to become elite, but on the other, she feels that in the age of AI, children should be allowed to grow up happily.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: A 6-year-old child doesn&rsquo;t need to learn anything; their only job is to play. Don&rsquo;t worry about &ldquo;losing at the starting line&rdquo;; in both investing and life, you need to &ldquo;win at the finish line.&rdquo; Forcing a child to learn will not lead to success. You should take your child to experience the world (travel, museums, libraries) and let him discover his own interests. With hundreds of millions in assets, are you worried your child won&rsquo;t have food to eat? Letting him develop naturally is the best way.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Unnamed Student (House) 
    <div id="unnamed-student-house" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#unnamed-student-house" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question: He once again raised concerns about selling his house. He calculated his situation and believes that after selling the house, the principal invested in QQQ would need five to six years of &ldquo;hardship&rdquo; to double, by which time he might not even be able to buy back his current house.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: This is classic short-sightedness. The teacher did a 30-year calculation for him on the spot: assume he sells his house now and gets back 180,000 in principal, with the house valued at 300,000. In 30 years, at a 6% annualized growth rate, the house will be worth 1.7 million. But the 180,000 principal invested in QQQ, at a 15% annualized return, will become 12 million in 30 years. 1.7 million versus 12 million, which one do you choose? The so-called &ldquo;hardship&rdquo; is your own imagination. Renting can offer more freedom; you can rent a luxury apartment with a swimming pool and gym, and your quality of life might even be higher.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Unnamed Student (Property) 
    <div id="unnamed-student-property" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#unnamed-student-property" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: She discovered that flipping &ldquo;pre-construction properties&rdquo; in Singapore offers very high returns. With a 25% down payment, the profit from the property&rsquo;s appreciation in three to four years can exceed the principal, making the short-term return rate seem higher than QQQ&rsquo;s.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: If you don&rsquo;t believe it, you can go and try. But buying and selling property has transaction costs (6%) and taxes. Many people have already suffered this loss; buying a house will keep you poor for a lifetime. If you want to verify it for yourself, then go ahead.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Meng 
    <div id="meng" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#meng" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question (from the comment section): My assets are less than 10 million, my monthly income is 120,000, and my expenses are 100,000, leaving me with a monthly cash flow of 20,000. Can I, as soon as I receive my 120,000 income each month, immediately buy 100,000 of 00865B and 20,000 of 00662, and then immediately pledge them to borrow 100,000?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: No! Absolutely do not do this. You can&rsquo;t possibly invest 100,000 and expect to borrow 100,000 back; the risk is extremely high. Moreover, your allocation is 80% bonds, which has a very low Beta and poor returns. It&rsquo;s not worth borrowing money for at all.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">IV. Key Quotes 
    <div id="iv-key-quotes" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv-key-quotes" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>Selling your house isn&rsquo;t enduring hardship, it&rsquo;s taking nourishment! You&rsquo;ll understand in the future.
&ndash; James Chan
Context: In response to student Evelyn&rsquo;s psychological struggle about her living space shrinking and feeling a decline in quality of life after selling her house, Teacher James used this vivid metaphor to clarify that this is a short-term adjustment for massive future wealth growth, an act that nurtures the future.</p></blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>We don&rsquo;t need to win at the starting line; we just need to win at the finish line.
&ndash; James Chan
Context: When answering a student&rsquo;s question about how to educate her 6-year-old child in Singapore&rsquo;s fiercely competitive environment, the teacher emphasized the importance of letting children grow up happily and discover their interests, opposing premature, &ldquo;involution&rdquo;-style education.</p></blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>When you have money in the bank, the bank cares a lot about me. &hellip; I also owe the bank money, I owe them a lot. &hellip; (But) I&rsquo;m spending my equity.
&ndash; James Chan
Context: When discussing the relationship between property and banks with a student, the teacher clarified the correct relationship the wealthy have with banks: not as debtors passively repaying loans, but as asset owners actively using their assets (through pledging) to generate cash flow.</p></blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>In investing, once you make an operational mistake, you must correct it immediately and get back on your original planned track. You cannot let a mistake stand.
&ndash; James Chan
Context: When instructing student Vicky on how to handle the mistake of buying too many bonds, the teacher stated unequivocally the only correct principle for dealing with errors.</p></blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>You should listen to his philosophy, not his stock prices. If they ever talk about stock prices, that&rsquo;s nonsense.
&ndash; James Chan
Context: When commenting on the AI-generated &ldquo;Charlie Munger&rdquo; video circulating online, the teacher taught everyone how to selectively absorb information, focusing on learning the mindset and life wisdom of investment masters, rather than getting entangled in their (possibly fabricated) predictions of specific stock prices.</p></blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>Teaching is the most profitable.
&ndash; Qing
Context: Student Qing shared his observation of some investment bloggers, noting that they themselves admit their most profitable business is running courses and memberships, not their own investing, which highlighted the selflessness of Teacher James&rsquo;s free sharing.</p></blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>Your money allows you to stay in high-quality hotels all over the world. &hellip; You really have to slowly learn to adjust your energy, to truly treasure yourself a bit more, to love yourself a bit more.
&ndash; Cherry
Context: Student Cherry shared her insights while traveling in Europe, encouraging everyone to use their wealth to experience the world and improve their quality of life, rather than being shackled by material possessions (like a house).</p></blockquote>


<h2 class="relative group">V. Summary 
    <div id="v-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#v-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This session was rich in content and highly practical. Teacher James not only clearly defined the applicable scope of the tool QQQI, helping those planning for retirement to better construct their cash flow, but also once again clarified the fundamental investment logic of QQQ, strengthening everyone&rsquo;s confidence in long-term holding. The Q&amp;A interaction was particularly brilliant, ranging from specific cross-border account management to profound analyses of investment psychology. The repeated debates on &ldquo;selling a house to invest&rdquo; were especially notable, where the teacher, through firm logic and highly persuasive metaphors, helped students overcome the fear and doubt associated with transitioning from traditional concepts to a modern investment mindset. The entire discussion emphasized the critical role of discipline, critical thinking, and a long-term perspective for investment success.</p>

  



<div
  
    class="flex px-4 py-3 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900"
  >

  <span
    
      class="text-primary-400 ltr:pr-3 rtl:pl-3 flex items-center"
    >

    

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M506.3 417l-213.3-364c-16.33-28-57.54-28-73.98 0l-213.2 364C-10.59 444.9 9.849 480 42.74 480h426.6C502.1 480 522.6 445 506.3 417zM232 168c0-13.25 10.75-24 24-24S280 154.8 280 168v128c0 13.25-10.75 24-23.1 24S232 309.3 232 296V168zM256 416c-17.36 0-31.44-14.08-31.44-31.44c0-17.36 14.07-31.44 31.44-31.44s31.44 14.08 31.44 31.44C287.4 401.9 273.4 416 256 416z"/></svg>

  </span>


  </span>

  <span
    
      class="dark:text-neutral-300"
    ><strong>Disclaimer:</strong> This article is for personal study notes only and does not constitute any investment advice.</span>
</div>

]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>00541 2x Leverage Won't Go to Zero, But Will Drop Until You Doubt Life: Without Rebalancing, No One Can Save You</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1763875778898/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1763875778898/</guid><description>In this episode, Teacher James delves into the true definition of financial freedom: the complete disregard for the existence of money and the market. The content covers the mindset for recent market volatility, reminders for smart rebalancing at year-end, and warnings against AI fraud. On the technical side, he provides a detailed analysis of the target audience and tax implications for high-dividend ETFs (JEPQ, QQQI), as well as how to handle the premium of the China 513100 fund. Additionally, through student Q&amp;amp;A, the session discusses the pros and cons of real estate versus stock assets, the disruptive impact of AI technology on the future, and wisdom regarding interpersonal relationships and retirement life.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<lite-youtube videoid="TW-ffBXPKsU" playlabel="TW-ffBXPKsU" params=""></lite-youtube>



<h2 class="relative group">I. Topic of the Episode 
    <div id="i-topic-of-the-episode" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-topic-of-the-episode" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>The theme of this episode focuses on <strong>&ldquo;True Freedom&rdquo;</strong> and <strong>&ldquo;An Investment Mindset that Ignores the Market.&rdquo;</strong> Teacher James emphasizes that market volatility (such as a 5% rise or fall) and international situations should be irrelevant to investors. True freedom is when daily life is no longer constrained by monetary considerations. Furthermore, as the end of the year approaches, students are reminded to perform &ldquo;Smart Rebalancing.&rdquo; The session also highlights the characteristics and use cases of high-dividend ETFs (such as QQQI, JEPQ) and deeply explores how AI technology is changing content creation and future lifestyles.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">II. Presentation Content 
    <div id="ii-presentation-content" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii-presentation-content" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">1. Investment Mindset and the Definition of Freedom 
    <div id="1-investment-mindset-and-the-definition-of-freedom" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#1-investment-mindset-and-the-definition-of-freedom" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Ignoring Market Volatility</strong>: The market fluctuated by 10% over the past two weeks, but this should have zero impact on long-term index investors. If you can manage to be completely unaware of last week&rsquo;s market fluctuations, or even log into your account only once a year, you are a successful investor.</li>
<li><strong>Financial Freedom</strong>: The definition of freedom is &ldquo;money is not within your considerations.&rdquo; Whether dining out, traveling, or buying a house, being able to act as if you are buying a pair of slippers without considering the price—that is attaining the realm of freedom.</li>
<li><strong>Year-End Operations</strong>: It is currently November/December, which is a good time for <strong>Smart Rebalancing</strong>. If you don&rsquo;t want to do it now, doing it early next year is also fine.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">2. Fraud Warning 
    <div id="2-fraud-warning" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#2-fraud-warning" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>AI Identity Theft</strong>: Fraud groups are using AI technology (such as ChatGPT) to impersonate Teacher James (ID: Chairman1, etc.) and reply in the YouTube comments section, even using AI-generated voice.</li>
<li><strong>Sole Contact Method</strong>: Please recognize Teacher James&rsquo;s correct ID. All communication should be conducted via Email; do not easily trust private messages within YouTube or Clubhouse.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">3. New YouTube Features and Content Dissemination 
    <div id="3-new-youtube-features-and-content-dissemination" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#3-new-youtube-features-and-content-dissemination" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Multi-Language Audio Tracks</strong>: YouTube now features AI automatic audio track translation. Uploaded Chinese videos can be automatically translated into English voiceovers, giving future content global dissemination capabilities.</li>
<li><strong>Setup Method</strong>: Select &ldquo;Audio Track&rdquo; in the video settings to switch languages. While this increases content reach, it also implies that English content can more aggressively conduct global cultural export.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">4. Investment Tools and Asset Allocation 
    <div id="4-investment-tools-and-asset-allocation" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#4-investment-tools-and-asset-allocation" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>China 513100 Premium Issue</strong>:
<ul>
<li>Do not obsess over the premium. Due to foreign exchange controls, financial institutions cannot immediately arbitrage to close the gap, so the premium may exist for a long time (even 100 years).</li>
<li><strong>Strategy</strong>: Buy immediately at market price. Getting &ldquo;on the bus&rdquo; is what matters most; do not miss the market rally while waiting for the premium to converge.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>High-Dividend ETF Analysis (JEPQ, QQQI)</strong>:
<ul>
<li><strong>Target Audience</strong>: Those who have retired and need stable cash flow. <strong>Young people should not invest in this</strong>; they should focus on growth.</li>
<li><strong>Characteristics</strong>:
<ul>
<li><strong>JEPQ</strong>: Dividend yield approx. 10%, Beta approx. 0.7-0.8 (lower volatility).</li>
<li><strong>QQQI</strong>: Dividend yield approx. 12-13%, Beta approx. 0.9-1.1 (volatility close to QQQ).</li>
<li><strong>Major Holdings</strong>: These funds typically hold about 80% in QQQ and use the other 20% for options strategies (Covered Call, etc.) to generate cash flow.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Tax Issues</strong>:
<ul>
<li>US Tax Residents: Primarily treated as Long-term capital gains (preferential tax rate), not ordinary Income.</li>
<li>Taiwan/Overseas Investors: If the brokerage (e.g., SinoPac re-consignment, with IBKR as the upstream) has QI status, there may be an automatic Refund, allowing for full dividend receipt. Generally, non-US residents face 30% withholding, but products like QQQI may have higher refund ratios due to their structural characteristics.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Risk Warning</strong>: These are not Cash (Money Market); they will still fall with the market (potentially dropping 20-30%) and risk must be considered.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Leveraged Fund Risks</strong>:
<ul>
<li>Although leveraged funds (like TQQQ) won&rsquo;t go to zero, they can face a 99% decline.</li>
<li><strong>Smart Rebalancing</strong> must be executed: convert profits to cash during rises so you have funds to replenish positions during major market crashes (e.g., an 85% drop).</li>
<li>Leveraged positions must not exceed the prototype fund or cash positions.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">5. Real Estate and Life Philosophy 
    <div id="5-real-estate-and-life-philosophy" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#5-real-estate-and-life-philosophy" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Houses are Cages</strong>: Young people should not buy houses too early; carrying a mortgage is like locking yourself in a cage. Buying a house should only be considered when it feels as easy as buying slippers.</li>
<li><strong>Advantages of Stock Pledging</strong>: Stock pledging has no upper age limit and is flexible to handle; whereas real estate loans (like reverse mortgages) face increasing restrictions with age. Stocks are better assets than real estate and are easier to divide for inheritance.</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">III. Q&amp;A Session 
    <div id="iii-qa-session" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii-qa-session" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Ray 
    <div id="ray" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ray" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing</strong>: Recently listened to a speech by Charlie Munger and learned about holding cash, understanding risk, antifragility, and not being jealous.</li>
<li><strong>Question</strong>: Munger always emphasized &ldquo;no leverage&rdquo; and &ldquo;no borrowing,&rdquo; but Buffett actually uses insurance float as leverage. Why did Munger advise this? Does it conflict with our concept of &ldquo;leveraged investing&rdquo;?
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s Reply</strong>:
<ol>
<li>Munger opposed <strong>borrowing for consumption</strong> (e.g., Americans borrowing to buy mansions, luxury cars, paying for travel in installments), which leads to being &ldquo;exquisitely poor.&rdquo;</li>
<li>Munger opposed <strong>all-in, unhedged leveraged investment</strong> (like going all-in on Bitcoin or a single stock).</li>
<li>Our borrowing is based on <strong>asset allocation and risk control</strong>, which is completely different from the gambling-style borrowing Munger opposed.</li>
<li>Regarding jealousy: Never compare yourself with others; compare with yourself. Win at the finish line, not at the starting line. Be overflowing with confidence and ignore outside noise.</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Jialin 
    <div id="jialin" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#jialin" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Question 1</strong>: My firm, which I ran for 15 years, is closing due to hiring difficulties. Although I have enough money, I feel I wasted my youth and feel sad. How do I adjust?</li>
<li><strong>Question 2</strong>: Single, 50 years old, no children, assets approx. 35 million TWD, annual expenses 1.8 million. Previously advised a 3-1-6 allocation; can I now use 18 million to buy high-dividend ETFs (like 0056 or QQQI) and do a 70/30 allocation with the rest?
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s Reply</strong>:
<ul>
<li><strong>Regarding Asset Allocation</strong>: Since you have 35 million, taking 20 million to buy QQQI or 0056 generates over 2 million in cash flow annually, fully covering the 1.8 million expenses with surplus. Keep 5 million in cash and buy 00662 with the rest for long-term growth. You have plenty of money; enjoy it to the fullest.</li>
<li><strong>Regarding Mindset</strong>: Closing the firm is a good thing; it ends the torture. Life doesn&rsquo;t require &ldquo;doing things&rdquo;; it&rsquo;s okay to contain &ldquo;idleness.&rdquo; Establish <strong>rituals</strong> in life (gardening, keeping fish, pour-over coffee, reading), enjoy freedom, and don&rsquo;t need work to prove your value.</li>
<li><strong>Special Advice</strong>: Single people need to build a close circle of friends who can &ldquo;go to the emergency room with you at 2 AM.&rdquo; This is very important.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Haoqing 
    <div id="haoqing" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#haoqing" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Question</strong>: I have a retired client couple with few assets, living on Social Security. They own a large house worth about 6 million USD. The wife has an emotional attachment to &ldquo;home&rdquo; and refuses to sell, wanting to turn it into an Airbnb while they move back to Taiwan. Is this wise?
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s Reply</strong>:
<ul>
<li>Very unwise. Keeping a big house (&ldquo;old hen&rdquo;) that doesn&rsquo;t lay eggs is not cost-effective. The maintenance costs (property tax, repairs) for a 6 million dollar house are extremely high.</li>
<li><strong>Advice</strong>: Sell the house, cash out 3-4 million USD, invest in QQQI, and generate 300,000-400,000 USD in annual cash flow.</li>
<li><strong>Lifestyle</strong>: With this huge cash flow, they can rent the highest-end apartments (with pools, gyms, social events) anywhere in the world (including the US) and enjoy true freedom, instead of being an Airbnb landlord dealing with messes. Mindsets must change; don&rsquo;t be trapped by &ldquo;poor man&rsquo;s thinking.&rdquo;</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">BB 
    <div id="bb" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#bb" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing</strong>: The biggest takeaway from following the teacher is &ldquo;peace of mind.&rdquo; I used to feel that not working meant losing, now I understand &ldquo;it&rsquo;s okay not to do it.&rdquo;</li>
<li><strong>Question</strong>: Considering moving back to the Bay Area. No longer obsessed with buying a house or top school districts; thinking renting and mid-to-upper school districts are fine?
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s Reply</strong>:
<ul>
<li>Strongly support this. Even as a VP, you can &ldquo;work with one hand&rdquo;; being less busy actually improves efficiency.</li>
<li>Renting in the Bay Area ($4500-5000) gets you into luxury apartments with excellent facilities, offering a higher quality of life.</li>
<li><strong>Regarding School Districts</strong>: You don&rsquo;t need to squeeze children into top school districts that are entirely Asian. Mid-to-upper Mixed school districts are actually better for children to integrate into American society and diverse cultures.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Washington 
    <div id="washington" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#washington" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Question 1</strong>: TQQQ recently did a stock split. Is this good or bad?
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s Reply</strong>: Neither good nor bad; the essence hasn&rsquo;t changed at all. It&rsquo;s like exchanging a 100-dollar bill for two 50-dollar bills. The value remains the same; it&rsquo;s just a numbers game in accounting.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question 2</strong>: regarding retirement, some say the brain degenerates if you retire, others say retiring early is good. What&rsquo;s your view?
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s Reply</strong>: The key is <strong>Freedom</strong>. If you don&rsquo;t dare to live somewhere because taxes are high (like California), that is not freedom. The goal should be to be unconstrained by money and location.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question 3</strong>: My son bought a life insurance policy (Whole Life), paying $1000/month. He has paid 130k. Initially told he only needed to pay for 10 years, now the agent says he has to pay until age 100?
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s Reply</strong>: This is <strong>garbage</strong>. I suggest stopping it (Cancel) immediately. Instead of paying $1000 to the insurance company every month, put it into QQQ. Savings/Whole Life insurance for young people usually has low returns, and eventually, even the principal might be eaten up by premiums.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Pei 
    <div id="pei" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#pei" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing</strong>: Watched a video by Professor Zeng Shiqiang saying that the fate between parents and children is for &ldquo;separation,&rdquo; not possession. Shared a story where her father forced her brother to drop out and become an apprentice because he didn&rsquo;t study well, leading to a lifelong rift.
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s Reply</strong>: Strongly agree. Children are independent individuals; studying isn&rsquo;t the only path. A parent&rsquo;s responsibility is love and guidance, not control. Do not do things based on traditional concepts that you will regret for the rest of your life.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Billy 
    <div id="billy" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#billy" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Question</strong>: Saw a YQQQ (Inverse ETF) with a seemingly high dividend yield (30%+). Is it worth investing?
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s Reply</strong>: <strong>Absolutely do not touch it.</strong> This is a toxic asset. Although the yield looks high, the share price may drop 28% or more annually. With principal loss plus tax costs, the total return is negative. Don&rsquo;t touch things you don&rsquo;t understand.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Wang Zhihua 
    <div id="wang-zhihua" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#wang-zhihua" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Question 1</strong>: Confirming regarding investing in China fund 513100 from the mainland: should I buy directly regardless of the premium?
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s Reply</strong>: Yes, ignore the premium and buy directly at market price.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question 2</strong>: Bought previously and it dropped 30%. Should I replenish now or wait?
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s Reply</strong>: Replenish now. Investing for children looks at a 20-30 year horizon. Buy when you have money; don&rsquo;t hold cash.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question 3</strong>: Can mainlanders buy QQQI through Hong Kong brokerages? Is it suitable?
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s Reply</strong>: You can buy it. QQQI (80% QQQ + 20% Option Strategy) has both growth and cash flow. If you are retired or need cash flow, calculate the purchase amount based on your required annual income (e.g., if you need 60,000 RMB annual income, buy the corresponding principal amount of QQQI).</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Mike 
    <div id="mike" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#mike" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Question 1</strong>: Michael Burry and others believe AI hardware (GPUs, etc.) depreciates too slowly, actual obsolescence is fast, and there might be financial fraud or a bubble?
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s Reply</strong>: This is nonsense. It is normal for tech hardware (like data centers, GPUs) to depreciate over 5-7 years. The release of a new generation doesn&rsquo;t mean old ones are scrapped immediately; old equipment continues to generate value (Perform). Michael Burry is often wrong on the short side, and his fund performance is not good.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question 2</strong>: What is the physical entity of the &ldquo;Cloud&rdquo; in the AI era? Since the Internet corresponds to the Cloud, what does AI correspond to?
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s Reply</strong>:
<ul>
<li>AI is <strong>Everywhere</strong>. In the future, there will be no concept of Apps, only Input (Voice/Vision) and Output (Screen/Execution).</li>
<li>AI will become your <strong>Agent</strong>, handling all miscellaneous tasks (ordering coffee, booking doctors, making spreadsheets, buying tickets).</li>
<li>Companies controlling platforms and entry points like Google and Apple will dominate. Google is currently leading in AI technology (Gemini, etc.).</li>
<li>Elon Musk launching computing power into space (Space-based AI) is also a trend.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Rabbit (Tu Baobao) 
    <div id="rabbit-tu-baobao" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#rabbit-tu-baobao" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Comment</strong>: Everyone selling is wrong.
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s Reply</strong>: Correct. Selling at any time is wrong; buying at any time is right.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">IV. Highlighted Views 
    <div id="iv-highlighted-views" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv-highlighted-views" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>The definition of freedom is that money is not within your considerations.
&ndash; Teacher James</p></blockquote>
<p>This view was presented when explaining the true realm of financial freedom, emphasizing that freedom is not about how much money you have, but that life decisions are no longer constrained by money.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Return rate is not determined by asset allocation; return rate is determined by the future market. Asset allocation determines whether you can survive.
&ndash; Teacher James</p></blockquote>
<p>This view was presented to correct students who overly pursue backtested performance simulations, emphasizing that the primary purpose of asset allocation is risk control and psychological comfort.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Don&rsquo;t buy a house; buying a house is building a cage for yourself and locking yourself inside.
&ndash; Teacher James</p></blockquote>
<p>This view was presented when answering questions about young people buying homes and handling real estate after retirement, advocating not letting real estate limit life&rsquo;s freedom.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The fate between parents and children is not for being together, but for separation.
&ndash; Student Pei (Quoting Professor Zeng Shiqiang)</p></blockquote>
<p>This view was cited during a student&rsquo;s sharing of family relationship insights, emphasizing that parents should respect their children&rsquo;s independence and learn to exit gracefully.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>All selling is wrong, and all buying (at any time) is right.
&ndash; Teacher James</p></blockquote>
<p>This view was in response to a comment in the live stream, reiterating the core philosophy of index investing: long-term holding, buy only, never sell.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">V. Summary 
    <div id="v-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#v-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>In this episode, Teacher James further deepened the core concept of &ldquo;Financial Freedom&rdquo;—achieving complete indifference to money and market fluctuations. On the practical side, detailed explanations of high-dividend tools like QQQI were provided for the retired demographic, along with a strong recommendation to sell inefficient real estate assets and switch to financial assets to obtain true freedom and cash flow. Regarding the tech horizon, the teacher depicted a future where AI Agents will replace traditional Apps and reminded everyone to use AI tools to improve efficiency. Finally, regarding family relationships, the importance of respecting independent individuals and emotional connections was emphasized, encouraging everyone to live a &ldquo;free life&rdquo; unbound by money.</p>

  



<div
  
    class="flex px-4 py-3 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900"
  >

  <span
    
      class="text-primary-400 ltr:pr-3 rtl:pl-3 flex items-center"
    >

    

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M506.3 417l-213.3-364c-16.33-28-57.54-28-73.98 0l-213.2 364C-10.59 444.9 9.849 480 42.74 480h426.6C502.1 480 522.6 445 506.3 417zM232 168c0-13.25 10.75-24 24-24S280 154.8 280 168v128c0 13.25-10.75 24-23.1 24S232 309.3 232 296V168zM256 416c-17.36 0-31.44-14.08-31.44-31.44c0-17.36 14.07-31.44 31.44-31.44s31.44 14.08 31.44 31.44C287.4 401.9 273.4 416 256 416z"/></svg>

  </span>


  </span>

  <span
    
      class="dark:text-neutral-300"
    ><strong>Disclaimer:</strong> This article is merely personal study notes and does not constitute any investment advice.</span>
</div>

]]></content:encoded></item></channel></rss>