<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>QQQI on QQQ Investor</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/tags/qqqi/</link><description>Recent content in QQQI on QQQ Investor</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jomonylw.github.io/en/tags/qqqi/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>00542 A 2.5% retirement withdrawal rate is key; QQQ is not about tech, it's about the strongest companies! The investment focus isn't on industry classification, but on the correct logic for long-term wealth building</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1764465235759/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1764465235759/</guid><description>In this session, Teacher James explains in detail the application scenarios of QQQI as a retirement cash flow tool and provides an in-depth analysis clarifying that QQQ is not purely a high-tech fund, but an investment in the current one hundred strongest companies. The Q&amp;amp;A session was lively, discussing asset allocation and stock pledging operations in different regions like Hong Kong, Canada, and Mainland China. Through long-term data comparison, the immense advantage of the &amp;#39;sell your house, rent, and invest in indexes&amp;#39; strategy was re-emphasized to help students overcome psychological barriers to investing.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<lite-youtube videoid="A65OoUXqteY" playlabel="A65OoUXqteY" params=""></lite-youtube>



<h2 class="relative group">I. Main Topic of the Session 
    <div id="i-main-topic-of-the-session" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-main-topic-of-the-session" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>The core of this class revolved around two key points: first, introducing the proper use of the high-dividend ETF <strong>QQQI</strong> for retirees and investors needing cash flow, emphasizing its role as a supplementary cash flow tool rather than a substitute for cash itself; second, through in-depth analysis, clarifying the common misconception about <strong>QQQ (Nasdaq 100 Index)</strong>, pointing out that its investment logic is to &ldquo;invest in the strongest companies of the moment,&rdquo; not limited to the &ldquo;high-tech&rdquo; sector. Teacher James used examples and a historical perspective to explain the dynamic adaptability of the index and reiterated the core investment philosophy of holding for the long term and ignoring market fluctuations.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">II. Briefing Content 
    <div id="ii-briefing-content" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii-briefing-content" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Reminder: Beware of Scams 
    <div id="reminder-beware-of-scams" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#reminder-beware-of-scams" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Teacher James once again reminded everyone that scam groups are continuously using his name and profile picture to impersonate him.</li>
<li>The teacher emphasized that he has over 4,000 followers, while the scammers only have a few dozen, making them easy to distinguish.</li>
<li>Initially, scammers may imitate the teacher&rsquo;s tone, even using AI tools to answer questions, but their ultimate goal is to defraud people of money or request to manage their accounts. Please be vigilant and do not engage in private chats or send money to any &ldquo;James Chan&rdquo; who actively contacts you offering investment advice.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Investment Philosophy: Simple, Firm, No Forecasting 
    <div id="investment-philosophy-simple-firm-no-forecasting" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#investment-philosophy-simple-firm-no-forecasting" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Market Irrelevance</strong>: Market volatility, international situations, economic data, and company earnings reports are all irrelevant to our investment decisions.</li>
<li><strong>Core Strategy</strong>: The only correct strategy is to &ldquo;buy whenever you have money, hold for the long term, and never sell.&rdquo;</li>
<li><strong>Investment Target</strong>: Do not invest in individual stocks; focus on broad-market index funds to avoid the risks associated with individual company earnings and operations.</li>
<li><strong>Risk Awareness</strong>: The market can drop by 50% or even 80% at any time. Investors must manage their own risk and ensure that the funds invested are for the long term and will not be needed.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">QQQI: A Cash Flow Tool for Retirees 
    <div id="qqqi-a-cash-flow-tool-for-retirees" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#qqqi-a-cash-flow-tool-for-retirees" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Target Audience</strong>: QQQI is suitable for those who are retired or need a stable cash flow, especially when your annual expenses exceed 2.5% of your total assets.</li>
<li><strong>Functional Positioning</strong>: QQQI is a tool to <strong>generate cash flow</strong>, but it <strong>cannot be equated with cash</strong>. Your emergency fund should still be kept in highly liquid assets like money market funds (e.g., 00865B).</li>
<li><strong>Allocation Scenario</strong>: If your retirement assets are less than 40 times your annual expenses (i.e., your withdrawal rate is higher than 2.5%), you can pair it with a portion of QQQI to increase overall cash flow yield to meet living expenses. Young people or investors still in the accumulation phase should continue to invest in growth-oriented index funds like QQQ, 00662, etc.</li>
<li><strong>Practical Application</strong>:
<ul>
<li>In the United States, QQQI can be held in both retirement and individual accounts.</li>
<li>In Taiwan, you can purchase QQQI through a sub-brokerage (such as Yuanta, Fubon, Cathay). Most of the dividends distributed can be reclaimed through tax refunds.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Case Study</strong>: A friend of the teacher followed his advice early on, sold his house, and went all-in on QQQ (00662). His assets grew by 1.5 times in five to six years, achieving financial freedom. He now enjoys a high-quality retired life. This stands in stark contrast to those who work their entire lives for a house, a car, and an insurance company.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Analyzing QQQ: Investing in the Strongest Companies, Not a Pure Tech Fund 
    <div id="analyzing-qqq-investing-in-the-strongest-companies-not-a-pure-tech-fund" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#analyzing-qqq-investing-in-the-strongest-companies-not-a-pure-tech-fund" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Dispelling the Misconception</strong>: Many believe that investing in QQQ is investing in &ldquo;American high-tech.&rdquo; This is not entirely accurate. Truly pure technology sector funds are like XLK or VGT, but we do not recommend investing in any sector-specific funds.</li>
<li><strong>The Essence of QQQ</strong>: QQQ invests in the <strong>100 strongest companies listed on the Nasdaq Stock Exchange</strong>. It is an index without a &ldquo;personality&rdquo;; its only criterion is &ldquo;strength.&rdquo;</li>
<li><strong>Dynamic Adaptability</strong>:
<ul>
<li>In the current era, the strongest companies happen to be mostly high-tech firms.</li>
<li>However, if we went back 40 years, the strongest companies might have been those making radios, televisions, or trains, and they would have been included in the index. The definition of &ldquo;high-tech&rdquo; changes with the times.</li>
<li>The index also includes companies like Costco and Starbucks, which are not high-tech but are extremely powerful.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Core Viewpoint</strong>: We invest in QQQ because we believe that human progress is driven by these strongest companies. We are investing in a <strong>mechanism that dynamically selects the strongest players</strong>, not betting on a specific industry. Obsessing over whether it is a &ldquo;high-tech fund&rdquo; is pointless; what matters is its excellent long-term performance.</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">III. Q&amp;A Session 
    <div id="iii-qa-session" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii-qa-session" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Momo 
    <div id="momo" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#momo" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Discussed the process of stock pledging at HSBC in Hong Kong. She found HSBC&rsquo;s loan-to-value ratios to be relatively conservative (70% for underlying stocks, 90% for cash, leveraged ETFs cannot be pledged), which is lower than in the US or Taiwan.</li>
<li>Question 1: She designed a low-risk allocation of 50% Nasdaq and 50% cash (Beta=0.5), with annual expenses accounting for about 3% of total assets. She wanted to confirm if this approach is safe and whether using the cash portion would create risk. Additionally, she heard that HSBC uses the entire account as collateral, rather than differentiating by asset type, and wanted to verify this.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: The pledging rules at HSBC Hong Kong are identical to those in the US. It&rsquo;s normal for leveraged funds to have no pledge value. She has two options: 1. If taxes are not a concern, she can build a 4-3-3 portfolio within HSBC, buying Hong Kong-listed leveraged ETFs and rebalancing. 2. To avoid domestic capital gains tax, she could, like other students, buy and sell leveraged ETFs through an overseas broker like IBKR, but she must be mindful of potential future US estate tax issues. The teacher emphasized that when you need money, you should &ldquo;borrow&rdquo; from your credit line, not &ldquo;sell assets.&rdquo; A single withdrawal should preferably not exceed 10% of total assets, and always ensure your cash position is greater than your total liabilities; this is very safe.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2: She is helping her mother with financial management and, to give her mother a sense of involvement, is debating whether to open a Joint Account or manage it herself and provide regular updates.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: There are several options, depending on her mother&rsquo;s preference. They could open a joint account; she could open an account in her mother&rsquo;s name, and her mother could sign a Power of Attorney for her to operate it; or she could open it in her name and just share the login details so her mother can view it anytime. The simplest way is to show her the monthly statement and discuss the account&rsquo;s status together.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Zhihua Wang 
    <div id="zhihua-wang" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#zhihua-wang" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question: Is the dividend yield of QQYI fixed? He observed it changed from 12% last week to 13.64% this week.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: The dividend yield is related to market volatility, so the amount paid out each month will vary slightly, but the annual total is generally stable between 10%-13%. It is not fixed. The teacher also demonstrated live how to use ChatGPT to calculate asset allocation ratios: by inputting the expected returns of different portfolios (e.g., 2.5% for a 4-3-3 portfolio, 11% for QQQI), the AI can help you calculate the capital proportions needed to achieve a target return rate (e.g., 4% or 6%).</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Jet 
    <div id="jet" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#jet" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question: Does the teacher have any recommended retirement locations in the US? The requirements are safety, good climate, and few natural disasters.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: (Jokingly) You&rsquo;re welcome to be my neighbor in Cupertino, California. It&rsquo;s next to Apple&rsquo;s headquarters, very safe, our area has no wildfire issues, and there are many excellent hospitals.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Tianluzhixia 
    <div id="tianluzhixia" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#tianluzhixia" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question: He is currently in South Korea and learned that the stock pledging interest rate is around 4.5%, which feels higher than in the US and Taiwan. Is it still worth doing?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: 4.5% is very cheap! The rates in the US are now up to 6%, so 4.5% is a very good rate and completely worth doing. South Korea has a well-developed financial system, and being able to buy 2x leveraged ETFs is also great.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Wendy 
    <div id="wendy" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#wendy" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question: She is a citizen of mainland China but has accounts and funds in mainland China, Hong Kong (Standard Chartered Bank), and IBKR (opened previously in Canada). She feels her asset allocation is chaotic and doesn&rsquo;t know how to distribute it.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: First, as a Chinese tax resident, it is not advisable to keep large assets in IBKR due to the risk of US estate tax; the funds should be consolidated into a Hong Kong account as soon as possible. Second, it&rsquo;s important to distinguish between &ldquo;margin financing&rdquo; at mainland brokers (borrowing money to buy stocks, cash cannot be withdrawn) and &ldquo;stock pledging&rdquo; at Hong Kong banks (collateralizing stocks to borrow cash for spending). He advised her to keep about 1 year of living expenses in China, 2-3 years of cash in Hong Kong, and invest the majority of the remaining funds in the Nasdaq 100 index. She could allocate a small portion (e.g., 10%) to a 2x leveraged ETF since she is still young and not yet retired.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Liang 
    <div id="liang" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#liang" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question 1: An internal staff member from a free tax filing software platform she uses in Canada contacted her, pointing out that her mutual fund fees were high and promoting investment advice to her. She felt this was a violation of her privacy.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: This is most likely because she agreed to the user agreement upon registration, which included a clause allowing the platform to use her data for internal marketing. This kind of investment advice is a &ldquo;scam&rdquo;; just ignore it. He re-emphasized the first rule of investing: stay away from any advice from financial advisors and banks.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2: She shared a news story from Canada where a couple passed away in the same year, leaving their children with a massive tax bill on their RRSP (Registered Retirement Savings Plan) and vacation home. This made her feel that estate planning in Canada is very difficult.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: The teacher expressed sympathy for Canada&rsquo;s high-tax environment and noted this is one reason he does not recommend immigrating there. This sparked a lively discussion about Canadian taxes (such as the deemed disposition at death, capital gains tax, gift tax, etc.), highlighting the complex realities of wealth planning in different countries.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Vicky 
    <div id="vicky" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#vicky" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question: She made an operational error during a trade. She intended to buy 12 shares of 00865B but ended up buying 12 lots (12,000 shares), forcing her to use her stock pledge loan to cover the funds, which raised her debt ratio to 14%. She asked if she should hold these extra bonds and pay back the money later.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: Absolutely not! In investing, once you make an operational mistake, you must correct it immediately and get back on your original planned track. You cannot let a mistake stand. This was an unplanned, passive borrowing act, which is wrong. She should sell the extra bonds as soon as possible and pay off the pledged loan.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Meihao Weilai 
    <div id="meihao-weilai" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#meihao-weilai" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question: She observed that during recent market volatility, her leveraged ETF portion deviated from its target allocation. She had an impulse to rebalance but resisted because it wasn&rsquo;t her scheduled annual rebalancing time (December/January). Now that the market has rebounded, she is wondering if she made a mistake. She wants to confirm if she should strictly adhere to the once-a-year discipline.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: Yes, you must adhere strictly. You absolutely cannot act based on short-term market fluctuations, or you will become a short-term trader. The discipline is to operate only once a year, pick a time (like December or January), get it done, and then you are finished until the next year. The practice of investing is to reach a state where you don&rsquo;t look at your account and are unaffected by market sentiment.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Jenny 
    <div id="jenny" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#jenny" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question 1: She plans to open an account at HSBC Hong Kong for pledging, using a 4-3-3 allocation. She wanted to confirm if she still needs to follow the principle that the &ldquo;total pledged loan amount should be less than the cash portion (30%)&rdquo;?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: Yes, for absolute safety, you should follow this principle.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2: She currently has an IBKR account in Canada. After opening an HSBC account, should she keep both accounts and operate them in parallel?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: Not recommended. She should consolidate all assets into the HSBC Hong Kong account. Keeping the IBKR account will always expose her to the risk of US estate tax. This &ldquo;leg&rdquo; is a &ldquo;lame leg&rdquo; that will need to be &ldquo;amputated&rdquo; sooner or later, so it&rsquo;s better to deal with it now. He suggested selling the assets directly in IBKR and transferring the cash, rather than attempting a complicated asset transfer.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Doris 
    <div id="doris" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#doris" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: No particular questions, just came on to wish the teacher and classmates a Happy Thanksgiving.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: Thank you, glad you came on.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Liuxiaojuan 
    <div id="liuxiaojuan" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#liuxiaojuan" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Accidentally pressed the button to come on stage and said hello to the teacher.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: Hello.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Rosemary 
    <div id="rosemary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#rosemary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Also pressed by accident, wished the teacher a Happy Thanksgiving.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: Okay, thank you.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Qing 
    <div id="qing" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#qing" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: He observed some investment bloggers on YouTube and found that they privately admit their most profitable business is actually &ldquo;teaching&rdquo; and &ldquo;memberships,&rdquo; not their own investment operations. He used this to comment on Teacher James&rsquo;s &ldquo;Buddha-like heart&rdquo; for teaching for free.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: Thanks for sharing.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Evelyn 
    <div id="evelyn" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#evelyn" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question: She has made up her mind to sell her primary residence to invest but is facing a huge psychological barrier. She calculated that the future rent would be about the same as her current mortgage payment, but her living space would shrink to one-third of its original size. This makes her feel like &ldquo;life is going backward,&rdquo; as if she is &ldquo;sacrificing today&rsquo;s quality of life for an imaginary tomorrow.&rdquo;
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: This is a matter of changing your perspective. By selling the house, you gain a large sum of cash to invest, which means your assets start working for you. A smaller living space means a simpler life, less cleaning, and you can spend your time and money on improving experiences. More importantly, this is a short-term &ldquo;sacrifice.&rdquo; Five or ten years from now, when your invested assets have doubled or grown, you can use the returns to rent a much larger and more luxurious place than the one you sold. This isn&rsquo;t &ldquo;enduring hardship&rdquo;; it&rsquo;s &ldquo;taking nourishment&rdquo; for the sake of exponential future freedom.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Suwei 
    <div id="suwei" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#suwei" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question: He saw an AI video on YouTube imitating Charlie Munger, claiming that QQQ and SPY are overvalued because too many people are buying them, and their prices have detached from the actual value of their constituent stocks, with future returns unlikely to exceed 10%. He is confused by this.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: This is typical nonsense. First, the source of the video is questionable; it&rsquo;s likely AI-generated. Second, the &ldquo;price is too high&rdquo; argument has been made every year for the past decade, yet the market keeps hitting new highs. In the long run, QQQ&rsquo;s annualized return will reach 15% or even higher. Investors need to have critical thinking skills. If you can&rsquo;t distinguish the authenticity of information, the safest approach is not to listen or watch, but to simply execute your established investment strategy.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Cherry 
    <div id="cherry" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#cherry" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: She is currently traveling in Barcelona, Spain, and shared her observations of the relaxed, enjoy-the-moment attitude she saw in Europe. She believes that Chinese culture often makes people too tense, only knowing how to work hard without relaxing. She encouraged everyone that money is a tool for improving quality of life and experiencing the world, not just for accumulating numbers. The brand new, high-quality hotel she stayed in locally cost only about $100 USD per night, proving that without being tied down by property, one can live very well all over the world.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: A very good sharing.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Unnamed Student (Singapore) 
    <div id="unnamed-student-singapore" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#unnamed-student-singapore" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question 1: She works in China and lives in Singapore and wanted to confirm her investment strategy. Should she adopt a leveraged strategy of 60% QQQ + 20% pledge + 20% cash, or since she still has an income, should she go all-in on QQQ and invest a fixed amount monthly?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: For an investor who is new to this concept and unfamiliar with stock pledging, it is recommended to use a simpler method: keep one to two years of living expenses as cash, and with the rest of the money, &ldquo;buy whenever you have money&rdquo; in QQQ. Do not engage in pledging.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2: Her child is 6 years old, and in Singapore&rsquo;s highly competitive environment, she feels very anxious. On one hand, she wants her child to become elite, but on the other, she feels that in the age of AI, children should be allowed to grow up happily.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: A 6-year-old child doesn&rsquo;t need to learn anything; their only job is to play. Don&rsquo;t worry about &ldquo;losing at the starting line&rdquo;; in both investing and life, you need to &ldquo;win at the finish line.&rdquo; Forcing a child to learn will not lead to success. You should take your child to experience the world (travel, museums, libraries) and let him discover his own interests. With hundreds of millions in assets, are you worried your child won&rsquo;t have food to eat? Letting him develop naturally is the best way.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Unnamed Student (House) 
    <div id="unnamed-student-house" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#unnamed-student-house" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question: He once again raised concerns about selling his house. He calculated his situation and believes that after selling the house, the principal invested in QQQ would need five to six years of &ldquo;hardship&rdquo; to double, by which time he might not even be able to buy back his current house.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: This is classic short-sightedness. The teacher did a 30-year calculation for him on the spot: assume he sells his house now and gets back 180,000 in principal, with the house valued at 300,000. In 30 years, at a 6% annualized growth rate, the house will be worth 1.7 million. But the 180,000 principal invested in QQQ, at a 15% annualized return, will become 12 million in 30 years. 1.7 million versus 12 million, which one do you choose? The so-called &ldquo;hardship&rdquo; is your own imagination. Renting can offer more freedom; you can rent a luxury apartment with a swimming pool and gym, and your quality of life might even be higher.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Unnamed Student (Property) 
    <div id="unnamed-student-property" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#unnamed-student-property" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: She discovered that flipping &ldquo;pre-construction properties&rdquo; in Singapore offers very high returns. With a 25% down payment, the profit from the property&rsquo;s appreciation in three to four years can exceed the principal, making the short-term return rate seem higher than QQQ&rsquo;s.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: If you don&rsquo;t believe it, you can go and try. But buying and selling property has transaction costs (6%) and taxes. Many people have already suffered this loss; buying a house will keep you poor for a lifetime. If you want to verify it for yourself, then go ahead.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Meng 
    <div id="meng" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#meng" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question (from the comment section): My assets are less than 10 million, my monthly income is 120,000, and my expenses are 100,000, leaving me with a monthly cash flow of 20,000. Can I, as soon as I receive my 120,000 income each month, immediately buy 100,000 of 00865B and 20,000 of 00662, and then immediately pledge them to borrow 100,000?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: No! Absolutely do not do this. You can&rsquo;t possibly invest 100,000 and expect to borrow 100,000 back; the risk is extremely high. Moreover, your allocation is 80% bonds, which has a very low Beta and poor returns. It&rsquo;s not worth borrowing money for at all.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">IV. Key Quotes 
    <div id="iv-key-quotes" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv-key-quotes" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>Selling your house isn&rsquo;t enduring hardship, it&rsquo;s taking nourishment! You&rsquo;ll understand in the future.
&ndash; James Chan
Context: In response to student Evelyn&rsquo;s psychological struggle about her living space shrinking and feeling a decline in quality of life after selling her house, Teacher James used this vivid metaphor to clarify that this is a short-term adjustment for massive future wealth growth, an act that nurtures the future.</p></blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>We don&rsquo;t need to win at the starting line; we just need to win at the finish line.
&ndash; James Chan
Context: When answering a student&rsquo;s question about how to educate her 6-year-old child in Singapore&rsquo;s fiercely competitive environment, the teacher emphasized the importance of letting children grow up happily and discover their interests, opposing premature, &ldquo;involution&rdquo;-style education.</p></blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>When you have money in the bank, the bank cares a lot about me. &hellip; I also owe the bank money, I owe them a lot. &hellip; (But) I&rsquo;m spending my equity.
&ndash; James Chan
Context: When discussing the relationship between property and banks with a student, the teacher clarified the correct relationship the wealthy have with banks: not as debtors passively repaying loans, but as asset owners actively using their assets (through pledging) to generate cash flow.</p></blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>In investing, once you make an operational mistake, you must correct it immediately and get back on your original planned track. You cannot let a mistake stand.
&ndash; James Chan
Context: When instructing student Vicky on how to handle the mistake of buying too many bonds, the teacher stated unequivocally the only correct principle for dealing with errors.</p></blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>You should listen to his philosophy, not his stock prices. If they ever talk about stock prices, that&rsquo;s nonsense.
&ndash; James Chan
Context: When commenting on the AI-generated &ldquo;Charlie Munger&rdquo; video circulating online, the teacher taught everyone how to selectively absorb information, focusing on learning the mindset and life wisdom of investment masters, rather than getting entangled in their (possibly fabricated) predictions of specific stock prices.</p></blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>Teaching is the most profitable.
&ndash; Qing
Context: Student Qing shared his observation of some investment bloggers, noting that they themselves admit their most profitable business is running courses and memberships, not their own investing, which highlighted the selflessness of Teacher James&rsquo;s free sharing.</p></blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>Your money allows you to stay in high-quality hotels all over the world. &hellip; You really have to slowly learn to adjust your energy, to truly treasure yourself a bit more, to love yourself a bit more.
&ndash; Cherry
Context: Student Cherry shared her insights while traveling in Europe, encouraging everyone to use their wealth to experience the world and improve their quality of life, rather than being shackled by material possessions (like a house).</p></blockquote>


<h2 class="relative group">V. Summary 
    <div id="v-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#v-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This session was rich in content and highly practical. Teacher James not only clearly defined the applicable scope of the tool QQQI, helping those planning for retirement to better construct their cash flow, but also once again clarified the fundamental investment logic of QQQ, strengthening everyone&rsquo;s confidence in long-term holding. The Q&amp;A interaction was particularly brilliant, ranging from specific cross-border account management to profound analyses of investment psychology. The repeated debates on &ldquo;selling a house to invest&rdquo; were especially notable, where the teacher, through firm logic and highly persuasive metaphors, helped students overcome the fear and doubt associated with transitioning from traditional concepts to a modern investment mindset. The entire discussion emphasized the critical role of discipline, critical thinking, and a long-term perspective for investment success.</p>

  



<div
  
    class="flex px-4 py-3 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900"
  >

  <span
    
      class="text-primary-400 ltr:pr-3 rtl:pl-3 flex items-center"
    >

    

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M506.3 417l-213.3-364c-16.33-28-57.54-28-73.98 0l-213.2 364C-10.59 444.9 9.849 480 42.74 480h426.6C502.1 480 522.6 445 506.3 417zM232 168c0-13.25 10.75-24 24-24S280 154.8 280 168v128c0 13.25-10.75 24-23.1 24S232 309.3 232 296V168zM256 416c-17.36 0-31.44-14.08-31.44-31.44c0-17.36 14.07-31.44 31.44-31.44s31.44 14.08 31.44 31.44C287.4 401.9 273.4 416 256 416z"/></svg>

  </span>


  </span>

  <span
    
      class="dark:text-neutral-300"
    ><strong>Disclaimer:</strong> This article is for personal study notes only and does not constitute any investment advice.</span>
</div>

]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>00541 2x Leverage Won't Go to Zero, But Will Drop Until You Doubt Life: Without Rebalancing, No One Can Save You</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1763875778898/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1763875778898/</guid><description>In this episode, Teacher James delves into the true definition of financial freedom: the complete disregard for the existence of money and the market. The content covers the mindset for recent market volatility, reminders for smart rebalancing at year-end, and warnings against AI fraud. On the technical side, he provides a detailed analysis of the target audience and tax implications for high-dividend ETFs (JEPQ, QQQI), as well as how to handle the premium of the China 513100 fund. Additionally, through student Q&amp;amp;A, the session discusses the pros and cons of real estate versus stock assets, the disruptive impact of AI technology on the future, and wisdom regarding interpersonal relationships and retirement life.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<lite-youtube videoid="TW-ffBXPKsU" playlabel="TW-ffBXPKsU" params=""></lite-youtube>



<h2 class="relative group">I. Topic of the Episode 
    <div id="i-topic-of-the-episode" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-topic-of-the-episode" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>The theme of this episode focuses on <strong>&ldquo;True Freedom&rdquo;</strong> and <strong>&ldquo;An Investment Mindset that Ignores the Market.&rdquo;</strong> Teacher James emphasizes that market volatility (such as a 5% rise or fall) and international situations should be irrelevant to investors. True freedom is when daily life is no longer constrained by monetary considerations. Furthermore, as the end of the year approaches, students are reminded to perform &ldquo;Smart Rebalancing.&rdquo; The session also highlights the characteristics and use cases of high-dividend ETFs (such as QQQI, JEPQ) and deeply explores how AI technology is changing content creation and future lifestyles.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">II. Presentation Content 
    <div id="ii-presentation-content" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii-presentation-content" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">1. Investment Mindset and the Definition of Freedom 
    <div id="1-investment-mindset-and-the-definition-of-freedom" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#1-investment-mindset-and-the-definition-of-freedom" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Ignoring Market Volatility</strong>: The market fluctuated by 10% over the past two weeks, but this should have zero impact on long-term index investors. If you can manage to be completely unaware of last week&rsquo;s market fluctuations, or even log into your account only once a year, you are a successful investor.</li>
<li><strong>Financial Freedom</strong>: The definition of freedom is &ldquo;money is not within your considerations.&rdquo; Whether dining out, traveling, or buying a house, being able to act as if you are buying a pair of slippers without considering the price—that is attaining the realm of freedom.</li>
<li><strong>Year-End Operations</strong>: It is currently November/December, which is a good time for <strong>Smart Rebalancing</strong>. If you don&rsquo;t want to do it now, doing it early next year is also fine.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">2. Fraud Warning 
    <div id="2-fraud-warning" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#2-fraud-warning" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>AI Identity Theft</strong>: Fraud groups are using AI technology (such as ChatGPT) to impersonate Teacher James (ID: Chairman1, etc.) and reply in the YouTube comments section, even using AI-generated voice.</li>
<li><strong>Sole Contact Method</strong>: Please recognize Teacher James&rsquo;s correct ID. All communication should be conducted via Email; do not easily trust private messages within YouTube or Clubhouse.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">3. New YouTube Features and Content Dissemination 
    <div id="3-new-youtube-features-and-content-dissemination" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#3-new-youtube-features-and-content-dissemination" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Multi-Language Audio Tracks</strong>: YouTube now features AI automatic audio track translation. Uploaded Chinese videos can be automatically translated into English voiceovers, giving future content global dissemination capabilities.</li>
<li><strong>Setup Method</strong>: Select &ldquo;Audio Track&rdquo; in the video settings to switch languages. While this increases content reach, it also implies that English content can more aggressively conduct global cultural export.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">4. Investment Tools and Asset Allocation 
    <div id="4-investment-tools-and-asset-allocation" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#4-investment-tools-and-asset-allocation" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>China 513100 Premium Issue</strong>:
<ul>
<li>Do not obsess over the premium. Due to foreign exchange controls, financial institutions cannot immediately arbitrage to close the gap, so the premium may exist for a long time (even 100 years).</li>
<li><strong>Strategy</strong>: Buy immediately at market price. Getting &ldquo;on the bus&rdquo; is what matters most; do not miss the market rally while waiting for the premium to converge.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>High-Dividend ETF Analysis (JEPQ, QQQI)</strong>:
<ul>
<li><strong>Target Audience</strong>: Those who have retired and need stable cash flow. <strong>Young people should not invest in this</strong>; they should focus on growth.</li>
<li><strong>Characteristics</strong>:
<ul>
<li><strong>JEPQ</strong>: Dividend yield approx. 10%, Beta approx. 0.7-0.8 (lower volatility).</li>
<li><strong>QQQI</strong>: Dividend yield approx. 12-13%, Beta approx. 0.9-1.1 (volatility close to QQQ).</li>
<li><strong>Major Holdings</strong>: These funds typically hold about 80% in QQQ and use the other 20% for options strategies (Covered Call, etc.) to generate cash flow.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Tax Issues</strong>:
<ul>
<li>US Tax Residents: Primarily treated as Long-term capital gains (preferential tax rate), not ordinary Income.</li>
<li>Taiwan/Overseas Investors: If the brokerage (e.g., SinoPac re-consignment, with IBKR as the upstream) has QI status, there may be an automatic Refund, allowing for full dividend receipt. Generally, non-US residents face 30% withholding, but products like QQQI may have higher refund ratios due to their structural characteristics.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Risk Warning</strong>: These are not Cash (Money Market); they will still fall with the market (potentially dropping 20-30%) and risk must be considered.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Leveraged Fund Risks</strong>:
<ul>
<li>Although leveraged funds (like TQQQ) won&rsquo;t go to zero, they can face a 99% decline.</li>
<li><strong>Smart Rebalancing</strong> must be executed: convert profits to cash during rises so you have funds to replenish positions during major market crashes (e.g., an 85% drop).</li>
<li>Leveraged positions must not exceed the prototype fund or cash positions.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">5. Real Estate and Life Philosophy 
    <div id="5-real-estate-and-life-philosophy" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#5-real-estate-and-life-philosophy" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Houses are Cages</strong>: Young people should not buy houses too early; carrying a mortgage is like locking yourself in a cage. Buying a house should only be considered when it feels as easy as buying slippers.</li>
<li><strong>Advantages of Stock Pledging</strong>: Stock pledging has no upper age limit and is flexible to handle; whereas real estate loans (like reverse mortgages) face increasing restrictions with age. Stocks are better assets than real estate and are easier to divide for inheritance.</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">III. Q&amp;A Session 
    <div id="iii-qa-session" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii-qa-session" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Ray 
    <div id="ray" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ray" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing</strong>: Recently listened to a speech by Charlie Munger and learned about holding cash, understanding risk, antifragility, and not being jealous.</li>
<li><strong>Question</strong>: Munger always emphasized &ldquo;no leverage&rdquo; and &ldquo;no borrowing,&rdquo; but Buffett actually uses insurance float as leverage. Why did Munger advise this? Does it conflict with our concept of &ldquo;leveraged investing&rdquo;?
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s Reply</strong>:
<ol>
<li>Munger opposed <strong>borrowing for consumption</strong> (e.g., Americans borrowing to buy mansions, luxury cars, paying for travel in installments), which leads to being &ldquo;exquisitely poor.&rdquo;</li>
<li>Munger opposed <strong>all-in, unhedged leveraged investment</strong> (like going all-in on Bitcoin or a single stock).</li>
<li>Our borrowing is based on <strong>asset allocation and risk control</strong>, which is completely different from the gambling-style borrowing Munger opposed.</li>
<li>Regarding jealousy: Never compare yourself with others; compare with yourself. Win at the finish line, not at the starting line. Be overflowing with confidence and ignore outside noise.</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Jialin 
    <div id="jialin" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#jialin" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Question 1</strong>: My firm, which I ran for 15 years, is closing due to hiring difficulties. Although I have enough money, I feel I wasted my youth and feel sad. How do I adjust?</li>
<li><strong>Question 2</strong>: Single, 50 years old, no children, assets approx. 35 million TWD, annual expenses 1.8 million. Previously advised a 3-1-6 allocation; can I now use 18 million to buy high-dividend ETFs (like 0056 or QQQI) and do a 70/30 allocation with the rest?
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s Reply</strong>:
<ul>
<li><strong>Regarding Asset Allocation</strong>: Since you have 35 million, taking 20 million to buy QQQI or 0056 generates over 2 million in cash flow annually, fully covering the 1.8 million expenses with surplus. Keep 5 million in cash and buy 00662 with the rest for long-term growth. You have plenty of money; enjoy it to the fullest.</li>
<li><strong>Regarding Mindset</strong>: Closing the firm is a good thing; it ends the torture. Life doesn&rsquo;t require &ldquo;doing things&rdquo;; it&rsquo;s okay to contain &ldquo;idleness.&rdquo; Establish <strong>rituals</strong> in life (gardening, keeping fish, pour-over coffee, reading), enjoy freedom, and don&rsquo;t need work to prove your value.</li>
<li><strong>Special Advice</strong>: Single people need to build a close circle of friends who can &ldquo;go to the emergency room with you at 2 AM.&rdquo; This is very important.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Haoqing 
    <div id="haoqing" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#haoqing" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Question</strong>: I have a retired client couple with few assets, living on Social Security. They own a large house worth about 6 million USD. The wife has an emotional attachment to &ldquo;home&rdquo; and refuses to sell, wanting to turn it into an Airbnb while they move back to Taiwan. Is this wise?
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s Reply</strong>:
<ul>
<li>Very unwise. Keeping a big house (&ldquo;old hen&rdquo;) that doesn&rsquo;t lay eggs is not cost-effective. The maintenance costs (property tax, repairs) for a 6 million dollar house are extremely high.</li>
<li><strong>Advice</strong>: Sell the house, cash out 3-4 million USD, invest in QQQI, and generate 300,000-400,000 USD in annual cash flow.</li>
<li><strong>Lifestyle</strong>: With this huge cash flow, they can rent the highest-end apartments (with pools, gyms, social events) anywhere in the world (including the US) and enjoy true freedom, instead of being an Airbnb landlord dealing with messes. Mindsets must change; don&rsquo;t be trapped by &ldquo;poor man&rsquo;s thinking.&rdquo;</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">BB 
    <div id="bb" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#bb" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing</strong>: The biggest takeaway from following the teacher is &ldquo;peace of mind.&rdquo; I used to feel that not working meant losing, now I understand &ldquo;it&rsquo;s okay not to do it.&rdquo;</li>
<li><strong>Question</strong>: Considering moving back to the Bay Area. No longer obsessed with buying a house or top school districts; thinking renting and mid-to-upper school districts are fine?
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s Reply</strong>:
<ul>
<li>Strongly support this. Even as a VP, you can &ldquo;work with one hand&rdquo;; being less busy actually improves efficiency.</li>
<li>Renting in the Bay Area ($4500-5000) gets you into luxury apartments with excellent facilities, offering a higher quality of life.</li>
<li><strong>Regarding School Districts</strong>: You don&rsquo;t need to squeeze children into top school districts that are entirely Asian. Mid-to-upper Mixed school districts are actually better for children to integrate into American society and diverse cultures.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Washington 
    <div id="washington" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#washington" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Question 1</strong>: TQQQ recently did a stock split. Is this good or bad?
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s Reply</strong>: Neither good nor bad; the essence hasn&rsquo;t changed at all. It&rsquo;s like exchanging a 100-dollar bill for two 50-dollar bills. The value remains the same; it&rsquo;s just a numbers game in accounting.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question 2</strong>: regarding retirement, some say the brain degenerates if you retire, others say retiring early is good. What&rsquo;s your view?
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s Reply</strong>: The key is <strong>Freedom</strong>. If you don&rsquo;t dare to live somewhere because taxes are high (like California), that is not freedom. The goal should be to be unconstrained by money and location.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question 3</strong>: My son bought a life insurance policy (Whole Life), paying $1000/month. He has paid 130k. Initially told he only needed to pay for 10 years, now the agent says he has to pay until age 100?
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s Reply</strong>: This is <strong>garbage</strong>. I suggest stopping it (Cancel) immediately. Instead of paying $1000 to the insurance company every month, put it into QQQ. Savings/Whole Life insurance for young people usually has low returns, and eventually, even the principal might be eaten up by premiums.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Pei 
    <div id="pei" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#pei" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing</strong>: Watched a video by Professor Zeng Shiqiang saying that the fate between parents and children is for &ldquo;separation,&rdquo; not possession. Shared a story where her father forced her brother to drop out and become an apprentice because he didn&rsquo;t study well, leading to a lifelong rift.
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s Reply</strong>: Strongly agree. Children are independent individuals; studying isn&rsquo;t the only path. A parent&rsquo;s responsibility is love and guidance, not control. Do not do things based on traditional concepts that you will regret for the rest of your life.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Billy 
    <div id="billy" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#billy" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Question</strong>: Saw a YQQQ (Inverse ETF) with a seemingly high dividend yield (30%+). Is it worth investing?
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s Reply</strong>: <strong>Absolutely do not touch it.</strong> This is a toxic asset. Although the yield looks high, the share price may drop 28% or more annually. With principal loss plus tax costs, the total return is negative. Don&rsquo;t touch things you don&rsquo;t understand.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Wang Zhihua 
    <div id="wang-zhihua" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#wang-zhihua" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Question 1</strong>: Confirming regarding investing in China fund 513100 from the mainland: should I buy directly regardless of the premium?
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s Reply</strong>: Yes, ignore the premium and buy directly at market price.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question 2</strong>: Bought previously and it dropped 30%. Should I replenish now or wait?
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s Reply</strong>: Replenish now. Investing for children looks at a 20-30 year horizon. Buy when you have money; don&rsquo;t hold cash.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question 3</strong>: Can mainlanders buy QQQI through Hong Kong brokerages? Is it suitable?
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s Reply</strong>: You can buy it. QQQI (80% QQQ + 20% Option Strategy) has both growth and cash flow. If you are retired or need cash flow, calculate the purchase amount based on your required annual income (e.g., if you need 60,000 RMB annual income, buy the corresponding principal amount of QQQI).</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Mike 
    <div id="mike" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#mike" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Question 1</strong>: Michael Burry and others believe AI hardware (GPUs, etc.) depreciates too slowly, actual obsolescence is fast, and there might be financial fraud or a bubble?
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s Reply</strong>: This is nonsense. It is normal for tech hardware (like data centers, GPUs) to depreciate over 5-7 years. The release of a new generation doesn&rsquo;t mean old ones are scrapped immediately; old equipment continues to generate value (Perform). Michael Burry is often wrong on the short side, and his fund performance is not good.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question 2</strong>: What is the physical entity of the &ldquo;Cloud&rdquo; in the AI era? Since the Internet corresponds to the Cloud, what does AI correspond to?
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s Reply</strong>:
<ul>
<li>AI is <strong>Everywhere</strong>. In the future, there will be no concept of Apps, only Input (Voice/Vision) and Output (Screen/Execution).</li>
<li>AI will become your <strong>Agent</strong>, handling all miscellaneous tasks (ordering coffee, booking doctors, making spreadsheets, buying tickets).</li>
<li>Companies controlling platforms and entry points like Google and Apple will dominate. Google is currently leading in AI technology (Gemini, etc.).</li>
<li>Elon Musk launching computing power into space (Space-based AI) is also a trend.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Rabbit (Tu Baobao) 
    <div id="rabbit-tu-baobao" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#rabbit-tu-baobao" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Comment</strong>: Everyone selling is wrong.
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s Reply</strong>: Correct. Selling at any time is wrong; buying at any time is right.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">IV. Highlighted Views 
    <div id="iv-highlighted-views" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv-highlighted-views" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>The definition of freedom is that money is not within your considerations.
&ndash; Teacher James</p></blockquote>
<p>This view was presented when explaining the true realm of financial freedom, emphasizing that freedom is not about how much money you have, but that life decisions are no longer constrained by money.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Return rate is not determined by asset allocation; return rate is determined by the future market. Asset allocation determines whether you can survive.
&ndash; Teacher James</p></blockquote>
<p>This view was presented to correct students who overly pursue backtested performance simulations, emphasizing that the primary purpose of asset allocation is risk control and psychological comfort.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Don&rsquo;t buy a house; buying a house is building a cage for yourself and locking yourself inside.
&ndash; Teacher James</p></blockquote>
<p>This view was presented when answering questions about young people buying homes and handling real estate after retirement, advocating not letting real estate limit life&rsquo;s freedom.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The fate between parents and children is not for being together, but for separation.
&ndash; Student Pei (Quoting Professor Zeng Shiqiang)</p></blockquote>
<p>This view was cited during a student&rsquo;s sharing of family relationship insights, emphasizing that parents should respect their children&rsquo;s independence and learn to exit gracefully.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>All selling is wrong, and all buying (at any time) is right.
&ndash; Teacher James</p></blockquote>
<p>This view was in response to a comment in the live stream, reiterating the core philosophy of index investing: long-term holding, buy only, never sell.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">V. Summary 
    <div id="v-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#v-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>In this episode, Teacher James further deepened the core concept of &ldquo;Financial Freedom&rdquo;—achieving complete indifference to money and market fluctuations. On the practical side, detailed explanations of high-dividend tools like QQQI were provided for the retired demographic, along with a strong recommendation to sell inefficient real estate assets and switch to financial assets to obtain true freedom and cash flow. Regarding the tech horizon, the teacher depicted a future where AI Agents will replace traditional Apps and reminded everyone to use AI tools to improve efficiency. Finally, regarding family relationships, the importance of respecting independent individuals and emotional connections was emphasized, encouraging everyone to live a &ldquo;free life&rdquo; unbound by money.</p>

  



<div
  
    class="flex px-4 py-3 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900"
  >

  <span
    
      class="text-primary-400 ltr:pr-3 rtl:pl-3 flex items-center"
    >

    

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M506.3 417l-213.3-364c-16.33-28-57.54-28-73.98 0l-213.2 364C-10.59 444.9 9.849 480 42.74 480h426.6C502.1 480 522.6 445 506.3 417zM232 168c0-13.25 10.75-24 24-24S280 154.8 280 168v128c0 13.25-10.75 24-23.1 24S232 309.3 232 296V168zM256 416c-17.36 0-31.44-14.08-31.44-31.44c0-17.36 14.07-31.44 31.44-31.44s31.44 14.08 31.44 31.44C287.4 401.9 273.4 416 256 416z"/></svg>

  </span>


  </span>

  <span
    
      class="dark:text-neutral-300"
    ><strong>Disclaimer:</strong> This article is merely personal study notes and does not constitute any investment advice.</span>
</div>

]]></content:encoded></item></channel></rss>