<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Life Philosophy on QQQ Investor</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/tags/life-philosophy/</link><description>Recent content in Life Philosophy on QQQ Investor</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jomonylw.github.io/en/tags/life-philosophy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>00536 Those Who Use AI Are Busier; Those Who Invest in QQQ Are More at Leisure: Learning to Invest Is the True Artificial Intelligence</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1760861307961/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1760861307961/</guid><description>In this session, James elaborates on the three &amp;#39;Seven Levels&amp;#39; theories of investment learning, wealth accumulation, and investment operations, providing an in-depth exploration of the complete path from beginner to the wealthy class. He also shares insights on the impact of the Artificial Intelligence (AI) era on our lives and investments, emphasizing that long-term holding of the Nasdaq-100 index fund, combined with asset allocation and stock pledging, is the ultimate strategy for achieving financial freedom and life&amp;#39;s purpose.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<lite-youtube videoid="mKGVKQyGwqs" playlabel="mKGVKQyGwqs" params=""></lite-youtube>



<h2 class="relative group">I. Theme of the Session 
    <div id="i-theme-of-the-session" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-theme-of-the-session" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This session delves into multiple dimensions of investment and wealth. The core ideas revolve around three &ldquo;Seven Levels&rdquo; theories:</p>
<ol>
<li><strong>The Seven Levels of Investment Learning</strong>: The journey from initial exposure to forming an unwavering belief.</li>
<li><strong>The Seven Levels of Wealth Accumulation</strong>: The path from understanding investment to maximizing wealth through concentration, leverage, tax savings, and longevity.</li>
<li><strong>The Seven Levels of Investment Operations</strong>: From the confusion of short-term trading to finally embracing the wealthy class strategy of &ldquo;invest only in indexes, never sell, and live off pledged assets.&rdquo;
The course emphasizes that true wealth stems from correct cognition and discipline, and points out that in the AI era, we should use technology to liberate ourselves and return to the essence of life, rather than becoming busier.</li>
</ol>


<h2 class="relative group">II. Briefing Content 
    <div id="ii-briefing-content" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii-briefing-content" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Market Noise and Investment Mentality 
    <div id="market-noise-and-investment-mentality" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#market-noise-and-investment-mentality" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Ignore Short-Term Volatility</strong>: The market has been highly volatile recently due to events like US-China tariffs and a potential US government shutdown, but investors should ignore this market noise and avoid making incorrect moves. Typically, any action based on short-term predictions is wrong.</li>
<li><strong>Limitations of Technical Analysis</strong>: The accuracy of technical analysis is about the same as a coin toss, roughly 50/50, and should not be the primary basis for investment decisions.</li>
<li><strong>Personal Responsibility in Investing</strong>: Investment sharing is for experience exchange only and does not constitute advice. Everyone&rsquo;s financial situation is different; final decisions require personal learning and execution, for which individuals are responsible.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">The Impact of AI and the Evolution of Investment Philosophy 
    <div id="the-impact-of-ai-and-the-evolution-of-investment-philosophy" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#the-impact-of-ai-and-the-evolution-of-investment-philosophy" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>AI Makes the Impossible Possible, But Also Makes People Busier</strong>: Technological advancements like AI have made things previously unimaginable (such as quickly creating multilingual videos) possible. However, this doesn&rsquo;t mean people become more idle; on the contrary, they become busier because there are more things they can do.</li>
<li><strong>Encourage Using AI to Spread Correct Investment Philosophies</strong>: Students can use AI tools like NotebookLM or ChatGPT to translate investment philosophies into articles or videos in different languages, helping to &ldquo;inform&rdquo; more people of their right to be wealthy.</li>
<li><strong>Investment Philosophy is Evolving DNA</strong>: Our investment philosophy is constantly evolving and being optimized. For example, it was once emphasized that those who pledge assets &ldquo;must&rdquo; allocate to leveraged funds to maintain returns. The current view, however, is that for the sake of stability, one can pledge assets without holding leveraged funds. Students need to keep up with their learning to avoid sticking to outdated knowledge, as the investment world is like biological evolution—ceasing to evolve risks being eliminated.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">The Three &ldquo;Seven Levels&rdquo; of Investing and Wealth 
    <div id="the-three-seven-levels-of-investing-and-wealth" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#the-three-seven-levels-of-investing-and-wealth" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ol>
<li>
<p><strong>The Seven Levels of Investment Learning</strong>:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Hearing</strong>: Just encountering the information, possibly thinking it&rsquo;s a scam.</li>
<li><strong>Knowing</strong>: Beginning to realize there&rsquo;s substance to it.</li>
<li><strong>Understanding</strong>: Developing cognition after in-depth research.</li>
<li><strong>Believing</strong>: Transitioning from cognition to trust.</li>
<li><strong>Executing</strong>: Putting belief into action, the key being &ldquo;buy when you have money, immediately, at market price.&rdquo;</li>
<li><strong>Enduring</strong>: Being able to withstand the pain and hold on when the market drops by 40% or even more.</li>
<li><strong>Faith</strong>: Reaching a state of inner peace where market fluctuations don&rsquo;t matter. This is usually built on proper asset allocation and sufficient cash flow.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>The Seven Levels of Wealth (Differences in Magnitude)</strong>:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Knowing How to Invest vs. Not Knowing</strong>: This is the first dividing line, separating 90% of the world&rsquo;s population.</li>
<li><strong>Investing Correctly vs. Incorrectly</strong>: Among those who know how to invest, choosing the most efficient assets (e.g., QQQ vs. VOO/VT) can result in a hundredfold difference in assets over the long term.</li>
<li><strong>Han Xin Deploying Troops (Concentrating Capital)</strong>: Concentrating funds in the highest-return assets instead of diversifying into inefficient products like insurance, annuities, and bonds can create another hundredfold gap in assets.</li>
<li><strong>Pledging and Borrowing</strong>: Learning to use stock pledging to obtain liquidity instead of selling assets widens the asset gap again.</li>
<li><strong>Borrowing Without Repaying</strong>: Understanding that a pledge loan is an expansion of assets, not a traditional debt that needs to be repaid. Compared to those who rush to repay, the potential for wealth growth is entirely different.</li>
<li><strong>Smart Tax Savings</strong>: Through legal tax planning (like Roth Conversions in the US), one can save enormous amounts in taxes, further widening the wealth gap.</li>
<li><strong>Longevity</strong>: When all the above are done correctly, the longer you live, the more significant the compounding effect, and the more assets you accumulate. Longevity is the key determinant of ultimate wealth.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>The Seven Levels of Investment Operations</strong>:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Level One</strong>: New to the market, occasionally making money on individual stocks, thinking investing is easy.</li>
<li><strong>Level Two</strong>: Trying derivatives like options, possibly profiting in the short term, but likely losing money in the long run.</li>
<li><strong>Level Three</strong>: Starting to study financial reports and industry trends, trying to buy low and sell high, but the more you know, the more you lose.</li>
<li><strong>Level Four</strong>: Obsessed with technical analysis and futures, engaging in frantic short-term trading, thinking you&rsquo;re a stock market guru, but actually being closest to bankruptcy.</li>
<li><strong>Level Five</strong>: Understanding that investing is about sharing in a company&rsquo;s growth and knowing how to pick good companies, but still suffering from the huge volatility of individual stocks. You work like a dog for mediocre returns.</li>
<li><strong>Level Six</strong>: Grasping the power of long-term holding and starting to make big profits, but still needing to constantly research and switch companies. Having cash on hand after selling becomes a new source of anxiety. It&rsquo;s still a busy operational life.</li>
<li><strong>Level Seven (The Ultimate)</strong>: Investing only in index funds (QQQ). Buy whenever you have money, never sell, buy with your eyes closed. Implement proper asset allocation (e.g., 433), keep enough cash, and fear no market crash. Live off loans from stock pledging and never repay them, allowing assets to continuously generate wealth. This is the true wealthy class.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ol>


<h3 class="relative group">Life Philosophy and Financial Freedom 
    <div id="life-philosophy-and-financial-freedom" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#life-philosophy-and-financial-freedom" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>The Astonishing Power of Compounding</strong>: Using the example of investing NT$10,000 per month, at an 18% annualized return, it can grow to NT$547 million in 40 years. This shows that becoming wealthy is achievable for ordinary people; it is a &ldquo;God-given&rdquo; right. The key is whether one is informed and takes action.</li>
<li><strong>The Nature of Work and the Meaning of Life</strong>: Our lives should not be solely for work and survival. Viewing one&rsquo;s job as the entirety of life is a form of enslavement by capitalism. Only after being free from work pressure can one truly understand what &ldquo;life&rdquo; is and pursue what one loves, like gardening or enjoying a pastoral life.</li>
<li><strong>The Risks of Leveraged ETFs</strong>: One must deeply understand the nature of leveraged ETFs (like TQQQ). They can bring tenfold returns in the short term but can also drop to zero (a 99.999% decline) in a single major crash. Therefore, their risk must be managed through asset allocation and rebalancing; never go all-in.</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">III. Q&amp;A Session 
    <div id="iii-qa-session" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii-qa-session" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Kate 
    <div id="kate" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#kate" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Share: She recently heard a story that Tony Robbins suggests two things for success: first, imitate someone you want to become; second, practice positive meditation daily. She applied this to herself by imitating James, practicing the seven levels of investing step-by-step—from understanding investing and doing it right to pledging assets without repayment—and believes she is on the right path. She also mentioned that Taiwan&rsquo;s inheritance tax is very low.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: He agrees that Taiwan&rsquo;s inheritance tax is low (maximum 20%), so there&rsquo;s no need for complex trusts or planning. The best &ldquo;tax avoidance&rdquo; is to &ldquo;have many children and grandchildren&rdquo; and use the annual gift tax exemption to transfer wealth to future generations early, which has an amazing compounding effect. He shared a cautionary tale of a bank deceiving a family into taking out a massive loan to &ldquo;plan&rdquo; for inheritance tax, warning that bank promotions can sometimes be scams.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Ola 
    <div id="ola" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ola" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Share: He has opened Custodial Accounts for his three young children, with a portfolio of 60% QQQ, 20% QLD, and 20% SGOV. He plans to invest small amounts regularly. His goal is not to give them a certain amount of money but to &ldquo;teach them how to fish,&rdquo; allowing them to see the account grow from a young age and giving him the opportunity to teach them the complete financial system in the future, including Pledge Loans. This is both a transfer of wealth and wisdom.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: He strongly agrees with this educational approach. He pointed out that gifting early is the best estate planning. For example, giving a daughter $20,000 annually for 40 years could grow to nearly $100 billion at an 18% return, completely tax-free, which is far more significant than worrying about the inheritance tax exemption amount.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Lu 
    <div id="lu" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#lu" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Share:
<ol>
<li>Reminded everyone to be aware of scam accounts on Clubhouse impersonating James.</li>
<li>She believes new students should systematically study James&rsquo;s past lessons from the beginning rather than jumping around, which can lead to confusion. Younger students, in particular, might not understand why some of the advice is conservative, as earlier courses were often geared towards those nearing retirement.</li>
<li>Suggested creating a more &ldquo;pure&rdquo; EACC discussion space to avoid mixing with other investment philosophies.</li>
</ol>
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: Thanked her for the reminders. He will consider opening a Case Study session, possibly on Saturdays after the briefing, to discuss one or two specific cases to help with &ldquo;clinical learning.&rdquo; He will think about the suggestion of a separate room.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Dr. An 
    <div id="dr-an" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#dr-an" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Share: As a long-time student since 2011, he shared several key benefits:
<ol>
<li><strong>Han Xin Deploying Troops</strong>: Following James&rsquo;s advice, he canceled unnecessary investment-linked insurance policies, sold an idle property in Taiwan to invest in US index funds, and did not rush to pay off his mortgage. These three decisions significantly improved his financial situation.</li>
<li><strong>Evolution of Investment Philosophy</strong>: He recalled that he initially only learned to &ldquo;Buy and Hold SPY,&rdquo; which was just 1/5 of the entire system. Now, the system has evolved to include a complete solution with QQQ, Pledge Loans, a 2% withdrawal rate, and 433 asset allocation, which makes him feel more secure and at ease.
. <strong>Unity with Spouse</strong>: He and his wife learn together and are in complete agreement on family financial decisions, which makes execution very smooth. This is a great blessing.</li>
</ol>
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: Thanked Dr. An for his sharing and added that he made another very important decision—the Roth Conversion, which saves a huge amount in taxes. Dr. An was also one of the course instructors.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">W.W. 
    <div id="ww" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ww" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question: Regarding the Traditional IRA, some suggest holding cash in it so the future tax base is low. But she thought if she put it all in QQQ, although the future tax would be higher, the growth would also be much higher than cash. Isn&rsquo;t that better?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: This is a balance between risk and taxes. James provided a strategy: suppose you convert $100,000 to a Roth account annually. You could buy $100,000 of TQQQ (3x leverage) in the Roth. To balance the risk of the entire portfolio, you could hold $200,000 in cash in your Traditional IRA. This way, your high-growth component (TQQQ) is in the tax-free Roth account, while the cash in the Traditional IRA hedges the risk. This optimizes the tax structure without reducing the overall return potential.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Ling 
    <div id="ling" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ling" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Share: She shared an experience helping a novice investor friend. The friend initially claimed she could tolerate a 50% fluctuation, but when told the loss could last for 3-5 years, she immediately said she couldn&rsquo;t accept it; her bottom line was not losing principal for more than 1-2 years. Through this conversation, Ling deeply realized that everyone&rsquo;s definition of and tolerance for &ldquo;risk&rdquo; is completely different. Before taking any investment action (like buying immediately at market price), the first task is to thoroughly understand what level of risk you can truly bear.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: He highly praised Ling&rsquo;s clear logic. He emphasized that knowing your own risk tolerance is the first step in investing, more important than any strategy. He used the 2000 dot-com bubble as an example, where QQQ took 15 years to return to its high, which is why he recommends keeping enough cash for 15-20 years. <strong>&ldquo;Survival is more important than making money.&rdquo;</strong> Before you understand yourself, you should keep more cash; the rate of return is not the top priority.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Cocity 
    <div id="cocity" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#cocity" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question: He raised a macro question about the global &ldquo;de-dollarization&rdquo; trend and central banks hoarding gold. He wanted to know if this poses a long-term threat to an investment strategy centered on US dollar assets and whether we need to prepare for it.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: He acknowledged that this trend is real. However, he offered several counterpoints: 1. The US debt problem could be resolved by productivity gains from AI (e.g., an extra 1.5% GDP growth annually). 2. A thought experiment: If the US government announced a &ldquo;ban on using US dollars for gold transactions,&rdquo; the entire dollar-denominated gold market would collapse instantly, and the value of gold hoarded by countries would plummet. The US has many tools left in its toolbox to maintain its hegemony. The disputes between the US and China over chips and rare earths are games between nations and do not affect our long-term confidence in US technological development, which is unrelated to investing in QQQ.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Wang Zhihua 
    <div id="wang-zhihua" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#wang-zhihua" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question: As a new student from Beijing, he asked which QQQ product he should buy. Should he buy the US-listed QQQ directly, the Hong Kong-listed 3086/9086, or the A-share listed 513100? Also, he wants to dollar-cost average for his daughter; is a leveraged ETF (TQQQ) suitable?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: He recommended buying a Hong Kong-issued product (like 3086), primarily to avoid US inheritance tax. Hong Kong also has a 2x leveraged Nasdaq fund (like CSOP NASDAQ-100 INDEX DAILY (2X) LEVERAGED PRODUCT - 7261) and money market funds that can be used for asset allocation. For his daughter&rsquo;s money, he can buy 513100 in China or a Stock Connect product in Hong Kong. Additionally, James mentioned that a Simplified Chinese version of his &ldquo;Bible of Financial Management&rdquo; is available and he can ask for it.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Pella 
    <div id="pella" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#pella" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Share: She expressed deep gratitude for James&rsquo;s patience, even with a &ldquo;snail&rdquo; like her who learns slowly. She shared that she has already invested by refinancing her house and has taught her children, who now compete to treat her to meals. She also shared this philosophy with friends doing missionary work in remote countries, and they have started investing. What she is most grateful for is James&rsquo;s &ldquo;religious-like spirit&rdquo; of wanting all beings to be wealthy.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: He thanked her for sharing and said that everyone contributes to society in their own way. His ability is to spread the concept of wealth to help more people achieve financial security.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Julia 
    <div id="julia" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#julia" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Share: She shared her experience using AI (ChatGPT) to research the tax issues of Health Savings Accounts (HSA) in California. She found that AI would &ldquo;confidently spout nonsense,&rdquo; with different AIs and online articles providing contradictory information, creating a phenomenon of &ldquo;mutual contamination.&rdquo; In the end, she had to return to first principles and personally check the original tax code to confirm the correct information: in California, both HSA contributions and investment gains are subject to state tax, significantly reducing the tax benefits.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: He completely agreed. He emphasized that current AI is still an &ldquo;amateur&rdquo; tool or &ldquo;toy&rdquo; and cannot be used for serious professional fields like tax or law. He himself found that AI makes basic numerical errors when creating videos. He reiterated that he does not recommend using HSAs and added a clarification that he might have previously confused HSAs with 529 plans. The beneficiary for withdrawals from a 529 account is a designated beneficiary (like a child), whereas the HSA holder can use the funds themselves.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">L. Zhang 
    <div id="l-zhang" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#l-zhang" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Share: As a new listener, she said she had benefited greatly but felt she still had a long way to go, so she would be a quiet listener for now. She was very grateful to have found James.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: He welcomed her and encouraged her to share or ask questions whenever she feels ready.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">IV. Highlight Quotes 
    <div id="iv-highlight-quotes" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv-highlight-quotes" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>Wealth is a natural gift&hellip; you have the right to be wealthy, and you need to be informed of this.
&ndash; James
Background: James explained his original intention for starting the channel was that many people don&rsquo;t know they are inherently entitled to become wealthy through correct investing.</p></blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>The more advanced technology and AI become&hellip; people who use AI don&rsquo;t become more idle but busier, because there are more and more things you can do.
&ndash; James
Background: When discussing the impact of AI, James pointed out that AI is a tool that expands the boundaries of our capabilities, resulting in us being able to do, and wanting to do, more things, rather than making us idle.</p></blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>A person doesn&rsquo;t know what it is to be human until they are without a job. That is what you call a &rsquo;life.'
&ndash; James
Background: In explaining his life philosophy, James criticized the idea of &ldquo;living to work,&rdquo; believing that only by breaking free from the shackles of work can one truly experience and understand the meaning of life.</p></blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>Survival is more important than making money.
&ndash; James
Background: When commenting on Ling&rsquo;s case study about risk perception, James emphasized that survival is the first principle of investing. Managing risk and keeping sufficient cash is far more important than chasing short-term high returns.</p></blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>Everyone&rsquo;s understanding of risk can be completely different&hellip; You must first figure out what you consider to be risk before you allocate your assets.
&ndash; Ling
Background: Ling shared her experience helping a novice investor friend and discovered a huge gap between the friend&rsquo;s stated risk tolerance and her actual psychological bottom line, leading to this conclusion.</p></blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>AI will confidently spout nonsense&hellip; In the world today, there is some information&hellip; that is prone to this kind of mutual contamination.
&ndash; Julia
Background: Julia shared her pitfalls when using AI to research complex tax issues, finding that AI and incorrect online information form a vicious cycle, mutually citing and amplifying errors.</p></blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>Invest only in index funds, buy whenever you have money and never sell, buy with your eyes closed&hellip; Do your asset allocation&hellip; live off loans from stock pledging, and never repay them.
&ndash; James
Background: When summarizing the seventh and highest level of investment operations, James used this phrase to encapsulate the essence of the strategy for achieving ultimate financial freedom.</p></blockquote>


<h2 class="relative group">V. Summary 
    <div id="v-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#v-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This session was a systematic and in-depth review of investment philosophy and life-wealth concepts. Through a clear, three-tiered &ldquo;seven-level ladder&rdquo; model, James constructed a complete growth blueprint for listeners, from investment novice to wealthy magnate. The course not only taught &ldquo;what to do&rdquo; (invest in indexes, don&rsquo;t sell, use pledging wisely) but also profoundly explained &ldquo;why to do it&rdquo; (understand risk, ignore noise, believe in compounding) and the ultimate goal (achieve freedom in life, not be enslaved by work). The students&rsquo; sharing and questions—from practical operations to macroeconomics and the critical use of AI tools—greatly enriched the breadth and depth of the discussion, once again confirming that investment success ultimately stems from continuous learning, deep self-awareness, and a firm philosophical belief.</p>

  



<div
  
    class="flex px-4 py-3 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900"
  >

  <span
    
      class="text-primary-400 ltr:pr-3 rtl:pl-3 flex items-center"
    >

    

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M506.3 417l-213.3-364c-16.33-28-57.54-28-73.98 0l-213.2 364C-10.59 444.9 9.849 480 42.74 480h426.6C502.1 480 522.6 445 506.3 417zM232 168c0-13.25 10.75-24 24-24S280 154.8 280 168v128c0 13.25-10.75 24-23.1 24S232 309.3 232 296V168zM256 416c-17.36 0-31.44-14.08-31.44-31.44c0-17.36 14.07-31.44 31.44-31.44s31.44 14.08 31.44 31.44C287.4 401.9 273.4 416 256 416z"/></svg>

  </span>


  </span>

  <span
    
      class="dark:text-neutral-300"
    ><strong>Disclaimer:</strong> This article is for personal study notes only and does not constitute any investment advice.</span>
</div>

]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>00529 Raising Children is Better Than Maintaining a House: The Truth About Reverse Mortgages and Retirement Cash Flow</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1756605737350/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1756605737350/</guid><description>In this session, Teacher James shares the core mindset of investing: the market always goes up, and investors should focus on their own lives rather than external distractions. The content covers life philosophy, children&amp;#39;s education, asset allocation, reverse mortgages, and pledged loans, emphasizing the importance of intrinsic value and a long-term perspective.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<lite-youtube videoid="6znudRqitcQ" playlabel="6znudRqitcQ" params=""></lite-youtube>



<h2 class="relative group">I. Main Theme 
    <div id="i-main-theme" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-main-theme" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This session&rsquo;s theme revolves around &ldquo;The market always goes up, live for yourself.&rdquo; The core idea is that the essence of investing is very simple: believe in the market&rsquo;s long-term upward trend and hold on. The real challenge is psychological. Therefore, we should not be disturbed by short-term market fluctuations, financial news, world events, or other external information. Instead, we should shift our focus back to life itself—concentrating on health, happiness, family, and personal values, viewing money as a tool to achieve freedom and abundance in life, not as the ultimate goal.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">II. Briefing Content 
    <div id="ii-briefing-content" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii-briefing-content" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Life is More Important Than Investing 
    <div id="life-is-more-important-than-investing" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#life-is-more-important-than-investing" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Wealth and Happiness</strong>: Wealth is a gift, happiness is a human right, and health is the foundation. Money is just a tool to achieve a free, abundant, and happy life; investing itself is not the purpose of life.</li>
<li><strong>Children&rsquo;s Education</strong>:
<ul>
<li>Focus on cultivating the right values in children (not stealing, robbing, breaking the law, or taking drugs) and appreciating their talents, rather than just focusing on academic performance.</li>
<li>Parents should not impose their own expectations or unfulfilled dreams on their children, such as forcing them to study abroad. This puts immense pressure on the children.</li>
<li>A true home is where the parents are. Children should be encouraged to pursue their own ideals, not to satisfy their parents&rsquo; expectations.</li>
<li>Compared to buying a house for a child, it&rsquo;s better to have and raise the child first, because wealth can be created, but childbirth has a time window.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Live in the Present, Focus on Yourself</strong>:
<ul>
<li>In life, focus on your own goals. Don&rsquo;t get sidetracked by trivial matters (like fussing over exchange rates or searching for better investments), as this will only delay the process of achieving financial freedom.</li>
<li>Teacher James uses his own management experience as an example: At the company, he focused on only the three most important tasks each day. Once completed, he could go home. This approach is efficient and goal-oriented. Conversely, trying to do everything results in being busy all day with nothing accomplished.</li>
<li>Live your own life, not one led by the media and online information. Cutting off useless external information will not result in any loss.</li>
<li>True living is about &ldquo;presence&rdquo;—living in the moment. Whether eating, gardening, or traveling, you should be fully engaged and feel the beauty of life itself. External distractions, like what Trump said, have no bearing on our lives or investments.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Investment Strategies and Financial Tools 
    <div id="investment-strategies-and-financial-tools" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#investment-strategies-and-financial-tools" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Do the Right Thing and Persist</strong>: The secret to successful investing is to &ldquo;do the right thing and stick with it for the long term.&rdquo; For example, invest whenever you have money, regardless of the exchange rate, without timing the market. Once you have identified the right path (like investing in QQQ), you should forge ahead without looking back.</li>
<li><strong>Reverse Mortgage</strong>:
<ul>
<li>This is an excellent tool for &ldquo;activating assets&rdquo; and is not just for people short on cash.</li>
<li>It provides a steady cash flow, as if the house is working for you. This money can be used for investment, thus increasing your assets while retaining the property.</li>
<li>It&rsquo;s a great option for parents with insufficient retirement funds, allowing them to live better lives without their children needing to provide financial support.</li>
<li>For elderly individuals with weak financial management skills and only one house left, a reverse mortgage is more stable than selling the house to invest, avoiding the risk of losing their last home.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>The Power of Borrowing to Invest</strong>:
<ul>
<li>An example: If you use your own $30,000 to buy a car, the potential value of that money in 50 years (about $32 million) is lost. But if you take a pledged loan of $30,000 to buy the car and invest your own $30,000, in 50 years you will have $32 million in assets, while the debt is only $340,000.</li>
<li>Conclusion: Make good use of financial leverage. Borrow for consumption or investment, and let your own money continue to grow.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Example of Leveraged Asset Allocation</strong>:
<ul>
<li>Teacher James shares his asset allocation model: 40% QQQ (1x), 15% QLD (2x), 10% TQQQ (3x), and 35% cash.</li>
<li>The Beta value of this portfolio is calculated as: (40% * 1) + (15% * 2) + (10% * 3) = 0.4 + 0.3 + 0.3 = 1.0.</li>
<li>This allocation, while having an overall risk comparable to holding 100% QQQ (Beta=1.0), retains a large amount of cash (35%) for risk control and rebalancing during market downturns.</li>
<li><strong>Key Point</strong>: Any asset allocation that includes leveraged funds <strong>must</strong> implement a smart rebalancing strategy.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">III. Q&amp;A Session 
    <div id="iii-qa-session" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii-qa-session" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Cady 
    <div id="cady" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#cady" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: She once went against everyone&rsquo;s advice to support her sister&rsquo;s dream of a working holiday in Australia. Now, her sister is living very happily in Germany. She has come to realize that since her child doesn&rsquo;t want to study abroad, she&rsquo;ll save the money for her own study tours in retirement. She is practicing not imposing her expectations on her child.
<ul>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo;s Comment: That&rsquo;s excellent. One must live for oneself, not for others. Don&rsquo;t impose your expectations on people. For children, parents only have the duty to agree, not the right to disagree. Your child&rsquo;s life is not under your jurisdiction.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chen Feng 
    <div id="chen-feng" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chen-feng" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing:
<ol>
<li>He has compiled his years of learning from the teacher into the &ldquo;Great Way is Simple Investment Method&rdquo; and created the &ldquo;Chen Feng Leads the Way&rdquo; website to share it.</li>
<li>He summarizes the CLEC investment method into three simple but not easy things: <strong>Asset Allocation</strong> (70/30 for beginners, eventually 433), <strong>Rebalancing</strong> (once a year), and <strong>Living off Pledged Loans</strong>.</li>
<li>He believes the hardest part of investing is psychology, which is why the teacher insists on holding weekly classes to help everyone adjust their mindset.</li>
<li>He announced his official retirement in August 2025 and will have more time in the future to share his experiences and help more people achieve the ideal that &ldquo;wealth is a gift, happiness is a human right.&rdquo;</li>
</ol>
<ul>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo;s Comment: Thank you to Chen Feng (a senior executive at a high-tech company in Taiwan) for his sharing and contributions. He has done a lot for the community (website, AI training) and actively helps everyone in the LINE group. Teacher James announced that he is making him a community Moderator.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Hai Wai Gu Zhong 
    <div id="hai-wai-gu-zhong" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#hai-wai-gu-zhong" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: After renting out a house he owns, he recently took it back for his own use and found being a landlord very troublesome. He had to deal with various damages and cleaning for walls, doors, and windows, and deeply realized that the actual return on real estate investment is not as high as it seems.</li>
<li>Question 1: Since the house was bought by his family, he can&rsquo;t sell it freely. He&rsquo;s thinking of taking out a mortgage-like loan on the house (interest-only payments) and investing the cash into 00662. Is this idea feasible?
<ul>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo;s Reply: Absolutely correct, you should do it immediately. Borrow any money you can as soon as possible. The power of borrowing to invest is immense. He demonstrated the huge opportunity cost difference by calculating the 50-year outcomes of buying a car with $30,000 versus borrowing $1 million.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2: The teacher advises young people to invest first and buy a house later when they are &ldquo;old.&rdquo; What age does &ldquo;old&rdquo; approximately refer to?
<ul>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo;s Reply: You will know when the time comes; you don&rsquo;t need someone else to tell you. When you are wealthy enough, buying a house will be as easy as buying slippers, and you can even use borrowed money to buy one casually. At that point, you could also choose to live in a luxurious retirement community—the choice is yours.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">May 
    <div id="may" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#may" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question: She is in her fifties/sixties and wants to take out a pledged loan in China on her fully paid-off house, but banks only offer a maximum term of 3-5 years, which is too risky. How does the teacher obtain long-term loans?
<ul>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo;s Reply: The best long-term loan is a &ldquo;stock-pledged loan,&rdquo; which can be structured to never pay back the principal, and even the interest can be rolled into the principal. Mortgages and personal loans have fixed terms and are not suitable. For short-term loans (like 3-5 years), don&rsquo;t borrow unless you are confident you can repay even if the market crashes. He suggests she sell her house in China, even at a lower price, as long as she can liquidate it. Abroad, she can try using Interactive Brokers (IB) for stock-pledged loans.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Rui 
    <div id="rui" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#rui" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Inspired by the teacher, he successfully borrowed a large sum of money from the bank against his assets and discovered that car loans don&rsquo;t count towards his debt ratio. He plans to use a 2% pledged loan to pay off the car loan, thereby investing more funds into the 433 allocation. He now feels that the speed of his asset growth has surpassed his annual salary.</li>
<li>Question: He saw a YouTuber say that Chinese engineers in Silicon Valley are unhappy due to endless &ldquo;comparisons&rdquo; (of degrees, companies, salaries, houses, wives, children). As someone with a master&rsquo;s degree, he also felt insecure in an environment full of PhDs. How does the teacher view &ldquo;comparison&rdquo;? And how can the teacher confidently pay his subordinates a higher salary than his own?
<ul>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo;s Reply: Quoting Munger, &ldquo;Envy is a really stupid sin.&rdquo; Don&rsquo;t compare; the key is a strong inner self. You must affirm from within that you are the best. The way you see yourself is more important than how others see you. He uses his own experience of leading a team of PhDs without a PhD himself, and designing Microsoft&rsquo;s Media architecture and the computer Hibernate patent, to illustrate that success is unrelated to academic degrees but is related to confidence and intellect.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Mindy 
    <div id="mindy" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#mindy" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question 1: She is 60 and retired. As recommended, she has allocated TQQQ in her smaller Roth IRA account. However, the AI on Chen Feng&rsquo;s website advises her not to use leverage at her age and to keep many years of cash. How much cash should a retiree actually keep? Is it 30% or 15 years&rsquo; worth of living expenses?
<ul>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo;s Reply: Don&rsquo;t fully trust the AI; follow the teacher&rsquo;s instruction. Her allocation (TQQQ in Roth, cash in Traditional IRA) is correct. Retirees should keep <strong>30% cash</strong>, which is approximately equivalent to <strong>15 years&rsquo; worth</strong> of living expenses. This is not due to pessimism about the market; on the contrary, the market may rise even faster in the future. This is the result of the CLEC investment system&rsquo;s &ldquo;DNA evolution&rdquo; after being tested by the market, making it better able to withstand future extreme risks.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2: She saw other financial bloggers advocating for market timing using &ldquo;economic indicator signals&rdquo; and is worried that buying TQQQ at a market high will lead to significant decay.
<ul>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo;s Reply: Don&rsquo;t refer to other people&rsquo;s investment systems; they won&rsquo;t be compatible. Within the 433 asset allocation, there is no so-called &ldquo;decay&rdquo; problem for TQQQ because the large cash reserve acts as a buffer, and the actual drop of the portfolio during a downturn will be less than that of 100% QQQ.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Tina 
    <div id="tina" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#tina" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question 1: She is 43 and just immigrated to the US. Her 401k and IRA accounts have very little money. To implement the 433 allocation, it seems she can only buy leveraged ETFs in a taxable brokerage account. Is this acceptable?
<ul>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo;s Reply: Yes. In the early stages when funds are insufficient, you can use a 433 allocation in a brokerage account to maintain a higher Beta and sufficient cash. Although rebalancing will generate taxes, the priority is to &ldquo;make money first.&rdquo; However, you must <strong>do smart rebalancing every year</strong>, because a 30% leveraged position is very risky and cannot be left unattended.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2: For dollar-cost averaging for an 11-year-old child, the teacher previously recommended QLD. Why not the better TQQQ?
<ul>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo;s Reply: TQQQ has extremely high volatility. Calculating from the 2000 peak, it might take over 20 years to break even, whereas QLD breaks even faster. For a child&rsquo;s long-term investment of over 20 years, both are acceptable, but the premise is that you <strong>must persist in buying continuously</strong>, regardless of market ups and downs. If the investment horizon is uncertain or you want to be more conservative, QLD is the safer choice.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Xin 
    <div id="xin" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#xin" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question: Should high-net-worth families be concerned about the 40% US estate tax? Should they set up an irrevocable trust in advance to avoid it?
<ul>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo;s Reply: First, the US estate tax exemption has been permanently set at $15 million per person, meaning a couple has a $30 million exemption. Most families don&rsquo;t need to worry. Second, he does not recommend setting up an irrevocable charitable trust because they usually require an annual donation of 5% of assets, which is a huge burden and constraint on the children. A better way is to use the annual gift tax exclusion (e.g., $20,000) and start gifting early. Over the long term, the growth of the gifted assets will far exceed the estate tax exemption amount.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Bill 
    <div id="bill" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#bill" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question: When the market drops and rebalancing is needed for the TQQQ in a Roth account, if the annual contribution limit of $7,000 is not enough, can funds be converted from a Traditional IRA?
<ul>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo;s Reply: Yes, that is exactly the correct operation. You can use the annual contribution limit, and if that&rsquo;s not enough, use a Roth Conversion to supplement the cash.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Lucy 
    <div id="lucy" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#lucy" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question: She (in Canada) obtained extra cash for investment through a home refinance. Can the interest on this portion of the loan be deducted as an investment expense for tax purposes?
<ul>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo;s Reply: Only when you sell an asset and generate a realized capital gain do you have taxable investment income against which related expenses might be deducted. If you just hold and don&rsquo;t sell, there is no taxable event. Canada&rsquo;s Tax-Free Savings Account (TFSA) is similar to the US Roth IRA, and investment and rebalancing operations should be conducted within it.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Vincent 
    <div id="vincent" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#vincent" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question (from the comment section): With 30 million TWD in assets, if I withdraw 2% for living expenses, 600,000 per year is not enough. Do I have to wait until my assets double to 60 million to live a good life?
<ul>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo;s Reply: Not necessarily. You can increase the withdrawal rate by adjusting your asset allocation. For example, you can change the 433 allocation (Beta=1) to a 424 or 514 allocation with a higher cash percentage, which lowers the portfolio&rsquo;s volatility (Beta&lt;1). Once the volatility is reduced, the annual withdrawal rate can be safely increased to 3% or 3.5%.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Student 
    <div id="student" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#student" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question (from the comment section): Is it okay for a 12-year-old child to dollar-cost average into 00670L (a 2x leveraged ETF in Taiwan)?
<ul>
<li>Teacher James&rsquo;s Reply: If you can ensure continuous investment for over 20 years (e.g., until age 32), it is acceptable. However, if the investment horizon is shorter (e.g., until they become independent at 24), it is recommended to do half-and-half (half leveraged, half non-leveraged) or invest entirely in the non-leveraged ETF to reduce risk.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">IV. Highlighted Quotes 
    <div id="iv-highlighted-quotes" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv-highlighted-quotes" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>Wealth is a gift, happiness is a human right, and health is the foundation of life.
&ndash; Teacher James</p></blockquote>
<p>Context: At the beginning of the class, the teacher explained the relationship between investment and life, emphasizing that our ultimate goals are happiness and health, while wealth is an innate right and a tool to achieve those goals.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Are you living your own life, or a life defined by the external environment? Don&rsquo;t be led by outside information.
&ndash; Teacher James</p></blockquote>
<p>Context: The teacher advised students not to be engrossed in media and online information all day, as that is living a life defined by others, not their own. One should return to their inner self and focus on their own life.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Envy is a really stupid sin.
&ndash; Teacher James (quoting Charlie Munger)</p></blockquote>
<p>Context: When answering a student&rsquo;s question about &ldquo;comparison,&rdquo; the teacher quoted Munger&rsquo;s famous line, pointing out that comparing oneself to others is a source of unhappiness and a foolish act.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>You are what you think you are, and that is more important than how others see you. If you don&rsquo;t even believe in what you are, how can others believe in what you are?
&ndash; Teacher James</p></blockquote>
<p>Context: The teacher encouraged students to build self-confidence. He believes that personal value is determined by self-perception, not by external evaluations or labels like academic degrees.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>When borrowing money, we don&rsquo;t fear high interest rates; we fear that the term is too short.
&ndash; Teacher James</p></blockquote>
<p>Context: When answering a question about loans, the teacher stressed the importance of the loan term. As long as the term is long enough, even with a higher interest rate, the long-term growth of assets is sufficient to cover the costs, whereas short-term loans carry immense risk.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Be clear about what you want. For everything else that is different from what you want, you don&rsquo;t need to care, you don&rsquo;t need to mind, and you don&rsquo;t need to compare.
&ndash; Chen Feng</p></blockquote>
<p>Context: Student Chen Feng shared this perspective when explaining how he avoids the &ldquo;comparison&rdquo; mindset. He believes that as long as you are clear about your own goals, you will not be disturbed by external factors unrelated to them.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>If you keep following our DNA, your DNA will evolve. This is how you can prepare for potential future risks and changes.
&ndash; Teacher James</p></blockquote>
<p>Context: When explaining why he now recommends holding more cash (30%), the teacher compared the CLEC investment system to a biological DNA. This system continuously evolves after being tested by the market, becoming better adapted to various future environments. Therefore, students need to keep learning to acquire this &ldquo;evolved&rdquo; and robust system.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>If you are 100% in leveraged funds, you might go to hell; it would be like a dream that ends in 30 years.
&ndash; Teacher James</p></blockquote>
<p>Context: When reminding students of the risks of leveraged funds, the teacher seriously pointed out that being fully invested in leveraged funds without asset allocation and rebalancing could ultimately lead to a total loss in a major market crash.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">V. Summary 
    <div id="v-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#v-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This session once again emphasized the core of the CLEC investment philosophy: investing is simple, mindset is supreme. Starting from a high-level life philosophy, Teacher James guided everyone to shift their focus from the complex noise of the market to the simple purity of their personal lives, fostering the belief to &ldquo;live for yourself.&rdquo; The course not only shared profound insights on children&rsquo;s education and self-worth realization but also delved into the practical application of financial tools like &ldquo;reverse mortgages&rdquo; and &ldquo;pledged loans.&rdquo; It also provided detailed explanations on the risk control and long-term operational principles of asset allocation (especially the 433 strategy involving leveraged funds). Through active questions and sharing from students, many practical confusions—such as allocation in different accounts, tax issues, and retirement cash flow planning—were clearly answered. Ultimately, the course returned to a fundamental point: build a strong inner self and adhere to the right principles, and wealth will naturally follow.</p>

  



<div
  
    class="flex px-4 py-3 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900"
  >

  <span
    
      class="text-primary-400 ltr:pr-3 rtl:pl-3 flex items-center"
    >

    

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M506.3 417l-213.3-364c-16.33-28-57.54-28-73.98 0l-213.2 364C-10.59 444.9 9.849 480 42.74 480h426.6C502.1 480 522.6 445 506.3 417zM232 168c0-13.25 10.75-24 24-24S280 154.8 280 168v128c0 13.25-10.75 24-23.1 24S232 309.3 232 296V168zM256 416c-17.36 0-31.44-14.08-31.44-31.44c0-17.36 14.07-31.44 31.44-31.44s31.44 14.08 31.44 31.44C287.4 401.9 273.4 416 256 416z"/></svg>

  </span>


  </span>

  <span
    
      class="dark:text-neutral-300"
    ><strong>Disclaimer:</strong> This article is for personal learning notes only and does not constitute any investment advice.</span>
</div>

]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>00518 From Houses to Bonds: Asset Allocation is a Master Strategy, Avoid Scams, Understand Risks, and Return to the Index</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1749950529180/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1749950529180/</guid><description>Teacher James shares his philosophy of long-term investment in the Nasdaq 100 index fund, emphasizing risk control, asset allocation (especially the importance of cash), and a positive investment mindset. The content covers his views on current market volatility, bond investments, financial products, individual stocks versus ETFs, as well as practical sharing and Q&amp;amp;A with students, supplemented by the teacher&amp;#39;s profound reflections on personal experiences, educational philosophy, and social responsibility.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<lite-youtube videoid="JlFNunk6brQ" playlabel="JlFNunk6brQ" params=""></lite-youtube>



<h2 class="relative group">I. Theme of the Session 
    <div id="i-theme-of-the-session" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-theme-of-the-session" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>The core of this lecture is to emphasize <strong>persisting in long-term investment in the Nasdaq 100 index fund, prioritizing risk control and reasonable asset allocation, and maintaining an extremely optimistic investment mindset</strong>. Teacher James points out that market volatility is normal; investors should ignore short-term fluctuations, focus on long-term growth, recognize the critical role of cash in asset allocation, and ultimately achieve financial freedom and life&rsquo;s purpose.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">II. Briefing Content 
    <div id="ii-briefing-content" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii-briefing-content" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Opening and Investment Mindset 
    <div id="opening-and-investment-mindset" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#opening-and-investment-mindset" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>The Market&rsquo;s Normal State</strong>: Global situations and market turmoil are normal. Investors should remain calm and not be disturbed by short-term volatility, international affairs, market analysis, financial statements, or economic conditions.</li>
<li><strong>Disclaimer</strong>: This channel is a pro bono sharing platform and does not constitute investment advice. There are no fees, no alternate accounts, and be wary of scams. Investing involves risk, which you must manage yourself. Relevant links are pinned in the YouTube comments section.</li>
<li><strong>Learning Path</strong>: Newcomers are advised to start with &ldquo;00451 The One-Dollar Investment Lecture,&rdquo; think independently, and find a method that suits them. Quiet study improves the quality of thought more than joining too many groups.</li>
<li><strong>Core Investment Vehicle</strong>: Focus on the Nasdaq 100 index fund (like QQQ). Page 10 of the handout provides a selection of related funds worldwide. The videos started in 2018, and there is a complete 2022 course playlist available.</li>
<li><strong>Investment Mentality</strong>: Always be extremely optimistic, always face the sun; the market will eventually go up. Investing requires patience (ignoring market fluctuations), and financial freedom is worth the wait. Please like, comment, and subscribe on all platforms.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Macroeconomics and the Bond Myth 
    <div id="macroeconomics-and-the-bond-myth" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#macroeconomics-and-the-bond-myth" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Stablecoins and Short-Term Treasuries</strong>: A student asked if the issuance of stablecoins would increase demand for short-term treasuries and lower their interest rates. Teacher James believes short-term treasury rates are tied to the central bank&rsquo;s rates and won&rsquo;t fall significantly because of this. Short-term treasuries are similar to money market funds with low volatility. The central bank&rsquo;s rate is the benchmark; no one would buy a bond with a lower rate.</li>
<li><strong>The Trap of Long-Term Bonds</strong>: Long-term bond interest is linked to inflation expectations for many years to come, and the interest is fixed.
<ul>
<li><strong>Example</strong>: For a 30-year Treasury bond with a 5% coupon rate, if inflation is 3%, the real annualized rate of return (Real IRR) is only 1.94%. In contrast, if short-term rates are 4%, it is far superior to the real return of long-term bonds. The $5 in interest you receive after 30 years will have long been devalued.</li>
<li><strong>Conclusion</strong>: It is not recommended for individual investors to buy long-term government bonds. Issuing long-term bonds is advantageous for the U.S. Treasury because the long-term interest is close to zero for the issuer (after considering inflation). Even if the central bank&rsquo;s rate is below 2%, buying long-term bonds is not necessarily a good deal. The Treasury has its own issuance plan and won&rsquo;t easily change it due to shifts in the central bank&rsquo;s rates. The idea of issuing 100-year bonds is impractical and tantamount to default.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Risk Control and Asset Allocation 
    <div id="risk-control-and-asset-allocation" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#risk-control-and-asset-allocation" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Risk Awareness</strong>: The first priority in investing is risk control; the world is full of uncertainties (like the conflict in Israel).</li>
<li><strong>The Importance of Asset Allocation</strong>: Good asset allocation is a &ldquo;master strategy&rdquo; (奇门遁甲), a powerful &ldquo;Army, Navy, and Air Force&rdquo; deployment.
<ul>
<li><strong>Cash</strong>: The &ldquo;food and air&rdquo; of asset allocation, the most important part. Sufficient cash prevents market panic.</li>
<li><strong>Index Fund</strong>: The &ldquo;aircraft carrier&rdquo; of asset allocation.</li>
<li><strong>Leveraged Fund</strong>: Like the &ldquo;missile force.&rdquo;</li>
<li><strong>Stock Pledging</strong>: The &ldquo;Transformer&rdquo; of asset allocation.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>The Courage to Sell a House for Investment</strong>: Selling your primary residence to rent and investing the funds in an index is an excellent financial strategy, but it requires a strong mind and the courage to face social judgment (e.g., fear of being told you&rsquo;re &ldquo;not doing well&rdquo;). In reality, this is a sign of &ldquo;doing exceptionally well.&rdquo;</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Investment Concepts and Behavioral Psychology 
    <div id="investment-concepts-and-behavioral-psychology" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#investment-concepts-and-behavioral-psychology" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>The Difficulty of Educating Family and Friends</strong>: Family and friends would rather trust the annuities and savings insurance (1% return) recommended by bank advisors than accept advice about index funds (10% long-term return), even when presented with spreadsheets. The main reason is the fear of &ldquo;what if it drops?&rdquo;
<ul>
<li><strong>Counter-strategy</strong>: First, become a &ldquo;big tree&rdquo; yourself and influence them with your own success. Your words carry little weight when you&rsquo;re insignificant; &ldquo;familiarity breeds contempt&rdquo; (近庙欺神). It&rsquo;s hard to distinguish &ldquo;saints&rdquo; from &ldquo;demons&rdquo; in society.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Cognitive Roots of the Wealth Gap</strong>: Poverty is often caused by a lack of awareness, not systemic issues. CLEC aims to &ldquo;cure&rdquo; this &ldquo;disease of poverty,&rdquo; but it&rsquo;s very difficult; even family members may not accept it. Some people can&rsquo;t accept good medicine and instead buy things like long-term bonds.</li>
<li><strong>The Challenges of Individual Stock Investing</strong>:
<ul>
<li><strong>Example</strong>: NVIDIA&rsquo;s stock price fluctuates wildly. It was once sold off due to poor sales and excess inventory, then soared because of AI. It&rsquo;s difficult for individual investors to grasp; even if you bought it, you might not have held on for the entire ride.</li>
<li><strong>Conclusion</strong>: Individual stocks are volatile, information is asymmetric, and they can suddenly be cut in half or go to zero. ETFs provide a more stable way to share in market growth. It&rsquo;s also very hard to stick with a portfolio of mixed-quality individual stocks.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>The Dangers of Short-Term Trading</strong>: Short-term trading is like &ldquo;gambling + drug addiction.&rdquo; It&rsquo;s addictive and leads not only to financial loss but also the loss of family, health, and self, potentially ruining one&rsquo;s entire life. There&rsquo;s no need to become a &ldquo;boy wonder trader.&rdquo;</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Critique of Chaos in the Financial Industry 
    <div id="critique-of-chaos-in-the-financial-industry" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#critique-of-chaos-in-the-financial-industry" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Profit Motives of Banks and Insurance Companies</strong>: Criticizes post offices and banks for persuading depositors (especially the elderly) to buy annuity insurance, structured notes, and similar products. This is a failure of financial regulators.</li>
<li><strong>Regulatory Issues</strong>: Believes financial regulators should ensure the separation of savings, insurance, wealth management, and lending to avoid conflicts of interest. American commercial banks (like BofA) don&rsquo;t proactively sell insurance. Taiwan&rsquo;s &ldquo;Financial Holding Company&rdquo; model is described as an &ldquo;all-encompassing, one-stop-shop scam.&rdquo; Charles Schwab only mentions loan options when a client has a large funding need.</li>
<li><strong>The Goal of the Insurance Industry</strong>: To convert large amounts of fixed deposits into insurance policies, which is the main objective of the insurance industry, given the huge amount of fixed deposits in Taiwan.</li>
<li><strong>The Risk of Mortgaging Property to Buy Insurance</strong>: There have been cases where the property mortgage remains, but the insurance policy&rsquo;s value drops to zero, leaving people homeless. These institutions &ldquo;will go as far as making people homeless.&rdquo;</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Responses to Chat Comments and Additional Remarks (Teacher James&rsquo;s collective response to student comments and personal reflections) 
    <div id="responses-to-chat-comments-and-additional-remarks-teacher-jamess-collective-response-to-student-comments-and-personal-reflections" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#responses-to-chat-comments-and-additional-remarks-teacher-jamess-collective-response-to-student-comments-and-personal-reflections" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>On Publishing a Book/Media Exposure</strong>: Teacher James frankly states that if he were to publicly promote his ideas like &ldquo;investing with loans&rdquo; and &ldquo;not buying a house,&rdquo; he could violate financial regulations (practicing without a license), offend powerful interest groups (real estate, insurance, finance), and even face cyberbullying and political pressure (being labeled &ldquo;pro-Taiwan independence&rdquo; or &ldquo;pro-CCP&rdquo;). He could be &ldquo;torn to shreds&rdquo; or even &ldquo;end up in jail.&rdquo; If he doesn&rsquo;t discuss many of these topics, the teaching loses its meaning. The very people you help might turn around and curse you.</li>
<li><strong>Insurance</strong>: An insurance policy with a 1.06% annual return is acceptable if it includes protection, but it&rsquo;s generally not recommended.</li>
<li><strong>Caring for Parents</strong>: Re-emphasizes the loneliness and health risks of elderly people living alone (not taking medicine on time, not measuring blood sugar/pressure, leading to complications like worsening COPD, minor strokes, brain atrophy, mental disorders). Advises children to pay attention and provide companionship early. Even if parents seem self-sufficient, consider arranging for a caregiver early to prevent accidents and ensure a regular routine (medication, diet, avoiding falls). Shares his regret of not returning to Taiwan in time to accompany his mother, who, despite having other children in Taiwan, was not adequately cared for while living alone. Emphasizes that parents&rsquo; health is the children&rsquo;s happiness.</li>
<li><strong>A Partner&rsquo;s Investment Philosophy</strong>: Accept individual differences. Due to different upbringings and personal experiences (like living through the dot-com and 2008 bubbles), security levels and cognitions vary. Lead by example and influence them gradually with long-term results; don&rsquo;t force it. It&rsquo;s normal for them not to listen to you, just as you may not listen to them.</li>
<li><strong>00662 (Taiwan ETF) Currency Impact</strong>: Short-term currency fluctuations are normal. For instance, when the Taiwan dollar depreciated in the previous two years, 00662 outperformed QQQ. In the long run, currency effects tend to cancel each other out.</li>
<li><strong>Credit Loans vs. Stock Pledges</strong>: Credit loans are relatively independent and safe. Stock pledges are high-risk; a sharp market downturn could trigger a margin call, making it like a &ldquo;loan shark&rdquo; — you have to pay back when they demand it, or you&rsquo;re &ldquo;shot dead with one bullet.&rdquo;</li>
<li><strong>Brokerage Firms Raising Pledge Rates and Risks</strong>: Brokerages like Capital Securities in Taiwan might raise interest rates after a client has borrowed, or even restrict withdrawals (due to limited funding pools), &ldquo;luring you into a trap.&rdquo; It&rsquo;s advisable to prioritize more stable brokerages like Yuanta Securities.</li>
<li><strong>Apply for Credit Loans Early</strong>: Bank credit policies can change. When you qualify (e.g., with an interest rate below 2%), you should apply early. Seize the opportunity when a bank proactively offers you a loan.</li>
<li><strong>Stock Pledging in Hong Kong</strong>: HSBC is a good choice, especially for VIP clients with large capital (e.g., over 1 million HKD). HSBC&rsquo;s pledge interest rates are currently low. Friends from Malaysia, Singapore, Australia, etc., who successfully open an account and get a pledge loan from HSBC are welcome to share their experiences.</li>
<li><strong>QQQ Compounding</strong>: The annualized rate of return (CAGR), according to Teacher James&rsquo;s research, is around 18% (including dividend reinvestment).</li>
<li><strong>Repayment of Investment Mortgage</strong>: Typically, it&rsquo;s a lump-sum repayment at maturity (10-15 years). By then, you can sell some stocks or use another pledged loan to repay it. You need more than 15 years to ensure profitability.</li>
<li><strong>Compound Frequency</strong>: Refers to capital gains and dividend reinvestment.</li>
<li><strong>Philosophy of Helping Others</strong>: There are different levels of helping others. The lowest is for others (hoping for their well-being). The next is for oneself (deriving happiness or meaning from it). The highest is selflessness (helping is a natural act, regardless of for whom, or whether it brings happiness, like the Buddha or Jesus; it&rsquo;s natural ethics). Using helping others to add meaning and happiness to one&rsquo;s own life is actually &ldquo;not right.&rdquo; The highest state is &ldquo;like water flowing without a trace&rdquo; (传过水无痕).</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">III. Q&amp;A Session 
    <div id="iii-qa-session" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii-qa-session" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Kacy 
    <div id="kacy" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#kacy" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing</strong>: An elderly friend, who was once very influential in the market, agrees with Teacher James&rsquo;s index investing philosophy. This elder confessed that his past outsized returns were due to information asymmetry and his influence (manipulating small-cap stocks), which is not replicable for ordinary investors. He believes it&rsquo;s not easy for ordinary people to make money in the market, and index investing is the most correct path.
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s Comment</strong>: Index investing not only makes you money but also gives you a &ldquo;life&rdquo; (improves quality of life). Even if you make money from short-term trading, you might lose your life due to constant anxiety (e.g., being unable to take a 15-day vacation with peace of mind).</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Sharing (Follow-up)</strong>:
<ol>
<li>Reflecting on her family life, she emphasizes love and companionship for her parents to avoid regrets. She sees Teacher James&rsquo;s actions as &ldquo;dedication&rdquo; rather than &ldquo;charity&rdquo; with a sense of superiority and feels for the misunderstandings he might face.</li>
<li>Shares her future plans: to establish a women&rsquo;s financial academy (focusing on female financial awareness, as Chinese women are relatively disadvantaged, and financial independence provides more confidence), volunteer in hospice care (to learn about &ldquo;fasting until death&rdquo; and euthanasia), travel, read, and set up scholarships, reflecting a desire for &ldquo;altruism&rdquo; (influenced by Kazuo Inamori&rsquo;s philosophy of &ldquo;altruism&rdquo;).</li>
</ol>
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s Comment</strong>:
<ol>
<li>Commends Kacy&rsquo;s practice of accompanying her parents. Shares the joy of his own father, in his 90s, still planning a trip to Korea. Advises that for elderly parents, even if they appear healthy, one should consider arranging for a caregiver early to prevent accidents and ensure a regular routine (medication, diet). Parents&rsquo; health is the children&rsquo;s happiness. If parents have medical needs, like follow-up visits every three months or low-dose lung cancer screenings, they should be supported.</li>
<li>Greatly admires Kacy&rsquo;s &ldquo;altruistic&rdquo; plans, believing that from a women&rsquo;s financial academy to educating disadvantaged groups, it&rsquo;s all very meaningful. It&rsquo;s right to start planning now.</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">C 
    <div id="c" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#c" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing</strong>: His mother noticed his mood has become calmer and happier recently. He explained it&rsquo;s because through investing (practicing the teacher&rsquo;s teachings), he has found meaning in life and is confident about his future wealth, no longer worrying about finances. This has led to an internal change from external influences.
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s Comment</strong>: Shares his own longing and regrets regarding his mother, how in his youth he failed to fully grasp the loneliness and hardship of an elderly person living alone (e.g., his mother falling while going to the doctor alone, and his own failure to return to Taiwan to be with her). Reminds everyone to care for their parents, especially those living alone, after achieving financial freedom early, to avoid life&rsquo;s regrets. Advises young people to learn from wise elders (like Warren Buffett) to avoid many pitfalls and find a &ldquo;mental coach.&rdquo;</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question</strong>: Following the teacher&rsquo;s guidance, he used an investment mortgage to invest in 00662. After using a portion of the funds from high-dividend ETFs to pay the monthly interest, there&rsquo;s still a surplus each month. Should he invest this in 00865 (short-term bond/cash-like ETF) or continue buying fractional shares of 00662?
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s Response</strong>: Continue buying 00662. The emergency fund (00865) only needs to be built up to a certain level (e.g., 2-3 years of living expenses for someone employed). Any excess funds should be invested in growth assets.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">IM 
    <div id="im" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#im" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing 1</strong>: Recalls entering the market in 2018, with emotions fluctuating with the market, having once lost 50%. A wise friend enlightened her (&ldquo;Save money when you&rsquo;re making it, and just wait it out when it&rsquo;s down&rdquo;), teaching her to remain calm through ups and downs and become numb to the market. Mentions how wealthy people view money (a piece of clothing costs 500-600k; money is like trash to them). Grateful for the teacher&rsquo;s guidance that has &ldquo;filled her head.&rdquo;</li>
<li><strong>Sharing 2</strong>: Has come to understand the teacher&rsquo;s mindset that &ldquo;all sharing is for self-fulfillment, not for rewards.&rdquo; When sharing investment ideas with others, she encounters different reactions: some (who have worked for 20-30 years and are set in their ways) cling to old concepts, while others, despite living in hardship (a single mother working two jobs), are willing to listen. Through sharing, she has also gained a sense of value by giving back the knowledge she has learned.
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s Comment</strong>: (Regarding Sharing 2) Helping others can bring happiness, but the highest state is to be &ldquo;unaffected by helping,&rdquo; meaning helping others is a natural act, not for happiness, not for self. The lowest level is &ldquo;for others,&rdquo; i.e., for their benefit; the second level is &ldquo;for oneself,&rdquo; i.e., achieving self-actualization through helping (the teacher admits his own teaching is to find value in retirement); the highest is &ldquo;selflessness,&rdquo; where even the thought of &ldquo;for myself&rdquo; is gone.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question</strong>: After sharing investment concepts with friends, how can she determine if they truly understand? Are there any questions to ask to test them? (Friends listen and think it&rsquo;s logical but can&rsquo;t articulate it themselves.)
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s Response</strong>: It&rsquo;s hard to judge with simple questions. True understanding is reflected in action (like opening an account to invest). A more effective way is like how Frank guided him back in the day (meeting for dinner every week, hand-holding him through opening an account, starting with a $200 Mutual Fund), guiding them step-by-step to open an account, make their first investment, and follow up continuously. This is a process of &ldquo;sowing seeds&rdquo;; whether and when they sprout is unknown. He himself was &ldquo;led by the hand&rdquo; by Frank to get started. Now, he is willing to be such a guide, with the Bodhisattva spirit of &ldquo;If I don&rsquo;t descend into hell, who will?&rdquo;</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Man 
    <div id="man" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#man" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing</strong>: Gained insights from gardening.
<ol>
<li><strong>Individual Differences</strong>: The same seeds planted result in different flowers, just as people receive information differently. Their internal &ldquo;genes&rdquo; determine their level of acceptance and reaction (some &ldquo;get it,&rdquo; others &ldquo;laugh it off&rdquo;). The gardener (the sharer) cannot change the seed&rsquo;s nature.</li>
<li><strong>Patient Guidance</strong>: A good gardener will loosen the soil and water, helping it grow, just as a mentor guides students to open accounts and invest.</li>
<li><strong>Inner Joy</strong>: The pleasure derived from tilling the soil and weeding surpasses the rewards of all fame and fortune. This effort is not for a return but for self-actualization.</li>
<li><strong>Practical Example</strong>: She once guided a friend to buy QQQ. The friend sold during a dip and missed the subsequent 45% gain. She only sent a screenshot and said no more, believing it was also &ldquo;fate.&rdquo;</li>
<li><strong>Translating for the Elderly at a Doctor&rsquo;s Visit</strong>: Shares her experience as a volunteer translator for the elderly, realizing their immense need in medical communication. Such small acts can bring great help and a ray of light into their lives.</li>
</ol>
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s Comment</strong>: Agrees with the views on &ldquo;destiny&rdquo; and intrinsic motivation. Shares his own experience of planting tomatoes, where three seeds grew very differently; one was a &ldquo;chosen seedling&rdquo; and very robust, while others were &ldquo;sickly.&rdquo; Cites Dr. Yang Ding-I&rsquo;s view to &ldquo;look inward.&rdquo; For people you can&rsquo;t change, don&rsquo;t force it. Be yourself, don&rsquo;t be discouraged by it; giving up is an option. Affirms the value of her volunteer work.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Sifei 
    <div id="sifei" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#sifei" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing</strong>: Came into contact with CLEC in 2024 through a friend (who had mentioned it 5 years ago, but she was indifferent at the time). In her 50s, she has been interested in investing since graduating from college and has been exploring on her own for years. She was deeply moved after listening to the lectures and has invested a lot of time in studying (finished the 2021-2022 courses and is now re-listening). She shared it with a hundred people, and only two took action, but she still feels gratified.</li>
<li><strong>Question</strong>: Regarding the choice between a credit loan and a stock pledge in Taiwan. She leans towards using the stock pledge first (2.56% interest, no principal repayment, only interest), because of its convenience. She thinks she can use a credit loan (already approved for a 3 million TWD limit, but requires installment repayments) as a backup if the stock market crashes. She believes her job is stable (banks are always begging her to take out loans), so she&rsquo;s not afraid of unemployment and can access the credit loan anytime.
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s Response</strong>: (In a firm tone, repeatedly emphasizing) <strong>Absolutely do not do this!</strong>
<ol>
<li><strong>Core Principle</strong>: Money borrowed from a stock pledge <strong>must not be reinvested in the stock market</strong>. It can only be used for living expenses or to repay other loans. This is &ldquo;the first thing.&rdquo;</li>
<li><strong>Huge Risk</strong>: When the market crashes, banks may tighten credit (&ldquo;take away the umbrella in the rain&rdquo;), and you might not be able to borrow money then. If you lose your job at the same time, it&rsquo;s even more impossible. A credit loan is not something you can just &ldquo;hold there&rdquo; forever.</li>
<li><strong>Deploy All Troops (韩信点兵)</strong>: All available &ldquo;forces&rdquo; (including the credit loan) should be deployed to the &ldquo;battlefield&rdquo; (investment) as early as possible.</li>
<li><strong>The Correct Approach</strong>: You should first take out the credit loan (e.g., 3 million TWD) and invest it in the market. The monthly loan repayments can be paid using funds from a low-interest stock pledge. This way, the principal continues to work in the market, and your personal salary can also be invested. Don&rsquo;t take a huge risk just because you&rsquo;re &ldquo;too lazy to repay the principal&rdquo; or tempted by the short-term convenience of a pledge.</li>
<li><strong>Safety of Credit Loans</strong>: A credit loan is a relatively safe form of leverage, not directly linked to market fluctuations, and you won&rsquo;t get a margin call. With a stock pledge, even if you only borrow 10% (e.g., pledging 1 million from a 10 million asset portfolio—the teacher thinks 10% is already a huge risk, let alone the 2-3 million she wants to borrow), you could face risks in an extreme market downturn.</li>
<li><strong>Brokerage Risk</strong>: Some brokerages in Taiwan (like Capital Securities) may change their pledge interest rates, and their limited funding pools might prevent you from withdrawing funds as needed.
(Kacy and other students also chimed in, emphasizing the risk of banks &ldquo;taking away the umbrella in the rain&rdquo; and the fundamental difference between credit loans and pledges, and that pledged money cannot be used to buy more stocks).</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Xiao Zhang 
    <div id="xiao-zhang" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#xiao-zhang" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Did not speak or content was not recorded.</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">IV. Highlighted Quotes 
    <div id="iv-highlighted-quotes" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv-highlighted-quotes" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>Market fluctuations have nothing to do with me, international affairs have nothing to do with me, market analysis has nothing to do with me, financial statements have nothing to do with us, and the economic situation doesn&rsquo;t matter at all. Don&rsquo;t pay attention to it. The more you pay attention, the more mistakes you&rsquo;ll make.
&ndash; Teacher James</p></blockquote>
<p>Background: Teacher James emphasized at the beginning the composure investors should have, not letting external noise affect their investment decisions.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Investing requires patience, and financial freedom is worth the wait. What is patience? It is to be unconcerned with market fluctuations.
&ndash; Teacher James</p></blockquote>
<p>Background: Explaining that the core of long-term investing lies in the psychological tolerance for market volatility.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Cash is the food and air of asset allocation.
&ndash; Teacher James</p></blockquote>
<p>Background: Emphasizing the extreme importance of holding sufficient cash for risk management and psychological stability in asset allocation.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>You are poor because of a lack of awareness, not because the system made you poor.
&ndash; Teacher James</p></blockquote>
<p>Background: When discussing the difficulty of teaching family about investing, pointing out that the wealth gap often stems from cognitive differences.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Short-term trading doesn&rsquo;t just want your money; it will want your life and your lifelong happiness.
&ndash; Teacher James</p></blockquote>
<p>Background: A stern warning about the immense dangers of short-term trading, comparing it to gambling and drug addiction.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>In investing, we first seek safety, then profit. First, seek safety; do what is foolproof first.
&ndash; Teacher James</p></blockquote>
<p>Background: Emphasizing that the primary principle of investing is safety, in response to a student&rsquo;s question about credit loans versus stock pledges.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>When you are making money, you should also be humble and look at everything with humility. Just as Teacher James taught me, whether the market goes up or down, OK, be numb to it. It doesn&rsquo;t have a big impact on our daily lives.
&ndash; IM</p></blockquote>
<p>Background: Student IM sharing her transformation from anxiously watching the market to maintaining a calm composure towards market fluctuations.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The things we invest in others, when we invest, it&rsquo;s not for a return. It&rsquo;s because you have to do this thing. You have to do what is meaningful to you; this is the value of your being.
&ndash; Man</p></blockquote>
<p>Background: Student Man drawing an analogy from gardening to the intrinsic value of sharing knowledge and helping others, without seeking external rewards.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Life is really not just about money&hellip; Wealth is about having enough.
&ndash; Kacy</p></blockquote>
<p>Background: Student Kacy sharing her pursuit of quality of life, believing that more wealth is not necessarily better; having enough is sufficient.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The highest level is helping others without any sense of happiness, without feeling&hellip; Even the &lsquo;for myself&rsquo; is gone. This is what I have learned, that even the &lsquo;for myself&rsquo; is gone.
&ndash; Teacher James</p></blockquote>
<p>Background: When responding to IM&rsquo;s question about the motivation for sharing, he explains the three levels of helping behavior, the highest of which is selfless altruism, a natural act.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">V. Summary 
    <div id="v-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#v-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>In this session, Teacher James systematically re-emphasized his core investment philosophy: consistently buy and hold the Nasdaq 100 index fund, fearless of short-term market volatility. He focused on analyzing the extreme importance of risk control, viewing reasonable asset allocation (especially an adequate cash reserve) as the cornerstone of investment success. Through specific examples, the teacher revealed the investment value trap of long-term bonds and severely criticized certain misleading and detrimental practices in the financial industry, especially warning investors against low-return products like annuities and savings insurance. At the same time, he pointed out the huge uncertainty of individual stock investing and the destructive nature of short-term trading. During the Q&amp;A session, students actively shared their insights and confusions from their investment practices, family communication, and personal growth. Teacher James not only provided specific investment advice (such as the correct use and risk perception of credit loans versus stock pledges) but also guided students from a life philosophy perspective to reflect on the meaning of wealth, work, family, and personal value, encouraging everyone on the path to financial freedom to continuously enhance their cognition, maintain a positive mindset, pay attention to family and social responsibilities, and ultimately give back to society.</p>

  



<div
  
    class="flex px-4 py-3 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900"
  >

  <span
    
      class="text-primary-400 ltr:pr-3 rtl:pl-3 flex items-center"
    >

    

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M506.3 417l-213.3-364c-16.33-28-57.54-28-73.98 0l-213.2 364C-10.59 444.9 9.849 480 42.74 480h426.6C502.1 480 522.6 445 506.3 417zM232 168c0-13.25 10.75-24 24-24S280 154.8 280 168v128c0 13.25-10.75 24-23.1 24S232 309.3 232 296V168zM256 416c-17.36 0-31.44-14.08-31.44-31.44c0-17.36 14.07-31.44 31.44-31.44s31.44 14.08 31.44 31.44C287.4 401.9 273.4 416 256 416z"/></svg>

  </span>


  </span>

  <span
    
      class="dark:text-neutral-300"
    ><strong>Disclaimer:</strong> This article is for personal study notes only and does not constitute any investment advice.</span>
</div>

]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>00494 Leveraging Debt for Wealth: A New Approach to Retirement Planning; Unlocking Family Assets: Combining Equity-Release Mortgages with Index Funds</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1733617616782/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1733617616782/</guid><description>In this session, James discusses the utilization of revolving line of credit home loans, investment philosophy, how to overcome the psychological pressure brought on by market fluctuations, and how to extract wisdom from life experiences. He emphasizes the importance of long-term and value investing, reiterating the investment philosophy of &amp;#39;buy when you have money, never sell.&amp;#39; He also addresses questions from students regarding leveraged funds, price-to-earnings ratios, and newly issued ETFs.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<lite-youtube videoid="g4KoDgPDNjs" playlabel="g4KoDgPDNjs" params=""></lite-youtube>



<h2 class="relative group">I. Main Topic 
    <div id="i-main-topic" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-main-topic" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This session revolves around investment and life wisdom. The core idea is to maintain a long-term perspective on investments, avoid being influenced by short-term market fluctuations, and continuously learn from life experiences to form one&rsquo;s own investment philosophy and life wisdom.  Just like life, investment also requires continuous learning and reflection.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">II. Presentation Content 
    <div id="ii-presentation-content" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii-presentation-content" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Utilizing Revolving Line of Credit Home Loans 
    <div id="utilizing-revolving-line-of-credit-home-loans" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#utilizing-revolving-line-of-credit-home-loans" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>People nearing retirement can consider using a revolving line of credit home loan (HELOC), treating the credit line as a part of their cash reserves for living expenses without touching the principal investment, thereby increasing overall asset returns.  For example, if someone has $40 million in retirement funds and obtains a $10 million HELOC, the total assets become $50 million, and the annual disposable funds increase from $800,000 to $1 million.</li>
<li>The HELOC credit line can supplement the 20% cash portion of asset allocation.</li>
<li>Note: It&rsquo;s easier to obtain a HELOC before retirement; it becomes more difficult afterward. The loan term typically doesn&rsquo;t exceed age 90.</li>
<li>It&rsquo;s not recommended to take out a loan after retirement to repay the HELOC.</li>
<li>A listener shared a strategy of using a HELOC for living expenses, which James considers a good option.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Investment Philosophy and Market Analysis 
    <div id="investment-philosophy-and-market-analysis" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#investment-philosophy-and-market-analysis" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>The market, like life, requires a long-term perspective to see the big picture. Avoid being misled by short-term fluctuations.</li>
<li>In the age of AI, human development will accelerate, and the market will continue to rise. The next two to three decades will be a period of prosperity. QQQ might reach $500,000.</li>
<li>Focus on long-term trends in investing. Don&rsquo;t be swayed by short-term market analysts or news.  Focus on long-term growth, not short-term gains.</li>
<li>If you can&rsquo;t withstand a 50% loss, it&rsquo;s not recommended to enter the market.</li>
<li>Invest in Nasdaq 100 index funds (QQQ), unless retirement funds are insufficient.</li>
<li>Short-term declines are inevitable. Be mentally prepared and maintain sufficient cash reserves.</li>
<li>Reiterates the long-term investment strategy of &ldquo;buy when you have money, never sell,&rdquo; and recommends single lump-sum market price purchases.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Extracting Life Wisdom 
    <div id="extracting-life-wisdom" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#extracting-life-wisdom" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Strive for daily progress, reflect and summarize regularly (daily, monthly, yearly). Extract life philosophy from experiences and store them in your personal &ldquo;database&rdquo; to continuously accumulate wisdom.</li>
<li>Reflect on everything, from trivial matters (like growing tomatoes) to major social events, to form a comprehensive outlook on life and investment philosophy.</li>
<li>Learn from past experiences. Reflect on what you would do differently if given a second chance to improve yourself.</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">III. Q&amp;A Session 
    <div id="iii-qa-session" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii-qa-session" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Michael 
    <div id="michael" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#michael" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question 1: How to use the smart rebalancing strategy before retirement?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: As long as you hold leveraged funds, you can use the smart rebalancing strategy.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2: How to calculate the Beta value of a portfolio holding TQQQ, QQQ, and cash?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: Calculate the weighted average based on the proportion of each asset and its corresponding Beta value (cash is 0, QQQ is 1, TQQQ is 3). He reshared the calculation formula with the audience.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Louis Lu 
    <div id="louis-lu" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#louis-lu" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Expressed admiration for James&rsquo;s insights from a month prior regarding the possibility of Bitcoin becoming a reserve currency for the US dollar, noting that James&rsquo;s response aligned with Federal Reserve Chairman Powell&rsquo;s views.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Comment:  Expressed gratitude for the acknowledgment and mentioned that it&rsquo;s a fundamental concept in finance and monetary policy, covered in previous lessons.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Shu Fen 
    <div id="shu-fen" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#shu-fen" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing:  Shared her experience of investing most of her retirement funds in savings insurance a few years ago, resulting in much lower returns than expected. This year, she redeemed a portion of the funds and invested in QQQ, achieving better returns (13.68% in three months). However, with the current market reaching new highs, she&rsquo;s hesitant to invest further, finding it difficult to overcome the psychological barrier of &ldquo;buying with eyes closed.&rdquo;
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Comment: Courage comes from the subconscious and requires training.  Believe that the market will continue to rise and practice self-hypnosis to reinforce the &ldquo;buy when you have money&rdquo; concept. Used the example of QQQ potentially reaching $500,000 to illustrate that the current price is still very cheap.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Sen Lin 
    <div id="sen-lin" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#sen-lin" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question: What&rsquo;s the difference between 00662 and QQQ?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply:  Suggested referring to the relevant link, as this question has been answered multiple times to avoid redundant explanations.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Yi Wan 
    <div id="yi-wan" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#yi-wan" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Agreed with James&rsquo;s investment method but hesitated to share it with older or same-age individuals. Felt more comfortable sharing with younger people, such as encouraging students to start saving $50-$100 per month.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Comment: Sharing depends on缘分 (affinity/serendipity).  Sometimes our remedy is another&rsquo;s poison. Sharing can also have negative consequences.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Zai 
    <div id="zai" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#zai" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Responded to Shu Fen&rsquo;s question about lump-sum buying, suggesting buying in batches or on specific dates, such as birthdays, to overcome psychological barriers.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Comment: Investing requires reaching a state of belief.  Continuous self-hypnosis is needed.  &ldquo;Buy immediately at market price when you have money&rdquo; is the only truth, no further analysis needed.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Ai Na 
    <div id="ai-na" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ai-na" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: After following James&rsquo;s advice, she redeemed funds from savings insurance and invested in QQQ and QLD. However, due to insufficient trading frequency, she couldn&rsquo;t purchase QQQ 2D. Her current living expenses are primarily covered by alimony, and the cost of living in Taiwan is relatively low.</li>
<li>Question 1: Does she need to buy and sell repeatedly to meet the trading frequency requirement?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: Yes, she can make small, frequent trades to meet the brokerage&rsquo;s requirements.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2: Can she buy fractional shares in Taiwan?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: Yes, but it&rsquo;s recommended to buy whole shares first and use the remaining funds for fractional shares.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 3: How to calculate retirement fund needs?  Can she receive social security?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: Calculate retirement fund needs based on annual expenses. Alimony can be considered income, but it&rsquo;s recommended to claim social security (even if her ex-husband objects) and adjust the asset allocation ratio accordingly, as alimony is not a permanent income source. She needs to be prepared.  Also recommended switching from SWVXX to BOXX.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chen Feng 
    <div id="chen-feng" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chen-feng" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Shared his personal investment journey, starting from entering the stock market in 2021, experiencing the &ldquo;bruised and battered&rdquo; phase of short-term trading, to shifting to long-term investing after encountering James&rsquo;s channel. He also established a study group of nearly 300 people, experiencing the benefits of &ldquo;teaching and learning from each other.&rdquo; He shared how he introduced the investment philosophy to his sister with 30 years of stock market experience, emphasizing the importance of a gradual approach.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Comment: Affirmed PC&rsquo;s sharing, adding the principles of &ldquo;Buddha saves those who are destined&rdquo; and &ldquo;Sentient beings save the Buddha.&rdquo;  When sharing investment concepts with family, start with small amounts of capital, like planting seeds and nurturing them gradually.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Nai Xi 
    <div id="nai-xi" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#nai-xi" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Thanked James and her friend Yu Sheng for their help.  Shared experiences of learning and sharing investment concepts with friends and expressed gratitude for the study group.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Comment: Shared his early investment experience in 1990, being introduced to investing by his friend Frank, who patiently explained investment knowledge to him weekly, eventually igniting his passion for investing.  Emphasized the importance of mentors.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">IM 
    <div id="im" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#im" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Felt that James is cultivating logical thinking in students and shared experiences of communicating investment concepts with others.</li>
<li>Question 1: How did James achieve such a comprehensive understanding?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: Continuously review and summarize life experiences, extracting the essence, like refining an elixir.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2: How to communicate with people who believe &ldquo;the first $1 million is difficult&rdquo; and are hesitant to go all in?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: Guide them to think about how to achieve the first $1 million goal and the path to wealth.  Suggest small investments based on their risk tolerance, like planting seeds, to gradually cultivate investment confidence.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Hao Qing 
    <div id="hao-qing" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#hao-qing" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing 1: Discussed the psychological pressure of buying after a stock reaches new highs. Experienced investors feel more pressure due to having reference points, while newcomers are more receptive. Like buying discounted items in a supermarket, having the original price as a reference makes purchasing more appealing.</li>
<li>Sharing 2: Shared his views on two newly issued ETFs by Invesco (QBI and QQLV) and compared them to QQQ. QBI selects larger market cap stocks from QQQ, while QQLV selects stocks with lower volatility.</li>
<li>Question: What are James&rsquo;s views on these two new ETFs?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: Doesn&rsquo;t recommend investing in unfamiliar ETFs, even if they perform well.  Stick to investments within your circle of competence.  Used the analogy of marriage, advising to choose a partner you understand. Re-emphasized the importance of focusing on asset allocation and Beta adjustments rather than selecting new investment targets.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">IV. Key Takeaways 
    <div id="iv-key-takeaways" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv-key-takeaways" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>Buy immediately at market price when you have money.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>This is James&rsquo;s repeatedly emphasized investment philosophy, aiming to overcome investors&rsquo; psychological barriers and seize market opportunities.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Life shouldn&rsquo;t be lived in vain.  Continuously reflect, summarize, and extract wisdom from experiences.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>This is not just investment wisdom, but life wisdom.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Teaching and learning promote each other. Buddha saves sentient beings, and sentient beings save the Buddha.
&ndash; James, Chen Feng</p></blockquote>
<p>Both teachers and students can grow through the process of teaching and sharing.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The seed itself is not the problem, it&rsquo;s the soil.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>An analogy for the dissemination of investment philosophy. Even good ideas require the right environment to take root.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">V. Summary 
    <div id="v-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#v-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This session covered investment philosophy, financial management skills, and life wisdom.  James reiterated the importance of long-term and value investing and encouraged everyone to overcome the psychological pressure of market fluctuations, firmly implementing the &ldquo;buy when you have money, never sell&rdquo; strategy. He also reminded everyone to continuously learn and extract wisdom from life experiences to ultimately achieve financial freedom and fulfill life&rsquo;s value. He also encouraged listeners to find their own mentors, learn from each other, and grow together, just like his early experiences.</p>

  



<div
  
    class="flex px-4 py-3 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900"
  >

  <span
    
      class="text-primary-400 ltr:pr-3 rtl:pl-3 flex items-center"
    >

    

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M506.3 417l-213.3-364c-16.33-28-57.54-28-73.98 0l-213.2 364C-10.59 444.9 9.849 480 42.74 480h426.6C502.1 480 522.6 445 506.3 417zM232 168c0-13.25 10.75-24 24-24S280 154.8 280 168v128c0 13.25-10.75 24-23.1 24S232 309.3 232 296V168zM256 416c-17.36 0-31.44-14.08-31.44-31.44c0-17.36 14.07-31.44 31.44-31.44s31.44 14.08 31.44 31.44C287.4 401.9 273.4 416 256 416z"/></svg>

  </span>


  </span>

  <span
    
      class="dark:text-neutral-300"
    ><strong>Disclaimer:</strong> This article is for personal learning notes only and does not constitute any investment advice.</span>
</div>

]]></content:encoded></item></channel></rss>