<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Insurance on QQQ Investor</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/tags/insurance/</link><description>Recent content in Insurance on QQQ Investor</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jomonylw.github.io/en/tags/insurance/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>00496 Global Markets and the Tech Wave: How to Seize Opportunities for Wealth Growth Amidst Volatility. The Philosophy of Financial Freedom: From Personalized Investing to Exploring Life's Values</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1735482278058/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1735482278058/</guid><description>At the end of 2024, with market fluctuations, Teacher James shared his insights on the current economic situation, financial markets, and investment strategies. In addition, several students asked questions online, covering asset allocation, business operations, health and wellness, tax planning, stock leveraging, and other areas.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Part One
<lite-youtube videoid="9F1rAWjCGX8" playlabel="9F1rAWjCGX8" params=""></lite-youtube>
</p>
<p>Part Two
<lite-youtube videoid="oPb4m81Nv24" playlabel="oPb4m81Nv24" params=""></lite-youtube>
</p>


<h2 class="relative group">I. Main Topic of the Session 
    <div id="i-main-topic-of-the-session" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-main-topic-of-the-session" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>Investment mindset and strategy adjustments amidst year-end market volatility, along with comprehensive reflections on personal life and financial health.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">II. Presentation Content 
    <div id="ii-presentation-content" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii-presentation-content" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Market Volatility and Investment Mindset 
    <div id="market-volatility-and-investment-mindset" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#market-volatility-and-investment-mindset" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>The only constant in the market is volatility. Investors should ignore market fluctuations, international situations, market analysis, financial reports, and economic situations, and focus on long-term investment.</li>
<li>Disclaimer: The content of the COC investment and financial management channel is for educational purposes only and does not constitute investment advice. Investment involves high risks, and proper asset allocation is necessary.</li>
<li>Newcomers should watch the YouTube episode 00451 &ldquo;Investment Lecture Worth 100 Million&rdquo; and also find related content on Bilibili and podcasts.</li>
<li>Investing requires independent thinking. Do not blindly follow advice or join any groups to avoid being deceived.</li>
<li>The Nasdaq 100 index fund is recommended as the only focused fund, with others being supplementary.</li>
<li>The handout includes information on Nasdaq 100 index funds worldwide, including leveraged funds, and information on retirement accounts in various regions, with content continuously updated.</li>
<li>The &ldquo;Investment Lecture Worth 100 Million&rdquo; video is the most important. Investors should always be extremely optimistic; the market will eventually rise and reach new highs.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">UK and European Financial Information 
    <div id="uk-and-european-financial-information" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#uk-and-european-financial-information" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Showcasing information provided by a UK friend regarding UK investments, loans, retirement accounts, ETFs, and insurance companies, particularly information on 2x leveraged funds on the PEA website.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">US-China Trade War and Globalization 
    <div id="us-china-trade-war-and-globalization" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#us-china-trade-war-and-globalization" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Issues like the US-China trade war and tariffs do not affect technological advancements and the innovation of American companies, thus having little impact on index investing.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Risks and Returns of Leveraged Funds 
    <div id="risks-and-returns-of-leveraged-funds" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#risks-and-returns-of-leveraged-funds" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>The risk of a 2x leveraged fund is not simply double, and the return is not twice the annualized rate of return, but approximately 1.4 times.</li>
<li>The annualized return of QQQ over 20 years is 14%, while QLD&rsquo;s is 19.6%. QLD&rsquo;s total return over 20 years is 2.6 times that of QQQ, far exceeding double.</li>
<li>Combining leveraged funds with cash can reduce risk and increase returns.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Investment Wisdom and Market Essence 
    <div id="investment-wisdom-and-market-essence" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#investment-wisdom-and-market-essence" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>The market is always smarter than individual investors. Stock picking and timing the market are futile.</li>
<li>In a bull market, many &ldquo;gurus&rdquo; emerge, but they disappear when the market falls; this is a market norm.</li>
<li>Controlling the major stocks on Wall Street means controlling the world.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Investment Sharing and Personal Insights 
    <div id="investment-sharing-and-personal-insights" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#investment-sharing-and-personal-insights" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Investment sharers need to provide clear, diverse, and universally applicable investment methods and benefit from them.</li>
<li>Buffett&rsquo;s investment philosophy emphasizes long-term investment, perfecting the investment system.</li>
<li>Understanding the essence of finance, economics, accounting, and logic helps resist external interference and adhere to index investing.</li>
<li>Asset allocation is simplified into two types: 433 (conservative) and 442 (aggressive), pursuing safety rather than high returns, with cash being a safe asset.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Finance and Monetary Theory 
    <div id="finance-and-monetary-theory" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#finance-and-monetary-theory" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>The foundation of capitalism is currency. Understanding monetary theory is crucial to understanding finance, investment, and the economy.</li>
<li>The status of the US dollar as the world&rsquo;s reserve currency determines the subordinate status of other countries, especially those holding large amounts of US dollar foreign exchange reserves.</li>
<li>China and other emerging countries are trying to break away from their dependence on the US dollar to escape US control.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Life&rsquo;s Meaning and Happiness 
    <div id="lifes-meaning-and-happiness" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#lifes-meaning-and-happiness" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>The happiest thing in life is giving. Happiness is a human right. Sharing and giving energy on a spiritual level can bring more happiness than material things.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Extremes of Capitalism and Social Issues 
    <div id="extremes-of-capitalism-and-social-issues" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#extremes-of-capitalism-and-social-issues" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Capitalism will lead to an expansion of the wealth gap. The development of robots will make spiritual education even more important.</li>
<li>Systemic discrimination exists in society, leading to a vicious cycle of poverty. Our goal is to help eliminate poverty as much as possible.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">US Accounting System and Social Phenomena 
    <div id="us-accounting-system-and-social-phenomena" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#us-accounting-system-and-social-phenomena" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>The US accounting system is very complete. Phenomena like &ldquo;zero-dollar shopping&rdquo; are the result of accounting costs and leftist thinking, and there is no need to over-interpret them.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Wealth and Government Relations 
    <div id="wealth-and-government-relations" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#wealth-and-government-relations" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Wealthy individuals escape government control by paying taxes, while the poor are trapped.</li>
<li>Legitimate tax avoidance is an important topic.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Personalization of Diet and Asset Allocation 
    <div id="personalization-of-diet-and-asset-allocation" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#personalization-of-diet-and-asset-allocation" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Both diet and asset allocation should be customized according to individual circumstances and cannot be generalized.</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">III. Q&amp;A Session 
    <div id="iii-qa-session" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii-qa-session" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Zhang Yong 
    <div id="zhang-yong" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#zhang-yong" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing</strong>: The chaos in the domestic insurance industry, where banks lure customers into buying insurance with high commissions, is even linked to the performance evaluations of customer managers. Many customers do not understand investments and choose low-yield or even risky insurance products to preserve their capital. He also shared a case of a friend who was defrauded of over 1.7 million in a romance scam, illustrating the complexity of the domestic financial environment.
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s comment</strong>: The US financial system strictly separates life insurance from other financial businesses, and there is no such thing as banks selling insurance. The financial supervision in China and Taiwan is problematic. Banks should focus on deposit and loan business and should not be involved in insurance and investment. This chaos will ultimately harm the interests of emerging countries.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question</strong>: Does Teacher James share content each week based on reflections on the same theme, or does he summarize viewpoints from reading many books?
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s reply</strong>: In addition to reading a lot of books, more importantly, independent thinking and critical thinking are involved. The formation of monetary theory stems from thinking about the nature of capitalism, and the content of the handouts mostly comes from students&rsquo; questions and his own reflections. This information is endless. To be an excellent sharer, one needs to have basic knowledge, thinking ability, and originality.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Xiao Cai 
    <div id="xiao-cai" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#xiao-cai" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing 1</strong>: Took over the family food business ten years ago when the company&rsquo;s assets and liabilities were zero. After ten years of operation, the company turned a profit, and its current value (including real estate) is about 300 million NTD. Over the past decade, he distributed about 200 million NTD of revenue to his family, retaining 100 million NTD for loan purposes. Currently, he has invested 80 million in 00662 (a 2x leveraged Nasdaq 100 index ETF) and 20 million in 00631L (Taiwan&rsquo;s 50 Positive 2 ETF).
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s comment</strong>: None</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question 1</strong>: The bank will allocate a loan of 60 million NTD on January 1st. Should this fund be used to buy 00662 all at once, or should he wait for a 20% market drop before buying? Also, if the market crashes and 00662 and 00631L go to zero, how will he deal with it?
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s reply</strong>: If the market goes to zero, the company can still make loan payments. The worst-case scenario is that the land is auctioned off, and he can still get tens of millions. Since the worst has been considered, how to buy the 60 million is not important. If it were me, I would buy it all on Monday. If you choose to wait for a 20% drop before buying, you can follow your plan and inform everyone when you buy.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question 2</strong>: How to maintain good health?
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s reply</strong>: Regular comprehensive physical examinations are necessary. I have been doing annual check-ups since my thirties. Wellness, like asset allocation, needs to be personalized. The advice I can give everyone now is to eat well, sleep well, and don&rsquo;t worry. What to eat specifically, what exercises to do, etc., need to be decided according to personal circumstances and cannot be given a unified recommendation.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question 3</strong>: What are your views on Taiwan&rsquo;s politics and how to support political parties?
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s reply</strong>: Regarding politics and religious beliefs, everyone has different positions and viewpoints. Discussing these issues in the classroom is meaningless and fruitless. It is recommended that students do not discuss these topics in the classroom and keep their opinions to themselves.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question 4</strong>: How to preserve assets in response to potential cross-strait issues? He currently has about 200 million NTD in assets in Taiwan and a house worth 8 million in Vietnam. How should he allocate his assets?
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s reply</strong>: If you can&rsquo;t sleep due to worries about cross-strait issues, it&rsquo;s recommended to immigrate as soon as possible. If you choose to stay in Taiwan, you need to make some decisions, such as whether to close the company. If the 40 employees are causing you distress, consider closing the company and compensating them. Life decisions should be decisive, not prolonged. Be responsible for your own happiness.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Additional question</strong>: How to get rid of the shackles of the family business?
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s reply</strong>: You have managed the company very well. The choice is your life. Do whatever makes you happy. If the family business makes you unhappy, shut it down and give the employees a good severance package. Consider your own life, not your father&rsquo;s. If your father&rsquo;s business is no longer your concern, and it&rsquo;s not bringing you happiness, then let it go.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Repeated emphasis</strong>: Believes that apart from investment and financial management, health is the most important asset in life, and cited the example of &ldquo;Yu (Yuan) Lingqi&rdquo; to emphasize the importance of regular health check-ups, hoping the channel will pay more attention to health issues.
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s reply</strong>: Health is very important. Everyone&rsquo;s health condition is different, and it is impossible to provide a unified recommendation. Everyone needs to pay attention to and manage their health according to their own situation.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Lare 
    <div id="lare" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#lare" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Question</strong>: Based in Canada, unable to leverage stocks. If income decreases in a certain year, and the tax rate drops from 32% to 24%, is it worth selling some stocks to increase income to the 32% tax bracket to improve the future cost basis?
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s reply</strong>: It is not recommended to sell stocks because selling incurs taxes. Canada&rsquo;s tax system is very unfavorable for stock investments. When immigrating, consider future generations and choose countries with development prospects. In Canada, you can consider using an IB account for loans, but this will face inheritance tax issues, possibly up to 40%. Therefore, when planning estates, minimize assets in IB accounts. In the long run, trusts can be used to avoid taxes. It is currently not recommended to sell stocks for short-term tax benefits. Consider selling after retirement when income is lower.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Additional explanation</strong>: IB accounts have a low financing ratio for Canadian stocks, only up to 50%.
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s addition</strong>: You can borrow 40% first, and add more if needed. But ultimately, there will still be inheritance tax issues.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Terry 
    <div id="terry" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#terry" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Question 1</strong>: How to transfer taxable accounts or retirement accounts to tax-free accounts, such as Roth IRA? What are the specific steps?
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s reply</strong>: If it&rsquo;s within the same brokerage, such as Charles Schwab, you can fill out a form online directly. If it&rsquo;s at different brokerages, you need to contact the brokerage to obtain and fill out a form. For specific steps, you can refer to the previously released video &ldquo;Investment and Financial Management Tips 26: How to Transfer from a Traditional Taxable Account to a Roth IRA Online at 722.&rdquo;</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question 2</strong>: What is your view on Crypto, and will QQQ include Crypto companies in the future?
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s reply</strong>: I don&rsquo;t know much about Crypto and am not sure if it will exist forever, so I won&rsquo;t answer.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">IM 
    <div id="im" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#im" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing</strong>: Through learning, I realized that my investment was too risky, and emergency funds should not all be invested in QQQ. Now I have withdrawn 36 months of emergency funds back to the Money Market Fund. When starting with small funds, one should focus on their main job and increase income sources. After investing in index funds, my mindset changed, and I began to focus on the importance of timing. Therefore, I started to focus on diet, fitness, and learning from the experiences of long-lived people around me. In addition, I learned from investing to avoid risks, such as giving up dangerous activities like diving.
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s comment</strong>: It is wise to learn from the experiences of others. Being overly aggressive is human nature, but it is important to realize and correct it in time. It is wrong to increase positions when the market is rising and to be fearful when it is falling. It should be the other way around. Emergency funds should not be added to.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question</strong>: How to judge whether you are being too adventurous? For example, increasing the leverage ratio of asset allocation from 1.0 to 1.8 when stocks are rising.
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s reply</strong>: This is also a necessary evil. Now that you realize it&rsquo;s not right, you can start to retreat, or when it rises, you buy in, and when it falls, you get scared. Oh, what to do? Then start to retreat. Once you have learned, don&rsquo;t do it again. So, as Buffett said, when others are greedy, you should be fearful, and when others are fearful, you should be greedy. That&rsquo;s the right pace. So, when you want to increase your position in the future, it should be when others are fearful. That&rsquo;s how I do it. This emergency fund should not be increased. Regardless of whether the market is rising or falling, you should not add to this cervical spine disease. How could you add to it? This is not allowed. Then, if you use our asset allocation, when the market falls, you automatically buy in for one year, and when the market rises, you automatically withdraw from the leveraged fund. This is passive, and this has already achieved the practice of being greedy when others are fearful and being fearful when others are greedy.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Patty 
    <div id="patty" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#patty" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Question</strong>: The relationship between the asset-backed ratio and cash reserves. If asset-backed financing is carried out, how to ensure that the cash on hand is greater than the pledged amount? For example, with assets of 1 million, allocated according to the 721 ratio, 200,000 is pledged, but 100,000 in cash cannot be moved. Is it necessary to balance for one or two years to accumulate 200,000 in cash before making a pledge?
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s reply</strong>: You cannot borrow 200,000 all at once; you can only borrow 2% per year. When conducting asset-backed financing, the asset allocation should be 433, not 721. Borrow 2% each year and conduct &ldquo;smart rebalancing.&rdquo; Even if the market falls, you will not be forced to liquidate. The cash ratio may be lower than the loan ratio in extreme cases (such as a continuous 10-year decline), but since the total asset value is still greater than the debt, there will be no problem.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Mike 
    <div id="mike" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#mike" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing</strong>: A friend&rsquo;s experience. The friend took over his father&rsquo;s family business and eventually had health problems due to overwork. He later sold the company for over 600 million and invested the funds in QQQ. He is now very happy.
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s comment</strong>: None</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question 1</strong>: Regarding 401k and RMD. Previously, company stock was placed in a 401k, and now it has a high value, facing the RMD issue. After Trump takes office, is it possible to abolish RMD and change it to a 15% capital gains tax?
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s reply</strong>: This possibility is extremely slim. The government is unlikely to give up the tax revenue brought by RMD.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question 2</strong>: Regarding the Debt to Equity Ratio of companies. It is found that there are large differences in the debt-to-equity ratios of Buffett and many technology companies. Is this related to the nature of the industry? For example, the debt-to-equity ratio of software companies is usually low, while that of hardware companies like Apple is high. So, for individuals, is it a healthy level to control the debt-to-equity ratio at 0.2?
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s reply</strong>: The higher the debt-to-equity ratio, the higher the ROE usually is, but this needs to be based on healthy debt. Healthy debt refers to debt that can be repaid through its own operating activities, such as credit, stock-backed loans (under safe circumstances), and mortgages (that can be repaid). Apple&rsquo;s debt-to-equity ratio is high because it borrows a lot of money to pay dividends and places assets overseas. In addition, it has a large amount of accounts payable. Therefore, it cannot be simply considered that a high debt-to-equity ratio is bad. It is necessary to analyze the nature and safety of the debt specifically.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question 3</strong>: What are your thoughts on the Jetson Orin product launched by Nvidia? This product is mainly for the personal AI market, is cheap, can use ChatGPT to generate code, and runs locally, thereby creating your own AI database.
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s reply</strong>: I don&rsquo;t know much about this product. Our AI is mainly trained using ChatGPT as a personal assistant. Currently, I don&rsquo;t use other devices for personal AI.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">IV. Highlighted Quotes 
    <div id="iv-highlighted-quotes" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv-highlighted-quotes" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>The only constant in the market is volatility.
&ndash; Teacher James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This viewpoint emphasizes the normality of market fluctuations. Investors should be mentally prepared and not be affected by short-term market fluctuations.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Investing requires independent thinking. Do not blindly follow advice or join any groups to avoid being deceived.
&ndash; Teacher James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This viewpoint emphasizes the importance of independent thinking in investing. Investors should make investment decisions based on their own judgment rather than blindly following others&rsquo; opinions or joining unreliable investment groups.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The happiest thing in life is giving. Happiness is a human right. Sharing and giving energy on a spiritual level can bring more happiness than material things.
&ndash; Teacher James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This viewpoint emphasizes that spiritual pursuits are more important than material ones. Giving and sharing can bring greater happiness.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>If you, as a commercial bank, do lending well, then focus on lending. Deposits are 2%. Then your lending is 3.5%, 4%. You just make that 2% difference. This is what a commercial bank should do. Commerce should not touch insurance.
&ndash; Teacher James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This viewpoint points out that commercial banks should focus on deposit and loan business instead of being involved in areas like insurance, which not only violates financial regulations but also harms the interests of customers.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Happiness is a human right. If you are alive, you should be happy. If you live so miserably, why bother?
&ndash; Teacher James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This viewpoint reminds everyone to pursue happiness and not sacrifice their happiness for money or other goals.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Impotence is also a kind of strength because accepting one&rsquo;s own impotence and acknowledging one&rsquo;s own impotence is also a kind of strength.
&ndash; Teacher James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This viewpoint expresses a broad-minded attitude towards life. Acknowledging one&rsquo;s limitations is not a bad thing; instead, it can make one more relaxed.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The truly wealthy are those who foresee a future eternally disconnected from government oversight, swiftly settling their dues to escape the clutches of authority.
&ndash; Teacher James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This perspective highlights how affluent individuals utilize legitimate tax avoidance strategies to minimize governmental control over their wealth.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Learning from the experiences of others is a wise approach.
&ndash; IM</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This viewpoint emphasizes the importance of learning and drawing lessons from others&rsquo; experiences, which can help us avoid making the same mistakes.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>When others are greedy, you should be fearful; when others are fearful, you should be greedy.
&ndash; Teacher James, quoting Buffett</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This is a very important principle in investing, namely, contrarian thinking, staying calm when the market is frenzied and looking for opportunities when the market is panicking.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Just be happy. There&rsquo;s nothing to it, nothing to fight for, no particular meaning, nothing that grand or great.
&ndash; Teacher James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This viewpoint expresses a detached attitude towards life. Don&rsquo;t put too much pressure on yourself; learn to enjoy life.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Don&rsquo;t wait until it&rsquo;s too late, leaving no time for regrets.
&ndash; Teacher James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Drawing on investment principles, this perspective underscores the importance of early health screenings, urging not to wait until problems arise before regretting, echoing Xiao Cai&rsquo;s shared viewpoint.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>We investors are always extremely optimistic. Market fluctuations should be ignored. The market will eventually rise and always reach new highs.
&ndash; Teacher James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This viewpoint emphasizes the optimistic attitude towards the long-term trend of the market and the neglect of short-term fluctuations, demonstrating the proper mindset for long-term investors.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">V. Summary 
    <div id="v-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#v-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>The content of this episode of the investment and financial management channel is rich. Teacher James not only shared his views on the current market and investment strategies but also answered the practical questions of many students, involving asset allocation, business operations, health and wellness, tax planning, and other aspects. In addition, he also emphasized the importance of happiness and health, as well as investment concepts such as independent thinking, long-term investment, and reasonable tax avoidance. In summary, the content of this episode provides valuable guidance and inspiration for investors, helping everyone make wise decisions in a complex market environment and have a healthier and happier life.</p>

  



<div
  
    class="flex px-4 py-3 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900"
  >

  <span
    
      class="text-primary-400 ltr:pr-3 rtl:pl-3 flex items-center"
    >

    

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M506.3 417l-213.3-364c-16.33-28-57.54-28-73.98 0l-213.2 364C-10.59 444.9 9.849 480 42.74 480h426.6C502.1 480 522.6 445 506.3 417zM232 168c0-13.25 10.75-24 24-24S280 154.8 280 168v128c0 13.25-10.75 24-23.1 24S232 309.3 232 296V168zM256 416c-17.36 0-31.44-14.08-31.44-31.44c0-17.36 14.07-31.44 31.44-31.44s31.44 14.08 31.44 31.44C287.4 401.9 273.4 416 256 416z"/></svg>

  </span>


  </span>

  <span
    
      class="dark:text-neutral-300"
    ><strong>Disclaimer:</strong> This article is only a personal study note and does not constitute any investment advice.</span>
</div>

]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>00493 Financial Risks and Investment Wisdom: How to Accumulate and Utilize Assets; Stock Pledge and Asset Allocation: Smart Choices for Risk Reduction</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1733026874385/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1733026874385/</guid><description>In this episode, James reiterates the current market highs and advises investors to remain patient, adhere to long-term investment strategies, and avoid being swayed by short-term fluctuations. He also addresses questions from students regarding asset allocation, stock pledging, insurance, annuities, children&amp;#39;s education, and how to cope with market volatility, sharing his understanding of Modern Monetary Theory (MMT).</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<lite-youtube videoid="V0d8y8-Jl-w" playlabel="V0d8y8-Jl-w" params=""></lite-youtube>



<h2 class="relative group">I. Main Topic 
    <div id="i-main-topic" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-main-topic" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>The market continues to reach new highs.  Investing doesn&rsquo;t require constant attention; the key is to stick to a long-term investment strategy, maintain a well-diversified asset allocation, and remain patient. The real risk isn&rsquo;t short-term volatility, but the inability to accumulate sufficient wealth over the long term, and not knowing how to utilize accumulated wealth effectively.  Furthermore, it&rsquo;s crucial to be wary of various financial traps and maintain rational investment practices.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">II. Briefing Content 
    <div id="ii-briefing-content" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii-briefing-content" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Market Trends and Investment Strategies 
    <div id="market-trends-and-investment-strategies" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#market-trends-and-investment-strategies" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>The market is at a new high. Don&rsquo;t waste time over-analyzing; stick to long-term investing, buy and hold.  The market generally trends upwards; instead of predicting pullbacks, enter the market early.</li>
<li>Investing doesn&rsquo;t require excessive time. After placing your order, step away and let time work its magic through compounding.</li>
<li>Be wary of scams. Don&rsquo;t trust any investment advice that guarantees stable returns or daily gains.  Be extremely cautious of &ldquo;guaranteed profit&rdquo; schemes.</li>
<li>Ignore the advice of financial advisors and insurance agents. They rarely have the investor&rsquo;s best interests at heart and are often motivated by their own profits. Many financial products are designed to benefit the seller, not the investor.</li>
<li>Investing isn&rsquo;t simple. Even asset allocation within a Nasdaq 100 index fund requires in-depth research and adjustments based on individual circumstances.</li>
<li>Investors should always remain optimistic. The market will eventually rise. Patiently await wealth accumulation. Time is an investor&rsquo;s friend.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Risk Management and Wealth Goals 
    <div id="risk-management-and-wealth-goals" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#risk-management-and-wealth-goals" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>The biggest risks are not market fluctuations, but the failure to accumulate sufficient wealth over the long term and not knowing how to utilize accumulated wealth effectively. The ultimate goal of investing is to achieve financial freedom and enjoy life.</li>
<li>Avoid the instinctive reaction to short-term losses. Overcome fear and don&rsquo;t panic sell. Market downturns are normal and present buying opportunities.</li>
<li>View bear markets as opportunities. Buying low translates to higher future returns. Learn to think contrarily and utilize market fluctuations for mindless rebalancing.</li>
<li>The investment objective is to mitigate the risk of financial hardship, not to maximize returns. A sound investment strategy is more crucial than chasing high returns.</li>
<li>Choose a simple, low-cost, passive index investment strategy, such as a Nasdaq 100 index fund, and hold a portion in cash to maintain psychological balance and cope with market volatility.</li>
<li>Holding safe assets (like certificates of deposit and money market funds) can mitigate short-term risks, stabilize emotions during market fluctuations, and provide a sense of security.</li>
<li>The proportion of safe assets held should be adjusted based on age and risk tolerance. Retirees are advised to hold cash equivalent to 5 years of living expenses, while those yet to retire can hold more.</li>
<li>Young people should prioritize term life insurance to protect their families and avoid other types of insurance to prevent being misled by insurance companies.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Other Advice 
    <div id="other-advice" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#other-advice" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Be skeptical of all information, especially regarding money. Learn to think independently and don&rsquo;t blindly trust so-called &ldquo;experts.&rdquo;</li>
<li>Don&rsquo;t buy insurance or annuities for investment purposes. The essence of insurance is protection, not investment; annuities have high fees and low returns.</li>
<li>Don&rsquo;t disclose your wealth to your children. Encourage them to strive independently and create wealth through their own abilities.</li>
<li>Engage in rational discussions, view investments with a mathematical mindset, and analyze investment results with data.</li>
<li>Avoid over-investing in real estate. Maintain ample cash flow. Real estate has poor liquidity and is difficult to liquidate.</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">III. Q&amp;A Session 
    <div id="iii-qa-session" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii-qa-session" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Ke An 
    <div id="ke-an" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ke-an" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: 16 years old, living in the Netherlands.  Thanked James for his investment methods, which allowed her parents to take her on trips throughout Europe. She also shared that she finds her business management classes easier to understand than her classmates, thanks to James&rsquo;s teachings.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s comments: Praised Ke An&rsquo;s travel experiences and learning attitude, encouraging her to continue learning and explore her career interests.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question: Concerned about starting investing late, wants to open an account and start investing soon. Has saved NT$200,000 and plans to invest in 00662.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s reply: Affirmed the advantage of starting to invest at 16, emphasizing that time is the greatest asset.  Advised her to balance learning, life, and investment, and to enjoy her youth.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Ji Ya 
    <div id="ji-ya" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ji-ya" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question: Has savings equivalent to 8 years of living expenses. Working 40 hours a week only covers expenses. Driving for Uber could increase income but wants more free time. Unsure how to balance work and life and whether early retirement is possible. Is currently 42 years old.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s reply: In 15 years, the 8x annual expenses will grow to 50x due to compounding, enabling retirement. Suggested a BETA of 1.2 to increase investment returns, or driving for Uber a few hours a week to accelerate wealth accumulation and achieve early retirement.  Emphasized that pursuing early retirement shouldn&rsquo;t be the sole focus and that finding a balance between work and life is important. Health is paramount.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chun Xia 
    <div id="chun-xia" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chun-xia" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question 1: Plans to invest a loan of NT$7 million and aims for a return of NT$20-30 million within 10-15 years. Should the investment be lump-sum or staggered?  Has additional monthly income of NT$30,000-40,000.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s reply: Based on a 14% annualized return, there will be NT$67 million after 15 years, reaching the NT$20-30 million target within 10 years. Recommended a lump-sum investment to capitalize on market growth.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2: Wants to share investment philosophy with family in China.  Inquired about account opening procedures and trading software options in China.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s reply: Suggested Chun Xia email him for an introduction to a leader familiar with the Chinese market who can provide specific guidance on account opening and software selection.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Peter 
    <div id="peter" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#peter" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question: How to persuade family members to invest? They&rsquo;ve heard the advice but haven&rsquo;t acted, finding it difficult.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s reply: Acknowledged the &ldquo;familiarity bias&rdquo; that makes it difficult for family members to accept advice. Suggested Peter lead by example, sharing his investment philosophy and success stories. Encourage them to start with a small investment, like $100,000 in QQQ, and offer to cover any losses to build their confidence. He particularly recommended starting with retirement accounts and broad market index funds.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Ling 
    <div id="ling" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ling" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question:  Regarding children&rsquo;s education fund investment plan. Initially planned to invest all children&rsquo;s allowances in 00662 with monthly contributions, but has doubts after hearing James&rsquo;s lessons on children&rsquo;s education.  Should the plan be adjusted?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s reply: Advised prioritizing personal wealth accumulation and achieving financial freedom before focusing on children&rsquo;s education funds. Suggested redirecting the monthly contributions to personal investments to accelerate wealth growth.  Income like Lunar New Year red envelopes can continue to be invested for the children.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Dennis 
    <div id="dennis" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#dennis" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing 1: An insurance agent passed away due to financial problems, highlighting the importance of risk management, even for insurance professionals.</li>
<li>Sharing 2: Family recommended a video by an MIT professor about national debt, who argued that national debt is another form of taxation.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s reply: Explained Modern Monetary Theory (MMT).  U.S. national debt represents savings held by the public. The U.S. government&rsquo;s debt is repaid by Americans. The value of the dollar lies in its credit and the goods and services it can buy, not the level of debt. The government can stimulate the economy by issuing national debt without worrying about excessive debt.  Issuing national debt and lottery tickets are essentially providing investment channels, not just taxation.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Sharing 3: Wants to learn more about MMT.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s reply: Recommended Dennis search for books and materials on &ldquo;Modern Monetary Theory&rdquo; for a deeper understanding of its principles and applications.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Hao Xin 
    <div id="hao-xin" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#hao-xin" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question:  Are the P/E ratios of QQQ and SPY overvalued? How to deal with market fluctuations? Concerned that a prolonged stagnant market will cause borrowing interest to exceed cash reserves.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s reply: P/E ratios are unreliable and unpredictable. Recommended passive rebalancing.  Cash reserves will increase as the market rises; reinvest during downturns. Suggested simulating the 2000-2009 market scenario to test the robustness of the asset allocation strategy. If the market does stagnate for a long time, adjust lifestyle, reduce expenses, or consider other income sources. In the long run, the market will always go up; maintain confidence.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Sharing: Received a suspected scam call where the caller claimed to be from the bank and requested personal information verification.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s comments:  Commended Hao Xin&rsquo;s vigilance and reminded everyone to be cautious of calls requesting personal information to avoid being scammed.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">IV. Key Takeaways 
    <div id="iv-key-takeaways" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv-key-takeaways" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;The first investment earns the most; that performance can never be replicated.&rdquo;
&ndash; Monica</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Monica&rsquo;s statement highlights the importance of early investment and the difficulty of timing the market. Early investments enjoy higher returns, and over time, even with the same investment strategy, it&rsquo;s hard to replicate those early gains.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;The U.S. government&rsquo;s debt is the public&rsquo;s savings.&rdquo;
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This perspective challenges the traditional understanding of national debt, emphasizing the unique nature of U.S. Treasury bonds.  U.S. national debt represents dollar-denominated assets held by U.S. citizens and global investors, reflecting confidence in the American economy.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;Survival is key, not maximizing returns.&rdquo;
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This statement pinpoints the core goal of investing, reminding investors not to be tempted by high returns at the expense of risk management. Preserving capital is more important than chasing high returns during market fluctuations.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;Time is an investor&rsquo;s friend.&rdquo;
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Only long-term investments can fully benefit from the power of compounding. Time is an investor&rsquo;s best ally.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">V. Summary 
    <div id="v-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#v-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>In this episode, James once again emphasized the importance of long-term investing and risk management, offering personalized advice tailored to each student&rsquo;s circumstances. His clear explanations helped students better understand market trends, investment strategies, and the essence of wealth management. He also shared his understanding of Modern Monetary Theory (MMT) and awareness of various financial traps, reminding investors to remain rational and avoid blindly chasing high returns.</p>

  



<div
  
    class="flex px-4 py-3 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900"
  >

  <span
    
      class="text-primary-400 ltr:pr-3 rtl:pl-3 flex items-center"
    >

    

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M506.3 417l-213.3-364c-16.33-28-57.54-28-73.98 0l-213.2 364C-10.59 444.9 9.849 480 42.74 480h426.6C502.1 480 522.6 445 506.3 417zM232 168c0-13.25 10.75-24 24-24S280 154.8 280 168v128c0 13.25-10.75 24-23.1 24S232 309.3 232 296V168zM256 416c-17.36 0-31.44-14.08-31.44-31.44c0-17.36 14.07-31.44 31.44-31.44s31.44 14.08 31.44 31.44C287.4 401.9 273.4 416 256 416z"/></svg>

  </span>


  </span>

  <span
    
      class="dark:text-neutral-300"
    ><strong>Disclaimer:</strong> This article is for personal learning notes only and does not constitute any investment advice.</span>
</div>

]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>00480 Is investing in Index Fund guaranteed to be profitable? How can one consistently make profits in the market?</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1728203545381/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1728203545381/</guid><description>This session focuses on investment cycles, covering how to identify market cycles, emphasizing the challenge of differentiating between premature and incorrect judgments, and illustrating with Buffett&amp;#39;s actions during the 2008 financial crisis. It also touches upon risks associated with real estate investment, insurance choices, stock pledges, and asset allocation strategies, particularly comparing and offering advice for the Taiwanese and US markets. In the Q&amp;amp;A section, students raised questions and shared insights on topics such as the aircraft carrier investment strategy, property tax, central bank policy, currency devaluation, and James addressed each one in detail.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Part 1:
<lite-youtube videoid="ztdWeAncmqY" playlabel="ztdWeAncmqY" params=""></lite-youtube>
</li>
<li>Part 2:
<lite-youtube videoid="Xvv1cCV3dHA" playlabel="Xvv1cCV3dHA" params=""></lite-youtube>
</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">I. Main Topic 
    <div id="i-main-topic" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-main-topic" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This session centered around investment cycles, exploring how to assess market cycles, highlighting the difficulty in distinguishing between acting too early and making wrong judgments during cycle shifts. It used Buffett&rsquo;s actions during the 2008 financial crisis as a case study. Additionally, it discussed risks related to real estate investment, insurance, and stock pledges, while providing an in-depth analysis of asset allocation strategies, particularly comparing and recommending approaches for the Taiwanese and US markets.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">II.  Briefing Content 
    <div id="ii--briefing-content" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii--briefing-content" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<ol>
<li>
<p><strong>Investment Cycles</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Investor sentiment is likened to a pendulum, swinging between extreme fear and extreme optimism.</li>
<li>Differentiating between premature judgments and incorrect ones during cycle changes is challenging, as exemplified by Buffett&rsquo;s public announcement of buying stocks in late 2008, followed by a further 30% market decline.</li>
<li>Swing trading is no longer recommended, as the market perpetually rises, making long-term investment the key.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Risks of Real Estate Investment</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Real estate investment is considered high-risk, requiring maintenance and incurring high holding costs like property taxes and HOA fees.</li>
<li>US property tax is a holding tax; the longer you hold, the more tax you pay.</li>
<li>Rental yields are low, around 2% in the US Bay Area after deducting expenses.</li>
<li>The biggest risks of buying a house are job loss and having outstanding mortgage debt at retirement.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Insurance Choices</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Avoid commercial insurance, such as life insurance, long-term care insurance, universal life insurance, etc.</li>
<li>Necessary insurance includes health insurance and term life insurance. Term life insurance is suitable for those who are the sole income source for their family, providing support for children under 18.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Risks of Stock Pledging</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Stock pledging is extremely risky, especially in the Taiwanese market, with a maintenance ratio requirement of 167%.</li>
<li>Absolutely forbid using borrowed funds from stock pledges for reinvestment.</li>
<li>In Taiwan, leveraged ETFs can be pledged, but risks still exist.</li>
<li>Be cautious about diversifying risks in stock pledging in Taiwan. Do not pledge all assets to the same financial institution, and avoid pledging everything at once.</li>
<li>Taiwanese investors are advised to adopt the &ldquo;Situation 3&rdquo; asset allocation strategy: 30% cash, 30% leverage, and 40% QQQ or other broad-based index funds.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Asset Allocation Strategies</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>When selecting investment targets, understand their risk and return characteristics, and allocate assets reasonably based on your circumstances.</li>
<li>Long-term investment in QQQ index funds is like piloting an aircraft carrierstable and offering considerable returns.</li>
<li>Investing in individual stocks and sectors is like sailing a small boathigh risk and susceptible to market fluctuations.</li>
<li>Investments in individual stocks and sectors are similar to the once-booming railway industry, which was eventually replaced by new technologies and industries. For example, the semiconductor industry may also be eliminated in the future.</li>
<li>QQQ index funds have a replacement mechanism to promptly remove underperforming stocks, maintaining overall growth momentum.</li>
<li>Investing in individual stocks requires the ability to identify potential opportunities and understand market and industry trends, as exemplified by James&rsquo; interaction with NVIDIA&rsquo;s CEO before its IPO and his purchase of Amazon shares during its slump.</li>
<li>For retirement accounts, it&rsquo;s recommended to invest all Rust account funds in leveraged ETFs, while 401K accounts can hold cash or bonds.</li>
<li>Be cautious when borrowing for investment; ensure cash flow can cover interest payments and manage risks effectively.</li>
<li>In the US, if capital gains tax is implemented, consider transferring funds to other countries.</li>
<li>Avoid investing in the Chinese market due to policy risks and economic downturn pressures.</li>
<li>Do not purchase annuity products; they offer low returns and carry risks.</li>
<li>After selling a house, do not deposit funds into IRA or traditional IRA accounts.</li>
<li>Be decisive in investing and avoid hesitation. For example, loss-making properties should be sold as soon as possible, and the funds should be invested in the stock market.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ol>


<h2 class="relative group">III. Q&amp;A Session 
    <div id="iii-qa-session" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii-qa-session" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p><strong>Eric:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing:</strong>  Used the analogy of QQQ index funds being like aircraft carriers and individual stocks being like small boats to illustrate the advantages of index fund investing.</li>
<li><strong>Sharing:</strong>  James&rsquo; channel not only shares investment knowledge but also many life stories, such as estate planning and tax planning, from which valuable lessons can be learned.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Brian:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Question:</strong>  For employed individuals using the &ldquo;Situation 2&rdquo; asset allocation strategy, is it possible to set a higher Beta value, such as 1.1 or 1.2?</li>
<li><strong>Answer:</strong>  There is no upper limit for Beta, as long as cash is at least twice the amount of borrowed funds. Excel spreadsheets can be used to simulate investment outcomes under different scenarios, allowing adjustments based on individual risk tolerance.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Mike:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing:</strong> The US is like a Bogue bird, adept at concealing its strength and waiting for the opportune moment to reap the rewards, which aligns with the long-term investment philosophy.</li>
<li><strong>Question:</strong>  Will the central bank ignore economic recession and focus solely on inflation?</li>
<li><strong>Answer:</strong>  The central bank will not ignore economic recession because it leads to increased unemployment, which is one of the central bank&rsquo;s key concerns. Economic recession and unemployment are closely related.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Cheng Ge (PC):</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing:</strong>  Illustrated the drawbacks of investment-linked insurance policies through a real-life case study, recommending early surrender and transferring funds to QQQ index funds to recoup losses within a shorter timeframe and achieve higher returns.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Lang:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Question:</strong>  Is it feasible to utilize market downturns to buy QLD leveraged ETFs using a Roth IRA account and convert a 401K account to cash, aiming to increase the proportion of funds in the Roth IRA account?</li>
<li><strong>Answer:</strong>  If Rust account funds are limited, they should all be invested in leveraged ETFs. The 401K account can hold cash as a hedge. There&rsquo;s no need to wait for market downturns to make the switch; asset allocation should be completed as early as possible.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Tina:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Question:</strong>  If the 401K account is already maxed out, is it still possible to invest in an IRA account?</li>
<li><strong>Answer:</strong> After maxing out the 401K account, you cannot contribute to a traditional IRA account, but you can contribute to a Roth IRA account. Specific eligibility depends on income level and IRA contribution limits. It&rsquo;s recommended to check the IRA contribution limit for relevant information.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>IAM:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Question:</strong>  Will events like the Malaysian currency devaluation and the Hong Kong emigration wave impact the US economy and the US dollar? How does the US prevent currency devaluation? Will the companies in the QQQ index fund be affected?</li>
<li><strong>Answer:</strong> A country&rsquo;s currency value depends on its creditworthiness, which is backed by national industries and power. The US possesses strong national strength and diversified industries, allowing the US dollar to maintain its strong position. The US government will safeguard the interests of American companies and citizens. It&rsquo;s uncertain whether US companies will be directly affected by US dollar devaluation, but they will undoubtedly be protected by the US government.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>TT:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Question:</strong>  Are you still considering cycle investing at present?</li>
<li><strong>Answer:</strong>  Yes, cycle investing will be considered, but not through the all-in, all-out approach used in the past. Instead, Beta adjustments will be employed to navigate market volatility, as it&rsquo;s difficult for a large number of investors to keep up with rapid trading, thus requiring a more robust strategy.</li>
<li><strong>Question:</strong>  Which US political party, Democrat or Republican, is more favorable to investors?</li>
<li><strong>Answer:</strong>  In the long run, policies of both parties have minimal impact on investors. The market adjusts according to policies; for example, higher tax rates may induce investors to hold assets for longer periods.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>YJ:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Question:</strong> Are there any differences in asset allocation strategies between Taiwan and the US? What is the role of the 00864B bond? Why is investing in 00757 no longer recommended?</li>
<li><strong>Answer:</strong> Asset allocation strategies are universally applicable. The main differences between Taiwan and the US lie in stock pledging rules and leveraged ETF choices. 00864B can be used as a cash alternative, similar to a USD fixed deposit. Reasons for no longer recommending investment in 00757 can be found in the videos from 2021 and 2022.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Jason:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Question:</strong> Can dollar-cost averaging (DCA) be used to invest in leveraged ETFs like Q2D?</li>
<li><strong>Answer:</strong> When investing in any asset, including leveraged ETFs, lump-sum purchasing should be adopted instead of DCA. Returns from DCA are likely to be lower than lump-sum purchasing.</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">IV. Key Takeaways 
    <div id="iv-key-takeaways" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv-key-takeaways" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>QQQ index funds are like aircraft carriers, offering stability and substantial returns, while individual stock and sector investments are like sailing small boats, carrying high risk and vulnerability to market fluctuations.
&ndash; James &amp; Eric</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Choosing long-term investment in QQQ index funds can mitigate the risks associated with individual stocks and sector investments, providing more stable returns.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The central bank will not disregard economic recession, as it leads to rising unemployment, a key indicator that the central bank monitors.
&ndash;  James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>One of the objectives of the central bank&rsquo;s monetary policy is to maintain low unemployment; therefore, it will not stand idly by in the face of economic recession.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Loss aversion is a common mistake among investors. Losses should be cut promptly, and funds should be reallocated to higher-quality assets.
&ndash; Cheng Ge (PC)</p>
</blockquote>
<p>It&rsquo;s crucial to overcome the psychological barrier of loss aversion in investing, decisively cutting losses to prevent them from escalating.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The US&rsquo;s national strength rests on four pillars: government, the financial industry, businesses, and national defense. These four pillars work in synergy to achieve strategic goals.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>America&rsquo;s robust, comprehensive national strength is the cornerstone of the US dollar&rsquo;s strong position.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>In the long term, policies of both US parties have a limited impact on investors; the market adjusts itself based on policies.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>The market has a self-regulating mechanism, enabling it to adapt to various policy environments.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>When investing in any asset, including leveraged ETFs, lump-sum purchasing should be adopted instead of dollar-cost averaging (DCA). Returns from DCA are likely to be lower than lump-sum purchasing.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;Buy whenever you have money&rdquo; is the investment strategy James consistently emphasizes. DCA is less efficient for long-term investment.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">V. Summary 
    <div id="v-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#v-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This session primarily revolved around investment cycles, with James explaining how to identify market cycles and emphasizing the distinction between premature and incorrect judgments, using Buffett&rsquo;s actions during the 2008 financial crisis as an example. Furthermore, it provided detailed insights into the risks of real estate investment, insurance selection, stock pledging, and asset allocation strategies. In the Q&amp;A segment, students raised questions and shared their perspectives on topics such as the aircraft carrier investment strategy, property tax, central bank policy, currency devaluation, and investment strategy in the Taiwanese market. James offered comprehensive answers to each question and reiterated the importance of long-term investment in QQQ index funds, along with the &ldquo;buy whenever you have money&rdquo; investment strategy.</p>

  



<div
  
    class="flex px-4 py-3 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900"
  >

  <span
    
      class="text-primary-400 ltr:pr-3 rtl:pl-3 flex items-center"
    >

    

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M506.3 417l-213.3-364c-16.33-28-57.54-28-73.98 0l-213.2 364C-10.59 444.9 9.849 480 42.74 480h426.6C502.1 480 522.6 445 506.3 417zM232 168c0-13.25 10.75-24 24-24S280 154.8 280 168v128c0 13.25-10.75 24-23.1 24S232 309.3 232 296V168zM256 416c-17.36 0-31.44-14.08-31.44-31.44c0-17.36 14.07-31.44 31.44-31.44s31.44 14.08 31.44 31.44C287.4 401.9 273.4 416 256 416z"/></svg>

  </span>


  </span>

  <span
    
      class="dark:text-neutral-300"
    ><strong>Disclaimer:</strong> This document is for personal learning and note-taking purposes only and does not constitute any investment advice.</span>
</div>

]]></content:encoded></item></channel></rss>