<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Real Estate on QQQ Investor</title>
    <link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/tags/real-estate/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Real Estate on QQQ Investor</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 23 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jomonylw.github.io/en/tags/real-estate/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>00492 Navigating Market Volatility: A Safe and Prudent Investment Approach; Leveraged ETF Strategies and Risk Management</title>
      <link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1732456561528/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1732456561528/</guid>
      <description>This lecture primarily discusses investment philosophy, asset allocation, real estate investment, retirement account management, and personal financial planning. James emphasizes the importance of long-term holding and advises investors to maintain undamaged capital (cash) to cope with market fluctuations. He also answers questions from the audience regarding retirement planning, tax optimization, and real estate investment, sharing specific case studies.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<lite-youtube videoid="oLims_tjx7E" playlabel="oLims_tjx7E" params=""></lite-youtube>



<h2 class="relative group">I. Main Topic 
    <div id="i-main-topic" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-main-topic" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This lecture focuses on the importance of long-term investing and asset allocation, especially the significance of holding cash (undamaged capital). James reiterates the idea that &ldquo;the only constant in the market is volatility&rdquo; and advises investors to adopt a &ldquo;buy and hold&rdquo; strategy similar to Warren Buffett&rsquo;s, investing long-term in Nasdaq 100 index funds (QQQ or 00662). He uses a rent vs. buy case study to demonstrate the advantages of long-term index fund investing. He also explains in detail the importance of maintaining undamaged capital (cash) in asset allocation to buy the dip during market downturns, thereby achieving long-term stable investment returns.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">II. Summary 
    <div id="ii-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Investment Philosophy and Strategy 
    <div id="investment-philosophy-and-strategy" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#investment-philosophy-and-strategy" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Long-term Holding:</strong> Investing requires a timeframe of 20+ years, ideally forever, without worrying about short-term market fluctuations. James uses Warren Buffett as an example, emphasizing the importance of long-term holding, stating that if one isn&rsquo;t prepared to hold for the long term, they shouldn&rsquo;t even hold for 10 minutes.</li>
<li><strong>Invest in the US:</strong> The US is the best country for fairness, justice, and open innovation, so invest only in the US.</li>
<li><strong>Index Funds:</strong> Invest in Nasdaq 100 index funds (QQQ/00662), and recommends new viewers watch introductory videos 00451, 288, and 398.</li>
<li><strong>Market Volatility:</strong> The only constant in the market is volatility. Ignore market fluctuations and adhere to long-term holding. The 2022 market correction was just a financial event, not a bubble.</li>
<li><strong>Bubbles:</strong> Bubbles are rare, occurring only twice in the past 25 years. The best way to deal with them is to ignore them and continue holding index funds.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Asset Allocation and Cash Management 
    <div id="asset-allocation-and-cash-management" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#asset-allocation-and-cash-management" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Undamaged Capital:</strong> Having undamaged capital (cash) is crucial. It helps investors stay calm during market panics and buy the dip, just like wealthy individuals.</li>
<li><strong>The Significance of Cash:</strong> Cash is a stabilizing force that overcomes human flaws in investing (fear and greed), allowing the power of compounding to fully take effect.</li>
<li><strong>Cash Ratio:</strong> Recommends a cash allocation of at least 20% in the portfolio.</li>
<li><strong>Retirement Planning:</strong>  To withdraw $30,000 annually from an investment account after retirement, $1.5 million in cash is needed. James suggests withdrawing $50,000 annually, requiring $2.5 million in cash, approximately 20% of total assets.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Real Estate Investment 
    <div id="real-estate-investment" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#real-estate-investment" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Renting is Superior to Buying:</strong>  In the long run, renting and investing in index funds yields higher returns than buying a house. James shares a PC Excel spreadsheet example demonstrating the advantages of rental investment and encourages viewers to modify the parameters for simulation calculations.</li>
<li><strong>Selling Advice:</strong> Recommends selling real estate and land, investing the funds in the stock market. There&rsquo;s no real estate that can&rsquo;t be sold, only prices that are too high. Even if sold at a lower price, investment returns may quickly compensate for the difference.</li>
<li><strong>Short-term Rental Investment:</strong>  Short-term rental investments aren&rsquo;t worthwhile unless the annualized return is at least 20%.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Retirement Account Management 
    <div id="retirement-account-management" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#retirement-account-management" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Traditional IRA to Roth IRA Conversion:</strong> Recommends converting funds from traditional IRA accounts to Roth IRA accounts when tax rates are lower (below 24%).</li>
<li><strong>Roth IRA Investment:</strong> Recommends investing in leveraged ETFs (TQQQ) within Roth IRA accounts, while holding more cash in traditional retirement accounts. Shares a case study suggesting viewers invest Roth IRA funds in TQQQ and hold more cash in traditional retirement accounts to optimize asset allocation.</li>
<li><strong>Leveraged ETFs:</strong> Retirees should not hold leveraged ETFs. Leveraged ETFs should be held in Roth IRA accounts.</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">III. Q&amp;A Session 
    <div id="iii-qa-session" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii-qa-session" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Lora 
    <div id="lora" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#lora" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Question 1: How can I deduct the interest on a pledged loan against the interest earned on cash holdings?</strong>
<ul>
<li><strong>James:</strong> There&rsquo;s no deduction. If the interest earned on your cash is higher than the loan interest, you&rsquo;re effectively earning more. I recommend buying non-dividend-paying stocks in your personal account, like BOXX, to avoid paying taxes on interest income. Since you don&rsquo;t have a Roth IRA, you can only operate within a brokerage account and will incur some tax costs.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question 2: Which trading software do you recommend?</strong>
<ul>
<li><strong>James:</strong>  Just use your broker&rsquo;s website; no need for additional software. I only use the web version. The &ldquo;positions&rdquo; page on your brokerage website allows you to view the profit and loss of each transaction and manage them in batches.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Run 
    <div id="run" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#run" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Question 1: Can Roth IRA funds be pledged as collateral?</strong>
<ul>
<li><strong>James:</strong> Roth IRA funds cannot be directly pledged. However, they can be used as a credit guarantee to lower interest rates on other loans.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question 2: How should I invest after maxing out my Roth IRA contributions?</strong>
<ul>
<li><strong>James:</strong>  Max out your Roth IRA contributions first. Invest the remaining funds in QQQ within a regular brokerage account.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Zhan 
    <div id="zhan" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#zhan" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Question 1: How should I handle my properties in Canada and the US?</strong>
<ul>
<li><strong>James:</strong> I recommend selling your Canadian property as soon as possible. If your US property is your primary residence, I also suggest selling it and renting instead. It&rsquo;s more cost-effective, as demonstrated in the rent vs. buy case study in the presentation.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question 2: What should I do with my Canadian pension plan?</strong>
<ul>
<li><strong>James:</strong> I recommend withdrawing the money from your pension plan and investing it in QQQ within a brokerage account. Don&rsquo;t use the 403(b) and TDA accounts provided by your school, as their performance is poor. Stick to your own IRA account.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">IM 
    <div id="im" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#im" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Comment 1: There&rsquo;s a significant wealth gap among young people, and some try to fill it by borrowing money. How can I avoid this trap?</strong>
<ul>
<li><strong>James:</strong> First, cultivate strong mental fortitude, which can be achieved through reading. Second, don&rsquo;t lend money casually. Third, don&rsquo;t buy things you don&rsquo;t need. Even Warren Buffett, despite his wealth, doesn&rsquo;t buy unnecessary things.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Comment 2: I participated in an 11-day meditation retreat and gained insights into the relationship between meditation and investing, particularly the importance of focus.</strong>
<ul>
<li><strong>James:</strong> Avoid distractions outside the stock market and focus on your investment strategy.  Treat distractions like &ldquo;demons and monsters&rdquo;—don&rsquo;t listen, don&rsquo;t watch, don&rsquo;t engage—and you&rsquo;ll maintain composure.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question: Does focusing solely on my own investments lead to detachment from the world?</strong>
<ul>
<li><strong>James:</strong> There&rsquo;s no need to be overly connected to worldly affairs. Focus on your investments and avoid excessive external information. Important information will eventually reach you.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Lin 
    <div id="lin" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#lin" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Question: How should I rebalance my portfolio?</strong>
<ul>
<li><strong>James:</strong> Since you&rsquo;re still working, you don&rsquo;t need to engage in complex rebalancing.  Just rebalance annually, adjusting the proportions of leveraged ETFs (00670L/TQQQ/Q2D) and cash. You can leave your 00662/QQQ holdings untouched. Alternatively, during your monthly investments, maintain an 80% allocation to 00662/QQQ and 20% to 00864B/cash.  (He then provides a specific example of adjusting the ratio between 00670L and cash).</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Lizi 
    <div id="lizi" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#lizi" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Question: How can I reduce the tax burden from RMDs (Required Minimum Distributions)?</strong>
<ul>
<li><strong>James:</strong> I recommend withdrawing $600,000 annually from your IRA and transferring it to a Roth IRA over the next seven years. You can invest in leveraged ETFs within the Roth IRA and hold cash in your traditional retirement account to lower your overall return and tax burden.  Start converting to a Roth IRA as soon as possible; don&rsquo;t wait until RMDs begin.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">IV. Key Takeaways 
    <div id="iv-key-takeaways" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv-key-takeaways" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;If you&rsquo;re not investing for 20+ years, don&rsquo;t tell me you&rsquo;re investing.&rdquo; &ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Investing requires a long-term perspective. Short-term market fluctuations should not influence investment decisions.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;Undamaged capital is the elixir that keeps us calm.&rdquo; &ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Holding cash helps investors remain composed during market volatility and seize opportunities to buy low.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;Don&rsquo;t engage with demons and monsters. If you don&rsquo;t engage, you don&rsquo;t need to train your mind.&rdquo; &ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Staying away from market noise and focusing on one&rsquo;s own investment strategy is key to maintaining rational investment decisions.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">V. Conclusion 
    <div id="v-conclusion" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#v-conclusion" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This lecture reiterates the importance of long-term investing, value investing, and asset allocation, analyzing them with practical examples.  James advises investors to hold Nasdaq 100 index funds and maintain a certain percentage of cash to cope with market fluctuations. He answers questions about retirement account management, real estate investment, and personal financial planning, providing specific advice based on individual circumstances. He emphasizes the importance of choosing the right investment strategy and asset allocation according to one&rsquo;s situation.</p>

  



<div
  
    class="flex px-4 py-3 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900"
  >

  <span
    
      class="text-primary-400 ltr:pr-3 rtl:pl-3 flex items-center"
    >

    

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M506.3 417l-213.3-364c-16.33-28-57.54-28-73.98 0l-213.2 364C-10.59 444.9 9.849 480 42.74 480h426.6C502.1 480 522.6 445 506.3 417zM232 168c0-13.25 10.75-24 24-24S280 154.8 280 168v128c0 13.25-10.75 24-23.1 24S232 309.3 232 296V168zM256 416c-17.36 0-31.44-14.08-31.44-31.44c0-17.36 14.07-31.44 31.44-31.44s31.44 14.08 31.44 31.44C287.4 401.9 273.4 416 256 416z"/></svg>

  </span>


  </span>

  <span
    
      class="dark:text-neutral-300"
    ><strong>Disclaimer:</strong> This is a personal learning summary and does not constitute investment advice.</span>
</div>

]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Personal Investment Bible: Investment Iron Law Ⅸ</title>
      <link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1731056005968/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1731056005968/</guid>
      <description>This article explores common misconceptions in investment and financial management, particularly the reliance on forecasting and technical analysis. The author argues that technical analysis cannot consistently help investors achieve excess returns and instead often leads to the trap of short-term trading.  The article advocates a long-term investment strategy of &amp;#39;buy any stock, buy anytime, and don&amp;#39;t sell,&amp;#39; emphasizing that the key to successful investing lies in selecting the right investment targets and holding them for the long term, rather than attempting to predict short-term market fluctuations.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[

<h2 class="relative group">Investment Iron Law Ⅸ: Grasping the General Market Trend 
    <div id="investment-iron-law--grasping-the-general-market-trend" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#investment-iron-law--grasping-the-general-market-trend" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>Basing investment decisions on technical analysis<br>
often indicates a lack of experience.<br>
In most cases, it won&rsquo;t make you money.</p>
</blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">The Blind Spots of Forecasting and Analysis 
    <div id="the-blind-spots-of-forecasting-and-analysis" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#the-blind-spots-of-forecasting-and-analysis" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>The reason many investors engage in frequent short-term trading, besides being attracted by price fluctuations, is mainly due to the so-called &ldquo;experts&rdquo; who flood the investment market with constant analysis and forecasts, providing investors with specious advice. This leads investors to frantically chase the &ldquo;buy low, sell high&rdquo; principle.  Let&rsquo;s discuss whether forecasting and analysis are truly effective. Can they genuinely help investors make a fortune?</p>
<p><strong>Is Technical Analysis Effective?</strong></p>
<p>In April 1993, the Taiwan <em>Economic Daily</em> published an article titled, &ldquo;Success in Stocks Depends on Entry and Exit Timing.&rdquo; This led many to believe that the most crucial task in investment analysis is determining the right moments to buy and sell.</p>
<p>The average investor believes the golden rule for wealth in the stock market is &ldquo;buy low, sell high.&rdquo;  They also believe the key to success lies in accurately grasping these timing opportunities. Consequently, countless investors try every means to predict future stock price trends to determine optimal buying and selling points.  In their quest for the Midas touch, various methods, from the scientific to the absurd, and even the supernatural, such as astrology and market horoscopes, have emerged.  Currently, the most widely used method is &ldquo;technical analysis.&rdquo;</p>
<p>In the author&rsquo;s humble opinion, technical analysis&rsquo;s popularity in the global investment market, and its continued prevalence among Taiwanese investors, stems from the fact that it appears sophisticated yet not overwhelmingly complex, thus attracting many novice investors.  These beginners often believe they must possess some secret technique to navigate the stock market, leading them to prioritize learning technical analysis upon entering the market.</p>
<p>Technical analysis originated from the Dow Theory in the 1930s, after which various technical analysis methods sprung up like mushrooms.  From the 1940s to the 1960s, technical analysis was highly popular in the US stock market.  However, with the advent of the Random Walk Theory, and the observation that most users of technical analysis ended up worse off, its popularity began to wane.  By the 1980s, when the author was studying investment analysis in the US stock market, established investment analysts rarely mentioned technical analysis.  At the time, if an investor claimed to use technical analysis for investment decisions, it implied inexperience and a high probability of losing money.</p>
<p>Technical analysis involves studying and analyzing past price trends and volume data to determine buying and selling timings. Its fundamental assumption is that history repeats itself. Therefore, by identifying the patterns of stock price movements, one can accurately predict future trends.</p>
<p><strong>Beating the Market is a Pipe Dream</strong></p>
<p>Numerous empirical studies by scholars have revealed many problems and controversies surrounding technical analysis.  Briefly summarized:</p>
<ul>
<li>
<ol>
<li>Historical patterns don&rsquo;t always repeat. Even if technical analysis has been effective for decades, it doesn&rsquo;t guarantee future success.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol start="2">
<li>If a particular technical analysis method consistently succeeds, its widespread adoption will eliminate its potential profits.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol start="3">
<li>The collective actions of technical analysts can create price patterns.  This means the price isn&rsquo;t reflecting a correct prediction but rather the analysts&rsquo; actions.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol start="4">
<li>Some technical indicators rely on comparisons with past data.  These values can change due to time and environment, making past standards inapplicable to the present.</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ul>
<p>If you were given a past stock chart and asked to devise a profitable investment strategy, everyone would understand &ldquo;buy low, sell high.&rdquo;  Profiting from trading in such a scenario would be easy.  However, investing is about the future. Future price movements are complex and unpredictable; no one possesses a future stock chart.  So, is &ldquo;buy low, sell high&rdquo; still a suitable investment strategy?  The answer is no.  The reason is simple: no one can predict market highs and lows in advance.</p>
<p>Using previously successful technical analysis methods doesn&rsquo;t guarantee future success in beating the market, as excess returns can be random.  Furthermore, concluding that technical analysis is effective based on occasional or random excess returns is misleading. While technical analysis might yield short-term gains, it cannot consistently outperform the market in the long run.</p>
<p>A student once asked me, if the market follows a random walk and technical analysis is ineffective, why are some technical analysis methods accurate at times?  Claiming technical analysis is ineffective means it can&rsquo;t generate long-term excess profits, not that its predictions are always wrong.  Technical analysis can sometimes be accurate, just like random guesses can be accurate.  Therefore, technical analysis isn&rsquo;t necessarily inaccurate; its accuracy is comparable to guessing.</p>
<p><strong>The Trap of Short-Term Trading</strong></p>
<p>Another significant drawback of technical analysis is that its methods focus on identifying buy and sell points.  These points constantly emerge, forcing investors to frequently buy and sell, trapping them in short-term trading and eroding returns through transaction costs. The ineffectiveness of technical analysis means that, on average, it doesn&rsquo;t generate excess returns over the long term. In other words, while sometimes accurate, it ultimately underperforms the market&rsquo;s average return (buy-and-hold strategy).</p>
<p>You might have used technical analysis methods with seemingly good results.  I admit some methods can be effective, but investors often overlook transaction costs.  Considering these costs, returns from technical analysis are unlikely to be high.  Furthermore, the effectiveness of any technical analysis method is inconsistent, making long-term high returns improbable.</p>
<p>Technical analysis exhausts investors, leading to significant losses.  Investors should abandon it and adopt a long-term &ldquo;buy-and-hold&rdquo; strategy to benefit from long-term market growth.  It&rsquo;s crucial to understand that market risk is inherent in any investment strategy.  Investors should be mentally prepared and avoid excessive optimism about short-term returns.  Profitable investing relies on correctly judging the overall market direction.  Obsessively seeking investment rules from past data, even if profitable, will likely incur time and effort costs exceeding the returns.</p>
<p>If you still believe technical analysis can lead to riches, ask yourself: who has become wealthy solely through technical analysis?</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Blind faith in predictions is worse than no prediction at all.
Prediction is more art than science.</p>
</blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">The Only Certainty is Uncertainty 
    <div id="the-only-certainty-is-uncertainty" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#the-only-certainty-is-uncertainty" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>The biggest mistake in investment strategies is overconfidence in prediction. If you&rsquo;ve tirelessly searched for prediction methods without success, or your developed methods are unreliable and unprofitable, don&rsquo;t be discouraged. All predictions face the same challenges.</p>
<p>Like you, forecasting experts cannot predict the future.  If they possessed a crystal ball, they would be wealthy, not making a living from predictions.  If this logic isn&rsquo;t convincing, ask yourself: &ldquo;Which self-made millionaire or consistently successful long-term investor has relied solely on prediction?&rdquo;  The answer is none.</p>
<p><strong>Investment Performance is Unrelated to Predictive Ability</strong></p>
<p>People often assume investment success hinges on predictive ability.  Those who predict better supposedly perform better, while investment failures are attributed to poor prediction. However, this isn&rsquo;t true. Most successful investors admit their inability to predict the future. They have no preconceived notions, and their success stems from sound strategies, not accurate predictions.</p>
<p>During my studies in the US, when I first dabbled in the US stock market, I shared the common belief that Wall Street analysts were remarkable and highly skilled at predicting market trends. After graduating from UC Berkeley in 1987, I left academia for a position at a major US brokerage firm, largely driven by the desire to learn from renowned analysts at Merrill Lynch.</p>
<p>At Merrill Lynch, I witnessed these analysts firsthand. After numerous interactions, I realized they couldn&rsquo;t accurately predict future stock prices. Some didn&rsquo;t even invest in stocks themselves. I often called analysts, asking which stocks to buy and when the market would rise. One analyst, perhaps tired of my persistent inquiries, frankly told me, &ldquo;Think about it. If I knew which stocks would rise and when the market would go up, would I be stuck working as an analyst?&rdquo;  It was then I understood that analysts don&rsquo;t possess predictive powers.</p>
<p>Upon returning to Taiwan, I observed that local newspapers and magazines were filled with &ldquo;Expert Predictions&rdquo; or &ldquo;Analyst Market Forecasts.&rdquo;  I interacted with several well-known analysts, studying their predictions carefully. My conclusion: there were no superior predictions in the Taiwan stock market.  These analysts and experts couldn&rsquo;t accurately grasp the market&rsquo;s future direction.</p>
<p><strong>Analysts Rely on Hype</strong></p>
<p>Why do so many analysts and experts constantly make predictions in the media? The reason is simple: supply follows demand. Readers crave these predictions, prompting newspapers and magazines to create dedicated columns.  Experts often publish predictions not because they possess foresight but because readers believe experts have superior knowledge of the future and eagerly seek their opinions.  Newspapers cater to this demand by soliciting expert articles.  Similarly, why do brokerage firms employ so many analysts to interpret market trends for clients? To meet customer needs.  In a competitive environment, analyst insights are considered a crucial service. Brokerage firms readily provide this service because research indicates that investors guided by experts tend towards short-term trading, generating higher commissions for the firms.</p>
<p>This demonstrates investors&rsquo; heavy reliance on expert predictions, which arise from investor demand. The problem is that the stock market is unpredictable.  No one can make accurate predictions, a widely acknowledged fact.  Yet, most investors still believe in expert forecasts.</p>
<p>A US poll once asked, &ldquo;Who lies to the public the most?&rdquo; The results: weather forecasters, stock analysts, and economic commentators.  This reveals not that expert predictions are always inaccurate but the public&rsquo;s unwavering faith in them, leading to heightened expectations.  These professions often require making future predictions under the assumption that &ldquo;experts must be able to predict; those who can&rsquo;t predict aren&rsquo;t experts.&rdquo;  This pressure compels many researchers and analysts to publish future predictions, despite the inherent uncertainty.  Being wrong is inevitable, and being perceived as liars arises from the public&rsquo;s initial belief in their predictions, leading to feelings of deception when they prove incorrect.</p>
<p>You might question this, citing instances of analysts who made remarkably accurate predictions, causing stocks to surge upon their recommendations.  However, have you noticed that these seemingly prophetic &ldquo;experts&rdquo; are rarely the same person and often disappear after a while?  In reality, these experts, unless backed by market manipulators who profit from deceiving retail investors, are simply experiencing probability at play.  Occasional streaks of accuracy are possible but not sustainable.</p>
<p><strong>Strategies to Lure Retail Investors</strong></p>
<p>Market manipulators aiming to pump and dump a stock, besides securing cooperation from major shareholders, must create a forecasting &ldquo;expert&rdquo; who, through media appearances, convinces retail investors to buy in.  As major shareholders lock up their shares and more investors join, it creates the illusion that the &ldquo;expert&rsquo;s&rdquo; predictions are coming true, causing the stock price to surge.</p>
<p>Joseph Granville was a popular technical analyst in the early 1980s.  His remarkably accurate market predictions in the late 1970s made him famous.  His large following gave him considerable market influence; his words could move the market by tens of points.  However, in early 1982, he predicted a major market crash, advising his followers to sell all their stocks.  Instead, the market surged from around 700 to over 1200 points within five months.  Those who heeded his advice missed a significant bull market, and Granville faded into obscurity.</p>
<p>I advise investors to avoid stocks being manipulated. Even if you make small profits initially, one loss could wipe out all gains and more.  Another reason: manipulated stocks involve major shareholder intervention.  These shareholders, instead of focusing on business operations and profits, are interested in quick gains through market manipulation, indicating poor management.  Such companies aren&rsquo;t worth investing in. Their scheme relies on retail investors&rsquo; money; retail investors have little chance of winning.  If retail investors could profit from this game, what would be the point for the major shareholders?</p>
<p>Another possibility for accurate predictions is simply probability.  Predictions are often diverse and contradictory, with some bullish, some bearish, and some expecting consolidation.  Inevitably, someone will be right, purely due to luck or higher guessing probability.</p>
<p><strong>More Wrong Guesses Than Right</strong></p>
<p>However, most people don&rsquo;t think this way.  When experts make several consecutive correct predictions, they gain credibility and are hailed as &ldquo;prophets.&rdquo;  People easily forget past incorrect predictions, treating the &ldquo;prophet&rsquo;s&rdquo; words as gospel.  This is extremely dangerous. Investors overlook the possibility of future incorrect predictions.</p>
<p>I&rsquo;m not entirely dismissing analysts and experts.  In the unpredictable investment world, many investors need expert guidance.  Analyst data and forecasts can be valuable reference material. My point is, regardless of your attitude towards expert predictions, remember: the future is dynamic and unpredictable.  Investment risk is an unavoidable reality and must be managed.</p>
<p>In early 1990, as the market peaked, most experts predicted continued growth. A prominent &ldquo;market prophet&rdquo; confidently proclaimed the market would reach 15,000 points within six months and 20,000 within a year.  Major media outlets reported this prediction.  The reality was starkly different.  Within six months, the market plummeted 2,000 points, shocking all experts.  Did these experts disappear?  No.  Newspapers and magazines still feature expert market forecasts.  The reason is simple: investors are &ldquo;used to&rdquo; hearing these predictions and many remain captivated by them.</p>
<p>I don&rsquo;t advocate completely ignoring predictions.  Predictions have value, and good predictions are worth considering.  However, whether you believe in predictions or not, and regardless of the predictor&rsquo;s reputation, remember: the future is fluid and unpredictable.  Investment risk is an inherent part of investing and must be managed.</p>
<p>You don&rsquo;t need predictive abilities to invest well or make money in the market. In this complex and volatile market, the only certainty is uncertainty.  In the investment world, profits come from choosing the right investments and holding them long-term, not from predicting market movements.  In summary, consider expert predictions, but remember they are just predictions.  Don&rsquo;t blindly trust them.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>There are no experts in the stock market, only winners and losers.</p>
</blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">Trust Yourself, Not the Experts 
    <div id="trust-yourself-not-the-experts" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#trust-yourself-not-the-experts" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>Some believe that lacking professional expertise makes achieving wealth through investment incredibly difficult. Yet, many who don&rsquo;t understand stocks or real estate still achieve financial success through investing.  Most successful investors aren&rsquo;t investment professionals, and investment professionals aren&rsquo;t necessarily successful investors.  This shows that expertise isn&rsquo;t a prerequisite for wealth creation through investment.</p>
<p>Investment and financial management aren&rsquo;t inherently complex.  The perceived complexity and reliance on experts stem from investors&rsquo; inability to cope with uncertainty, overcomplicating simple matters and turning financial management into a source of anxiety and confusion.  This anxiety hinders rational decision-making, leading people to constantly seek external opinions.</p>
<p><strong>10 Experts, 11 Opinions</strong></p>
<p>The inability to handle uncertainty creates the illusion that foresight or profound analytical skills are necessary for successful investing, leading to the belief that only &ldquo;experts&rdquo; can manage finances effectively. Consequently, many entrust their financial decisions to experts, who often offer conflicting &ldquo;expert opinions.&rdquo; Ten experts can have eleven different views, further complicating the investment world and adding to investor confusion.</p>
<p>Basing your financial decisions solely on expert opinions is extremely dangerous. Ultimately, investment responsibility lies with the individual. Investors should enhance their financial literacy and become their own experts.  Financial management doesn&rsquo;t require extensive professional knowledge. By following a few basic principles outlined in this book and acting accordingly, you can achieve wealth without relying on experts.  With the right investment philosophy, you might even outperform them.</p>
<p>Therefore, I urge investors to take immediate action, start investing, and stop asking questions like &ldquo;When will the market rise?&rdquo; &ldquo;Which stock should I buy?&rdquo; or &ldquo;Should I sell my xxx stock now?&rdquo;  These questions are pointless; no one knows the correct answers.</p>
<p>In 1983, when I began my doctoral studies at UC Berkeley, I started helping Taiwanese entrepreneurs invest in US stocks.  To excel at this, I dedicated immense effort to stock analysis, often neglecting sleep and meals. For one to two years, I practically lived in the Berkeley Haas School of Business library, devouring every investment book and analyzing all available stock information. I learned various technical, fundamental, and market analysis techniques.  To develop my unique investment analysis and prediction methods, I utilized Berkeley&rsquo;s advanced computers and extensive stock databases, writing programs to simulate various investment approaches.  This proved futile; I couldn&rsquo;t find a satisfactory method.  It was all for naught.</p>
<p>If anyone truly knew when the market would rise or which stock to buy, they would be wealthy enough not to need a job as an analyst or expert.  I reiterate: even without knowing &ldquo;when the market will rise&rdquo; or &ldquo;which stock to buy,&rdquo; you can still achieve wealth through investing.  Stop wasting time on these questions. Countless people have dedicated their lives to researching them since the inception of the stock market. They became stock experts but didn&rsquo;t achieve wealth through investing.</p>
<p><strong>Inaction and Effortless Gains</strong></p>
<p>Financial management doesn&rsquo;t require excessive time. Those who spend less time on it often perform better.</p>
<p>Statistics show that Taiwanese stock investors spend an average of 3.12 hours daily on stock analysis and market watching. Is stock picking difficult? Is making money in the stock market challenging?  Constantly chasing price fluctuations, what are your returns?  Those who diligently study stocks often lose the most money.</p>
<p>A common investor mistake is giving up.  They eagerly enter during bull markets and become disheartened during bear markets, abandoning the market entirely.  Lacking patience and perseverance, they rarely succeed.  Conversely, those with less financial acumen, admitting their inability to time the market, often persevere and ultimately fare better.</p>
<p>The path to investment wealth is simple: effortless gains. The investment strategy presented—&ldquo;buy any stock, buy anytime, don&rsquo;t sell&rdquo;—can be summarized as &ldquo;do nothing, gain effortlessly.&rdquo;</p>
<p>Who wouldn&rsquo;t want effortless gains? Surprisingly, most investors can&rsquo;t achieve this.  &ldquo;There&rsquo;s no such thing as a free lunch&rdquo; is a widely known principle. Applying this to investment, people assume they must master complex techniques and work harder than others to profit.  Intuitively, they believe more knowledge and effort equate to higher returns. This might hold true in other areas, but in finance, the opposite is often true. Knowledge and effort don&rsquo;t significantly contribute to investment returns.  Knowing more and constantly monitoring the market encourages impulsive trading, leading to &ldquo;effort without gain.&rdquo;</p>
<p><strong>Inaction is Superior to Action</strong></p>
<p>Even investment gurus like Warren Buffett and Peter Lynch admit they can&rsquo;t predict market movements. Admitting ignorance might seem foolish, but it&rsquo;s the beginning of financial wisdom.  Being &ldquo;foolish&rdquo; enough to &ldquo;buy any stock, buy anytime, don&rsquo;t sell&rdquo; is the starting point of wealth creation. Confucius said, &ldquo;Great wisdom appears foolish.&rdquo;  This refers to highly learned individuals who achieve mastery through natural means, without contrivance or cunning.  They appear unintelligent but are truly wise.  Lao Tzu also said, &ldquo;Great skill appears clumsy,&rdquo; and advocated for &ldquo;governing by non-interference.&rdquo;  This strategy, applied to the volatile investment environment, is a sound approach. Unless you have strong conviction about future trends, it&rsquo;s better to ignore the chaos and remain inactive.</p>
<p>Therefore, you don&rsquo;t need to be an investment expert or possess sophisticated techniques.  &ldquo;Do nothing, gain effortlessly&rdquo; is the key to financial wealth. You might think this sounds too simple, even boring.  Indeed, it is. But this simplicity is the path to riches and becoming a millionaire.  Before acting, ask yourself: &ldquo;Do I want wealth or to be a stock market expert?&rdquo;  If you want wealth through stocks, emulate the many who became rich by simply investing and then ignoring the market.  Decades later, compounding will make you wealthy. You could also dedicate yourself to becoming a stock market expert, but this rarely leads to riches.</p>
<p>My point is, even without knowing &ldquo;when the market will rise&rdquo; or &ldquo;which stock to buy,&rdquo; you can still achieve wealth through investing. Short-term market fluctuations are unpredictable, but the long-term trend is upward. Long-term investing is the key to profit.</p>
<p>&ldquo;Buy any stock, buy anytime, don&rsquo;t sell&rdquo;—so simple, effortless, and seemingly undeserved.  While it feels like unearned gain, don&rsquo;t feel guilty.  Investing in stocks contributes to economic development.  Constant trading harms individual wealth and offers no benefit to the overall economy or society.</p>
<p><strong>Easier Said Than Done</strong></p>
<p>Some worry and ask, &ldquo;You advise against saving money in banks.  If your book becomes a bestseller and this idea spreads, wouldn&rsquo;t it cause a nationwide bank run?&rdquo; This is an unnecessary concern. I&rsquo;ve been advocating against saving money in banks for three years, even before this book&rsquo;s publication. Many who hear this idea nod in agreement, as if enlightened, yet days, months, or years later, their money remains untouched in bank accounts.</p>
<p>Others question whether my &ldquo;buy any stock, buy anytime, don&rsquo;t sell&rdquo; theory, if widely adopted, would force brokerage firms to close, depriving the government of transaction taxes.  Again, there&rsquo;s no need for such concerns.  Those who frequently engage in short-term trading in stocks, futures, or margin accounts, even after understanding that it only benefits intermediaries, often can&rsquo;t resist continuing their behavior.  Like gambling, everyone knows the odds are stacked against them, yet gambling persists.</p>
<p><strong>I understand that &ldquo;don&rsquo;t save money in banks,&rdquo; &ldquo;avoid short-term trading,&rdquo; and &ldquo;diversify and hold long-term,&rdquo; are simple in theory but difficult in practice.  Nevertheless, I sincerely hope readers can integrate knowledge and action, diversifying most of their assets into stocks and real estate, holding them long-term. Achieving financial freedom is within reach.</strong></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Personal Investment Bible: Investment Iron Law Ⅵ</title>
      <link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1731056005965/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1731056005965/</guid>
      <description>This article explores how to resolve the crisis of being trapped in investments, emphasizing the importance of diversification and long-term holding.  It begins with the adage, &amp;#39;Don&amp;#39;t put all your eggs in one basket,&amp;#39; explaining the principles and methods of diversification, including diversifying investment targets, timing, and regions.  The article also discusses the principles of diversification, pointing out that the number of investment targets should not be excessive, and suggesting choosing investment targets with greater negative correlation.  Furthermore, it introduces two methods for diversifying investment timing: investing whenever funds are available and regular fixed-amount investment. Finally, the article emphasizes the importance of long-term holding, arguing that it can reduce the possibility of investment losses and contribute to higher returns.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[

<h2 class="relative group">Investment Iron Law Ⅵ: Escaping the Trap of Locked-in Investments 
    <div id="investment-iron-law--escaping-the-trap-of-locked-in-investments" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#investment-iron-law--escaping-the-trap-of-locked-in-investments" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>Don&rsquo;t put all your eggs in one basket.</p>
</blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">Diversification and Long-Term Holding 
    <div id="diversification-and-long-term-holding" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#diversification-and-long-term-holding" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>Many investors often ask me: &ldquo;Even if I believe that stocks and real estate have high returns and will rise in the long run, their prices fluctuate. Some investments will make a lot of money, while others will lose a lot of money. What should I invest in? What if the company I invest in goes bankrupt?&rdquo; &ldquo;When should I invest? What if I invest at the highest price point?&rdquo; &ldquo;When should I sell? What if I sell at the wrong time?&rdquo; These questions reflect the risks inherent in investment and financial management.</p>
<p><strong>Increase Returns, Reduce Risks</strong></p>
<p>The eight-character mantra of investment and financial management is: <strong>Increase returns, reduce risks</strong>. The simplest way to increase returns is to invest assets in high-return instruments, such as stocks and real estate. However, high-return investments come with high risks. For example, stock and real estate prices fluctuate, leading to both profits and losses. Therefore, investors seeking high returns must bear the accompanying risks. However, these risks are generally undesirable for most investors. The correct financial management concept is not to avoid investment because of these risks. To achieve high returns, one should venture into investments with these risks, and then find ways to mitigate and minimize their impact.</p>
<p>Therefore, reducing risks to avoid losses and increasing returns to create wealth are equally important for successful financial management. The primary goal of risk management is to find ways to reduce the risk of loss while increasing investment returns.</p>
<p>Investing in high-return targets faces three main risks:</p>
<ol>
<li>Choosing the wrong investment target.</li>
<li>Choosing the wrong investment timing.</li>
<li>Choosing the wrong selling timing.</li>
</ol>
<p>So how can we reduce these risks?</p>
<p><em>1. Reduce the risk of choosing the wrong investment target - Diversify investment targets.</em>
<em>2. Reduce the risk of choosing the wrong investment timing - Diversify investment timing.</em>
<em>3. Reduce the risk of choosing the wrong selling timing - Long-term holding.</em></p>
<p><strong>Reduce the Risk of Choosing the Wrong Investment Target - Diversify Investment Targets</strong></p>
<p>A conglomerate that owned a private jet once required its CEO and second-in-command to attend an international conference simultaneously. The conference organizers held a cocktail party to welcome these two VIPs. Guests and media eagerly awaited their arrival.  Amidst the cheers, only the second-in-command, who had arrived on a private jet, was present. The CEO was still at the international airport going through customs. It turned out that they had taken separate planes to mitigate risk. Indeed, with frequent air disasters, if they had taken the same flight and an accident occurred, it would have severely impacted the company.</p>
<p>Three thousand years ago, the Phoenicians invested heavily in building ships for international trade, venturing across the oceans. Successful voyages brought immense wealth; shipwrecks caused by hurricanes or typhoons resulted in total loss. Thus, the risks of overseas trade were enormous. A small group became incredibly wealthy through successful trade, while a few were ruined. However, the vast majority, fearing potential disasters, hesitated and missed out on substantial profits. Because few dared to take the risk, the limited supply of ships led to higher profits in maritime trade, benefiting those who invested.</p>
<p>Someone then devised an investment method that not only generated trade profits but also mitigated risks: diversification. The approach involved dividing the capital for one ship into ten parts, investing one-tenth in each of ten ships.  This diversified the risk.</p>
<p>Despite precautions, on average, three out of ten invested ships would sink due to storms. However, the profits from the remaining seven ships not only covered the losses but also yielded substantial returns. Diversification reduced risk while maintaining the return rate. The possibility of all ten ships encountering mishaps still existed, but it was minimal, significantly lower than the risk of investing in a single ship.</p>
<p>The most effective and widely adopted method for risk reduction is &ldquo;diversification.&rdquo; Diversification simply means increasing the variety of investments. Mark Twain once said, &ldquo;Don&rsquo;t put all your eggs in one basket.&rdquo; Distributing eggs across multiple baskets ensures that even if one basket falls, the remaining eggs are safe.  This approach aims to reduce risk.</p>
<p>The investment environment is unpredictable and constantly changing.  Fortuitous investments can yield high returns in the short term, but there&rsquo;s also a high probability that chosen investments could plummet immediately after purchase. Most people avoid this risk by keeping their funds in risk-free instruments like bank deposits or government bonds. <strong>However, the correct investment perspective is to invest in &ldquo;high-risk, high-expected return&rdquo; targets to achieve high returns, while employing diversification to mitigate risks.</strong></p>
<blockquote>
<p>Invest in ten ships.
Three sink.
The remaining ones still generate profits.</p>
</blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">Principles of Diversification 
    <div id="principles-of-diversification" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#principles-of-diversification" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>The method of diversifying risk has been practiced for millennia. The principle of diversification was introduced in the &ldquo;Portfolio Theory&rdquo; published in 1950 by Dr. Harry Markowitz, the 1990 Nobel laureate in economics. Diversification means increasing the types of investments. For example, when buying stocks, don&rsquo;t buy just one; divide the investment amount and purchase multiple stocks.  With sufficient capital, diversify beyond stocks into real estate, gold, art, and other asset classes.</p>
<p><strong>Increasing Investment Types Offsets Relative Risk</strong></p>
<p>Diversification reduces risk because different investment targets don&rsquo;t rise and fall in perfect unison. Even if they do, the magnitude of change varies. When several investments form a portfolio, the portfolio&rsquo;s return is the weighted average of individual investments.  Therefore, combining several high-return investments maintains high returns, while the portfolio&rsquo;s risk is reduced as the fluctuations of individual investments offset each other. Increasing the variety of investments in a portfolio decreases the overall portfolio risk. This explains why diversification – increasing the types of investments – reduces risk.</p>
<p>Therefore, when investing in stocks, don&rsquo;t just buy one type.  Purchase several different stocks.  Adequate diversification typically involves investing in ten or more stocks.  For investors with limited funds who want diversification, mutual funds are recommended. Most mutual funds invest in 30 or more stocks, so investing $10,000 in a mutual fund is equivalent to buying more than 30 stocks, providing sufficient diversification.</p>
<p><strong>Principles of Diversification</strong></p>
<p><em>1. Choose Investment Targets with Greater Negative Correlation</em></p>
<p>The less synchronized the price movements of investments in a portfolio, or the more they move in opposite directions, the better the diversification.  Choose investments whose price trends are inversely related to the existing portfolio. For example, gold is a good tool for diversification.  Historically, gold has been a high-risk investment, but its price tends to move inversely to stock prices.  During major international events like wars, political turmoil, or inflation, stock prices often fall while gold prices rise.  Applying this principle to stock investment, choose stocks from different industries for better diversification.</p>
<p><em>2. Avoid Excessive Diversification</em></p>
<p>While working as a consultant at a securities firm, I observed a woman in the VIP room with papers scattered across the table, gesturing frantically as if commanding an army. Assuming she was a major investor, I discreetly inquired with a broker and discovered her total investment was around $300,000, spread across over 30 stocks.  While aiming for diversification, she over-diversified, increasing management costs and diminishing returns. Excessive diversification is counterproductive. Even Warren Buffett, with his vast portfolio, invests in only about a dozen stocks.</p>
<p>Generally, increasing investment types reduces portfolio risk, but the risk reduction effect diminishes with each added type.  Holding numerous investments for fun is acceptable, but if the goal is risk reduction, understand that the diversification effect diminishes with increasing variety.  The difference in risk between holding 30 stocks and 20 stocks is negligible. <strong>Beyond a certain point, risk reduction plateaus, and further diversification offers no additional benefit.</strong></p>
<p>Balance diversification against management costs.  Diversification aims to reduce risk by increasing investment types across different instruments and targets.  While increasing types reduces risk, it increases management costs as tracking multiple assets becomes complex.</p>
<p>Peter Lynch, in his book &ldquo;One Up On Wall Street,&rdquo; stated: &ldquo;Investing in stocks is like having children – if you don&rsquo;t have the ability to raise them, don&rsquo;t have too many. No one says you have to invest in five or more stocks every time.&rdquo;</p>
<p><strong>Methods of Diversification</strong></p>
<p>Diversification methods include various investment instruments, targets, and regions:</p>
<p><strong>1. Diversification of Investment Instruments:</strong> Invest in different instruments, such as stocks, real estate, overseas mutual funds, art, and gold.</p>
<p><strong>2. Diversification of Investment Targets:</strong>  Invest in various targets.  For example, when investing in stocks, don&rsquo;t focus on just one. Spread funds across four or five or more stocks. Avoid concentrating on a few industries, as stocks within the same industry tend to move together. In real estate, if funds allow, invest in different property types like apartments, offices, shops, and studios, and diversify locations.</p>
<p><strong>3. Diversification of Investment Regions:</strong> Diversify investments across different countries or regions. Some investors worry about concentrating assets in one region due to political, war, and exchange rate risks.  Distributing assets geographically mitigates these risks.</p>
<p><strong>Concentrated Investment Requires Confidence</strong></p>
<p>Diversification reduces the likelihood of worst-case scenarios, but it also eliminates the possibility of the best-case scenarios. Full diversification makes extreme outcomes unlikely, resulting in returns close to the average.</p>
<p>Some argue for concentrating investments: &ldquo;Put all your eggs in one basket and watch it carefully.&rdquo; Admittedly, many successful investors concentrate their holdings.  Few individuals are experts in both stocks and real estate. The choice between diversification and concentration depends on individual circumstances. If you&rsquo;re proficient in a specific investment area, concentration might be preferable, offering potentially higher returns.  For example, a real estate expert wouldn&rsquo;t necessarily diversify into stocks.  Over-diversification could have hindered their success.</p>
<p>If you lack confidence in most investment areas, diversification is recommended. While it might not yield exceptional returns, it protects against significant losses. Diversified returns are close to average returns. As long as the chosen investments tend to appreciate over the long term, like stocks and real estate, achieving average returns is sufficient for wealth building.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Mitigate the risk of incorrect investment timing by diversifying investment timing.</p>
</blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">Diversifying Investment Timing 
    <div id="diversifying-investment-timing" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#diversifying-investment-timing" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>Diversification applies to both investment targets and timing. To mitigate the risk of mistiming the market, distribute investments over time.  Instead of investing a lump sum at once, divide it into portions and invest at different times.</p>
<p><strong>Foolproof Method for Investment Timing</strong></p>
<p>Two methods achieve diversified investment timing. <strong>The first is to invest whenever funds are available.</strong> A friend of mine invests $10,000 in stocks whenever his bank balance reaches $15,000, keeping his balance below $5,000. He also buys different stocks each time, diversifying both target and timing.</p>
<p><strong>Another method is Dollar-Cost Averaging (DCA), which is regularly investing a fixed amount in mutual funds.</strong>  Investors contribute a set amount at regular intervals (e.g., monthly, quarterly, or annually) at the prevailing net asset value (NAV).  A specified amount is automatically deducted from a designated bank account on a specific date each month and invested in a pre-selected mutual fund.  Since the investment amount is fixed, but the NAV fluctuates, the number of units purchased varies.  This naturally leads to buying more units when prices are low and fewer when prices are high.  Over the long term, DCA offers considerable returns and mitigates price fluctuation risks.</p>
<p><strong>Reducing the Risk of Choosing the Wrong Selling Timing - Long-Term Holding</strong></p>
<blockquote>
<p>Long-term holding reduces the likelihood of losses.
Choose long-term investment instead of being forced into it after becoming trapped.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Years ago, during training at Merrill Lynch, a securities analyst stated: &ldquo;Statistically, the stock market rises 55% of the days and falls 45%.  The problem is, we don&rsquo;t know which days will be up.&rdquo; The ratio of gains and losses in the Taiwan stock market is similar.</p>
<p>Therefore, if you, like the experts, don&rsquo;t know whether the market will rise or fall tomorrow, the smartest approach is to guess it will rise.  The more you guess, the higher your probability of being correct. If you consistently predict a market rise, the best strategy is: <strong>Buy whenever you have money, and hold.</strong> This seemingly simple approach is often the most effective.  Many fortunes have been built this way.</p>
<p>Stocks and real estate are characterized by high returns and high risks. Due to their inherent risk, prices fluctuate in the short term, but their high returns generate a long-term upward trend.  The longer the holding period, the lower the probability of loss.  My research on the Taiwan stock market showed that the probability of gains and losses changes with the holding period, as shown below:</p>
<p><em>Relationship between Stock Holding Period and Probability of Gain</em></p>
<table>
  <thead>
      <tr>
          <th style="text-align: left">Holding Period</th>
          <th style="text-align: left">Probability of Gain (%)</th>
          <th style="text-align: left">Probability of Loss (%)</th>
      </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
      <tr>
          <td style="text-align: left">1 Day</td>
          <td style="text-align: left">55</td>
          <td style="text-align: left">45</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td style="text-align: left">1 Month</td>
          <td style="text-align: left">60</td>
          <td style="text-align: left">40</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td style="text-align: left">1 Year</td>
          <td style="text-align: left">66</td>
          <td style="text-align: left">34</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td style="text-align: left">5 Years</td>
          <td style="text-align: left">99</td>
          <td style="text-align: left">1</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td style="text-align: left">10 Years</td>
          <td style="text-align: left">100</td>
          <td style="text-align: left">0</td>
      </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>
<p>The table demonstrates that while stock prices fluctuate in the short term, the probability of loss decreases with longer holding periods. A one-day holding has a 45% chance of loss, which decreases to 40% for one month, 34% for one year, and a mere 1% for five years, making a loss almost impossible.  Holding for ten years or more eliminates the possibility of loss entirely. Long-term holding not only reduces the likelihood of loss but is also crucial for increasing returns.</p>
<p>How can we build wealth from small investments? The key is the power of compounding, which requires both high returns and time. Investing in high-return instruments like stocks and real estate and holding them long-term allows compounding to work its magic, accelerating wealth growth. The longer the holding period (decades), the more apparent the high return rate becomes, and the investment loss risk rapidly decreases.</p>
<p><strong>The goal of risk management isn&rsquo;t to eliminate all risk, but to acknowledge its inevitable presence, understand it, analyze it, and then mitigate it.</strong> Never wait for absolute safety; it&rsquo;s an illusion.  High-expected return investments always carry risk, and no strategy can eliminate all risks.</p>
<p>Diversification reduces individual investment fluctuations, while long-term holding neutralizes short-term price swings.  Investing in stocks and real estate requires accepting short-term and individual investment volatility. By diversifying and holding long-term, these risks are mitigated, reducing overall investment risk. In the long run, this strategy allows investors to benefit from the high returns offered by stocks and real estate.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Personal Investment Bible: Investment Iron Law IV</title>
      <link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1731056005963/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1731056005963/</guid>
      <description>This article explores the financial strategy of &amp;#34;making money with other people&amp;#39;s money,&amp;#34; also known as leveraged investing. It analyzes the principle of financial leverage, emphasizing that the return on investment must be higher than the loan interest rate to be profitable.  Case studies of entrepreneurs like Chen Youhao and Weng Damming illustrate the advantages and risks of leveraged investing.  The article further discusses borrowing principles, how to build credit, how to avoid improper borrowing, and how to determine an appropriate level of debt. Finally, it points out that banks are a source of borrowing rather than a place to save money, and emphasizes the importance of prudent borrowing.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[

<h2 class="relative group">Investment Iron Law IV: Making Money with Other People&rsquo;s Money 
    <div id="investment-iron-law-iv-making-money-with-other-peoples-money" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#investment-iron-law-iv-making-money-with-other-peoples-money" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>By applying the principle of financial leverage, an investment of 500 million can double your business.</p>
</blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">Utilizing Leveraged Investing 
    <div id="utilizing-leveraged-investing" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#utilizing-leveraged-investing" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>The path to wealth through investment relies on &ldquo;making money with money.&rdquo;  Therefore, the prerequisite for investment is having capital.  A common dilemma faced by individuals when investing is, &ldquo;What if I don&rsquo;t have enough money?&rdquo; This can lead to missed opportunities. This book proposes a solution: &ldquo;If you don&rsquo;t have enough money, but someone else does and is willing to lend it to you, then borrow it.&rdquo; This is the highest realm of investment management—leveraged investing.</p>
<p><strong>Chen Youhao, President of the Tuntex Group: The Money-Making Method of Borrowing and Rolling</strong></p>
<p>Starting in the textile industry, Chen Youhao used financial leverage to rapidly expand the Tuntex Group into chemical fibers, construction, cement, hotels, petrochemicals, and other fields. With over 30 affiliated companies, it became one of the top 15 largest corporate groups in Taiwan. He also planned to invest nearly 7 billion USD in Taiwan and Thailand to expand chemical fiber plants.</p>
<p>Tuntex&rsquo;s growth never stopped, and its debt continued to rise. In 1995, Tuntex Group&rsquo;s core business, Tonwin Construction, had total assets of 59.6 billion TWD, revenue of 15.7 billion TWD, and net profit after tax of 2.6 billion TWD, but its debt ratio was still as high as 60.99%.</p>
<p>A graduate of the Department of Economics at National Taiwan University, Chen Youhao always prided himself on his sophisticated money-making method of borrowing and rolling. He had full confidence in Tuntex&rsquo;s financial management. His financial principles were: 1/3 self-owned capital, the rest borrowed from financial institutions; current assets must be greater than current liabilities, with a current ratio greater than 100%; and the ratio of self-owned capital to debt must not exceed 1/2.</p>
<p>Chen Youhao emphasized that whenever the company&rsquo;s debt ratio approached its limit, he would strictly control it, so the company&rsquo;s financial situation remained normal. However, whenever the construction industry was in a downturn, Tuntex would be plagued by rumors of financial difficulties. In June 1995, due to capital needs, Chen Youhao pledged 46.5 million shares of Tonwin, setting a record for the highest number of shares pledged by directors and supervisors that month. Chen Youhao repeatedly assured the public that Tuntex&rsquo;s finances were absolutely sound.</p>
<p>Despite the rumors damaging the company&rsquo;s image, Chen Youhao firmly believed that reasonable borrowing could enable the company to earn more profits. He was also confident that businesses funded by loans would be profitable because the return on investment was higher than the interest rate on loans.</p>
<p><strong>Is Borrowing to Invest Wrong?</strong></p>
<p>Is borrowing money for investment appropriate? Shakespeare wrote in Hamlet, &ldquo;Neither a borrower nor a lender be.&rdquo; This was once considered a golden rule. Our elders often warned their children not to borrow money from others or lend money to others; borrowing was not considered respectable and should be avoided unless absolutely necessary.</p>
<p>Indeed, most stories of financial ruin are caused by debt, such as the cases of Tsai Chen-chou of the Tenth Credit Cooperative and the stock market tycoon Lei Borong. Countless examples of bankruptcy caused by debt make people fear and avoid it.</p>
<p>However, among the famous wealthy individuals we know, such as Wang Yongqing, Kao Ching-yuan, Chang Yung-fa, and Wu Ho-Su, who didn&rsquo;t rely on borrowing to invest in their journey from rags to riches? The answer is &ldquo;none.&rdquo; Moreover, the more successful people are at making money, the more they tend to borrow. Looking at the financial statements of listed companies, are there any renowned high-performing enterprises in Taiwan, such as Formosa Plastics, Uni-President, and Evergreen, that have zero debt?  The message is clear: successful tycoons, like successful businesses, rarely achieve their wealth without using other people&rsquo;s money. In business management, appropriate borrowing is not only necessary but also reasonable.</p>
<p>If Shakespeare were alive in the 21st century and understood how capitalism works and how people become wealthy, he might change his words to: &ldquo;If you have no money, but others do and are willing to lend it to you, then borrow.&rdquo;</p>
<p>After reviewing these characteristics of success, reflect on your own financial situation. What percentage of your investment funds comes from borrowing? If, like most people, 100% of your investments are made with your own funds, you are overlooking an important tool for building wealth: borrowing.</p>
<p><strong>Borrowing is a Crucial Tool for Wealth Creation</strong></p>
<p>American investment consultant Robert Allen repeatedly emphasizes in his bestselling book <em>Creating Wealth</em>: &ldquo;You cannot become rich by investing without borrowing.&rdquo; I disagree with this argument. The examples in Chapter 1 of this book clearly demonstrate that with proper financial management, one can become a billionaire without relying on borrowed investments.  The American investment master Warren Buffett does not advocate leveraged investing.  Without debt, he is a prime example of building wealth solely through his own funds. However, there is a prerequisite for accumulating wealth using only your own funds: long-term patient waiting. Warren Buffett only rose to prominence after three to four decades of investing.</p>
<p>Although Robert Allen&rsquo;s argument that &ldquo;you cannot become rich without borrowing&rdquo; is incorrect, I must admit that the &ldquo;leveraged investing&rdquo; he advocates is an important means of building wealth, especially for those who want to accelerate the speed of wealth creation.  Leveraged investing is a tool that should not be ignored.</p>
<p>In conclusion, whether you want to accelerate wealth accumulation or can tolerate the pressure of leveraged investing, you must understand the nature and impact of leveraged investing before deciding if this tool is right for you.</p>
<ul>
<li>
<ol>
<li>Leveraged investing is a powerful tool, but it must be used wisely.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol start="2">
<li>It is possible to build wealth without borrowing.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol start="3">
<li>Leveraged investing, when used correctly, can accelerate wealth accumulation.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol start="4">
<li>Don&rsquo;t be afraid of leveraged investing, but be very careful.</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>Aim high with your business goals,
Once decided, go for it and never back down.
The key to success in business lies in courage and strategy.</p>
</blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">Weng Damming&rsquo;s Revival of the Family Business 
    <div id="weng-dammings-revival-of-the-family-business" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#weng-dammings-revival-of-the-family-business" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>In Taiwan, there are quite a few entrepreneurs skilled in financial leverage. Besides Chen Youhao, the president of the Tuntex Group, Weng Damming, the head of the Hualon Group, is also a master of this art.</p>
<p>Weng Damming, the head of the Hualon Group, became a highly controversial figure due to his unconventional style. After the death of his father, Weng Mingchang, Weng Damming shouldered the heavy responsibility of reviving the family business.  Starting in textiles, the Hualon Group owned Hualon Textile, Hualon Microelectronics, Yixin Trading, Jiashin Livestock, and Kuo Hua Life Insurance, among other affiliated companies.</p>
<p>Weng Damming adopted a high-leverage approach to business management. In 1994, the Hualon Group had total assets of 130 billion TWD and debts as high as over 50 billion TWD, of which over 30 billion TWD were short-term debts.  He used the stocks or real estate of affiliated companies as collateral for bank loans, with a pledge ratio of nearly 60%. Therefore, during the stock market crash and the real estate downturn, Weng Damming was troubled by rumors of financial difficulties.  Due to the sluggish stock and real estate markets, the collateral value of the Hualon Group was insufficient, requiring him to supplement the collateral or face the pressure of being &ldquo;liquidated.&rdquo; However, the seasoned Weng Damming, with his flexible financial management, once again demonstrated that the financial crisis was just a false alarm.</p>
<p>As Hualon Textile, the parent company of the Hualon Group, enjoyed stable profits and increased earnings with the gradual recovery of the textile industry, Weng Damming was able to borrow money fearlessly and aggressively expand into new businesses.  With a gambler&rsquo;s mentality, Weng Damming can be said to have maximized the principle of financial leverage. The story of this legendary figure shows us both the rewards and risks of leveraged investing.</p>
<p><strong>The Principle of Financial Leverage</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Act within your means; don&rsquo;t over-leverage, or you risk being shaken out.</li>
</ul>
<p>In finance, borrowing is known as &ldquo;financial leverage.&rdquo; Simply put, leverage is the principle of using a small force to achieve a large effect. Humans discovered the power of leverage early on and used it to move or lift heavy objects. The ancients used the principle of leverage to create magnificent engineering marvels such as the Great Wall and the pyramids. Modern wealthy individuals use the principle of financial leverage to create immense fortunes. Archimedes once said, &ldquo;Give me a place to stand, and I shall move the earth.&rdquo;  In investment management, financial leverage implies: &ldquo;Lend me enough money, and I can make any large investment.&rdquo;</p>
<p>Leveraged investing involves borrowing other people&rsquo;s money to make larger investments, thus utilizing the leverage effect.  Proper use of leverage can turn small amounts of money into large profits. Conversely, improper use can also lead to significant losses with small amounts of money. Here&rsquo;s an example to help readers understand how financial leverage works. Suppose you buy a house with 10 million in cash. A year later, you are fortunate enough to sell it for 13 million, making a 30% profit (R1). If you only paid 3 million in cash for the house and borrowed the remaining 7 million from the bank at a 10% interest rate, and then sold it for 13 million a year later, your profit margin would increase to 77% (R2).  Conversely, if the house price unfortunately drops by 30% after a year, and you sell it for 7 million, the person who bought it entirely in cash would lose 30% (R3). The investor who borrowed 7 million would see their loss expand to 123% (R4), meaning not only is the original investment lost, but they are also in debt. The calculation of the above rates of return is as follows:</p>
<p><math xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" display="block"><mtable displaystyle="true" columnalign="right center left" columnspacing="0 thickmathspace" rowspacing="3pt"><mtr><mtd><mi>R</mi><mn>1</mn></mtd><mtd><mi></mi><mo>=</mo></mtd><mtd><mi></mi><mo stretchy="false">(</mo><mn>1300</mn><mo>−</mo><mn>1000</mn><mo stretchy="false">)</mo><mrow><mo>/</mo></mrow><mn>1000</mn></mtd><mtd><mi></mi><mo>=</mo></mtd><mtd><mn>30</mn><mi mathvariant="normal">%</mi></mtd></mtr><mtr><mtd></mtd></mtr><mtr><mtd><mi>R</mi><mn>2</mn></mtd><mtd><mi></mi><mo>=</mo></mtd><mtd><mi></mi><mo stretchy="false">(</mo><mn>1300</mn><mo>−</mo><mn>1000</mn><mo>−</mo><mn>700</mn><mo>×</mo><mn>10</mn><mi mathvariant="normal">%</mi><mo stretchy="false">)</mo><mrow><mo>/</mo></mrow><mn>300</mn></mtd><mtd><mi></mi><mo>=</mo></mtd><mtd><mn>77</mn><mi mathvariant="normal">%</mi></mtd></mtr><mtr><mtd></mtd></mtr><mtr><mtd><mi>R</mi><mn>3</mn></mtd><mtd><mi></mi><mo>=</mo></mtd><mtd><mi></mi><mo stretchy="false">(</mo><mn>700</mn><mo>−</mo><mn>1000</mn><mo stretchy="false">)</mo><mrow><mo>/</mo></mrow><mn>1000</mn></mtd><mtd><mi></mi><mo>=</mo></mtd><mtd><mi></mi><mo>−</mo><mn>30</mn><mi mathvariant="normal">%</mi></mtd></mtr><mtr><mtd></mtd></mtr><mtr><mtd><mi>R</mi><mn>4</mn></mtd><mtd><mi></mi><mo>=</mo></mtd><mtd><mi></mi><mo stretchy="false">(</mo><mn>700</mn><mo>−</mo><mn>1000</mn><mo>−</mo><mn>700</mn><mo>×</mo><mn>10</mn><mi mathvariant="normal">%</mi><mo stretchy="false">)</mo><mrow><mo>/</mo></mrow><mn>300</mn></mtd><mtd><mi></mi><mo>=</mo></mtd><mtd><mi></mi><mo>−</mo><mn>123</mn><mi mathvariant="normal">%</mi></mtd></mtr><mtr><mtd></mtd></mtr><mtr><mtd><mo stretchy="false">(</mo><mo>Calculations in units of 10,000</mo><mo stretchy="false">)</mo></mtd></mtr></mtable></math></p>
<p>From the above example, we can clearly see how debt leverage exerts the power of &ldquo;using a small force to achieve a large effect.&rdquo; <strong>When the return on investment is higher than the interest rate on the loan, leveraged investing will increase the return on investment. When the return on investment is lower than the interest rate on the loan, the return on investment will decrease due to the borrowing.</strong></p>
<p>The main reason for the leverage effect is that loan interest is a cost that must be paid under any circumstances. Regardless of the investment return, the interest cost of borrowing remains fixed. Therefore, when the investment return is greater than the loan cost, the excess profit belongs to the borrower, creating a positive leverage effect and naturally increasing the return on investment of the principal. However, when the investment return is less than the loan interest cost, the borrower must bear the difference, resulting in a negative leverage effect, which reduces the return on the principal. This is especially true when the investment incurs a loss, as the borrowing cost will magnify the loss.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Financial leverage is like a seesaw,
It can lift you very high,
It can also cause you to fall hard.</p>
</blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">Two Major Principles of Borrowing 
    <div id="two-major-principles-of-borrowing" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#two-major-principles-of-borrowing" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>Financial leverage is like a seesaw: it can lift you very high or cause you to fall hard, depending on whether the leverage effect is positive or negative.  The key factor determining the direction of the leverage effect is which is higher: the return on investment or the interest rate on the loan. If the return on investment is greater than the interest rate, the leverage effect is positive. Conversely, if the return on investment is lower than the interest rate, the leverage effect becomes detrimental.</p>
<p><strong>Return on Investment Must Be Higher Than the Interest Rate</strong></p>
<p>Therefore, when deciding whether to use leveraged investing, the first things to consider are: What is the purpose of the loan? What is the expected return on investment for the target investment? Is it higher than the loan interest rate? If the return on investment of the targeted investment is significantly lower than the borrowing rate, the idea of leveraged investing should be dismissed early on. Otherwise, the result will certainly be detrimental rather than beneficial. If you can&rsquo;t understand what the expected return on investment is or whether the return is higher than the interest rate, then I advise you to understand these issues before borrowing!</p>
<p>Debt is synonymous with risk. Increasing debt increases risk and the possibility of personal or family bankruptcy. There are two major principles of leveraged investing:</p>
<ul>
<li>
<ol>
<li>The expected return on investment must be greater than the interest rate on the loan. For example, if the loan interest rate is 11%, it&rsquo;s only worthwhile if the after-tax return on investment is above 11%.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol start="2">
<li>In the worst-case scenario, your cash income must be sufficient to cover the principal and interest payments. For instance, if the investment price falls instead of rises after a few years, you must have enough cash income to repay the principal and interest on time.</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ul>
<p>Furthermore, investors must keep in mind that leveraged investing should not be based on the expectation that the price of the investment target will definitely rise, but rather on the preparation for a price drop.  Therefore, you should only engage in leveraged investing if you can still afford the interest payments even if the price continues to fall. You must also be able to withstand the psychological pressure that comes with leveraged investing.</p>
<p><strong>Avoiding Improper Borrowing</strong></p>
<p>Some readers may feel smug after reading this section because they are already engaged in what they consider leveraged investing. Upon further inquiry, however, it turns out they are borrowing money to buy lottery tickets, futures, or other speculative products, or even taking out loans to purchase consumer goods.  I must emphasize that these actions do not constitute proper &ldquo;leveraged investing.&rdquo;</p>
<p>Futures markets, margin trading (such as foreign exchange and bonds), or any gambling activities like lotteries and horse racing all have negative expected returns.  Long-term participation will inevitably lead to financial ruin.  Coupled with the deadly effect of borrowing, the result will undoubtedly be rapid bankruptcy.  Therefore, no matter how alluring these games are, remember:  It&rsquo;s okay to indulge occasionally for recreational purposes, but never borrow money to participate, or you will accelerate your path to bankruptcy with dire consequences.</p>
<p>Another point to remind readers of is to avoid borrowing money to purchase consumer goods. Borrowing to consume is like using future money to create &ldquo;false wealth.&rdquo; Unless absolutely necessary, the concept of borrowing for consumption should be avoided. Otherwise, the family&rsquo;s financial situation will be burdened.</p>
<p>For banks, consumer loans are extremely risky and require high interest rates.  Generally, consumer loan interest rates are above 10%.  Readers should understand that high-return investments have an amazing compounding effect.  Similarly, high-interest loans also have a dramatic compounding effect.  Take car loans, for example.  Assuming a 20% loan interest rate, after three and a half years, you will have to repay double the amount. This means that if you borrow money to buy a car now, three and a half years later, not only will the original car have depreciated significantly, but you will effectively have to pay for two new cars of the same model.  My advice on car loans is: don&rsquo;t take them. Wait until you can afford to pay in cash. Car loan interest rates are usually very high, often exceeding 15%, although there are occasional promotional periods with lower rates.  Fundamentally, except for commercial vehicles, cars are consumer goods with no investment return.  From an investment perspective, borrowing for car purchases is highly inadvisable.</p>
<p><strong>Uncontrolled Consumer Lending Easily Leads to Bankruptcy</strong></p>
<p>Credit cards, now a ubiquitous form of plastic currency worldwide, are also a typical example of consumer loans.  Since the popularization of credit cards, consumer behavior has undergone significant changes. While credit cards offer great convenience, their widespread use has led to a surge in bankruptcy cases among American families, with outstanding credit card debt exceeding 700 billion USD.  Some may wonder: how can credit cards lead to bankruptcy if you only spend what you have?  In fact, from a borrowing perspective, credit cards have an irresistible allure.</p>
<p>The greatest temptation of credit card borrowing lies in its simplicity.  With just a signature, you can make purchases in advance and even borrow cash from the bank, subtly inflating your spending power.  Remember: when using credit cards, never spend more than you can afford to repay each month.  Credit card interest rates are often above 20%, so you should always pay off your credit card balance promptly.  My advice is: &ldquo;If you can&rsquo;t control your spending urges, it&rsquo;s best not to apply for a credit card. If you apply for one for convenience, never use it for the sake of credit.  Use it only when it truly offers convenience.&rdquo;</p>
<p>While using credit cards for borrowing is convenient, those who entertain this idea should first understand the destructive power of a 20% interest rate. As mentioned earlier, if you save 14,000 per year and invest it in an investment tool with a 20% annual return, after 40 years, the 560,000 invested will grow to 102.81 million due to the power of compounding. Similarly, if someone borrows 14,000 per year on a credit card for 40 years, totaling 560,000, with a 20% interest rate, they will have to repay the bank 102.81 million after 40 years. This explains why the prevalence of credit card debt in the United States has historically led to numerous bankruptcies.</p>
<p>Another common type of loan is a mortgage.  Generally, mortgages are a sound form of leveraged investing because, in the long run, the average return on real estate is above 20%, while typical mortgage interest rates are around 10%, which meets the first principle of leveraged investing: the expected return on investment is higher than the interest rate on the loan. Whether it meets the second principle depends on the purchase conditions. In recent years, with the real estate market downturn and oversupply, some pre-sale housing promotions offer &ldquo;70% financing,&rdquo; allowing you to own a 10 million house with only a 3 million down payment. This is quite appealing, but investors often overlook the fact that while borrowing 7 million sounds great, they must be able to afford the monthly principal and interest payments of over 70,000. Without considering this, there is a risk of foreclosure and being forced to sell at a low price within months of purchase, suffering losses before enjoying any benefits of leveraged investing. Therefore, when purchasing real estate with borrowed funds, careful calculations must be made beforehand to choose a suitable house price that does not jeopardize the family&rsquo;s normal living expenses.</p>
<p>Although the initial burden of a mortgage is heavy, it becomes lighter over time as work experience and salary increase.  If you wait until you have saved enough money to buy a house, you might miss the opportunity entirely due to the rapid appreciation of house prices. Therefore, <strong>young people without real estate should consider buying a house as an investment. It not only forces them to save but also effectively combats inflation. Moreover, they can utilize the principle of financial leverage, using the bank&rsquo;s money to expand their credit and accumulate wealth.</strong></p>
<p><strong>How Much Debt Should You Take On?</strong></p>
<p>If you decide to use leveraged investing, the next question is: how much debt should you take on? This is a crucial question. Too much debt carries high risks, while too little debt fails to fully utilize the potential of making money with other people&rsquo;s money.</p>
<p>How much debt should a family take on?  Like &ldquo;how much debt should a company have,&rdquo; this is a question without a precise answer. In practice, it depends on the specific circumstances of each family. However, one thing is certain: if a family has the capacity to borrow but chooses not to, it is being too conservative and not managing its finances optimally. Conversely, excessive borrowing is too dangerous.  Before taking on debt, each family should consider its actual situation and make a wise judgment about its debt level.  As for how much to borrow, I recommend considering the following factors:</p>
<ul>
<li>
<ol>
<li>Income Stability:  Loan interest must be paid on time regardless of investment performance. If your income source is unstable, you may not be able to make regular interest payments, making high-leverage investments unsuitable. Similar to companies with stable income, they have a greater capacity to utilize more debt.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol start="2">
<li>Personal Assets: Borrowing from financial institutions requires tangible assets as collateral. Therefore, owning more assets suitable as collateral allows for larger leveraged investments.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol start="3">
<li>Return on Investment: Other things being equal, the higher the return on investment, the greater the benefits of financial leverage.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol start="4">
<li>Inflation Rate: Borrowing is more advantageous during periods of high inflation, as inflation allows you to repay debt with less valuable money.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol start="5">
<li>Risk Tolerance: Everyone has a different risk tolerance, related to personality and individual circumstances. Those with low risk tolerance should not over-leverage, even if it could lead to large profits, as the stress could take a toll.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol start="6">
<li>Market Interest Rate Levels: Generally, when market interest rates fall and bank funds are ample, not only is it easier for investors to borrow money, but the benefits of financial leverage are also greater. Therefore, falling interest rates present an opportune time for investors to consider leveraged investing.</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>Keeping money in the bank makes a person poor.</p>
</blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">The Bank is Not a Place for Saving Money 
    <div id="the-bank-is-not-a-place-for-saving-money" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#the-bank-is-not-a-place-for-saving-money" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>What is the function of a bank to you? Many people believe banks are for saving money. However, for those who truly understand investment management, banks are not a place to save money, but a source of borrowing.</p>
<p><strong>The function of a bank is to provide a place for those who are not good at managing money to save, so that those who are good at it can use that money to invest and make profits.</strong> Suppose someone deposits 14,000 per year into a bank at a 5% interest rate. After 40 years, the bank will owe this depositor 1.69 million. On the other hand, if an investor borrows 14,000 per year from the same bank at the same 5% interest rate and invests that money in stocks or real estate, achieving an average annual return of 20%, after 40 years, their investment would grow to 102.81 million, while they only need to repay the bank 1.69 million. In other words, the 101.12 million gained was made by utilizing the money of bank depositors.</p>
<p><strong>How to Build Credit</strong></p>
<p>In today&rsquo;s highly developed financial markets, there are numerous financing channels for businesses. However, for individuals, banks remain the primary source of borrowing.  Maintaining a close relationship with the bank and earning their trust is crucial for building personal credit.</p>
<p>Credit is the ability to borrow.  A person with high credit not only demonstrates a strong ability to repay loans but also indicates wealth. How do you build credit?  As the saying goes, &ldquo;Loan and repay, and borrowing again is easy.&rdquo; The first rule of building credit is to borrow money and repay it on time. Some people, to establish their creditworthiness (the ability to borrow), even borrow small sums of money for seemingly frivolous reasons, just to build a good borrowing record so they can borrow larger amounts in the future.</p>
<p>Discard the outdated notion that &ldquo;borrowing is not respectable.&rdquo; In the past, only those in dire financial straits would borrow money. Nowadays, such individuals can at most borrow small amounts from relatives and friends.  They would likely be unable to borrow a cent from a bank.  Today, those who can borrow from banks are typically wealthy individuals.</p>
<p>Based on current bank loan approval standards, without sufficient assets as collateral or evidence of stable future income and repayment ability, can anyone borrow money? Therefore, when I hear about someone heavily in debt, my first question is whether the source of the debt is banks or private loans.  If the source is entirely from banks, my immediate thought is: &ldquo;This person must be wealthy.&rdquo;</p>
<p><strong>Borrowing: A Double-Edged Sword</strong></p>
<p>Those who don&rsquo;t borrow cannot go bankrupt; similarly, those who don&rsquo;t borrow can hardly become immensely wealthy in a short period.  &ldquo;Debt&rdquo; appears in the lives of both the most successful and the most unsuccessful. While many wealthy individuals utilize debt to become rich, many poor people are ruined by misusing debt. Borrowing is a double-edged sword. Used correctly, it is a significant aid to investment and wealth creation. Used improperly, its destructive power can lead to complete ruin.  Prudence is essential when using it. It&rsquo;s like a double-edged sword that can save or harm, depending on how it&rsquo;s wielded.</p>
<p>I advise against rushing into leveraged investing before fully understanding its principles.  First, understand the nature of leveraged investing and carefully consider whether to use borrowing for investment.  Before borrowing, thoroughly understand how leveraged investing works. Only then can you truly achieve the goal of making money with other people&rsquo;s money without harming yourself.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Personal Investment Bible: Investment Iron Law V</title>
      <link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1731056005964/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1731056005964/</guid>
      <description>This article explores the relationship between risk and return in investment and financial management, emphasizing the importance of risk management.  It points out that all high-return investments come with high risks, and while risk aversion is human nature, excessive risk aversion can lead to missed opportunities. Using Forbes&amp;#39; philosophy on risk as an example, the author illustrates how to assess risks and rewards, advocating for calculated risks with adequate preparation.  The article also cautions readers against being seduced by high-risk, low-return speculative activities, encouraging them to start with small investments to gain experience, gradually overcome their fear of risk, and ultimately master risk to achieve wealth growth.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[

<h2 class="relative group">Investment Iron Law V: Mitigating Investment Risk 
    <div id="investment-iron-law-v-mitigating-investment-risk" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#investment-iron-law-v-mitigating-investment-risk" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>Investment and financial management should never prioritize returns while neglecting risks.</p>
</blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">Analyzing Risk, Minimizing Damage 
    <div id="analyzing-risk-minimizing-damage" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#analyzing-risk-minimizing-damage" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>In 1987, while working at Merrill Lynch in the United States, I met a seasoned investment veteran with decades of Wall Street experience. He once said, &ldquo;I can teach you how to pick stocks in an hour, but it would take me more than five years to teach you how to manage investment risk.&rdquo;</p>
<p><strong>Risk is Unavoidable</strong></p>
<p>In the ever-changing and unpredictable world of investment, uncertainties abound. We call these uncertainties risks. How you face these risks when they materialize is a question every investor must confront. <strong>Risk is called risk precisely because future outcomes are uncertain and unavoidable.</strong> Therefore, investment and financial management should never solely focus on returns while ignoring risks. In fact, managing risk is even more crucial. <strong>The purpose of risk management is not to eliminate risk entirely, but to acknowledge its inherent existence and impossibility of complete eradication.  It&rsquo;s about analyzing risk and subsequently mitigating it.</strong></p>
<p>While engaging in risk management, investors must understand that &ldquo;you can never be fully prepared for every risk.&rdquo;  You can strive to reduce risk, but don&rsquo;t attempt to eliminate it completely. Many try to avoid risk through predictions or expert advice.  However, no matter how accurate your forecasting techniques or how insightful the expert predictions, risk can never be fully avoided. <strong>The greatest danger of predictions is not their frequent inaccuracy, but the tendency for investors to blindly trust them, losing their risk awareness. They focus solely on whether the prediction comes true, neglecting the potential magnitude of the underlying risks.</strong>  Relying solely on predictions without thorough risk analysis is extremely dangerous. Any sound investment decision inherently involves unknowns, uncertainties, and risks.  Furthermore, investments without uncertainties and a degree of risk are unlikely to be good investments.</p>
<p><strong>All High-Return Investments Carry High Risks</strong></p>
<p>The key to successful investment and financial management lies in learning to grasp high returns while effectively managing the accompanying risks.</p>
<p>The investment environment is constantly changing and unpredictable. The only constant is change. Some external factors (such as interest rates, exchange rates, economic conditions, and inflation rates) are bound to change, although the nature of these changes remains unknown.  Additionally, unforeseen events (such as wars, political events, and natural disasters) are uncontrollable variables.  To succeed in this volatile investment world, the most important thing is not to lament change but to accept it as inevitable. <strong>Prepare for various changes and even anticipate them, because only through change can wealth be redistributed.</strong> Change is both a threat and an opportunity, depending on how you respond.  Skilled investors often find profitable opportunities amidst change.</p>
<p>People often assume investors love risk.  This is not true.  Successful investors possess a unique ability to manage risk. They don&rsquo;t see &ldquo;risk-taking&rdquo; as a source of amusement, nor do they find the act of taking risks thrilling or exciting. They take risks solely for the potential of high investment returns.  Since all high-return investments inherently carry high risks, risk-taking is an unavoidable part of the journey to financial success.</p>
<p>Many perceive stock investment as extremely risky, believing stock investors to be risk-seekers. In reality, investing in stocks is not about loving the risk associated with stocks. It&rsquo;s about understanding that all high-return investments carry high risks. To build wealth, you must take the risk of investing in high-return assets and bear the associated risks.  Savvy investors understand how to take calculated risks and mitigate them.  In fact, if risk mitigation measures are implemented effectively, the actual risks of investment and financial management are relatively small.</p>
<p><strong>Stocks and real estate offer high returns precisely because of their inherent volatility and risk.</strong> Because most people are risk-averse and avoid investing in risky assets like stocks and real estate, those who can tolerate risk are better positioned to reap higher returns.</p>
<p>Many shy away from stocks and real estate primarily because they fear losses, are intimidated by future uncertainties, or can&rsquo;t handle price fluctuations. <strong>In fact, short-term price fluctuations are perfectly normal and highlight the high-risk nature of high-return investments.</strong> Therefore, to achieve high returns, one must possess a spirit of adventure and be able to withstand significant volatility.</p>
<p><em>1. Unpredictable risks allow risk-takers to earn a risk premium.</em></p>
<p><em>2. We miss opportunities because we are afraid to take risks, not because the world doesn&rsquo;t offer them.</em></p>
<p><em>3. To achieve financial success through investment, you must take risks, because high returns always come with high risks.</em></p>
<blockquote>
<p>I dislike taking unnecessary risks, so before every activity, I do my best to take necessary precautions to mitigate risk.</p>
</blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">The Forbes Philosophy on Risk 
    <div id="the-forbes-philosophy-on-risk" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#the-forbes-philosophy-on-risk" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>Malcolm Forbes was a legendary figure in the American business world.  He amassed a fortune by founding Forbes magazine, possessed a priceless collection, and was listed among the 400 wealthiest Americans. He not only ran a high-risk magazine business but was also a renowned hot air balloonist and motorcycle enthusiast.  He once rode a motorcycle across Eurasia from Paris to Beijing.  He traveled the world, flying hot air balloons across the United States, and even ventured to Turkey and China, setting multiple world records and attracting widespread media attention, making him a household name.</p>
<p><strong>Averting Danger Before it Happens, Ensuring Safety</strong></p>
<p>Some labeled him an &ldquo;adventurer.&rdquo;  He offered an insightful explanation of this label, saying, &ldquo;Many people think I&rsquo;m a risk-lover.  I&rsquo;m not. Like most people, I strongly dislike risk. The reason I take risks today, despite my aversion to them, is simple: all good things in life come with risks. I take risks purely to live a rich and fulfilling life.”  &ldquo;Riding in a hot air balloon or on a motorcycle across different lands broadens one&rsquo;s horizons and exposes one to the world&rsquo;s beauty, enriching life. However, many people, despite yearning for these experiences, hesitate to engage in them because they perceive them as high-risk activities. But, once you actually try them, you&rsquo;ll find that if you take adequate precautions beforehand, the risks involved are quite small.” &ldquo;I dislike taking unnecessary risks, so before every activity, I strive to take the necessary preventative measures to mitigate risk.&rdquo;</p>
<p>Malcolm Forbes was risk-averse, but he took risks to experience the good things in life, and after taking those risks, he sought ways to mitigate them.</p>
<p><strong>Assess the Rewards and Risks, If It&rsquo;s Worth It – Take the Risk</strong></p>
<p>Are you afraid of taking risks? If so, you are not alone.  Most people are afraid of taking risks; very few are natural risk-takers.  But why are some people so composed in the face of risk, and even achieve success through it?  It&rsquo;s because they understand the principles of &ldquo;nothing ventured, nothing gained&rdquo; and &ldquo;no high risk, no high return.&rdquo;  Indeed, the correct perspective on risk should be: take risks worth taking, and then find ways to mitigate them.</p>
<p>Successful investors are driven by the pursuit of &ldquo;wealth.&rdquo; Although they must be prepared to withstand the pressure of price fluctuations, as long as the expected return is high and there&rsquo;s a risk premium, risk-taking will ultimately lead to success.</p>
<p>Before every investment, it&rsquo;s essential to understand the potential risks and develop contingency plans for every possible scenario. Analyze the degree of blind risk-taking, estimate the probability of success, and continuously re-evaluate throughout the process. I recommend investors create a risk-reward assessment table before making any investment, weighing all factors.  Ask yourself, &ldquo;Can I bear the consequences if the worst-case scenario unfolds?&rdquo; and &ldquo;Is the potential return of this investment attractive enough?&rdquo;</p>
<p>Always plan for the worst and prepare for the best. This is especially true for investment and financial management.  <strong>Before making any investment, no matter how confident you are, you should ask yourself, &ldquo;What is the worst possible outcome?&rdquo; Then ask, &ldquo;Can I bear the consequences if the worst happens?&rdquo; If the answer to both questions is yes, and the expected return is high enough, then you should invest. If the worst-case scenario is unbearable, then no matter how alluring the potential reward, you should categorically refuse to invest.</strong></p>
<p><strong>Don&rsquo;t Take Unnecessary Risks</strong></p>
<p>If you ever visit Las Vegas or Atlantic City, observe the lavishly decorated casinos carefully. You&rsquo;ll notice the absence of clocks and windows, and the ever-present bright lights.  &ldquo;There&rsquo;s no time in the mountains, and no time in casinos.&rdquo; Why are there no clocks or windows in casinos?  It&rsquo;s because casinos leverage the law of large numbers to win your money.  The lack of clocks and windows is designed to blur the lines between day and night, encouraging gamblers to play endlessly until they lose track of time. The longer you play, the more times you play, the higher the probability of the casino winning.  As the number of games increases, the expected value gradually reveals itself.  Gambling inevitably leads to losses because its expected value is negative.  This might not be apparent in a few instances, but over time, the expected value becomes increasingly evident. Therefore, prolonged gambling inevitably leads to losses.  This explains the saying &ldquo;nine out of ten gamblers lose&rdquo; and &ldquo;long-term gambling leads to certain loss,&rdquo; which aligns perfectly with the principle of the law of large numbers. The law of large numbers states that the more times a game is played, the closer the return gets to the expected value of that game.</p>
<p>I had a classmate in the doctoral program at UC Berkeley who excelled in mathematics and frequented Las Vegas casinos on weekends.  Curious, I asked him, &ldquo;You&rsquo;re so smart and you know that gambling is designed against the players. Are you trying to win money?&rdquo;  He replied, &ldquo;I never go there to win money. I gamble to relieve stress.&rdquo;  He explained that after a heartbreak in college, he tried various methods to cope, such as drinking, speeding, and traveling, but none were effective.  He eventually found that only gambling could allow him to truly escape. Gambling can be a form of entertainment, but it&rsquo;s certainly not a way to make money. Its expected average return is lower than bank deposits, making it impossible to build wealth through such activities.</p>
<p>Many people hold the misconception that &ldquo;high risk always equates to high return.&rdquo; This misunderstanding stems from a misinterpretation of the definition of &ldquo;return.&rdquo; High risk might indeed offer high potential returns, but this represents the maximum possible return, which has a very low probability.  However, in the context of &ldquo;high risk, high return,&rdquo; the &ldquo;return&rdquo; refers to the expected return (long-term average return), not the maximum possible return.  Indeed, gambling boasts incredibly high maximum potential returns, but its average, or expected, return is negative. Taking such risks is not only unprofitable but also detrimental.</p>
<p><strong>There are No High-Return, Zero-Risk Investments</strong></p>
<p>Success requires risk-taking, but risk-taking doesn&rsquo;t guarantee success.  One must take calculated risks. A calculated risk is one that, on average, offers high returns over the long term.</p>
<p>Some people&rsquo;s problem isn&rsquo;t a lack of risk-taking spirit but a tendency to take unnecessary risks. They don&rsquo;t know what risks to take to achieve financial success. As detailed in previous chapters, the cornerstone of investment success is the power of compounding, which only works effectively with high returns.  Over the long term, stocks and real estate are asset classes that offer high expected returns.  Therefore, taking calculated risks means investing in assets with high expected returns and bravely bearing the associated risks.</p>
<p>Consider a game where participants must pay $100. There&rsquo;s a 99.9% chance of losing $100 and a 0.1% chance of winning $95,000. Would you play?  In a survey I conducted with hundreds of students, over 65% chose to play this high-risk game.  Their reasoning was simple: while the risk was high, the potential loss was capped at $100, while the potential gain was a whopping $95,000.  However, the expected return of this game is negative.  Even if you get lucky and win once, in the long run, you&rsquo;re bound to lose.  This is a classic example of a risk not worth taking.</p>
<p>Avoid risks that don&rsquo;t offer high returns. Activities like futures trading, margin trading in foreign exchange and bonds, lotteries, and short-term stock trading all carry high risks and often have negative returns.  In other words, these are high-risk, negative-return activities.  You can engage in these activities for entertainment, but never delude yourself into believing they will bring you wealth.</p>
<p><strong>There are no high-return, zero-risk investment opportunities.</strong> In a society filled with intelligent individuals, such opportunities are impossible. If someone offers you a high-return, risk-free investment opportunity, they are undoubtedly trying to scam you.</p>
<p>I remind readers again: don&rsquo;t blindly chase high returns and jump into risky ventures.  Speculative activities like those mentioned above are not truly high-return investment tools, but they are definitely high-risk endeavors.  These risks are not worth taking.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Absolute safety is a myth. The real danger is not taking any risks. In a volatile environment, the biggest risk is not taking any risks.</p>
</blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">Don&rsquo;t Shy Away from Risk Entirely 
    <div id="dont-shy-away-from-risk-entirely" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#dont-shy-away-from-risk-entirely" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>The future world is changing rapidly.  Changes will accelerate across all aspects of business, economics, finance, politics, and society, creating a more complex financial landscape.  <strong>It&rsquo;s foreseeable that wealth redistribution will also accelerate.</strong> Risk aversion is human nature.  In the past, you could live a stable life without taking risks.  However, <strong>in the face of the volatile investment environment of the future, not taking risks becomes the biggest risk of all.</strong></p>
<p><strong>Fear of Falling Will Keep You from Running Fast</strong></p>
<p>Fear of risk prevents many from investing, causing them to miss out on the opportunity to build wealth.  Keeping money in a bank seems safe and risk-free. However, as previously analyzed, inflation severely erodes the real value of money.  From a financial management perspective, keeping money in a bank carries the greatest risk.  Decades later, when those around you who invested wisely become millionaires, those who kept their money in banks may face financial hardship.  My point is: don&rsquo;t shy away from risk entirely. Risk isn&rsquo;t as terrifying as it seems.  Taking calculated risks with high potential returns is absolutely worthwhile.</p>
<p>I&rsquo;m often asked, &ldquo;Teacher, will the stock market fall again?&rdquo; My answer is, &ldquo;I don&rsquo;t know.&rdquo;  Then they ask, &ldquo;When will it start rising?&rdquo; My answer remains, &ldquo;I don&rsquo;t know.&rdquo;  They further inquire, &ldquo;Which stock should I buy?  Can you give me a hot tip?&rdquo; My answer is still, &ldquo;I don&rsquo;t know.&rdquo;  Then they question skeptically, &ldquo;How can you invest when you don&rsquo;t know anything? Isn&rsquo;t that too risky?&rdquo; My response is, &ldquo;You must invest and manage your finances without knowing the answers to these questions to succeed.&rdquo;</p>
<p>Why invest when the answers are unknown and the future is uncertain? The reason is simple: While the future is full of risks, one thing is certain: as long as the economy continues to grow and corporate profitability rises, the long-term return on investment in the stock market will inevitably surpass bank deposits, and by a significant margin.  Repeatedly avoiding worthwhile risks will prevent you from building wealth.</p>
<p><strong>How to Cultivate a Risk-Taking Spirit</strong></p>
<p><em>A courageous risk-taker is not someone without fear, but someone with the power to overcome it.</em></p>
<p>The spirit of adventure isn&rsquo;t innate; it&rsquo;s developed through practice, through taking risks, failing, taking risks again, failing again… step by step.</p>
<p>Everyone is capable of taking risks, and everyone has had the experience of taking bold risks.  As toddlers, we dared to stand and learn to walk, falling and getting back up countless times.  Learning to ride a bicycle involved numerous falls, followed by getting back up, falling again, and getting back up again, until we finally mastered it. Most life skills, such as swimming, skating, driving, public speaking, and so on, are not innate instincts.  Learning these skills requires going through a phase of risk-taking, embracing the spirit of perseverance, and trying repeatedly.  Learning investment and financial management is no exception; it requires this standard process of risk-taking.  To become a successful investor, you must first discard the habit of risk aversion, rediscover your lost instinct for adventure, and cultivate a healthy risk-taking spirit.</p>
<p>Does investing have to be extremely risky?  In reality, the risks involved in investment and financial management are no greater than the examples mentioned above.  It&rsquo;s just that as we reach an age where we believe we are qualified to manage finances, our risk-taking spirit has diminished significantly. As children, almost everyone learns to walk.  A little older, most learn to ride a bicycle.  But as we grow older, the number of people who learn more adventurous activities like swimming and skating decreases considerably.  In adulthood, the number of people comfortable with public speaking dwindles even further.</p>
<p><strong>Our risk-taking spirit seems to fade with age.  This is partly because experiencing failures and mistakes naturally leads to frustration and discouragement. Without sufficient motivation, we tend to avoid taking risks to minimize the blow of failure.  Another contributing factor is traditional education.  Out of a desire to protect children, adults often reprimand them for any risky behavior, instilling a habit of prioritizing safety and avoiding mistakes.  Children then strive to be &ldquo;good kids&rdquo; who never do anything wrong.  As we age, this risk aversion becomes ingrained. While avoiding risk isn&rsquo;t inherently bad, excessive risk aversion becomes a significant obstacle to successful investment and financial management.</strong></p>
<p><strong>The First Priority of Financial Management: Overcoming Fear</strong></p>
<p>When individuals can control their fear, they can control their thoughts and actions.  Self-control enables them to remain calm in chaotic environments, make necessary decisions without being paralyzed by the uncertainty of the outcomes, and be prepared to bear the consequences of failure when things don&rsquo;t go as planned. This courage and risk-taking spirit in the face of danger are essential qualities for investors.</p>
<p><strong>Courageous risk-takers are not fearless; they simply recognize risk and overcome their fear of it.</strong> Courage stems from controlling fear, and cultivating a risk-taking spirit begins with understanding risk.</p>
<p>To become a successful investor, you must first discard the habit of avoiding risk.  Admittedly, changing long-held risk-averse habits is no easy feat.  However, since risk-taking is an indispensable element of successful financial management, the first priority in learning to manage your finances is to overcome fear and force yourself to take risks.  Cultivate a healthy risk-taking spirit, invest bravely in assets with high expected returns, and bear the associated risks.</p>
<p><strong>Top performers in any field achieve success by bravely facing their fears and taking calculated risks.</strong> Those who achieve financial success and fulfill their dreams through investment share this same spirit of adventure. <strong>Remember: excessive caution hinders success.  Without a spirit of adventure, dreams will forever remain dreams.</strong></p>
<blockquote>
<p>Mastering risk is the foundation of successful financial management.</p>
</blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">Overcoming Risk – Start Small 
    <div id="overcoming-risk--start-small" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#overcoming-risk--start-small" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>Skilled risk-takers never test the depth of the water by stepping in with both feet. They extend one foot first, and if the situation seems unfavorable, they quickly withdraw.  An African proverb states, &ldquo;Only a fool tests the depth of the water with both feet.&rdquo;  Similarly, only a fool would go all-in without any investment experience.</p>
<p><strong>Gain Experience with Small Amounts of Money</strong></p>
<p>When faced with unfamiliar investment opportunities, don&rsquo;t put all your eggs in one basket. Start small.  Skilled generals don&rsquo;t expose their main forces to unnecessary danger.  To gather intelligence and gain an advantage, they deploy small reconnaissance units deep into enemy territory to identify low-risk, high-impact attack strategies.</p>
<p>The same principle applies to investment risk-taking strategies.  When dealing with unfamiliar investments, unclear situations, or a lack of confidence, avoid going all-in.  Start small, using small amounts of money to gain experience and familiarize yourself with the situation. Once you have sufficient experience and confidence, then you can invest larger sums.</p>
<p>As the saying goes, &ldquo;All things are difficult before they are easy.&rdquo; The best way to overcome fear is to confront what you fear head-on.  Since risk-taking is an essential part of building wealth through investment, don&rsquo;t shy away from it.  Start with small investments to build your risk tolerance.  With experience, the feeling of fear will gradually dissipate.  By progressively overcoming small fears, you can then face larger risks. You&rsquo;ll soon discover that the experience gained through risk-taking is helping you steadily approach your dreams.</p>
<p><strong>Once You&rsquo;re Used to Risk, You&rsquo;ll Find It&rsquo;s Not So Scary</strong></p>
<p>Risk aversion is human nature, but don&rsquo;t let a single investment failure shatter your confidence and prevent you from investing again, turning you into a perpetual loser.  Conversely, don&rsquo;t let a stroke of good luck make you forget the existence of risk, leading you to borrow heavily and invest recklessly, resulting in irreparable losses.  Successful and unsuccessful investors alike fear risk; they simply react to it differently.</p>
<p>Dear readers, if you haven&rsquo;t tried investing yet, take the plunge for the sake of building wealth!  If you take appropriate risk mitigation measures after investing, I can assure you from experience: &ldquo;The risks of investing are actually quite small, even smaller than the risk of riding a bicycle.  After 10 or 20 years of investing, when you see your wealth growing rapidly, the feeling will be hundreds of times better than riding a bicycle.&rdquo;</p>
<p><strong>The first element of investing is a strong adventurous spirit, seeking to generate substantial risk premiums between risk and safety.</strong> No matter what investment you choose, as long as it offers high expected returns, risk is inevitable. Investors should embrace calculated risks and accumulate financial knowledge and experience along the way. Risk naturally decreases with accumulated knowledge, and wealth grows at an increasing pace.</p>
<p>This book dedicates significant space to discussing risk because the biggest challenge people face in financial management is their inability to confront risk directly.  They don&rsquo;t know how to face or manage risk, and some are even afraid to take any risks.  They don&rsquo;t realize that the biggest obstacle to successful investment and financial management is the fear of risk. This mindset is understandable, as most investment and financial management decisions are made amidst uncertainty and change. In short, to achieve financial success through investment, you must be willing to take calculated risks. Currently, many people suffer significant losses due to blind risk-taking and involvement in high-risk speculative activities.</p>
<p>If you are unwilling to take risks and prefer a conservative approach, be prepared for a life of mediocrity, as this is unavoidable. Of course, there&rsquo;s nothing wrong with a conservative and mediocre life if it brings you happiness. The choice is yours. <strong>People usually regret the things they didn&rsquo;t do, not the things they tried.</strong> Therefore, my advice is: <strong>Take risks, but be cautious and learn how to manage them.</strong></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Personal Investment Bible: Investment Iron Law I</title>
      <link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1731056005960/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1731056005960/</guid>
      <description>This article criticizes the traditional financial concept of “saving money in the bank”.  It points out that under inflation, low bank deposit interest rates struggle to withstand erosion from inflation, effectively resulting in “the more you save, the less you have”. This viewpoint is supported by examples from biblical stories, savings rate data, and the Nobel Prize Foundation&amp;#39;s case, encouraging readers to invest their funds in long-term, high-return investment tools like stocks and real estate to achieve wealth appreciation.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[

<h2 class="relative group">Investment Iron Law I: Don&rsquo;t Keep Your Money in the Bank 
    <div id="investment-iron-law-i-dont-keep-your-money-in-the-bank" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#investment-iron-law-i-dont-keep-your-money-in-the-bank" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>The vast majority of people who fail at financial management don&rsquo;t do so because they don&rsquo;t earn enough,
but because they put their assets in the wrong place.
Have you ever heard of anyone getting rich from bank savings?</p>
</blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">Saving Equals Wasting Resources 
    <div id="saving-equals-wasting-resources" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#saving-equals-wasting-resources" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>There&rsquo;s a parable in the Bible about financial stewardship. A landowner entrusted his property to three servants. He gave the first servant five units of money, the second two, and the third one. He told them to cherish and manage their wealth wisely, and he would return in a year to see how they had fared.</p>
<p><strong>Wasting Time and Money</strong></p>
<p>The first servant invested his money; the second bought raw materials and produced goods to sell; the third, for safety, buried his money under a tree. A year later, the landowner returned.  The first two servants had doubled their wealth, pleasing the landowner.  Only the third servant&rsquo;s money remained unchanged. He explained, &ldquo;Fearing loss through mismanagement, I kept the money safe. Today, I return it untouched.&rdquo;</p>
<p>The landowner was furious.  &ldquo;You lazy servant!&rdquo; he scolded. &ldquo;You didn&rsquo;t even try to utilize your wealth!&rdquo;  Wealth not utilized is wasted money and wasted potential. The third servant was rebuked not for misusing the money, nor for losing it through failed investments, but for keeping it &ldquo;safe&rdquo; and unproductive.</p>
<p>Keeping money in the bank is the most common approach to personal finance today, and also the biggest mistake people make.  Therefore, the first and most important financial rule this book offers is: <em>Don&rsquo;t keep your money in the bank.</em>  &ldquo;Bank&rdquo; here refers to post offices, commercial banks, and any other financial institution where money can be deposited.</p>
<p>Many believe that earning interest in a bank, benefiting from compound interest, constitutes sound financial planning. In reality, with inflation, the real rate of return is close to zero, meaning no real financial gain. Therefore, leaving money in the bank is equivalent to no financial management at all.</p>
<p>It&rsquo;s impossible to predict how much wealth each person will accumulate through financial management. The only certainty is that getting rich solely through bank savings is incredibly difficult.  Ask yourself, &ldquo;Have you ever heard of anyone getting rich purely from bank deposits?&rdquo;  Those who keep all their savings in the bank often find themselves not only failing to become wealthy in their old age but also struggling to maintain financial independence. Such stories are common.  Those who choose bank deposits as their primary financial management method do so primarily for safety. However, readers must understand:  <strong>&ldquo;Money in the bank is safest in the short term, but the most dangerous form of financial management in the long term.&rdquo;</strong></p>
<p><strong>Blind Spots in Personal Finance</strong></p>
<p><em>Most people manage their finances by keeping their money in the bank, so most people are not wealthy.</em></p>
<p>If accumulating immense wealth were as easy as the examples suggest, then most people over 65 today would be millionaires. However, this is far from reality.  Millionaires over 65 are few and far between, with many senior citizens facing financial hardship, relying on continued work or support from their children to make ends meet.</p>
<p>Surveys on the elderly in Taiwan reveal increasingly serious financial challenges for senior citizens.  Among approximately 1.48 million people aged 65 and above, about 13% rely on financial assistance from family and friends or social welfare.  This demonstrates a serious problem with most people&rsquo;s financial concepts and investment methods. How else could they reach old age not only without wealth but without even basic financial independence?</p>
<p>Taiwan&rsquo;s savings rate has historically been above 30%, currently hovering between 20% and 30%, consistently ranking among the highest globally. This indicates excellent performance in saving and budgeting. Consequently, we can deduce that flawed financial management is the primary reason for the lack of financial independence among ordinary people. To understand where they go wrong, we must first observe how they handle their assets. In various lectures, I often ask the audience, &ldquo;How are your assets stored?&rdquo;  The majority answer: &ldquo;In the bank.&rdquo;</p>
<p><strong>Prioritizing Security over Investment</strong></p>
<p>Surveys on Taiwanese household investment preferences reveal that the top three investment choices are demand deposits (72%), rotating savings and credit associations (53%), and time deposits (36%). Clearly, most people lean towards traditional financial methods.  Furthermore, when asked, &ldquo;If you had 10 million Taiwan dollars in savings, how would you use it?&rdquo;, about 41% of surveyed households said they would deposit it in a financial institution to earn interest. This illustrates the widespread preference for bank savings.</p>
<p>Indeed, people have high savings rates and a strong preference for depositing money in financial institutions to earn interest.  In early 1996, total deposits in Taiwanese financial institutions reached 12.6 trillion Taiwan dollars.  With a population of 21 million, this translates to an average deposit of 600,000 Taiwan dollars per person, regardless of age.  For an average family of four, this amounts to 2.4 million Taiwan dollars.  This demonstrates a strong inclination towards bank savings. However, this traditional and conservative approach is the primary reason why most people fail to achieve wealth through investment.</p>
<p>This phenomenon reveals an over-reliance on traditional bank deposits for financial management. People prioritize safety and convenience over the rate of return. However, focusing solely on earning and saving money, then depositing it in a bank, is often the first step towards financial mismanagement.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Keeping money in the bank is like having no financial plan at all.</p>
</blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">Deposit Interest Rates Lack True Compound Interest Benefits 
    <div id="deposit-interest-rates-lack-true-compound-interest-benefits" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#deposit-interest-rates-lack-true-compound-interest-benefits" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>What&rsquo;s wrong with bank deposits? The problem lies in the low interest rates (return on investment), making them unsuitable for long-term investment tools.</p>
<p>How much interest can bank deposits earn?  The salaries of average office workers are usually directly deposited into demand deposit accounts (current interest rates around 2%-4%). A portion serves as temporary funds or covers daily expenses, while the remainder is transferred to time deposits (current interest rates around 5%-8%) for investment purposes. Thus, the average interest rate earned on bank deposits is about 5%.</p>
<p><strong>5% Interest is Hardly a Path to Wealth</strong></p>
<p>Most people have a basic understanding of compound interest, believing that interest earned on bank deposits, accumulating over time, can create substantial wealth. This misconception arises from a superficial understanding of compounding.  The vast differences in final returns resulting from different rates of return on the same principal over the same period often come as a surprise.</p>
<p>Let&rsquo;s illustrate with an example. Suppose someone saves 14,000 Taiwan dollars annually at the end of each year for 40 years, depositing everything into a bank account with an average interest rate of 5%. How much will they accumulate after 40 years? Before answering, recall the similar example from the previous section, but with the money in a bank instead of invested in stocks or real estate with an average annual return of 20%.</p>
<p>You might guess 25 million, 10 million, or even a conservative 5 million Taiwan dollars.  The correct answer, however, is only 1.69 million.  This can be calculated using the future value of an annuity formula:</p>
<p><math xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" display="block"><mtable displaystyle="true" columnalign="right center left" columnspacing="0 thickmathspace" rowspacing="3pt"><mtr><mtd><mn>14,000</mn><mo>×</mo><mfrac><mrow><msup><mrow><mo stretchy="false">(</mo><mn>1</mn><mo>+</mo><mn>0.05</mn><mo stretchy="false">)</mo></mrow><mrow><mn>40</mn></mrow></msup><mo>−</mo><mn>1</mn></mrow><mn>0.05</mn></mfrac></mtd><mtd><mi></mi><mo>=</mo></mtd><mtd><mn>1,690,000</mn></mtd></mtr><mtr><mtd><mn>14,000</mn><mo>×</mo><mfrac><mrow><msup><mrow><mo stretchy="false">(</mo><mn>1</mn><mo>+</mo><mn>0.20</mn><mo stretchy="false">)</mo></mrow><mrow><mn>40</mn></mrow></msup><mo>−</mo><mn>1</mn></mrow><mn>0.20</mn></mfrac></mtd><mtd><mi></mi><mo>=</mo></mtd><mtd><mn>102,810,000</mn></mtd></mtr></mtable></math></p>
<p>Let&rsquo;s compare this with the 20% return scenario.  The only difference between the two formulas is the rate of return (5% vs. 20%). A 20% return over 40 years yields 102.81 million Taiwan dollars, while a 5% return over the same period yields only 1.69 million, less than a fraction of the former. The difference is over 60 times! This illustrates the power of compound interest.  Many assume they benefit from compound interest in a bank, but at a 5% return, even with compounding over a long period, the wealth creation effect is very limited.</p>
<p>This example demonstrates that one of the keys to successful financial management is the rate of return. The key is not just whether your assets are invested, but <em>where</em> they are invested and what the rate of return is.</p>
<ul>
<li>
<ol>
<li>The key to financial management lies in how your assets are allocated. The rate of return has a decisive impact on your future wealth.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol start="2">
<li>While bank savings provide interest income and the benefit of compounding,  you&rsquo;ll find that as you age, bank deposits contribute little to overall wealth growth.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol start="3">
<li>The first step towards building wealth through investment is to allocate assets to investments with high long-term rates of return.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol start="4">
<li>&ldquo;Financial Management&rdquo; is a significant factor contributing to wealth disparity in society.</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>Inflation makes money worth less and less.</p>
</blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">The Invisible Killer of Currency Value: Inflation 
    <div id="the-invisible-killer-of-currency-value-inflation" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#the-invisible-killer-of-currency-value-inflation" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>Forty years ago, a millionaire was truly wealthy.  Today, a millionaire might struggle to afford a house. Why?  Inflation.  Every investor must consider the impact of inflation.</p>
<p><em>Inflation reduces the purchasing power of money and lowers the real rate of return, diminishing the effect of wealth accumulation.</em></p>
<p>Over the past 30 years, the average annual inflation rate in Taiwan has been around 5%. What about the future?  Inflation and economic growth are closely linked. As Taiwan&rsquo;s economy continues to grow, inflation is expected to remain around 5% annually.</p>
<p>Inflation means continuously rising prices, which translates to decreasing purchasing power.  If you keep your money in a demand deposit account earning 4% interest with a 5% inflation rate, what happens?  Your purchasing power decreases.  The longer your money sits in a savings account, the less it&rsquo;s worth.  What used to cost 10 Taiwan dollars for a newspaper now costs 15. Your 10 dollars can now only buy two-thirds of a newspaper. With inflation, money in the bank shrinks like wool submerged in water.</p>
<p><strong>Saving Alone Won&rsquo;t Make You Rich, Not Even in Two Lifetimes</strong></p>
<p>With 5% inflation and a nominal interest rate of around 5% on bank deposits, your real rate of return is zero. In this scenario, the effect of compound interest is nullified.  Wealth accumulation relies solely on painstaking saving. Imagine someone saves 500,000 Taiwan dollars a year. How long would it take to become a billionaire?  200 years!</p>
<p>Saving 500,000 Taiwan dollars a year is difficult; living for 200 years is even harder!  Therefore, even with diligent saving and budgeting, if all the money is kept in the bank, this person won&rsquo;t become wealthy in this lifetime, and worse, not even in the next! The average lifespan is around 75 years, meaning two lifetimes total only 150 years.  It would take a third lifetime for someone relying solely on bank savings to potentially reach billionaire status.  If a family maintains the financial strategy of &ldquo;frugality and bank savings,&rdquo; it would take at least 200 years, or about seven generations, for them to potentially become wealthy.  Conversely, with proper financial management, wealth can be achieved in 40 years (half a lifetime).</p>
<p><strong>Money in the Bank Should Be Spent Sooner Rather Than Later</strong></p>
<p>I remember 30 years ago, when I was in second or third grade, a popsicle cost 20 cents, and a red bean ice cream cost 50 cents.  My parents gave me 50 cents each day for allowance, which I invariably spent on red bean ice cream after school. My parents constantly encouraged me to save, so my father opened a bank account for me. If I had been obedient and developed good saving habits from a young age, saving those 50 cents daily and earning 8% interest, it would have grown tenfold over 30 years, to 5 Taiwan dollars.  However, a red bean ice cream now costs 15 Taiwan dollars. Those 5 dollars can only buy one-third of a red bean ice cream. More importantly, for a小学生 30 years ago, a red bean ice cream was precious.  Even a dozen red bean ice creams today couldn&rsquo;t compare to the value of one back then. Had I followed my parents&rsquo; financial advice and kept my money in the bank, I would regret it now.</p>
<p>Therefore, if you&rsquo;re going to keep money in the bank, my sincere advice is: &ldquo;Spend it sooner rather than later!&rdquo; This might sound shocking, but there&rsquo;s logic to it.  From an economic perspective, money has more value and higher utility when used sooner. We save money in the bank, delaying gratification for the sake of greater enjoyment in the future.  However, with inflation, money left in the bank often leads to <em>less</em> enjoyment.</p>
<p><strong>The Value of Money Decreases with Age</strong></p>
<p>My wife and her friends developed a financial philosophy: &ldquo;Money is most valuable when spent while young.&rdquo; This makes economic sense.  Their reasoning: &ldquo;When you&rsquo;re old, delicacies might harm your health, traveling becomes difficult, and most importantly, wearing beautiful clothes attracts unwanted attention and ridicule.&rdquo;</p>
<p>Thus, everyone managing their finances must be mindful of the dual pressures of inflation and the diminishing value of money with age. Bank deposit interest rates cannot compensate for these losses. In other words, <strong>money in the bank, while nominally increasing, actually decreases in value.</strong></p>
<p>Of course, I&rsquo;m not encouraging you to spend all your savings immediately.  Rather, I&rsquo;m highlighting that if you keep money in the bank, you must consider the declining purchasing power due to inflation and the reduced economic benefit as you age.  The fundamental solution is to withdraw your money from the bank and invest it in instruments with higher returns than bank deposit rates. <strong>Therefore, the best way to combat inflation is: Don&rsquo;t keep your money in the bank. Invest in long-term, high-return assets like stocks and real estate.</strong></p>
<p>Because inflation decreases real returns and hinders wealth accumulation, even saving 14,000 Taiwan dollars annually and investing in stocks or real estate for 40 years to become a billionaire won&rsquo;t carry the same weight as being a billionaire today.  Therefore, under inflation, consider using the <em>real</em> rate of return. If the return on investment is 20% and inflation is 5%, the real return is 15%.  So how much should you save annually, investing in stocks or real estate with a nominal return of around 20% (real return of 15%), to become a billionaire in 40 years?  The answer is 57,000 Taiwan dollars per year.</p>
<p><math xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" display="block"><mn>57,000</mn><mo>×</mo><mfrac><mrow><msup><mrow><mo stretchy="false">(</mo><mn>1</mn><mo>+</mo><mn>0.15</mn><mo stretchy="false">)</mo></mrow><mrow><mn>40</mn></mrow></msup><mo>−</mo><mn>1</mn></mrow><mn>0.15</mn></mfrac><mo>=</mo><mn>101,410,000</mn><mspace linebreak="newline"></mspace></math></p>
<blockquote>
<p>A small step today makes a world of difference tomorrow.</p>
</blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">The Path to Wealth of Chang Pin-san, Former Chairman of Chang Hwa Bank 
    <div id="the-path-to-wealth-of-chang-pin-san-former-chairman-of-chang-hwa-bank" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#the-path-to-wealth-of-chang-pin-san-former-chairman-of-chang-hwa-bank" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>Chang Po-hsin, the current standing director of Chang Hwa Bank, with assets exceeding tens of billions, inherited and expanded upon the fortune of his father, Chang Pin-san, the former chairman of Chang Hwa Bank, earning him a place among Taiwan&rsquo;s wealthiest individuals.</p>
<p><strong>Trading Bank Deposits for Stock Dividends</strong></p>
<p>Forty years ago, both Chang Pin-san and my father were from Nantun District, Taichung City.  They were not only fellow townsmen but also colleagues. Back then, Chang Pin-san was just a junior manager at Chang Hwa Bank, without much wealth.  However, he borrowed money to buy Chang Hwa Bank shares from colleagues who wanted to sell them. At the time, stock dividends were far lower than bank interest. Despite this, Chang Pin-san persisted in borrowing money to acquire shares, holding onto them for the long term.  Other colleagues deposited the proceeds from their stock sales into banks. Years later, Chang Pin-san, owning the most shares, became the largest shareholder and eventually the chairman of Chang Hwa Bank, laying the foundation for his immense wealth.</p>
<p>Chang Pin-san was also friends with Lien Chen-tung, father of Lien Chan, and encouraged him to buy Chang Hwa Bank shares. The Lien family&rsquo;s fortune also originated from those hundreds of Chang Hwa Bank shares.</p>
<p>It&rsquo;s hard to believe that the path to wealth could be so simple: borrow money to buy a few Chang Hwa Bank shares, invest in some real estate, hold them long-term, and essentially forget about them.  Decades later, great wealth is attained. Those who sold their shares and deposited the money in banks are still wondering how others became rich. Some might attribute this to luck, but financial management is not about luck.  It&rsquo;s about the method chosen and the investment tools selected.  Therefore, if you don&rsquo;t want to be poor, don&rsquo;t keep your money in the bank.</p>
<p><strong>Bank Savings Shouldn&rsquo;t Exceed Living Expenses</strong></p>
<p>Someone once jokingly asked me, &ldquo;You&rsquo;re telling us not to keep money in the bank.  Are we supposed to pay with stocks or real estate certificates at the supermarket or restaurant?&rdquo; Of course not!  Advising against keeping money in the bank doesn&rsquo;t mean you can&rsquo;t have any money in the bank at all. Bank deposits offer advantages: security and convenience. They are ideal for storing funds needed for daily expenses. However, you can&rsquo;t have your cake and eat it too.  Convenience comes at the cost of high returns.</p>
<p>The wise approach is to clearly divide funds into two categories: daily expenses and investments.  Keep enough for daily needs in the bank, enjoying the security and convenience it offers. Invest the rest in higher-return assets like stocks and real estate.</p>
<p>In my opinion, keeping the equivalent of two months&rsquo; living expenses in the bank is sufficient for an individual or family. Most individuals and families receive regular income, which is deposited into their bank accounts. Therefore, one month&rsquo;s expenses for immediate use and another month&rsquo;s worth as a safety net should be ample.  The remaining funds should be invested in higher-return assets like stocks and real estate.  In other words, if your monthly expenses average 50,000 Taiwan dollars, and your bank balance consistently exceeds 100,000, you are not managing your finances effectively.  Actively seek suitable investment opportunities to make your surplus funds work for you.</p>
<p><strong>The &ldquo;Two Big, One Small&rdquo; Approach to Flexible Fund Management</strong></p>
<p>Some believe in maintaining substantial emergency funds. However, even if unforeseen circumstances drain your bank savings, there&rsquo;s no need to panic. The high-return investments mentioned earlier—stocks and real estate—are not as illiquid as some might think.  Listed stocks in Taiwan&rsquo;s active stock market can be sold almost any day of the year (excluding holidays), providing quick access to cash within a few days.  Reluctant to sell? Stocks can also be used as collateral for loans.</p>
<p>Real estate is less liquid than stocks, but many Taiwanese banks now offer &ldquo;revolving mortgage loans,&rdquo; allowing property owners to convert fixed assets into liquid assets. These loans involve mortgaging a property to secure a credit line of up to 70%-75% of the property&rsquo;s value. Borrowers can draw and repay funds as needed, with interest accruing only on the outstanding balance. For example, a 10 million Taiwan dollar property could secure a 7.5 million credit line.  Borrowing 5 million leaves 2.5 million available without interest charges, with interest accruing only on the 5 million borrowed.  Any surplus funds can be used to repay the loan, reducing interest costs.</p>
<p>Many financial experts recommend a &ldquo;three-part&rdquo; approach, dividing assets equally among bank savings, real estate, and more speculative investments. I propose a &ldquo;two big, one small&rdquo; approach: allocate most of your assets to stocks and real estate, keeping a small portion in a bank for daily expenses.  This isn&rsquo;t my invention. In fact, this is the portfolio strategy employed by many who have achieved wealth through investments.</p>
<ul>
<li>
<ol>
<li>Keeping money in the bank is the riskiest form of financial management.  Inflation erodes returns, leaving real interest rates near zero.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol start="2">
<li>Banks offer convenience, not high returns.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol start="3">
<li>Keep only two months&rsquo; worth of living expenses in the bank.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol start="4">
<li>Trying to get rich with money in the bank is like trying to win a baseball game without swinging the bat.</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ul>
<p>If all this hasn&rsquo;t convinced you to reconsider keeping most of your money in a financial institution, perhaps the story of the Nobel Prize Foundation&rsquo;s success might change your mind.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Change your asset management perspective, change your financial destiny.</p>
</blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">Lessons from the Nobel Prize Foundation 
    <div id="lessons-from-the-nobel-prize-foundation" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#lessons-from-the-nobel-prize-foundation" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>Every October, the Nobel Committee announces the Nobel laureates. The Nobel Prize attracts global attention not only for representing the highest academic honor but also because each laureate receives a substantial prize of 1 million US dollars.</p>
<p><strong>The Folly of Depleting Capital</strong></p>
<p>The Nobel Foundation awards several prizes annually, disbursing millions of dollars. This raises the question: How large is the Nobel fund to sustain such substantial payouts? The Nobel Foundation&rsquo;s success, besides the substantial initial donation by Alfred Nobel over a century ago, is largely attributed to its shrewd financial management.</p>
<p>Established in 1896 with a 9.8 million US dollar donation from Nobel, the foundation&rsquo;s purpose is to fund the prizes.  Flawless fund management was paramount.  Initially, its charter stipulated that investments be restricted to safe, fixed-income instruments like bank deposits and government bonds, explicitly excluding stocks and real estate to avoid market risks.</p>
<p>This capital preservation approach, prioritizing safety over returns, seemed prudent, preventing losses. However, sacrificing returns had consequences.  After 50 years of prize payouts and operating expenses, low returns depleted two-thirds of the Nobel fund, leaving only a little over 3 million US dollars by 1953.</p>
<p><strong>From 3 Million to 270 Million: The Secret</strong></p>
<p>Facing depletion, the Nobel Foundation&rsquo;s board recognized the importance of investment returns. In 1953, they made a groundbreaking change, amending the charter to shift from bank deposits and bonds to primarily stocks and real estate.  This shift in investment philosophy transformed the foundation&rsquo;s fate. Over the next 40 years, despite continued prize payouts and operating costs, the foundation not only recovered all previous losses but also grew its assets to 270 million US dollars by 1993.</p>
<p><em>Nobel Prize Foundation Asset Growth and Decline</em></p>
<table>
  <thead>
      <tr>
          <th style="text-align: left">Year</th>
          <th style="text-align: left">Total Assets (Million USD)</th>
          <th style="text-align: left">Remarks</th>
      </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
      <tr>
          <td style="text-align: left">1896</td>
          <td style="text-align: left">9.8</td>
          <td style="text-align: left">Foundation Established</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td style="text-align: left">1953</td>
          <td style="text-align: left">3.3</td>
          <td style="text-align: left">Investment Charter Amended</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td style="text-align: left">1993</td>
          <td style="text-align: left">270</td>
          <td style="text-align: left"></td>
      </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>
<p>Had the Nobel Foundation not changed its approach 40 years ago, clinging to bank savings, it would have vanished, unable to fund the prizes.  Perhaps other wealthy individuals would have established new foundations with larger prizes, replacing the Nobel Prize.</p>
<p>The Nobel Foundation&rsquo;s history underscores the importance of financial management.  Even a substantial initial fund, if mismanaged, can be depleted. Conversely, even with significant spending, skillful management can generate rapid growth.</p>
<p>I once heard of a Taiwanese hometown association that established a foundation with 100,000 Taiwan dollars 40 years ago to provide scholarships for children from their hometown.  Forty years later, the fund remains at 100,000 Taiwan dollars. While a significant sum back then, today it barely covers administrative costs, threatening the foundation&rsquo;s existence.  The problem? Neglecting financial management.</p>
<p>Learning from the Nobel Foundation, many US foundations, pension funds, university endowments, and even personal trusts have shifted from bank deposits and bonds to primarily stocks and real estate. In contrast, few Taiwanese foundations grasp this concept, and university endowments rarely address financial management seriously.  The fate of these foundations, if they don&rsquo;t adapt, is clear.</p>
<p>I often participate in corporate training programs, where I habitually ask companies about the size and investment strategy of their employee welfare funds.  The answers are usually similar: small funds, mostly in bank deposits, rarely exceeding a few hundred thousand or a million Taiwan dollars. However, in 1990, during my time at China Development Corporation, the employee welfare fund exceeded 200 million Taiwan dollars. Why?  Because it was primarily invested in China Development Corporation&rsquo;s own stock.</p>
<ul>
<li>
<ol>
<li>The Nobel Foundation&rsquo;s course correction 40 years ago secured its status today.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol start="2">
<li>Prioritizing security above all else leads to asset depletion.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol start="3">
<li>The growth and decline of wealth for individuals, families, businesses, or other entities depends on their investment strategy.</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ul>
<p>Will your hard-earned wealth shrink like the early Nobel fund, or grow like the later one? The key lies in <em>how</em> you invest. If, like many, you keep most of your money in the bank, it&rsquo;s not too late to change. The Nobel Foundation&rsquo;s story shows how a change in investment philosophy can transform everything.  Should you reconsider your financial habits and prioritize investments in stocks and real estate? Let the Nobel Foundation inspire your financial thinking. A single change in mindset can lead to immense wealth decades from now!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Personal Investment Bible: Preface</title>
      <link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1731056005958/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1731056005958/</guid>
      <description>This book aims to help readers establish a correct view of wealth management, learn financial knowledge, master easy wealth management techniques, and ultimately achieve financial freedom, even becoming millionaires. Author Huang Peiyuan uses the story of the Lien Chan family&amp;#39;s wealth management as an example, explaining the importance of wealth management in a simple and profound way, and combining his rich experience and academic research, proposes the key elements of wealth accumulation: regular savings, pursuing high returns, and long-term waiting. In addition, this book also emphasizes the inadequacy of financial education and the importance of continuous learning and adaptation in a rapidly changing investment environment.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[
  



<div
  
    class="flex px-4 py-3 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900"
  >

  <span
    
      class="text-primary-400 ltr:pr-3 rtl:pl-3 flex items-center"
    >

    

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M256 0C114.6 0 0 114.6 0 256s114.6 256 256 256s256-114.6 256-256S397.4 0 256 0zM256 128c17.67 0 32 14.33 32 32c0 17.67-14.33 32-32 32S224 177.7 224 160C224 142.3 238.3 128 256 128zM296 384h-80C202.8 384 192 373.3 192 360s10.75-24 24-24h16v-64H224c-13.25 0-24-10.75-24-24S210.8 224 224 224h32c13.25 0 24 10.75 24 24v88h16c13.25 0 24 10.75 24 24S309.3 384 296 384z"/></svg>

  </span>


  </span>

  <span
    
      class="dark:text-neutral-300"
    ><strong>Synopsis</strong><br>
Written by Mr. Huang Peiyuan from Taiwan, this book&rsquo;s greatest strength lies in its departure from traditional thinking. It uses clear and easy-to-understand language to teach correct wealth management methods. The book outlines thirteen ironclad rules for effortless wealth management, guiding readers on how to establish a correct view of financial management. Many people strive to make money but don&rsquo;t know how.  Many possess the conditions for wealth but miss opportunities due to a lack of financial literacy. Even worse, some lose everything due to investment mistakes. The author draws on practical experience and extensive academic research, exploring these thirteen ironclad rules to help you &ldquo;enjoy wealth management, achieve wealth with ease,&rdquo; and confidently join the ranks of millionaires.
<br>
<br>
<strong>About the Author</strong><br>
<strong>Huang Peiyuan</strong>, Ph.D. in Business Administration from the University of California, Berkeley, General Manager of Sancai Construction and Real Estate Co., Ltd. Former Director of the Institute of Business Administration, Tunghai University, Deputy Director of the Project Business Department, China Development Trust Company, Vice President of East-West Securities, USA, Investment Manager at Merrill Lynch, USA, and financial advisor to numerous companies.</span>
</div>



<h2 class="relative group">Learning Wealth Management from the Lien Chan Family 
    <div id="learning-wealth-management-from-the-lien-chan-family" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#learning-wealth-management-from-the-lien-chan-family" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>The people of Taiwan are not only surprised by the enormous wealth of the Lien Chan family, the former chairman of the Kuomintang, but also harbor doubts. How could two generations of civil servants, with their meager salaries, accumulate wealth comparable to that of tycoon families?</p>
<p>This suspicion is deeply ingrained, but the Lien family is a prominent political family in Taiwan, and no one wants to antagonize them by probing too deeply.</p>
<p>As a journalist, the Lien family&rsquo;s wealth has always been a puzzle to me. I even made a determined effort to uncover the truth, but to no avail.  Six months ago, Professor Huang Peiyuan, then director of the Institute of Business Administration at Tunghai University, spoke about his desire to combine theory and practice and publish a &ldquo;Personal Investment Bible.&rdquo; After reading Professor Huang&rsquo;s manuscript, the mystery of the Lien family&rsquo;s wealth became clear to me.  The Lien family is a perfect example of the principles in this &ldquo;Personal Investment Bible.&rdquo; Perhaps Lien Ya-tang, in his early years, wrote not only the renowned &ldquo;General History of Taiwan,&rdquo; but also a &ldquo;Wealth Management Manual&rdquo; passed down only within the family.</p>
<p>According to Professor Huang&rsquo;s (his title at the time; now he is in business) &ldquo;Personal Investment Bible,&rdquo; the first rule is &ldquo;Don&rsquo;t keep your money in the bank.&rdquo; The second is that if you want to get rich, invest in stocks and real estate.  This gives you the opportunity, with the income of an average office worker, to become a multimillionaire after 40 years of wealth management.</p>
<p>By this standard, the Lien family is indeed the most faithful follower of the &ldquo;Personal Investment Bible.&rdquo; When they had little wealth, Lien&rsquo;s mother (Lien Chan&rsquo;s mother) invested solely in stocks and real estate.  Over the past few decades, the Lien family remained steadfast, waiting for the appreciation of their stocks and real estate, which naturally led to the vast wealth that now arouses public suspicion.</p>
<p>Several decades ago, there were many business people who possessed similar wealth to the Lien family.  These individuals also worked hard to manage their businesses and accumulate more wealth.  However, compared to the Lien family now, most of them lament their inferiority in terms of wealth. The Lien family&rsquo;s role as pure investors fully demonstrates that &ldquo;as long as the concepts and methods are correct, wealth will naturally follow.&rdquo;</p>
<p>In fact, the theories and methods in the &ldquo;Personal Investment Bible&rdquo; have been discussed by countless scholars and experts in mature Western societies, but not many have truly adhered to them and become millionaires as a result.  The reason lies not in the inadequacy of the theories and methods, but in the lack of confidence and patience of those who apply them, leading them to give up halfway.</p>
<p>Therefore, I advise all readers of this book to truly believe in the theories presented, have long-term patience, and adhere to them unwaveringly in order to succeed.</p>
<p>We wish all readers the ability to enjoy a happy retirement with sufficient financial resources, which is perhaps the greatest contribution of the &ldquo;Personal Investment Bible&rdquo; to the public! (This article is written by the president of Business Weekly Taiwan)</p>


<h2 class="relative group">The Joy of Wealth Management, Achieving Wealth with Ease 
    <div id="the-joy-of-wealth-management-achieving-wealth-with-ease" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#the-joy-of-wealth-management-achieving-wealth-with-ease" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>When I was young, I thought that money was the most important thing in life; now that I am old, I know that it is.</p>
<p>— Oscar Wilde, British playwright</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This book is written for those who are determined to become wealthy and strive for financial independence. If you have tried every possible way to get rich and your home is filled with investment books, but you still can&rsquo;t figure out how to achieve wealth in your lifetime, congratulations! You have found the book you need. The investment and financial management concepts and methods described in this book are absolutely understandable and achievable for everyone. As long as you put them into practice, becoming a millionaire is not difficult.</p>
<p>I see many people working tirelessly to make money, hoping to improve their own and their families&rsquo; financial situation, but they can&rsquo;t find the right way. Many people clearly have the conditions to become rich through financial management, but they don&rsquo;t know how to manage their finances, resulting in missed opportunities.  Others know that investment and financial management can lead to wealth, but the problem is that what they know is not true, leading them astray and suffering from financial mismanagement.  The author sees these phenomena and often feels sorry for them.</p>
<p>The biggest problem in Taiwan at present is the serious lack of financial education. The public lacks a correct concept of financial management. They either don&rsquo;t know how to manage their finances and neglect it, or they use the wrong methods. As a result, some people not only fail to achieve wealth through financial management, but even fail to achieve basic financial independence.  Insufficient or incorrect financial concepts are harmful not only to one&rsquo;s own financial situation, but also to the public. This is the main motivation for the author to write this book, and what this book offers readers is the correct basic concept of investment and financial management.</p>
<p>As a scholar and a practitioner of financial management, I feel obligated to share my years of investment research results and practical experience in financial management with everyone, helping the public to easily manage their finances and achieve wealth through investment. The message this book wants to convey is: Financial management is actually very simple. Not only can everyone do it easily, but almost all young people have the conditions to achieve wealth through financial management.</p>
<p>This book is based on 20 years of practical financial management experience in the United States and Taiwan, 6 years of investment research at Tunghai University, and 15 years of experience as a financial advisor.  In fact, the concepts and practices in this book were developed 3 years ago.  For the past 3 years, the author has given lectures on this topic in various places and received tremendous feedback.  Many listeners have continuously requested that I compile these concepts and action guidelines into a book.  I personally also feel that these financial management concepts and action guidelines are indeed beneficial to the public and there is indeed a need to publish a book.</p>
<p>However, putting these concepts into words is a difficult task for me, so I have procrastinated for 3 years. Recently, thanks to the repeated urging of Mr. He, President of Business Weekly Cultural Enterprise, and Ms. Sun Meiqing, and the examples and suggestions provided by Ms. Shen Wenci, and especially the efforts of Mr. Yang Weikai, who spent several months helping me revise and proofread, this book has finally been completed. I express my sincere gratitude here.</p>
<p>If this book can be read by the general public, and if they can accept the concepts and financial management methods described in the book, then all the author&rsquo;s efforts will have been truly worthwhile. Good ideas should be shared with everyone. I hope everyone can benefit from them and easily become millionaires through financial management.</p>
<p>Finally, I dedicate this book to my parents, Mr. Huang Minting and Ms. Huang Juzhi, who raised and nurtured me.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">Preface 
    <div id="preface" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#preface" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>In recent years, Taiwan&rsquo;s economy has grown rapidly.  While continuous economic growth is certainly gratifying, the problem of uneven wealth distribution has become increasingly serious. Some blame inappropriate government policies, while others believe it&rsquo;s due to speculation, which has caused stock and housing prices to rise, widening the gap between rich and poor. The author believes that these factors are not the main cause. The real reason for the widening wealth gap is the significant disparity in financial literacy among the public.</p>
<p>Starting in 1986, Taiwan officially entered an era of abundant capital and a focus on wealth management.  The New Taiwan dollar slowly appreciated from 40 to 27 against the US dollar, and during this period, a large amount of foreign exchange flowed into Taiwan, creating a situation where &ldquo;money overflowed in Taiwan.&rdquo;</p>
<p>Due to the excess capital, people began to shift their money towards investing in stocks and real estate. The huge influx of funds into the stock and housing markets caused stock and housing prices to soar. Between 1986 and 1989, housing prices increased by an average of two to four times, and the weighted stock market index rose from over 700 points in early 1986 to 12,680 points in February 1990, an increase of 18 times.  Investing in stocks and participating in the capital market is inherently meaningful, and rising stock prices are a natural consequence of economic growth. Unfortunately, most investors adopted the wrong approach, believing that to profit in the stock market, they must buy low and sell high, earning the difference.  In reality, short-term trading is not only time-consuming and laborious but also incurs huge transaction costs, resulting in most investors losing money. The stock market is almost equated with a casino.</p>
<p>The purpose of this book is to enlighten the public&rsquo;s financial mindset by providing new perspectives, concepts, and methods to cope with the important yet complex investment environment. The author sincerely hopes that after reading this book, readers will develop a new financial mentality and adopt correct financial management methods.</p>
<p>&ldquo;Getting rich&rdquo; is almost everyone&rsquo;s desire, and most people think that their monthly income is not much, and the amount they can save is even less. At this rate of wealth accumulation, it seems impossible to get rich. But in fact, with enough time and proper financial management, becoming a millionaire is not impossible.  Wealth accumulation through financial management requires only three basic conditions: regular savings, the pursuit of high returns, and long-term waiting.</p>
<p>The easiest way to achieve wealth through financial management is to learn from those who have done so. What are their methods? The secret of most successful wealth managers is not that they are smarter, harder working, or luckier than others, but that they have the habits and practices of wealth creation.</p>
<p>In the past, family financial management was rarely mentioned in school education.  Perhaps this is because investment and financial management involve money, and most people think that making money with money has a connotation of getting something for nothing.  In formal school education, teachers avoid mentioning it, believing that talking about money in education may corrupt people&rsquo;s minds, especially making money with money, which doesn&rsquo;t seem noble.  However, long-term avoidance of this issue has only exacerbated the problem.</p>
<p>The people of Taiwan, through years of joint efforts, have created an economic miracle and accumulated a large amount of wealth. However, most individuals and families only know how to make money but not how to manage it, let alone how to use it wisely.  After acquiring wealth, individuals, families, and even the entire society have suffered rather than benefited. For example, in recent years, money games have been prevalent.  Many people are busy speculating in stocks and real estate, and various forms of gambling such as the Mark Six lottery, futures, and foreign exchange margin trading are still popular and becoming increasingly rampant.  Many people are obsessed with money games, all for the purpose of making money and improving their family&rsquo;s financial situation.  However, if we calmly review the investment results of the past few years, it is not difficult to find that in the end, few have profited, many have lost, and even more have gone bankrupt.  Everyone has worked in vain, and the result is only a rapid redistribution of wealth and a prevalence of unhealthy speculation in society. The wealth of individuals and society as a whole does not increase. This is all due to the public&rsquo;s lack of clear understanding of financial management concepts.</p>
<p>The consequence of poor financial literacy is not only personal loss and family misfortune but also a waste of overall social resources.  Let&rsquo;s face this issue that is crucial to individuals, families, and the entire society: family financial management.</p>
<p>As the saying goes, &ldquo;When a couple is poor, everything is sad.&rdquo;  This shows that if a family&rsquo;s financial situation cannot meet the needs of family life, or if finances are not managed properly, happiness is hard to come by. Of course, there are many factors that contribute to a happy family, and wealth is only one of them, as many family problems cannot be solved with money. There is a saying: &ldquo;Money is not everything, but without money, you can do nothing.&rdquo; Although money is not the center of a family, in our real society, most good things require money. Wealthy families are not necessarily happy, but families without money are usually even less so. To make ourselves and our families happier, investment and financial management are indeed imperative. Investment and financial management can not only improve the financial situation of an individual or a family, but it is also a good way to accumulate wealth.  Using financial management to achieve wealth is achievable for everyone, and it is something everyone should do.</p>
<p>Future wealth depends on the future investment environment, and the biggest characteristic of the investment environment, in a word, is change.  The entire financial environment is ever-changing and unpredictable. This has been true in the past and will be even more so in the future. In the world of investment and financial management, there is constant change. It can be said that &ldquo;the only constant is change.&rdquo; It is foreseeable that the changes in the next 10 years will exceed those of the previous 50 years. Changes are not only becoming faster, but also more complex, diversified, and international. Whether we like it or not, we are already in a rapidly changing environment.</p>
<p>Facing change, you can remain calm, adapt, and adopt the appropriate mental attitude. However, if you know how change will affect you, you may not dare to take it lightly. Because the natural consequence of any change is redistribution, including wealth, power, markets, personnel&hellip; In terms of wealth, any change in the investment environment will naturally affect the flow of money at all levels.  Indeed, in financial markets, capital markets, commodity markets, spot or futures markets worldwide, billions of dollars are traded every day, and wealth is constantly being redistributed.  Your wealth may increase significantly during the redistribution process, or it may shrink rapidly.  After long-term redistribution, you may become a billionaire, or you may become penniless, depending on how you face and deal with the changes.</p>
<p>Any change and the resulting redistribution poses a &ldquo;crisis&rdquo; to your wealth to a greater or lesser extent. The Chinese characters for &ldquo;crisis&rdquo; are profound and often quoted in foreign books because they contain both danger and opportunity. &ldquo;Wei&rdquo; represents the threat to wealth, and &ldquo;Ji&rdquo; represents the opportunity for wealth creation.</p>
<p>We can wait for changes and redistribution to determine our future wealth level, or we can make good use of the opportunities brought about by change and try to reduce its destructive power.  In this era of accelerating change, cultivating the ability to manage and respond to change is essential to controlling our own future.</p>
<p>Looking ahead, changes in business, economy, finance, politics, society, and other aspects will accelerate. The overall financial environment will become more complex and unpredictable, and it is foreseeable that future wealth redistribution will inevitably accelerate. Therefore, for ourselves, our families, and society, everyone should play the role of a financial manager.</p>
<p>This is an era of rapid change and abundant wealth, and it is also an era that forces us to manage our finances.  Everyone desires to become rich and improve their living standards or achieve their life goals. There are many ways to get rich, but the concept the author wants to elaborate on in this book is: Investment and financial management is one of the effective methods to achieve wealth. As long as you have the correct financial management concepts and put them into practice, whether you are rich or poor now, over time, you may become a millionaire through investment and financial management.</p>
<p>In this critical era related to our future wealth, you can no longer remain indifferent to financial management or ignorant of investment.  You must adopt the correct financial concepts as early as possible, constantly acquire new knowledge, and avoid mistakes in order to win in the process of wealth redistribution.</p>
<p><strong>The Story of the Mailman Who Got Rich</strong></p>
<p>My brother-in-law has a friend in Taichung, a middle-aged man with a dark complexion and an occasional shy smile. My first impression of him wasn&rsquo;t memorable until he drove away in a new BMW. The second time we met, he arrived in a Mercedes-Benz, which made me admire him.  I realized that appearances can be deceiving and quickly asked him what kind of big business he was in. He said he wasn&rsquo;t a businessman, just an ordinary office worker.  I pressed him further, asking which big company he worked for. He said he worked at the post office. I thought he must be a senior executive to be so prestigious and own two luxury cars.  The answer, however, was surprising. He replied, &ldquo;I&rsquo;m a mailman. I deliver mail by motorcycle in the morning, with a monthly salary of NT$30,000-40,000.&rdquo; I secretly speculated that he must specialize in delivering registered mail and was pocketing some of the contents.  He then told me his story. His previous generation were poor farmers who left behind some land, which he had always regarded as ancestral property and kept without selling. No one expected that recent land consolidation would increase the value of his land by dozens of times. Now, just by renting out houses, he earns NT$500,000 in rent every month.  This 48-year-old mailman didn&rsquo;t rely on increasing income and reducing expenditure, but simply by putting his assets in the right place, he now has assets of more than NT$300 million. This is one of the examples of wealth accumulation through financial management in Taiwanese society.</p>
<p>Similar stories seem to happen frequently around us. Before I taught at the university, I worked for an investment company. Once, during the election of directors and supervisors at a shareholders&rsquo; meeting, I discovered that a major shareholder holding more than NT$200 million worth of shares was actually a clerk in the company&rsquo;s personnel department.  It turned out that 35 years ago, when she joined the company as an employee, her salary was very low and her life was insecure, so she saved her meager salary. When company employees had fractional shares to transfer, she would buy them. After many years, this woman in her 50s, although unremarkable and not looking like a rich woman, now has a net worth of more than NT$200 million, enough to enjoy her retirement. In fact, there are countless examples of such ordinary office workers who have become wealthy through investment and financial management. Many people say that office workers cannot become rich, but in reality, wealthy office workers mostly don&rsquo;t like to show off, so the way to get rich through investment and financial management is often overlooked.</p>
<p><strong>What Differentiates the Rich from the Poor?</strong></p>
<p>Many hardworking office workers who toil daily for money have had the common experience of watching rich people in expensive clothes, living in luxurious villas, and driving by in luxury cars, looking impressive and enviable. While admiring them, you may have wondered: &ldquo;What makes them rich, but not me?&rdquo;</p>
<p>Many people attribute the wealth of these rich people directly to their being born rich, their successful entrepreneurial ventures, their being smarter, harder working, or luckier than others. However, family background, entrepreneurship, intelligence, hard work, and luck cannot explain all the reasons for wealth accumulation. We have all encountered many rich people, such as &ldquo;nouveau riche&rdquo; or &ldquo;landowners.&rdquo; They were not born into wealthy families, nor are they businessmen. They are not necessarily very smart, haven&rsquo;t received much higher education, and are not more frugal than us. Some of them even idle around all day. The only thing they seem to be better at than you is that they are rich.</p>
<p>What special skills do these rich people possess that are lacking in those office workers who diligently save money and work hard every day? How can they accumulate such enormous wealth in their lifetime? This is the question the author has been eager to explore for many years.  I have tried to explain their wealth with factors such as family background, entrepreneurship, occupation, education, IQ, and effort, but all seem to have failed. After years of observation, induction, and academic research, I have discovered a very important factor that is often overlooked by most people: the ability to invest and manage finances. At the same time, I have also discovered the following three facts:</p>
<p><em>1. One of the important factors that distinguishes the rich from the poor is: the ability to invest and manage finances.</em></p>
<p><em>2. Everyone can achieve wealth through investment and financial management.</em></p>
<p><em>3. The first thing to do to improve your financial situation is: to understand the basic concepts of investment and financial management.</em>
content_copy
Use code with caution.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Personal Investment Bible: The Correct Concept of Financial Management</title>
      <link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1731056005959/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1731056005959/</guid>
      <description>This article explores the correct concept of financial management, pointing out that investment is the key to wealth, rather than simply relying on increasing income and reducing expenditure.  Using the wealth comparison between Koo Chen-fu and Koo Li-hsiung, the financial management methods of the Lien Chan family, and an example of becoming a billionaire by investing $1,200 monthly for 40 years, the article illustrates the importance of investment and emphasizes the power of compound interest.  Furthermore, it analyzes the impact of financial habits on the wealth gap and how to educate the next generation to establish a correct concept of financial management, suggesting incorporating “Don&amp;#39;t keep money in the bank” into family precepts to cultivate investment awareness from an early age.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[

<h2 class="relative group">The Correct Concept of Financial Management 
    <div id="the-correct-concept-of-financial-management" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#the-correct-concept-of-financial-management" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>The key to winning the wealth race lies not in the starting point, but in choosing the right track.</p>
</blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">Investment Leads to Wealth 
    <div id="investment-leads-to-wealth" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#investment-leads-to-wealth" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>The Chinatrust Financial Holding Co., one of the top five conglomerates in Taiwan, was led by Koo Chen-fu, chairman of the Koo&rsquo;s Group, and Jeffrey Koo, chairman of Chinatrust Commercial Bank. The Koo&rsquo;s Group encompassed seven major business segments: finance, manufacturing, construction, hotels, media, services, and overseas operations, with over 50 affiliated companies and total assets exceeding NT$460 billion. Many wondered how this uncle-nephew duo achieved both political and business success, and who was wealthier.</p>
<p><strong>The Wealth Race Between Koo Chen-fu and Jeffrey Koo</strong></p>
<p>Wealth often correlates with personality. Koo Chen-fu was a slow and steady type, while Jeffrey Koo was more of a go-getter.  Due to their vastly different personalities, their investment approaches also differed significantly.  Koo Chen-fu&rsquo;s eldest son, Eugene Koo, the general manager of China Life Insurance in Taiwan, understood them well. He once said, &ldquo;Money put in Koo Chen-fu&rsquo;s pocket would never come out, but money put in Jeffrey Koo&rsquo;s pocket would disappear.&rdquo;  This was because Jeffrey Koo continuously reinvested his money, leading to greater wealth accumulation than his uncle. Jeffrey Koo&rsquo;s personal assets were spread across the US and Japan, invested in real estate, funds, hotels, golf courses, and banks.  Koo Chen-fu, in his 80s, was quite conservative. Regarding his financial management philosophy, he said, &ldquo;I neglect financial management and don&rsquo;t want to worry about money.&rdquo;  His personal income was deposited in the bank by his secretary, and aside from necessary expenses, the rest was converted into fixed-term deposits.</p>
<p>Over the years, Koo Chen-fu naturally had more cash on hand, as his money remained in the bank. However, in terms of wealth creation, Jeffrey Koo far surpassed him. Despite a 17-year age difference, with proper investment, one could still come out ahead.</p>
<p><strong>Investing $1,200 Monthly Can Make You a Billionaire in 40 Years</strong></p>
<p><em>It&rsquo;s not what you don&rsquo;t know that gets you into trouble. It&rsquo;s what you know for sure that just ain&rsquo;t so.</em></p>
<p>The first concept to understand about investment is: <strong>Investment not only improves financial situations but also allows anyone to achieve wealth.</strong></p>
<p>Let&rsquo;s illustrate with a simple example:</p>
<p>Suppose a young person with no savings starts saving NT$14,000 annually for 40 years.  If this money is invested in stocks or real estate with an average annual return of 20%, how much wealth will they accumulate after 40 years?</p>
<p>The author often asks this question in lectures. Most guesses range from NT$2 million to NT$8 million, with a maximum of NT$10 million. The correct answer, however, is a surprising NT$102.81 million!  For a 25-year-old, saving NT$14,000 annually (equivalent to $1,200 monthly) for 40 years, with a total investment of NT$560,000, could result in becoming a billionaire by age 65, assuming a 20% annual return in stocks or real estate.</p>
<p>This figure is calculated using the future value of an annuity formula in finance and investment. The calculation is as follows:</p>
<p><math xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" display="block"><mn>1.4</mn><mo>×</mo><mfrac><mrow><msup><mrow><mo stretchy="false">(</mo><mn>1</mn><mo>+</mo><mn>0.20</mn><mo stretchy="false">)</mo></mrow><mrow><mn>40</mn></mrow></msup><mo>−</mo><mn>1</mn></mrow><mn>0.20</mn></mfrac><mo>=</mo><mn>10281</mn><mspace linebreak="newline"></mspace></math>
(Units are in NT$10,000)</p>
<p>This formula illustrates how small amounts of money can grow significantly through investment.  Understanding the formula isn&rsquo;t crucial; most people who become billionaires through investment don&rsquo;t know it, and knowing it doesn&rsquo;t guarantee success.</p>
<p>Therefore, with youth, ambition, investment knowledge, and three key factors—saving NT$14,000 annually, investing in stocks or real estate, and patiently waiting for 40 years—anyone can achieve wealth through investment, regardless of their current economic situation.  These three factors are attainable for everyone:</p>
<ol>
<li>
<p>Saving NT$14,000 annually (NT$1,200 monthly) should be manageable for most. (If you can&rsquo;t save this much, focus on saving before investing. This book may not be as helpful yet, as you need some capital to start investing.)</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Historically, the long-term average return on stocks and real estate has been above 20%.  Consistently investing in these assets and holding them long-term can yield a 20% average return. These investment tools are accessible to everyone. (Data shows that the Taiwan stock market has averaged around 20% annual returns over the past 20 years; studies show similar returns for Taiwan real estate over the past 40 years.)</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>40 years seems long, but it&rsquo;s a timeframe most people have.  Starting work between 20 and 25 and retiring at 65 provides a 40-year investment window.  While some are born rich and others poor, most have a fair chance at accumulating wealth over 40 years.</p>
</li>
</ol>
<p>This example shows that investment not only improves finances but also provides a path to wealth.  With the right concepts and practices, anyone can achieve wealth through investment.</p>
<p><strong>Smart Investing Can Shorten the Journey by 10 Years</strong></p>
<p>While the initial example uses 40 years to demonstrate the power of investing, most readers are likely in a better position. They may already have savings and can save more than NT$14,000 annually, shortening their path to wealth.</p>
<p>The table below illustrates the wealth accumulation over 10-year intervals using the previous example (investing NT$14,000 annually with a 20% return):</p>
<p>If you have NT$360,000, congratulations! You&rsquo;ve saved 10 years of effort. By continuing to invest in stocks or real estate, you could become a billionaire in 30 years. With NT$2.61 million, you&rsquo;ve saved 20 years. With NT$16.55 million, you&rsquo;re even closer, needing only 10 more years.</p>
<table>
  <thead>
      <tr>
          <th style="text-align: left">Investment Years</th>
          <th style="text-align: left">Accumulated Amount (NT$10,000)</th>
          <th style="text-align: left">Amount Accumulated in the Last Decade (NT$10,000)</th>
      </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
      <tr>
          <td style="text-align: left">10</td>
          <td style="text-align: left">36</td>
          <td style="text-align: left">36</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td style="text-align: left">20</td>
          <td style="text-align: left">261</td>
          <td style="text-align: left">225</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td style="text-align: left">30</td>
          <td style="text-align: left">1655</td>
          <td style="text-align: left">1394</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td style="text-align: left">40</td>
          <td style="text-align: left">10281</td>
          <td style="text-align: left">8626</td>
      </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>
<p>Most readers likely have some savings, allowing them to achieve significant wealth in 20-30 years.</p>
<p><strong>Investing Doesn&rsquo;t Require Advanced Knowledge</strong></p>
<p><em>The trouble with the world is not that people know too little, but that they know so many things that just aren&rsquo;t so.</em></p>
<p>Many believe investing requires perfect timing and extensive financial knowledge.  This isn&rsquo;t entirely true.  After years of studying investment, and witnessing ordinary people achieve wealth through it, I can confidently say that investment success doesn&rsquo;t depend on academic qualifications, intelligence, technical skills, or predictive abilities.  It depends on doing the right things. Successful investors aren&rsquo;t necessarily highly educated or technically skilled; they can be ordinary people who understand fundamental principles.</p>
<p>By doing the right things, anyone can achieve wealth through investment, regardless of their background or effort. Investing doesn&rsquo;t require genius or specialized knowledge; common sense and consistent action are key. Investors don&rsquo;t need to rely on experts; with the right mindset, you can outperform them.</p>
<p>Investing isn&rsquo;t about complex techniques; it&rsquo;s about having the right mindset.  Successful investors simply cultivate habits that most people find uncomfortable or difficult to maintain. Do you understand that investing can create wealth? If so, are you actively pursuing it?</p>
<p>From another perspective, investing can be challenging. The difficulty lies not in needing advanced knowledge, but in going against ingrained habits. This is difficult for most people.</p>
<p>This book presents seemingly simple investment concepts, but wealth is built through consistent, correct habits. Start your investment journey by building the right habits!</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The amount of money you accumulate in your lifetime depends not on how much you earn, but on how you manage it.</p>
</blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">Saving Alone Is Not Enough 
    <div id="saving-alone-is-not-enough" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#saving-alone-is-not-enough" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>A Taiwanese proverb says, &ldquo;People have two legs, money has four.&rdquo; Money chases money faster than people chase money.</p>
<p>Traditional wisdom dictates that &ldquo;the path to wealth lies in diligence and frugality.&rdquo;  This held true in times of economic stagnation, but in today&rsquo;s rapidly changing economy, this mindset requires adjustment.</p>
<p>A century ago, before modern economics became widespread, during periods of economic stagnation and frequent wars, saving was indeed crucial for wealth accumulation. Today, however, with global economic growth and soaring stock and real estate prices, the focus should shift from saving to leveraging the power of compound interest for exponential growth.</p>
<p><strong>How Did Lien Chan Become Wealthy?</strong></p>
<p><em>With so many assets, it&rsquo;s impossible to monitor everything closely. During the period of entrusted management, the principle was to hold existing investments and not trade stocks or dispose of real estate.</em></p>
<p>Lien Chan, with an estimated net worth of nearly NT$6 billion, was one of Taiwan&rsquo;s wealthiest officials. His wealth wasn&rsquo;t accumulated through decades of frugal living on a government salary or through earning a doctoral degree.  It stemmed from his mother&rsquo;s shift in investment strategy over 40 years prior.</p>
<p>Around 1951, Chang Pin-san, former chairman of Chang Hwa Bank, advised Lien Chan&rsquo;s father, Lien Chen-tung, to invest in shares of the &ldquo;Big Three&rdquo; commercial banks.  Following this advice, Lien Chan&rsquo;s mother, Chao Lan-kun, invested her savings in hundreds of shares of Chang Hwa Bank, holding them long-term and letting their value appreciate naturally. This laid the foundation for the Lien family&rsquo;s fortune. Chao Lan-kun had a keen financial mind. Unlike other women who participated in rotating savings and credit associations or simply deposited money in banks, she actively invested.  She sold ancestral farmland in Miaoli and co-developed a property on Nanjing West Road with Huang Lie-huo, founder of Wei Chuan Foods Corporation, splitting the profits. This prime real estate became a significant source of wealth for the Lien family.</p>
<p>Stocks, real estate, and land were the Lien family&rsquo;s wealth-generating tools. Over the years, Lien Chan accumulated holdings in 19 different stocks, including Chang Hwa Bank, Taipei Business Bank, Hua Nan Bank, and Cathay Life Insurance.  His real estate holdings were located in prime areas like the Da&rsquo;an, Shilin, and Zhongshan districts, including 11 plots of land and 26 properties.</p>
<p>Lien Chan once described his family&rsquo;s investment approach as &ldquo;Wu Wei Er Zhi&rdquo; (doing nothing and achieving everything), meaning buying and holding long-term.  By investing in stocks and real estate 40 years ago and patiently holding them, with minimal trading and benefiting from annual returns exceeding 20%, they amassed a fortune nearing NT$10 billion.</p>
<p>You might argue that the Lien family was already wealthy 40 years ago. This might be true, but the point is that while they were prominent, many families in Taiwan were wealthier back then. Today, very few families surpass the Liens in wealth.  This is attributed to their early adoption of the correct investment strategy – focusing on stocks and real estate.</p>
<p><strong>The Key to Wealth Lies in Financial Management, Not Just Saving</strong></p>
<p><em>The ability to earn money is less important than having a mind for financial management, understanding how to make money work for you.</em></p>
<p>Chinese culture values diligence and frugality.  Older generations often teach younger ones that the path to wealth lies in these principles and careful budgeting.  The saying &ldquo;Great wealth comes from heaven, small wealth from frugality&rdquo; encourages thriftiness, as it&rsquo;s seen as the key to wealth.  This emphasis on saving is reflected in Taiwan&rsquo;s high savings rate.  However, I want to convey a crucial message: while saving is important, financial management is even more so.</p>
<p>In the previous example, how much of the NT$100+ million fortune came from diligence and frugality? The answer is NT$560,000, accumulated by saving NT$14,000 annually for 40 years.  This represents only 0.5% of the total.  The remaining 99.5% came from investment, specifically the power of compound interest at a 20% annual return over 40 years.  Which is more important, saving or investing? <strong>Therefore, lifetime wealth accumulation depends not on how much you earn, but on how you manage your money.</strong></p>
<p>If a worker realizes in old age that their wealth primarily comes from a lifetime of hard work and saving, it&rsquo;s almost certain they won&rsquo;t be very wealthy.  The key to wealth through investment isn&rsquo;t the ability to &ldquo;earn and save,&rdquo; but the ability to leverage the &ldquo;compounding power of money.&rdquo;  For most, improving their financial situation requires focusing on investment, not just saving.</p>
<p>Consider this: saving NT$1 million annually without investing would take 100 years to reach NT$100 million. In contrast, investing NT$14,000 annually could make you a billionaire in 40 years. If Chao Lan-kun had only focused on saving and not investing, would the Lien family be as wealthy as they are today?</p>
<p>I&rsquo;m not dismissing the importance of saving, but I want to emphasize that it shouldn&rsquo;t overshadow investment. Investment plays a crucial role in wealth accumulation.  For successful investors, wealth comes primarily from &ldquo;making money work for you,&rdquo; not from earning or saving. Therefore, in addition to being diligent and frugal, learn how to invest.</p>
<p>To improve your financial situation, remember: earning is important, but managing your money is more so. <strong>A correct investment mindset and wise investment choices have a greater impact on your future financial status than your current wealth or future income.</strong> For most, the first step towards improving their finances is not to increase saving, but to understand the correct investment concepts and take action.</p>
<p><em>1. For those who achieve wealth through investment, their fortune comes primarily from making money work for them, not from earning or saving.</em></p>
<p><em>2.  Less than 1% of a NT$100 million fortune comes directly from earned income.</em></p>
<p><em>3.  Investment is not a technique, but a mindset.</em></p>
<p><em>4. The key to financial management is having money to manage, not the amount of money.</em></p>
<blockquote>
<p>Those who learn to invest are like having a money-printing machine.</p>
</blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">How Investment Strategies Create the Wealth Gap 
    <div id="how-investment-strategies-create-the-wealth-gap" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#how-investment-strategies-create-the-wealth-gap" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>A study indicates that in recent years, the public has perceived a serious wealth gap in Taiwan, with a trend towards wealth polarization. Over 47% of respondents believe that &ldquo;speculation in stocks or real estate&rdquo; is the main cause of this widening gap, followed by &ldquo;personal work ability and effort&rdquo; (14%) and &ldquo;family background&rdquo; (11%).  This suggests a common belief that the wealth gap isn&rsquo;t solely due to individual effort, but also to systemic issues, luck, and unequal opportunities.</p>
<p>Indeed, &ldquo;stocks and real estate&rdquo; are major contributors to the wealth gap, while &ldquo;personal work ability and effort&rdquo; and &ldquo;family background&rdquo; have less impact. <strong>People often attribute their poverty to external factors like systemic issues, luck, or lack of opportunity, or use negative terms like &ldquo;speculation&rdquo; to explain their lack of action.</strong> Wealthy individuals often accumulate their wealth through real estate or stock investments, not primarily through &ldquo;speculation,&rdquo; but through &ldquo;holding appropriate investment assets.&rdquo;</p>
<p>Looking ahead, the wealth gap will likely continue to widen. Some will benefit, while others will suffer, depending on their ability to navigate the changing landscape. External factors alone don&rsquo;t determine our financial situation; our investment abilities play a crucial role.</p>
<p><em>1. Financial habits create the difference between the rich and the poor.</em></p>
<p><em>2. The prerequisite for building wealth through investment is allocating assets to high-return investments like stocks or real estate.</em></p>
<p><em>3. One way for the government to address the widening wealth gap is to educate the public about proper financial management.</em></p>
<p><strong>Greater Investment, Greater Returns</strong></p>
<p><em>&ldquo;Thoughts change actions, actions change habits, habits change character, and character changes destiny.&rdquo;</em></p>
<p>Imagine two classmates who join the same company after graduation, holding similar positions with the same salary.  Both are equally frugal, saving NT$14,000 annually for investment. The difference lies in their approach: one keeps their savings in the bank, while the other invests in stocks. Both largely leave their money untouched after depositing or investing it.</p>
<p>After 40 years, the stock investor becomes a billionaire, while the bank saver becomes a &ldquo;millionaire.&rdquo;  While a billion represents significant wealth, &ldquo;millionaire&rdquo; now evokes laughter, being synonymous with &ldquo;homeless&rdquo; in Taiwan&rsquo;s expensive housing market.</p>
<p>The &ldquo;millionaire&rdquo; classmate, seeing their former colleague with the same starting conditions become a billionaire, might assume foul play or lottery winnings. How could their wealth differ so drastically, with one rich and the other struggling?</p>
<p>Those with less wealth often attribute the success of the wealthy to luck or illicit activities. A more positive view might be that they worked harder or were more frugal.  However, they often overlook the critical factor: financial habits. The rich and poor manage their money differently: the rich hold assets like real estate and stocks, while the poor keep their money in the bank.</p>
<p>To become wealthy through investment, one must break free from conventional thinking. An adult who couldn&rsquo;t ride a bicycle saw a child doing so and complained, &ldquo;Only agile children can ride bikes.&rdquo; The child responded, &ldquo;Agility isn&rsquo;t necessary,&rdquo; and taught the adult to ride.  The adult quickly learned but, upon parting ways, instinctively pushed the bicycle home instead of riding it.  This illustrates the difficulty of breaking free from ingrained habits.</p>
<p>If financial management is the primary cause of the wealth gap, the solution lies in improving financial literacy and encouraging people to learn more about investing.</p>
<p><strong>Focusing Solely on Saving is Outdated</strong></p>
<p><em>If one adheres to the principles of investment, it&rsquo;s hard not to become wealthy. If one doesn&rsquo;t, it&rsquo;s hard to become wealthy.</em></p>
<p>I often wonder why, after over 200 years since their ancestors arrived in Taiwan with nothing, most Taiwanese families aren&rsquo;t significantly wealthy. Perhaps the problem lies in outdated family precepts that hinder wealth accumulation.</p>
<p>Family precepts are the guiding principles passed down through generations.  Most families emphasize diligence, frugality, and academic excellence, believing these are the keys to success and wealth.</p>
<p>Many families diligently follow these precepts, raising children who are both frugal and well-educated.  However, few families achieve significant wealth through these alone.  These precepts focus on earning money, not on managing it.  To build generational wealth, families need to update their guiding principles.  While &ldquo;diligence and frugality&rdquo; and &ldquo;academic excellence&rdquo; remain valuable, add another: &ldquo;Don&rsquo;t keep money in the bank.&rdquo;</p>
<p>Why retain &ldquo;diligence and frugality&rdquo;? While saving alone won&rsquo;t lead to great wealth, it&rsquo;s a virtue and a necessary foundation for investment.</p>
<p><strong>Educating the Next Generation Requires a Balanced Approach</strong></p>
<p>Why keep &ldquo;academic excellence&rdquo;?  Studies show a weak correlation between education and wealth.  Academic success doesn&rsquo;t guarantee financial success.  Based on this, I once stopped emphasizing academics with my children, resulting in declining grades.  Their teacher, puzzled, asked, &ldquo;You and your wife are both highly educated, why don&rsquo;t your children share this trait?&rdquo; I was ashamed.</p>
<p>I immediately reinstated the emphasis on academics. I realized it was partly for our own pride, but also because education can enhance social standing and job security. So, for both parents and children, academic pursuits remain important.</p>
<p>However, for future generations to prosper, add another precept: &ldquo;Don&rsquo;t keep money in the bank!&rdquo;  Encourage children to invest in assets like stocks and real estate, rather than leaving money in low-interest bank accounts.  Otherwise, building significant wealth might take generations.</p>
<p>Every Lunar New Year, I buy stocks for my children instead of giving cash. My second-grader is already learning the importance of investing over saving. This concept should be ingrained early as part of family values, fostering a healthy financial mindset from a young age.</p>
<p>In conclusion, most family precepts are outdated.  Building wealth for future generations requires new concepts and practices.  By updating family values and changing how we accumulate wealth, families can achieve lasting prosperity.</p>
<p><em>1. Diligence, frugality, and academic excellence alone are not enough for building lasting wealth.</em></p>
<p><em>2. Teach children not to keep money in the bank, cultivating a proper investment mindset from a young age.</em></p>
<p><em>3.  Leaving money to children might sustain them for a few years; teaching them how to manage it can provide for a lifetime and for generations to come.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>00490 Workers are just picking up trash; Mortgages are a risk for retirees; Buying a house won&#39;t make you rich.</title>
      <link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1730597712367/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1730597712367/</guid>
      <description>This session focuses on investment philosophy, asset allocation, lifestyle, and how to cope with market fluctuations. It emphasizes the importance of staying optimistic, continuous learning, and answers questions from the audience on Bitcoin, real estate, retirement planning, leveraged funds, and education funds.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<lite-youtube videoid="Ad9u7a-z6Ro" playlabel="Ad9u7a-z6Ro" params=""></lite-youtube>



<h2 class="relative group">I. Main Topic 
    <div id="i-main-topic" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-main-topic" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This session revolves around investment and life planning. The core ideas are: be optimistic about investment and keep learning, ignoring short-term market fluctuations; young people should focus on asset appreciation, with Nasdaq 100 index funds being the top choice; utilize leverage and allocate assets reasonably; retirees should plan carefully and avoid excessive debt; and one should stay optimistic and confident, avoid material comparisons, and pursue true freedom.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">II. Presentation Content 
    <div id="ii-presentation-content" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii-presentation-content" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Investment Philosophy and Market Analysis 
    <div id="investment-philosophy-and-market-analysis" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#investment-philosophy-and-market-analysis" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Market Fluctuations and Investment Mentality:</strong> The market is always fluctuating. Don&rsquo;t let short-term fluctuations affect your investment decisions. Stay optimistic.</li>
<li><strong>Currency Devaluation and Asset Appreciation:</strong> Money depreciates; only assets like stocks can preserve and increase in value. Currency devaluation is more severe in emerging countries, so it is advised to convert currency into assets. Taiwan&rsquo;s low wages and currency devaluation are related to the government&rsquo;s subsidy policies.</li>
<li><strong>Worker Mindset vs. Capitalist Mindset:</strong> Workers exchange labor for depreciating currency, while capitalists exchange currency for appreciating assets. Learn to invest and become a capitalist, exchanging &ldquo;trash&rdquo; (depreciating currency) for assets.</li>
<li><strong>Global Market Linkage:</strong> Global markets are highly interconnected, and diversifying investments into other regions has limited effectiveness. Focusing on the US stock market is recommended.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Asset Allocation Strategies 
    <div id="asset-allocation-strategies" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#asset-allocation-strategies" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Nasdaq 100 Index Funds:</strong> The preferred choice for young people. Long-term investment can yield substantial returns.  Global codes for purchasing Nasdaq 100 index funds were provided, and investing based on market conditions is recommended.</li>
<li><strong>The Importance of Cash:</strong> Cash reserves are crucial. 00864B and money market funds (like SWVXX, VOXX) are safeguards and should not be replaced with high-dividend products like SPHD, as principal safety is paramount.</li>
<li><strong>Smart Rebalancing:</strong> Suitable for those who use leveraged funds, are not retired, and have income.</li>
<li><strong>Risks of Real Estate Investment:</strong> Housing prices in the Bay Area are high, putting great pressure on young people to buy houses, which can easily lead to financial difficulties. Renting is recommended to maintain flexibility.</li>
<li><strong>Borrowing and Investment:</strong> Loans, mortgages, and car loans should be repaid with stable cash flow, not relying on stock market returns.</li>
<li><strong>Retirement Planning:</strong> Retirees should be cautious about borrowing and make plans based on the size of their retirement funds.  If retirement funds are 50 times the annual expenses, two options are available: 1. Keep the mortgage and car loan, using 2% of the retirement fund annually to cover all expenses; 2. Pay off the mortgage and car loan, invest 80% of the remaining funds in 00662, 20% in 00864B, and use 2% of the total funds annually for living expenses.</li>
<li><strong>Asset Allocation Case Study:</strong> A case study with 45 million Taiwan dollars illustrated asset allocation strategies when withdrawals are not needed. An 80/20 allocation or a combination of leveraged funds (60% 00662, 20% 00670L, 20% 00864B) is recommended.  For those with stable income and no need to withdraw from investments, 100% investment in QQQ can be considered.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Other Matters 
    <div id="other-matters" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#other-matters" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Class Suspension Notice:</strong> Class is suspended on November 9th and resumes on November 16th. After daylight saving time ends, the class time will be changed to 6:00 AM Pacific Time and 10:00 PM Taiwan time.</li>
<li><strong>Stay Optimistic:</strong> Maintain an optimistic mindset; the market will reward you. Like, subscribe, and leave comments on various platforms to benefit more people.</li>
<li><strong>Contact Information:</strong> Two email addresses were provided for contact.</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">III. Q&amp;A Session 
    <div id="iii-qa-session" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii-qa-session" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Brian: 
    <div id="brian" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#brian" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing 1: Read &ldquo;Investing is Asset Allocation, What You Don&rsquo;t Know,&rdquo; agreeing with the importance of accumulating the first pot of gold early; learning investment allows for more focus on work and personal improvement, spending time each day learning new skills and increasing self-worth.  Investment enables people to be more motivated to improve their professional skills rather than &ldquo;lying flat.&rdquo;</li>
<li>Sharing 2: Individuals can improve their earning potential through learning, even if their investment assets are reduced to zero, they can still rely on professional skills to make a comeback.</li>
<li>Question 1: What should I do if the Beta value is very low when the asset value plummets in the Excel sheet?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: The sheet is designed for acceleration during market rises and deceleration during falls. A low Beta value is normal and a reflection of risk control; no adjustment is needed.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2: Even knowing that investment should be mindless, I still worry when the Beta value drops. How should I cope?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: Deceleration during declines is the purpose of the investment strategy. Don&rsquo;t worry, stick to the plan, just like autopilot.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">LU: 
    <div id="lu" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#lu" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question 1: What is the impact of Trump&rsquo;s potential return to office on Bitcoin?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: The US has abandoned the gold standard and will not adopt a Bitcoin standard. Bitcoin is similar to gold and has an anti-inflationary function, but its future development is limited.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2: Can QQQ break through its previous high?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: It definitely can. The current market is bullish; there&rsquo;s no need to worry.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Wendy: 
    <div id="wendy" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#wendy" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing 1: Learned James&rsquo;s investment philosophy and successfully recouped the income lost during unemployment. Started reading recommended books such as &ldquo;The Richest Man in Babylon&rdquo; and &ldquo;The Most Important Thing.&rdquo;</li>
<li>No Questions</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Peter: 
    <div id="peter" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#peter" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing 1: Agrees with James&rsquo;s philosophy and has increased the investment proportion of QQQ, but some individual stocks have not been completely sold due to tax reasons.</li>
<li>Question 1: Advantages and disadvantages of converting 401K to Roth 401K?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: Just put new contributions into Roth 401K; don&rsquo;t convert existing funds. Convert at retirement.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2:  How to use HSA and 529 accounts?  Is there any problem with using a credit card to pay medical bills from an HSA?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply:  HSA, 529, and college fund accounts are not recommended because they lead to a loss of control over the funds. Using your own funds or loans is recommended.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 3: Are there any suggestions for increasing income and saving money besides a full-time job?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: Excessive saving is not recommended. Plan for retirement funds first, and the remaining money can be freely used and enjoyed.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Yi Jie (First Sister): 
    <div id="yi-jie-first-sister" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#yi-jie-first-sister" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing 1: Previously followed the advice of online influencers and invested in US stocks and treasury bonds, currently converting to QQQ.  Has a modest salary and one child.</li>
<li>Question 1: Can the 20% cash in the 80/20 allocation be replaced with Fubon 50 2X leverage?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply:  QQQ 2X leverage (00670L) is recommended. He explained the use of leveraged funds.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2: Is it feasible to regularly invest equal amounts in QQQ and 2X leverage?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: Feasible, but pay attention to cash reserves. A Beta of 1.1 or 1.2 allocation is recommended, adjusting according to market conditions.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 3: Can a child&rsquo;s Lunar New Year money be all-in on 2X leverage?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: If you can guarantee continuous regular investment for more than 30 years, it&rsquo;s worth considering, but be aware of the risks and be able to withstand significant asset shrinkage.  In the long run, the returns can be substantial, but psychological barriers must be overcome.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 4: Are the views of online influencers recommending treasury bonds correct? Are treasury bonds more valuable during a market crash?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: Incorrect. During market downturns, bond declines can be even greater.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">IAM: 
    <div id="iam" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iam" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing 1: Reflecting on the value of money, learning gratitude, and paying attention to community articles, realizing that spending money is spending one&rsquo;s life energy.</li>
<li>Sharing 2: Made 100 pages of notes and calculated the return on an 80,000 loan invested for 40 years; the result was shocking.</li>
<li>Question 1: Why are people not accustomed to borrowing for investment?  Confused about the phenomenon of young people being afraid to borrow for investment but willing to use installment plans for consumption.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: This is due to cultural influences.  Change your mindset and recognize that good debt can help accumulate wealth. Shared personal experiences and spending philosophy, emphasizing the freedom of spending after becoming wealthy.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">YJ Yuanlin: 
    <div id="yj-yuanlin" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#yj-yuanlin" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing 1: Investing boosts confidence, enabling focus on work and hobbies.</li>
<li>Question 1: In a down year, can TQQ replace QLD in smart rebalancing?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: Both are possible, but pay attention to risk control and avoid excessive pursuit of high risk. TQQ has greater volatility and requires a stronger psychological capacity.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">T: 
    <div id="t" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#t" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question 1: What are your thoughts on Elon Musk supporting Trump?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: Politicians&rsquo; decisions are the result of weighing pros and cons. Elon Musk&rsquo;s support for Trump stems from personal interests and positions, such as opposing certain liberal policies.  Entrepreneurs also have to choose between different political forces.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Yi Ni: 
    <div id="yi-ni" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#yi-ni" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question 1: How to invest and use Canadian education fund accounts?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: It&rsquo;s recommended to thoroughly research the specific rules of the account and consider methods like pledged loans to avoid locking up funds. Inquired about whether it&rsquo;s possible to withdraw all funds and the limitations, suggesting consulting with professionals.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Meng: 
    <div id="meng" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#meng" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing 1: In the high-tech era, privacy and freedom are difficult to have both.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Peter: 
    <div id="peter-1" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#peter-1" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing 1: It can be difficult for beginners to invest in QQQ, etc. It&rsquo;s suggested to start by buying one share and gradually build confidence.  James&rsquo;s explanations are very patient and benefit everyone.</li>
<li>Question 1: How to strengthen mental and psychological well-being?  James&rsquo;s experience sharing on meditation and hypnosis.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: Recommended Rachel&rsquo;s hypnosis channel and shared personal methods of using hypnosis and positive psychological suggestions. Suggested listening to hypnotic audios every night before sleep.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">IV. Key Takeaways 
    <div id="iv-key-takeaways" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv-key-takeaways" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>Rise faster, fall slower.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This is one of James&rsquo;s core investment philosophies. Through smart rebalancing strategies, increase investment during market rises to accelerate profits, and reduce investment during market downturns to mitigate losses.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Money is the least valuable thing when it has no value.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This reflects James&rsquo;s unique view on wealth. When wealth accumulates to a certain extent, the value of money itself is no longer important; what matters more is pursuing freedom and happiness.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>If you want freedom, and you want privacy, you will not have freedom. In the future world, if you want privacy, you will not have freedom.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This shows James&rsquo;s insight into future social trends. In the high-tech era, one needs to make trade-offs between privacy and freedom.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The more daring one is to borrow money, the broader their perspective.
&ndash; YJ Yuanlin</p>
</blockquote>
<p>YJ Yuanlin&rsquo;s sharing led to James&rsquo;s views on borrowing: good debt can help wealth growth.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>If you want freedom, you cannot care.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Echoing the topic of Elon Musk supporting Trump and the entrepreneurial spirit, true freedom is not caring about external opinions and focusing on one&rsquo;s goals.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>If you don&rsquo;t use ChatGPT now, you are outdated and will be eliminated.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>James advocates for new technologies and maintains an open attitude towards learning new things.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">V. Summary 
    <div id="v-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#v-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This session covered various aspects of investment philosophy, asset allocation, lifestyle, and how to cope with market fluctuations.  James answered the audience&rsquo;s questions with easy-to-understand language and rich examples, sharing his life experiences and insights, and encouraging everyone to stay optimistic, continue learning, and pursue true freedom and happiness.</p>

  



<div
  
    class="flex px-4 py-3 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900"
  >

  <span
    
      class="text-primary-400 ltr:pr-3 rtl:pl-3 flex items-center"
    >

    

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M506.3 417l-213.3-364c-16.33-28-57.54-28-73.98 0l-213.2 364C-10.59 444.9 9.849 480 42.74 480h426.6C502.1 480 522.6 445 506.3 417zM232 168c0-13.25 10.75-24 24-24S280 154.8 280 168v128c0 13.25-10.75 24-23.1 24S232 309.3 232 296V168zM256 416c-17.36 0-31.44-14.08-31.44-31.44c0-17.36 14.07-31.44 31.44-31.44s31.44 14.08 31.44 31.44C287.4 401.9 273.4 416 256 416z"/></svg>

  </span>


  </span>

  <span
    
      class="dark:text-neutral-300"
    ><strong>Disclaimer:</strong> This article is for personal learning notes only and does not constitute any investment advice.</span>
</div>

]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>00479 Three Easy Examples of Getting Rich, The Power of Starting Early and Compound Interest</title>
      <link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1728391134352/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1728391134352/</guid>
      <description>In this session, James reiterates the importance of long-term index fund investing, illustrating the power of compounding interest with multiple examples. He also explains how to avoid common investment pitfalls to achieve financial freedom.  Additionally, James addresses audience questions on asset allocation, real estate investment, trusts, and children&amp;#39;s education funds.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<lite-youtube videoid="1VSo2I6xqG0" playlabel="1VSo2I6xqG0" params=""></lite-youtube>



<h2 class="relative group">I. Main Topic 
    <div id="i-main-topic" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-main-topic" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This session focuses on long-term index fund investing. The core message is: hold index funds firmly, ignore market fluctuations, maintain a proper asset allocation, and leverage the compounding effect of time to achieve financial freedom.  James also warns against investment scams and emphasizes avoiding unnecessary risks, while offering advice on investing in children&rsquo;s education funds.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">II. Presentation Summary 
    <div id="ii-presentation-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii-presentation-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<ul>
<li><strong>Advantages of Index Funds:</strong> Long-term index fund investing eliminates the need to follow short-term market fluctuations, international affairs, financial reports, and economic data.  Focus on asset allocation and consistent investment.</li>
<li><strong>The Power of Compounding:</strong> James uses several examples to illustrate the magic of compounding:  A monthly investment of 1000 TWD can grow to 17.3 million TWD in 40 years; a lump-sum investment of 100,000 TWD can reach 18.8 million TWD in 40 years;  starting early is crucial, as a 10-year delay significantly impacts final returns; one share of QQQ at 500 USD will become 25,000 USD in 30 years and 94,000 USD in 40 years.</li>
<li><strong>Safe Asset Allocation:</strong> Asset allocation is more critical than any market commentary. James recommends deleveraging and reducing debt for those nearing retirement, holding a larger cash position.  For younger individuals with stable income, leveraging can be considered. He suggests using a beta of 1.0 as a benchmark, reducing beta when the market is overheated, and increasing it back to 1.0 during market downturns.  For cash allocation, he references Buffett and suggests a sample allocation (Scenario 3): 40% index funds, 30% 2x leveraged funds, and 30% cash.</li>
<li><strong>Beware of Investment Scams:</strong>  Don&rsquo;t trust investment information from unknown accounts or websites. Choose legitimate financial institutions.</li>
<li><strong>Don&rsquo;t Give Money Directly to Children:</strong> James uses personal anecdotes and case studies to caution against putting assets directly in children&rsquo;s names, as this may discourage their initiative or cause family conflicts.  However, investing children&rsquo;s &ldquo;lucky money&rdquo; (red envelopes) for them is recommended as an educational fund.</li>
<li><strong>Risks of Real Estate Investment:</strong> James reiterates his advice against early homeownership for young people, arguing that real estate is illiquid, high-risk, and ties up capital that could be used for other investments.  He highlights the added risk in Taiwan, where mortgage debt remains even after foreclosure.</li>
<li><strong>Recommended Learning Resources:</strong> He recommends a YouTube channel called &ldquo;什么值得读&rdquo; (What&rsquo;s Worth Reading) for valuable content on value investing.</li>
<li><strong>Emergency Fund:</strong> Maintain a cash reserve equivalent to six months of living expenses in a money market fund account. Investing this emergency fund in stocks is not recommended.</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">III. Q&amp;A Session 
    <div id="iii-qa-session" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii-qa-session" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p><strong>Jeff:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Shares:  Highlights misconceptions about investing held by two listeners and emphasizes the importance of carefully studying James&rsquo;s lecture notes, particularly the chart on page two.</li>
<li>James&rsquo;s response:  Affirms Jeff&rsquo;s points and re-emphasizes the importance of a solid investment philosophy to avoid being swayed by market noise.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Cat:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Shares: A listener holding 35 million TWD in 00662 still finds the 2% withdrawal rate insufficient. Discusses the spending needs and inheritance considerations of single individuals.</li>
<li>James&rsquo;s response: Different indices have different volatility and dividend yields, requiring adjustments to withdrawal rates. For higher withdrawals, consider ETFs with higher dividend yields, such as 0056, which yields around 4-5%.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>H:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Question:  High rental costs for young people, should they buy a house?  Mortgages offer tax deductions, while renting does not.  Concerned about insufficient funds for leveraged investing.</li>
<li>James&rsquo;s response:  Recommends watching the &ldquo;30 Years of Different Destinies&rdquo; video, which analyzes the pros and cons of renting versus buying.  Young people should prioritize investing in index funds to build wealth through compounding and consider buying a house later.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Yonglin:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Question: Should money be invested in children&rsquo;s names for long-term holding?  Should a mortgage-free house be sold to invest in index funds after retirement?</li>
<li>James&rsquo;s response:  Advises against putting money directly in children&rsquo;s names.  Retirees should deleverage, and selling a mortgage-free house to invest in index funds is a viable option.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Mike:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Shares: Success story of investing his children&rsquo;s education fund in QQQ.  Gives the example of Taoyuan Language in Taiwan, suggesting potential leveraged investment through real estate mortgages.</li>
<li>Question: How to establish a family trust and manage generational wealth like the Rockefeller family?</li>
<li>James&rsquo;s response:  Recommends contacting Lisa for trust advice when assets reach a certain level and age. For now, focus on investing. Trusts can be considered around 70-80 years old. Single individuals or those without children should rely on trusts, appointing guardians and executors.  Those with children can consider Trust 2.0, with the bank as executor and children as supervisors.  Family foundations managed by professional institutions are also an option.  Recommends the Walmart family&rsquo;s living trust as a model.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Becky, Jessie, and Other Participants:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Becky: Difficulties of renting at an older age.</li>
<li>Jessie: How to balance saving for an emergency fund, paying off a mortgage, and investing simultaneously.</li>
<li>Other Participants: Questions about real estate investment, cash management, insurance, Bitcoin, and Japanese government bonds.</li>
<li>James&rsquo;s response:  Addresses each question and reiterates his investment philosophy.  For example, young people should avoid real estate and insurance due to high risks; long-term bonds and municipal bonds are not suitable for emergency funds.</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">IV. Key Takeaways 
    <div id="iv-key-takeaways" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv-key-takeaways" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>Time is the source of all power.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>James uses examples like the evolution of Earth&rsquo;s ecosystem and human evolution to illustrate the power of time and emphasize the importance of long-term investing.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Don&rsquo;t casually help others with money.  People will resent you for it for a lifetime.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Cautions against testing human nature with money and emphasizes setting boundaries with financial assistance.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The earlier you invest, the better.  Keep enough emergency funds. The earlier you invest, the lower the risk.
&ndash; Jeff</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Emphasizes the importance of early investing and maintaining an emergency fund.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Laugh a little; how long a scammer can scam is determined by the fool.
&ndash; Mike</p>
</blockquote>
<p>A cynical comment on the prevalence of scammers and a reminder to stay vigilant.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">V. Conclusion 
    <div id="v-conclusion" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#v-conclusion" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>The core message of this session remains long-term index fund investing. James uses clear language and vivid examples to reiterate the power of compounding and the importance of starting early. He also addresses audience questions on asset allocation, real estate, trusts, emergency funds, and children&rsquo;s education funds, sharing advice on avoiding common investment traps and achieving financial freedom.  He further recommends learning resources and provides commentary on social phenomena.</p>

  



<div
  
    class="flex px-4 py-3 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900"
  >

  <span
    
      class="text-primary-400 ltr:pr-3 rtl:pl-3 flex items-center"
    >

    

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M506.3 417l-213.3-364c-16.33-28-57.54-28-73.98 0l-213.2 364C-10.59 444.9 9.849 480 42.74 480h426.6C502.1 480 522.6 445 506.3 417zM232 168c0-13.25 10.75-24 24-24S280 154.8 280 168v128c0 13.25-10.75 24-23.1 24S232 309.3 232 296V168zM256 416c-17.36 0-31.44-14.08-31.44-31.44c0-17.36 14.07-31.44 31.44-31.44s31.44 14.08 31.44 31.44C287.4 401.9 273.4 416 256 416z"/></svg>

  </span>


  </span>

  <span
    
      class="dark:text-neutral-300"
    ><strong>Disclaimer:</strong> This document is for personal learning notes only and does not constitute any investment advice.</span>
</div>

]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
