<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Financial Independence on QQQ Investor</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/tags/financial-independence/</link><description>Recent content in Financial Independence on QQQ Investor</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 14 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jomonylw.github.io/en/tags/financial-independence/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>00518 From Houses to Bonds: Asset Allocation is a Master Strategy, Avoid Scams, Understand Risks, and Return to the Index</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1749950529180/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1749950529180/</guid><description>Teacher James shares his philosophy of long-term investment in the Nasdaq 100 index fund, emphasizing risk control, asset allocation (especially the importance of cash), and a positive investment mindset. The content covers his views on current market volatility, bond investments, financial products, individual stocks versus ETFs, as well as practical sharing and Q&amp;amp;A with students, supplemented by the teacher&amp;#39;s profound reflections on personal experiences, educational philosophy, and social responsibility.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<lite-youtube videoid="JlFNunk6brQ" playlabel="JlFNunk6brQ" params=""></lite-youtube>



<h2 class="relative group">I. Theme of the Session 
    <div id="i-theme-of-the-session" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-theme-of-the-session" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>The core of this lecture is to emphasize <strong>persisting in long-term investment in the Nasdaq 100 index fund, prioritizing risk control and reasonable asset allocation, and maintaining an extremely optimistic investment mindset</strong>. Teacher James points out that market volatility is normal; investors should ignore short-term fluctuations, focus on long-term growth, recognize the critical role of cash in asset allocation, and ultimately achieve financial freedom and life&rsquo;s purpose.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">II. Briefing Content 
    <div id="ii-briefing-content" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii-briefing-content" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Opening and Investment Mindset 
    <div id="opening-and-investment-mindset" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#opening-and-investment-mindset" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>The Market&rsquo;s Normal State</strong>: Global situations and market turmoil are normal. Investors should remain calm and not be disturbed by short-term volatility, international affairs, market analysis, financial statements, or economic conditions.</li>
<li><strong>Disclaimer</strong>: This channel is a pro bono sharing platform and does not constitute investment advice. There are no fees, no alternate accounts, and be wary of scams. Investing involves risk, which you must manage yourself. Relevant links are pinned in the YouTube comments section.</li>
<li><strong>Learning Path</strong>: Newcomers are advised to start with &ldquo;00451 The One-Dollar Investment Lecture,&rdquo; think independently, and find a method that suits them. Quiet study improves the quality of thought more than joining too many groups.</li>
<li><strong>Core Investment Vehicle</strong>: Focus on the Nasdaq 100 index fund (like QQQ). Page 10 of the handout provides a selection of related funds worldwide. The videos started in 2018, and there is a complete 2022 course playlist available.</li>
<li><strong>Investment Mentality</strong>: Always be extremely optimistic, always face the sun; the market will eventually go up. Investing requires patience (ignoring market fluctuations), and financial freedom is worth the wait. Please like, comment, and subscribe on all platforms.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Macroeconomics and the Bond Myth 
    <div id="macroeconomics-and-the-bond-myth" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#macroeconomics-and-the-bond-myth" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Stablecoins and Short-Term Treasuries</strong>: A student asked if the issuance of stablecoins would increase demand for short-term treasuries and lower their interest rates. Teacher James believes short-term treasury rates are tied to the central bank&rsquo;s rates and won&rsquo;t fall significantly because of this. Short-term treasuries are similar to money market funds with low volatility. The central bank&rsquo;s rate is the benchmark; no one would buy a bond with a lower rate.</li>
<li><strong>The Trap of Long-Term Bonds</strong>: Long-term bond interest is linked to inflation expectations for many years to come, and the interest is fixed.
<ul>
<li><strong>Example</strong>: For a 30-year Treasury bond with a 5% coupon rate, if inflation is 3%, the real annualized rate of return (Real IRR) is only 1.94%. In contrast, if short-term rates are 4%, it is far superior to the real return of long-term bonds. The $5 in interest you receive after 30 years will have long been devalued.</li>
<li><strong>Conclusion</strong>: It is not recommended for individual investors to buy long-term government bonds. Issuing long-term bonds is advantageous for the U.S. Treasury because the long-term interest is close to zero for the issuer (after considering inflation). Even if the central bank&rsquo;s rate is below 2%, buying long-term bonds is not necessarily a good deal. The Treasury has its own issuance plan and won&rsquo;t easily change it due to shifts in the central bank&rsquo;s rates. The idea of issuing 100-year bonds is impractical and tantamount to default.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Risk Control and Asset Allocation 
    <div id="risk-control-and-asset-allocation" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#risk-control-and-asset-allocation" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Risk Awareness</strong>: The first priority in investing is risk control; the world is full of uncertainties (like the conflict in Israel).</li>
<li><strong>The Importance of Asset Allocation</strong>: Good asset allocation is a &ldquo;master strategy&rdquo; (奇门遁甲), a powerful &ldquo;Army, Navy, and Air Force&rdquo; deployment.
<ul>
<li><strong>Cash</strong>: The &ldquo;food and air&rdquo; of asset allocation, the most important part. Sufficient cash prevents market panic.</li>
<li><strong>Index Fund</strong>: The &ldquo;aircraft carrier&rdquo; of asset allocation.</li>
<li><strong>Leveraged Fund</strong>: Like the &ldquo;missile force.&rdquo;</li>
<li><strong>Stock Pledging</strong>: The &ldquo;Transformer&rdquo; of asset allocation.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>The Courage to Sell a House for Investment</strong>: Selling your primary residence to rent and investing the funds in an index is an excellent financial strategy, but it requires a strong mind and the courage to face social judgment (e.g., fear of being told you&rsquo;re &ldquo;not doing well&rdquo;). In reality, this is a sign of &ldquo;doing exceptionally well.&rdquo;</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Investment Concepts and Behavioral Psychology 
    <div id="investment-concepts-and-behavioral-psychology" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#investment-concepts-and-behavioral-psychology" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>The Difficulty of Educating Family and Friends</strong>: Family and friends would rather trust the annuities and savings insurance (1% return) recommended by bank advisors than accept advice about index funds (10% long-term return), even when presented with spreadsheets. The main reason is the fear of &ldquo;what if it drops?&rdquo;
<ul>
<li><strong>Counter-strategy</strong>: First, become a &ldquo;big tree&rdquo; yourself and influence them with your own success. Your words carry little weight when you&rsquo;re insignificant; &ldquo;familiarity breeds contempt&rdquo; (近庙欺神). It&rsquo;s hard to distinguish &ldquo;saints&rdquo; from &ldquo;demons&rdquo; in society.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Cognitive Roots of the Wealth Gap</strong>: Poverty is often caused by a lack of awareness, not systemic issues. CLEC aims to &ldquo;cure&rdquo; this &ldquo;disease of poverty,&rdquo; but it&rsquo;s very difficult; even family members may not accept it. Some people can&rsquo;t accept good medicine and instead buy things like long-term bonds.</li>
<li><strong>The Challenges of Individual Stock Investing</strong>:
<ul>
<li><strong>Example</strong>: NVIDIA&rsquo;s stock price fluctuates wildly. It was once sold off due to poor sales and excess inventory, then soared because of AI. It&rsquo;s difficult for individual investors to grasp; even if you bought it, you might not have held on for the entire ride.</li>
<li><strong>Conclusion</strong>: Individual stocks are volatile, information is asymmetric, and they can suddenly be cut in half or go to zero. ETFs provide a more stable way to share in market growth. It&rsquo;s also very hard to stick with a portfolio of mixed-quality individual stocks.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>The Dangers of Short-Term Trading</strong>: Short-term trading is like &ldquo;gambling + drug addiction.&rdquo; It&rsquo;s addictive and leads not only to financial loss but also the loss of family, health, and self, potentially ruining one&rsquo;s entire life. There&rsquo;s no need to become a &ldquo;boy wonder trader.&rdquo;</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Critique of Chaos in the Financial Industry 
    <div id="critique-of-chaos-in-the-financial-industry" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#critique-of-chaos-in-the-financial-industry" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Profit Motives of Banks and Insurance Companies</strong>: Criticizes post offices and banks for persuading depositors (especially the elderly) to buy annuity insurance, structured notes, and similar products. This is a failure of financial regulators.</li>
<li><strong>Regulatory Issues</strong>: Believes financial regulators should ensure the separation of savings, insurance, wealth management, and lending to avoid conflicts of interest. American commercial banks (like BofA) don&rsquo;t proactively sell insurance. Taiwan&rsquo;s &ldquo;Financial Holding Company&rdquo; model is described as an &ldquo;all-encompassing, one-stop-shop scam.&rdquo; Charles Schwab only mentions loan options when a client has a large funding need.</li>
<li><strong>The Goal of the Insurance Industry</strong>: To convert large amounts of fixed deposits into insurance policies, which is the main objective of the insurance industry, given the huge amount of fixed deposits in Taiwan.</li>
<li><strong>The Risk of Mortgaging Property to Buy Insurance</strong>: There have been cases where the property mortgage remains, but the insurance policy&rsquo;s value drops to zero, leaving people homeless. These institutions &ldquo;will go as far as making people homeless.&rdquo;</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Responses to Chat Comments and Additional Remarks (Teacher James&rsquo;s collective response to student comments and personal reflections) 
    <div id="responses-to-chat-comments-and-additional-remarks-teacher-jamess-collective-response-to-student-comments-and-personal-reflections" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#responses-to-chat-comments-and-additional-remarks-teacher-jamess-collective-response-to-student-comments-and-personal-reflections" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>On Publishing a Book/Media Exposure</strong>: Teacher James frankly states that if he were to publicly promote his ideas like &ldquo;investing with loans&rdquo; and &ldquo;not buying a house,&rdquo; he could violate financial regulations (practicing without a license), offend powerful interest groups (real estate, insurance, finance), and even face cyberbullying and political pressure (being labeled &ldquo;pro-Taiwan independence&rdquo; or &ldquo;pro-CCP&rdquo;). He could be &ldquo;torn to shreds&rdquo; or even &ldquo;end up in jail.&rdquo; If he doesn&rsquo;t discuss many of these topics, the teaching loses its meaning. The very people you help might turn around and curse you.</li>
<li><strong>Insurance</strong>: An insurance policy with a 1.06% annual return is acceptable if it includes protection, but it&rsquo;s generally not recommended.</li>
<li><strong>Caring for Parents</strong>: Re-emphasizes the loneliness and health risks of elderly people living alone (not taking medicine on time, not measuring blood sugar/pressure, leading to complications like worsening COPD, minor strokes, brain atrophy, mental disorders). Advises children to pay attention and provide companionship early. Even if parents seem self-sufficient, consider arranging for a caregiver early to prevent accidents and ensure a regular routine (medication, diet, avoiding falls). Shares his regret of not returning to Taiwan in time to accompany his mother, who, despite having other children in Taiwan, was not adequately cared for while living alone. Emphasizes that parents&rsquo; health is the children&rsquo;s happiness.</li>
<li><strong>A Partner&rsquo;s Investment Philosophy</strong>: Accept individual differences. Due to different upbringings and personal experiences (like living through the dot-com and 2008 bubbles), security levels and cognitions vary. Lead by example and influence them gradually with long-term results; don&rsquo;t force it. It&rsquo;s normal for them not to listen to you, just as you may not listen to them.</li>
<li><strong>00662 (Taiwan ETF) Currency Impact</strong>: Short-term currency fluctuations are normal. For instance, when the Taiwan dollar depreciated in the previous two years, 00662 outperformed QQQ. In the long run, currency effects tend to cancel each other out.</li>
<li><strong>Credit Loans vs. Stock Pledges</strong>: Credit loans are relatively independent and safe. Stock pledges are high-risk; a sharp market downturn could trigger a margin call, making it like a &ldquo;loan shark&rdquo; — you have to pay back when they demand it, or you&rsquo;re &ldquo;shot dead with one bullet.&rdquo;</li>
<li><strong>Brokerage Firms Raising Pledge Rates and Risks</strong>: Brokerages like Capital Securities in Taiwan might raise interest rates after a client has borrowed, or even restrict withdrawals (due to limited funding pools), &ldquo;luring you into a trap.&rdquo; It&rsquo;s advisable to prioritize more stable brokerages like Yuanta Securities.</li>
<li><strong>Apply for Credit Loans Early</strong>: Bank credit policies can change. When you qualify (e.g., with an interest rate below 2%), you should apply early. Seize the opportunity when a bank proactively offers you a loan.</li>
<li><strong>Stock Pledging in Hong Kong</strong>: HSBC is a good choice, especially for VIP clients with large capital (e.g., over 1 million HKD). HSBC&rsquo;s pledge interest rates are currently low. Friends from Malaysia, Singapore, Australia, etc., who successfully open an account and get a pledge loan from HSBC are welcome to share their experiences.</li>
<li><strong>QQQ Compounding</strong>: The annualized rate of return (CAGR), according to Teacher James&rsquo;s research, is around 18% (including dividend reinvestment).</li>
<li><strong>Repayment of Investment Mortgage</strong>: Typically, it&rsquo;s a lump-sum repayment at maturity (10-15 years). By then, you can sell some stocks or use another pledged loan to repay it. You need more than 15 years to ensure profitability.</li>
<li><strong>Compound Frequency</strong>: Refers to capital gains and dividend reinvestment.</li>
<li><strong>Philosophy of Helping Others</strong>: There are different levels of helping others. The lowest is for others (hoping for their well-being). The next is for oneself (deriving happiness or meaning from it). The highest is selflessness (helping is a natural act, regardless of for whom, or whether it brings happiness, like the Buddha or Jesus; it&rsquo;s natural ethics). Using helping others to add meaning and happiness to one&rsquo;s own life is actually &ldquo;not right.&rdquo; The highest state is &ldquo;like water flowing without a trace&rdquo; (传过水无痕).</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">III. Q&amp;A Session 
    <div id="iii-qa-session" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii-qa-session" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Kacy 
    <div id="kacy" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#kacy" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing</strong>: An elderly friend, who was once very influential in the market, agrees with Teacher James&rsquo;s index investing philosophy. This elder confessed that his past outsized returns were due to information asymmetry and his influence (manipulating small-cap stocks), which is not replicable for ordinary investors. He believes it&rsquo;s not easy for ordinary people to make money in the market, and index investing is the most correct path.
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s Comment</strong>: Index investing not only makes you money but also gives you a &ldquo;life&rdquo; (improves quality of life). Even if you make money from short-term trading, you might lose your life due to constant anxiety (e.g., being unable to take a 15-day vacation with peace of mind).</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Sharing (Follow-up)</strong>:
<ol>
<li>Reflecting on her family life, she emphasizes love and companionship for her parents to avoid regrets. She sees Teacher James&rsquo;s actions as &ldquo;dedication&rdquo; rather than &ldquo;charity&rdquo; with a sense of superiority and feels for the misunderstandings he might face.</li>
<li>Shares her future plans: to establish a women&rsquo;s financial academy (focusing on female financial awareness, as Chinese women are relatively disadvantaged, and financial independence provides more confidence), volunteer in hospice care (to learn about &ldquo;fasting until death&rdquo; and euthanasia), travel, read, and set up scholarships, reflecting a desire for &ldquo;altruism&rdquo; (influenced by Kazuo Inamori&rsquo;s philosophy of &ldquo;altruism&rdquo;).</li>
</ol>
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s Comment</strong>:
<ol>
<li>Commends Kacy&rsquo;s practice of accompanying her parents. Shares the joy of his own father, in his 90s, still planning a trip to Korea. Advises that for elderly parents, even if they appear healthy, one should consider arranging for a caregiver early to prevent accidents and ensure a regular routine (medication, diet). Parents&rsquo; health is the children&rsquo;s happiness. If parents have medical needs, like follow-up visits every three months or low-dose lung cancer screenings, they should be supported.</li>
<li>Greatly admires Kacy&rsquo;s &ldquo;altruistic&rdquo; plans, believing that from a women&rsquo;s financial academy to educating disadvantaged groups, it&rsquo;s all very meaningful. It&rsquo;s right to start planning now.</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">C 
    <div id="c" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#c" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing</strong>: His mother noticed his mood has become calmer and happier recently. He explained it&rsquo;s because through investing (practicing the teacher&rsquo;s teachings), he has found meaning in life and is confident about his future wealth, no longer worrying about finances. This has led to an internal change from external influences.
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s Comment</strong>: Shares his own longing and regrets regarding his mother, how in his youth he failed to fully grasp the loneliness and hardship of an elderly person living alone (e.g., his mother falling while going to the doctor alone, and his own failure to return to Taiwan to be with her). Reminds everyone to care for their parents, especially those living alone, after achieving financial freedom early, to avoid life&rsquo;s regrets. Advises young people to learn from wise elders (like Warren Buffett) to avoid many pitfalls and find a &ldquo;mental coach.&rdquo;</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question</strong>: Following the teacher&rsquo;s guidance, he used an investment mortgage to invest in 00662. After using a portion of the funds from high-dividend ETFs to pay the monthly interest, there&rsquo;s still a surplus each month. Should he invest this in 00865 (short-term bond/cash-like ETF) or continue buying fractional shares of 00662?
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s Response</strong>: Continue buying 00662. The emergency fund (00865) only needs to be built up to a certain level (e.g., 2-3 years of living expenses for someone employed). Any excess funds should be invested in growth assets.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">IM 
    <div id="im" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#im" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing 1</strong>: Recalls entering the market in 2018, with emotions fluctuating with the market, having once lost 50%. A wise friend enlightened her (&ldquo;Save money when you&rsquo;re making it, and just wait it out when it&rsquo;s down&rdquo;), teaching her to remain calm through ups and downs and become numb to the market. Mentions how wealthy people view money (a piece of clothing costs 500-600k; money is like trash to them). Grateful for the teacher&rsquo;s guidance that has &ldquo;filled her head.&rdquo;</li>
<li><strong>Sharing 2</strong>: Has come to understand the teacher&rsquo;s mindset that &ldquo;all sharing is for self-fulfillment, not for rewards.&rdquo; When sharing investment ideas with others, she encounters different reactions: some (who have worked for 20-30 years and are set in their ways) cling to old concepts, while others, despite living in hardship (a single mother working two jobs), are willing to listen. Through sharing, she has also gained a sense of value by giving back the knowledge she has learned.
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s Comment</strong>: (Regarding Sharing 2) Helping others can bring happiness, but the highest state is to be &ldquo;unaffected by helping,&rdquo; meaning helping others is a natural act, not for happiness, not for self. The lowest level is &ldquo;for others,&rdquo; i.e., for their benefit; the second level is &ldquo;for oneself,&rdquo; i.e., achieving self-actualization through helping (the teacher admits his own teaching is to find value in retirement); the highest is &ldquo;selflessness,&rdquo; where even the thought of &ldquo;for myself&rdquo; is gone.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question</strong>: After sharing investment concepts with friends, how can she determine if they truly understand? Are there any questions to ask to test them? (Friends listen and think it&rsquo;s logical but can&rsquo;t articulate it themselves.)
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s Response</strong>: It&rsquo;s hard to judge with simple questions. True understanding is reflected in action (like opening an account to invest). A more effective way is like how Frank guided him back in the day (meeting for dinner every week, hand-holding him through opening an account, starting with a $200 Mutual Fund), guiding them step-by-step to open an account, make their first investment, and follow up continuously. This is a process of &ldquo;sowing seeds&rdquo;; whether and when they sprout is unknown. He himself was &ldquo;led by the hand&rdquo; by Frank to get started. Now, he is willing to be such a guide, with the Bodhisattva spirit of &ldquo;If I don&rsquo;t descend into hell, who will?&rdquo;</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Man 
    <div id="man" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#man" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing</strong>: Gained insights from gardening.
<ol>
<li><strong>Individual Differences</strong>: The same seeds planted result in different flowers, just as people receive information differently. Their internal &ldquo;genes&rdquo; determine their level of acceptance and reaction (some &ldquo;get it,&rdquo; others &ldquo;laugh it off&rdquo;). The gardener (the sharer) cannot change the seed&rsquo;s nature.</li>
<li><strong>Patient Guidance</strong>: A good gardener will loosen the soil and water, helping it grow, just as a mentor guides students to open accounts and invest.</li>
<li><strong>Inner Joy</strong>: The pleasure derived from tilling the soil and weeding surpasses the rewards of all fame and fortune. This effort is not for a return but for self-actualization.</li>
<li><strong>Practical Example</strong>: She once guided a friend to buy QQQ. The friend sold during a dip and missed the subsequent 45% gain. She only sent a screenshot and said no more, believing it was also &ldquo;fate.&rdquo;</li>
<li><strong>Translating for the Elderly at a Doctor&rsquo;s Visit</strong>: Shares her experience as a volunteer translator for the elderly, realizing their immense need in medical communication. Such small acts can bring great help and a ray of light into their lives.</li>
</ol>
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s Comment</strong>: Agrees with the views on &ldquo;destiny&rdquo; and intrinsic motivation. Shares his own experience of planting tomatoes, where three seeds grew very differently; one was a &ldquo;chosen seedling&rdquo; and very robust, while others were &ldquo;sickly.&rdquo; Cites Dr. Yang Ding-I&rsquo;s view to &ldquo;look inward.&rdquo; For people you can&rsquo;t change, don&rsquo;t force it. Be yourself, don&rsquo;t be discouraged by it; giving up is an option. Affirms the value of her volunteer work.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Sifei 
    <div id="sifei" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#sifei" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing</strong>: Came into contact with CLEC in 2024 through a friend (who had mentioned it 5 years ago, but she was indifferent at the time). In her 50s, she has been interested in investing since graduating from college and has been exploring on her own for years. She was deeply moved after listening to the lectures and has invested a lot of time in studying (finished the 2021-2022 courses and is now re-listening). She shared it with a hundred people, and only two took action, but she still feels gratified.</li>
<li><strong>Question</strong>: Regarding the choice between a credit loan and a stock pledge in Taiwan. She leans towards using the stock pledge first (2.56% interest, no principal repayment, only interest), because of its convenience. She thinks she can use a credit loan (already approved for a 3 million TWD limit, but requires installment repayments) as a backup if the stock market crashes. She believes her job is stable (banks are always begging her to take out loans), so she&rsquo;s not afraid of unemployment and can access the credit loan anytime.
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s Response</strong>: (In a firm tone, repeatedly emphasizing) <strong>Absolutely do not do this!</strong>
<ol>
<li><strong>Core Principle</strong>: Money borrowed from a stock pledge <strong>must not be reinvested in the stock market</strong>. It can only be used for living expenses or to repay other loans. This is &ldquo;the first thing.&rdquo;</li>
<li><strong>Huge Risk</strong>: When the market crashes, banks may tighten credit (&ldquo;take away the umbrella in the rain&rdquo;), and you might not be able to borrow money then. If you lose your job at the same time, it&rsquo;s even more impossible. A credit loan is not something you can just &ldquo;hold there&rdquo; forever.</li>
<li><strong>Deploy All Troops (韩信点兵)</strong>: All available &ldquo;forces&rdquo; (including the credit loan) should be deployed to the &ldquo;battlefield&rdquo; (investment) as early as possible.</li>
<li><strong>The Correct Approach</strong>: You should first take out the credit loan (e.g., 3 million TWD) and invest it in the market. The monthly loan repayments can be paid using funds from a low-interest stock pledge. This way, the principal continues to work in the market, and your personal salary can also be invested. Don&rsquo;t take a huge risk just because you&rsquo;re &ldquo;too lazy to repay the principal&rdquo; or tempted by the short-term convenience of a pledge.</li>
<li><strong>Safety of Credit Loans</strong>: A credit loan is a relatively safe form of leverage, not directly linked to market fluctuations, and you won&rsquo;t get a margin call. With a stock pledge, even if you only borrow 10% (e.g., pledging 1 million from a 10 million asset portfolio—the teacher thinks 10% is already a huge risk, let alone the 2-3 million she wants to borrow), you could face risks in an extreme market downturn.</li>
<li><strong>Brokerage Risk</strong>: Some brokerages in Taiwan (like Capital Securities) may change their pledge interest rates, and their limited funding pools might prevent you from withdrawing funds as needed.
(Kacy and other students also chimed in, emphasizing the risk of banks &ldquo;taking away the umbrella in the rain&rdquo; and the fundamental difference between credit loans and pledges, and that pledged money cannot be used to buy more stocks).</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Xiao Zhang 
    <div id="xiao-zhang" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#xiao-zhang" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Did not speak or content was not recorded.</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">IV. Highlighted Quotes 
    <div id="iv-highlighted-quotes" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv-highlighted-quotes" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>Market fluctuations have nothing to do with me, international affairs have nothing to do with me, market analysis has nothing to do with me, financial statements have nothing to do with us, and the economic situation doesn&rsquo;t matter at all. Don&rsquo;t pay attention to it. The more you pay attention, the more mistakes you&rsquo;ll make.
&ndash; Teacher James</p></blockquote>
<p>Background: Teacher James emphasized at the beginning the composure investors should have, not letting external noise affect their investment decisions.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Investing requires patience, and financial freedom is worth the wait. What is patience? It is to be unconcerned with market fluctuations.
&ndash; Teacher James</p></blockquote>
<p>Background: Explaining that the core of long-term investing lies in the psychological tolerance for market volatility.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Cash is the food and air of asset allocation.
&ndash; Teacher James</p></blockquote>
<p>Background: Emphasizing the extreme importance of holding sufficient cash for risk management and psychological stability in asset allocation.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>You are poor because of a lack of awareness, not because the system made you poor.
&ndash; Teacher James</p></blockquote>
<p>Background: When discussing the difficulty of teaching family about investing, pointing out that the wealth gap often stems from cognitive differences.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Short-term trading doesn&rsquo;t just want your money; it will want your life and your lifelong happiness.
&ndash; Teacher James</p></blockquote>
<p>Background: A stern warning about the immense dangers of short-term trading, comparing it to gambling and drug addiction.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>In investing, we first seek safety, then profit. First, seek safety; do what is foolproof first.
&ndash; Teacher James</p></blockquote>
<p>Background: Emphasizing that the primary principle of investing is safety, in response to a student&rsquo;s question about credit loans versus stock pledges.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>When you are making money, you should also be humble and look at everything with humility. Just as Teacher James taught me, whether the market goes up or down, OK, be numb to it. It doesn&rsquo;t have a big impact on our daily lives.
&ndash; IM</p></blockquote>
<p>Background: Student IM sharing her transformation from anxiously watching the market to maintaining a calm composure towards market fluctuations.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The things we invest in others, when we invest, it&rsquo;s not for a return. It&rsquo;s because you have to do this thing. You have to do what is meaningful to you; this is the value of your being.
&ndash; Man</p></blockquote>
<p>Background: Student Man drawing an analogy from gardening to the intrinsic value of sharing knowledge and helping others, without seeking external rewards.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Life is really not just about money&hellip; Wealth is about having enough.
&ndash; Kacy</p></blockquote>
<p>Background: Student Kacy sharing her pursuit of quality of life, believing that more wealth is not necessarily better; having enough is sufficient.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The highest level is helping others without any sense of happiness, without feeling&hellip; Even the &lsquo;for myself&rsquo; is gone. This is what I have learned, that even the &lsquo;for myself&rsquo; is gone.
&ndash; Teacher James</p></blockquote>
<p>Background: When responding to IM&rsquo;s question about the motivation for sharing, he explains the three levels of helping behavior, the highest of which is selfless altruism, a natural act.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">V. Summary 
    <div id="v-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#v-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>In this session, Teacher James systematically re-emphasized his core investment philosophy: consistently buy and hold the Nasdaq 100 index fund, fearless of short-term market volatility. He focused on analyzing the extreme importance of risk control, viewing reasonable asset allocation (especially an adequate cash reserve) as the cornerstone of investment success. Through specific examples, the teacher revealed the investment value trap of long-term bonds and severely criticized certain misleading and detrimental practices in the financial industry, especially warning investors against low-return products like annuities and savings insurance. At the same time, he pointed out the huge uncertainty of individual stock investing and the destructive nature of short-term trading. During the Q&amp;A session, students actively shared their insights and confusions from their investment practices, family communication, and personal growth. Teacher James not only provided specific investment advice (such as the correct use and risk perception of credit loans versus stock pledges) but also guided students from a life philosophy perspective to reflect on the meaning of wealth, work, family, and personal value, encouraging everyone on the path to financial freedom to continuously enhance their cognition, maintain a positive mindset, pay attention to family and social responsibilities, and ultimately give back to society.</p>

  



<div
  
    class="flex px-4 py-3 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900"
  >

  <span
    
      class="text-primary-400 ltr:pr-3 rtl:pl-3 flex items-center"
    >

    

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M506.3 417l-213.3-364c-16.33-28-57.54-28-73.98 0l-213.2 364C-10.59 444.9 9.849 480 42.74 480h426.6C502.1 480 522.6 445 506.3 417zM232 168c0-13.25 10.75-24 24-24S280 154.8 280 168v128c0 13.25-10.75 24-23.1 24S232 309.3 232 296V168zM256 416c-17.36 0-31.44-14.08-31.44-31.44c0-17.36 14.07-31.44 31.44-31.44s31.44 14.08 31.44 31.44C287.4 401.9 273.4 416 256 416z"/></svg>

  </span>


  </span>

  <span
    
      class="dark:text-neutral-300"
    ><strong>Disclaimer:</strong> This article is for personal study notes only and does not constitute any investment advice.</span>
</div>

]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>A One Hundred Million Investment Life Lecture</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1736045402069/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1736045402069/</guid><description>This session delves into how ordinary people can achieve financial freedom through correct investment concepts and methods. Key points include: everyone has an innate talent for wealth; vision determines the height of wealth; it&amp;#39;s hard for salaried workers to escape the &amp;#39;rat race&amp;#39; because they are trapped in a carefully designed cycle; poverty is not an individual&amp;#39;s fault but rather caused by social structures; money is a tool for achieving goals; ordinary people can absolutely achieve financial freedom through long-term investment in index funds; one must shed the &amp;#39;poor mindset&amp;#39; and recognize their own wealth potential and rights; it&amp;#39;s best to start investing as early as possible, because the power of compounding requires time; bonds and real estate are not ideal long-term investment vehicles; investing in the future of humanity is investing in technological progress; the U.S. market is worth investing in due to its innovation capabilities and market mechanisms; the Nasdaq 100 index fund is an ideal choice for sharing the dividends of technological development; the method for investing in index funds is simple but not easy to execute; avoid common pitfalls on the investment journey; employ the &amp;#39;buy when you have money&amp;#39; and &amp;#39;never sell&amp;#39; investment strategies; market downturns are opportunities; stock pledges can help investors address capital needs without selling shares; independent thinking is crucial in investing.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<lite-youtube videoid="4FMjmyBpTzw" playlabel="4FMjmyBpTzw" params=""></lite-youtube>



<h3 class="relative group"><strong>Re-Examining Our Wealth Potential: You Could Have Been Richer</strong> 
    <div id="re-examining-our-wealth-potential-you-could-have-been-richer" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#re-examining-our-wealth-potential-you-could-have-been-richer" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>Many of us spend our entire lives struggling with money, working tirelessly for monthly bills, children&rsquo;s tuition, and meager retirement savings, like a hamster trapped in a cage, running hard but never escaping. Have you ever considered that you could have been richer? Have you ever thought that the sense of security you seek actually binds you, causing you to miss out on greater wealth?</p>
<p>Yes, everyone has an innate talent for wealth, a right we are born with, as natural as breathing, as natural as birds flying and fish swimming. Unfortunately, this right, this talent, has been forgotten, or even buried by our own hands through the &ldquo;education&rdquo; of reality and the &ldquo;discipline&rdquo; of society. From a young age, we are told: study hard, find a good job, work hard to earn money to support the family. No one tells us: you can be very rich, you have the right to be very rich, you don&rsquo;t even have to work so hard to have it all!</p>
<p>The value of this lecture is far more than teaching you one or two investment techniques; its true value lies in awakening you from that “hamster dilemma,” making you realize your dormant wealth potential, and showing you a path to financial freedom. This path does not require you to have Einstein&rsquo;s brain, nor does it require you to have Buffett&rsquo;s luck, it only requires you to change your mindset, and then, to move forward steadfastly.</p>


<h3 class="relative group"><strong>Vision Determines Wealth: How Far into the Future Do You See?</strong> 
    <div id="vision-determines-wealth-how-far-into-the-future-do-you-see" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#vision-determines-wealth-how-far-into-the-future-do-you-see" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>The extent of your vision dictates the height of your wealth. This isn&rsquo;t just some motivational slogan; it&rsquo;s a conclusion derived from rigorous logic and data analysis. Don&rsquo;t believe it? Let&rsquo;s crunch some numbers.</p>
<p>Many people find investing for something decades into the future to be too distant and unrealistic. But what if we look 60 years into the future? If you have 1 million now, through sensible investments and factoring in the power of compounding, you could have assets worth hundreds of millions or even billions of dollars in a few decades. This is entirely possible; it’s actually a conservative estimate.</p>
<p>Why don&rsquo;t ordinary people realize they can have so much wealth? The reason is simple: our concept of money is too narrow, we have insufficient understanding of our potential, and we lack a deep understanding of compounding, the &ldquo;eighth wonder of the world!&rdquo; Our understanding of money is still at the kindergarten level, while financial giants have a Ph.D.-level understanding of money, at least.</p>


<h3 class="relative group"><strong>The &ldquo;Rat Race&rdquo; Dilemma: Who Stole Your Wealth Dreams?</strong> 
    <div id="the" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#the" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>Why is it so hard for most salaried workers to escape the &ldquo;rat race&rdquo; dilemma? Because they are trapped in a carefully designed cycle: you work hard for a month, and before the paycheck even warms up, it has to go to capitalists, the government, and the bank. For that meager salary, you have to work like a rat running tirelessly in a cage, never escaping that vicious circle.</p>
<p>What&rsquo;s worse is that society constantly brainwashes you with &ldquo;consumerism,&rdquo; telling you that buying big houses, luxury cars, and branded bags is the standard for successful people. So, you&rsquo;re burdened with heavy loans, barely able to breathe under the weight of monthly interest payments. You don&rsquo;t dare to quit your job easily, and you don&rsquo;t dare to challenge your boss. You become a complete slave to capital.</p>
<p>Do you think this is your own choice? Do you think it&rsquo;s because you&rsquo;re not working hard enough? No! This is a structure intentionally or unintentionally maintained by the entire society and education system. What do schools cultivate? Compliant cogs in a machine, not independent-thinking creators. Financial institutions design complex financial products, ostensibly to help you manage your money, but in reality? They earn high fees and interest, while you can&rsquo;t even outpace inflation.</p>
<p>This “controlled environment” prevents you from realizing your potential for wealth, let alone changing your situation. You are like that hamster in the fable, the faster you run, the further you get from freedom.</p>


<h3 class="relative group"><strong>Re-Examining Poverty and Wealth: Breaking Down Class Barriers</strong> 
    <div id="re-examining-poverty-and-wealth-breaking-down-class-barriers" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#re-examining-poverty-and-wealth-breaking-down-class-barriers" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>Poverty is not your fault; it is the result of social structures that create class inequality. This structural inequality is like a thick curtain that obscures your innate talent for wealth, making you believe that you can only live a poor or middle-class life.</p>
<p>The statement &ldquo;wealth is a talent&rdquo; is not just a platitude, but a declaration, a solemn proclamation of your right! It tells you: you have the right to pursue a life of abundance, you have the right to enjoy beautiful things, you don&rsquo;t have to sacrifice your health, your happiness, or your dreams for money!</p>
<p>Recognizing this is the first step, and the most important step, to achieving financial freedom.</p>


<h3 class="relative group"><strong>The Essence of Money: Not an End, but a Bridge to Freedom</strong> 
    <div id="the-essence-of-money-not-an-end-but-a-bridge-to-freedom" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#the-essence-of-money-not-an-end-but-a-bridge-to-freedom" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>What is money? Money is a kind of energy, a tool. In a capitalist society, money can be used to exchange for various resources and services, including time, happiness, health, and even freedom. Money can also be used for investment, growing more money like seeds.</p>
<p>But remember, money itself is not the goal, but a means to achieve our life goals. We make money not to become slaves to it, but to live better, to realize our own dreams and those of our families, to have the ability to help those in need, and to better serve society.</p>
<p>Only by truly understanding the essence of money can we view it and use it correctly, rather than being enslaved by it.</p>


<h3 class="relative group"><strong>How Can Ordinary People Achieve Financial Freedom? It&rsquo;s Actually Very Simple!</strong> 
    <div id="how-can-ordinary-people-achieve-financial-freedom-it" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#how-can-ordinary-people-achieve-financial-freedom-it" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>Can ordinary people really achieve financial freedom? The answer is: of course they can! Moreover, achieving financial freedom is much simpler than you imagine.</p>
<p>The key to financial freedom is not about having a high IQ, or mastering complex techniques, but rather whether you have the correct investment mindset and whether you can persevere in executing it.</p>
<p>The path to financial freedom for ordinary people is actually very simple: choose the right investment vehicle, hold it for the long term, and let the power of compounding increase your wealth like a snowball. Specifically, it&rsquo;s recommended to invest in the U.S. Nasdaq 100 index fund, a relatively low-risk investment choice with excellent long-term performance. In the long run, its annualized return is considerable.</p>
<p>Many people might say, investing in index funds, isn&rsquo;t that something even an idiot can do? Yes, it&rsquo;s that simple! But the problem is, how many people can truly hold on for the long term?</p>
<p>Financial freedom is not achieved overnight; it requires patience and perseverance. In the course of investing, you will encounter all sorts of challenges and temptations, but as long as you believe in your choice and continue steadfastly, you will surely reach the other shore.</p>


<h3 class="relative group"><strong>Shedding the &ldquo;Poor Mindset&rdquo;: From &ldquo;Impossible&rdquo; to &ldquo;I Can Do It&rdquo;</strong> 
    <div id="shedding-the" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#shedding-the" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>The biggest characteristic of the &ldquo;poor mindset&rdquo; is self-limitation. They habitually limit themselves with &ldquo;impossible,&rdquo; &ldquo;can&rsquo;t do it,&rdquo; and &ldquo;too difficult.&rdquo; They don&rsquo;t see their potential or the hope for the future.</p>
<p>The key to shedding the &ldquo;poor mindset&rdquo; lies in changing your mindset and recognizing your wealth potential and rights. You have to believe that poverty is not your destiny, and that you have the ability to change your fate.</p>
<p>Specifically, you need to learn the right investment knowledge, rather than being led by so-called financial experts or the media. You need to understand that true wealth comes from long-term investment, not short-term speculation or blind consumption. You need to learn to delay gratification, using the money you save for investment, rather than for buying things that are non-essential.</p>
<p>More importantly, you need to cultivate the ability to think independently, not to be swayed by others or blindly follow trends. You need to develop an investment plan suitable for your own circumstances, and then steadfastly execute it.</p>
<p>Finally, you must remember that financial freedom is not something that happens overnight; it requires patience and perseverance, believing in the power of compounding, and adhering to long-term investment.</p>


<h3 class="relative group"><strong>Why Invest? Make Money Work for You, Not You for Money!</strong> 
    <div id="why-invest-make-money-work-for-you-not-you-for-money" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#why-invest-make-money-work-for-you-not-you-for-money" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>Why invest? The answer is simple: to make money work for us, not us for money.</p>
<p>Through investing, we can make our money grow continuously in the capital markets, thus realizing an increase in wealth. This increase can help us withstand inflation, ensure our future quality of life, and ultimately achieve financial freedom, so we no longer have to toil for a living.</p>
<p>Investing is also a way to plan for and secure the future. Through investment, we can accumulate funds for retirement, prepare for our children&rsquo;s education, and create conditions for realizing our dreams. Imagine, when you retire, you don&rsquo;t have to worry about whether your pension is enough, you can travel the world freely, do things you love, what a wonderful life that would be!</p>
<p>In addition, investing is also a way to participate in economic development. By investing in excellent companies, we can share the dividends of their growth, and also create value for society, promoting social progress.</p>


<h3 class="relative group"><strong>Why is it Better to Invest Early? Compounding: The Magic of Time</strong> 
    <div id="why-is-it-better-to-invest-early-compounding-the-magic-of-time" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#why-is-it-better-to-invest-early-compounding-the-magic-of-time" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>Why is it better to start investing early? The answer lies in the word &ldquo;compounding.&rdquo; Compounding, which Einstein called the &ldquo;eighth wonder of the world,&rdquo; is more powerful than you think.</p>
<p>For example, if we calculate with a 12% annual rate of return (a figure that can be achieved over the long term), a 30-year-old who invests $283 per month can accumulate approximately $1 million by the age of 60. But if they started investing at the age of 20, they would only need to invest $85 per month to reach the same goal!</p>
<p>See that? That is the power of compounding! The earlier you start investing, the less principal you need, and the shorter the time it takes to achieve your wealth goals. Because the effect of compounding causes your wealth to grow like a snowball, the longer the time, the faster the growth rate, and the greater the power.</p>
<p>Therefore, even if you don&rsquo;t have much capital right now, as long as you start investing early and stick with it over the long term, you can accumulate a considerable amount of wealth. Time is the best friend of investment.</p>


<h3 class="relative group"><strong>The Misunderstood Bonds and Real Estate: Don&rsquo;t Let Them Steal Your Future</strong> 
    <div id="the-misunderstood-bonds-and-real-estate-don" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#the-misunderstood-bonds-and-real-estate-don" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>Many people think bonds are a stable investment, and some even say they&rsquo;re safer than stocks. Is this really the case?</p>
<p>In the long term, bonds can actually be riskier than stocks. Don&rsquo;t believe it? Let&rsquo;s look at the data. How have different asset classes performed over the past 200 years, from the early 19th century to the early 21st century? The results show that the long-term returns of stocks are far higher than those of bonds, and bonds have sometimes even lost money over periods of 20 or even 30 years!</p>
<p>Why is this the case? Because the yield on bonds is usually low, making it difficult to withstand the erosion of inflation. Moreover, bond prices are affected by interest rate fluctuations and carry some risk. In contrast, although stocks fluctuate more in the short term, they have higher growth potential in the long term.</p>
<p>Let&rsquo;s talk about real estate. Many people believe that buying a house is the most value-preserving investment, and some even consider their house their most important asset. However, have you ever considered whether real estate is really a good investment?</p>
<p>From an investment perspective, the main problems with real estate are its poor liquidity, high maintenance costs, and unremarkable long-term returns. Imagine if someone spent 10 million Taiwan dollars to build a villa 35 years ago, could that villa be worth 30 million Taiwan dollars 35 years later? It’s unlikely. However, if they had invested that 10 million Taiwan dollars in the stock market, based on historical average returns, the current value would have increased by two orders of magnitude, possibly becoming 1 billion Taiwan dollars!</p>
<p>More importantly, real estate also involves complex factors such as location and market fluctuations, all of which can affect its investment returns, and ordinary people find it difficult to control them.</p>
<p>And what if you treat your home as a place to live? Then you&rsquo;ll be burdened with decades of loan payments, and monthly mortgage repayments will weigh you down. For this house, you have to work hard, not dare to quit easily, and not dare to pursue your dreams, you become a complete “house slave.” Isn&rsquo;t that putting the cart before the horse?</p>
<p>Remember, a home to live in is essentially a consumption, not an investment.</p>


<h3 class="relative group"><strong>Investing in the Future of Humanity is Investing in Technological Progress</strong> 
    <div id="investing-in-the-future-of-humanity-is-investing-in-technological-progress" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#investing-in-the-future-of-humanity-is-investing-in-technological-progress" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>Investing in the future of humanity is actually investing in technological progress and social development. Look at our history, from the agricultural age to the industrial age, and then to the information age, each significant social advancement has been accompanied by a leap in technology. This progress has led to tremendous improvements in productivity and an explosive growth in wealth.</p>
<p>Data shows that over the past 200 years, the long-term returns of the stock market have been far higher than those of bonds and gold. This reflects the continuous progress of human technology and productivity.</p>
<p>In the future, human society will continue to move forward, technology will continue to advance, which will bring more investment opportunities and space for wealth growth. By investing in excellent companies that represent the future and the direction of technological development, we can share in the enormous dividends that this growth will bring.</p>


<h3 class="relative group"><strong>Why the U.S.? Because That&rsquo;s Where Innovation Flourishes</strong> 
    <div id="why-the-us-because-that" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#why-the-us-because-that" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>Why should we look to the United States? Because it is a fertile ground for innovation, an environment where great companies are born.</p>
<p>The United States is home to the world&rsquo;s best companies and top scientific talent. These companies are like perpetual motion machines, continuously driving technological progress, creating new products and services, and leading global economic development.</p>
<p>Moreover, the U.S. is highly innovative, and the government usually supports the development of businesses. Furthermore, the U.S. capital markets are relatively mature and transparent, with well-established regulatory mechanisms that protect the rights of investors. This provides a relatively fair and safe investment environment for investors.</p>


<h3 class="relative group"><strong>Why the Nasdaq 100 Index Fund? Share the Dividends of Technology Giant Growth</strong> 
    <div id="why-the-nasdaq-100-index-fund-share-the-dividends-of-technology-giant-growth" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#why-the-nasdaq-100-index-fund-share-the-dividends-of-technology-giant-growth" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>For ordinary people, investing in individual stocks requires specialized knowledge and a lot of effort, and the risks are also relatively high. Is there a simpler, more effective way for us to share in the dividends of U.S. technological development?</p>
<p>The answer is: the Nasdaq 100 index fund.</p>
<p>The Nasdaq 100 index fund includes the 100 largest and most representative non-financial companies listed on the Nasdaq, which include many well-known tech giants such as Apple, Microsoft, and Amazon.</p>
<p>These companies represent the future development direction, the future of technology, with strong innovation capabilities and huge growth potential. By investing in the Nasdaq 100 index fund, we are investing in these excellent tech companies at the same time, sharing in the generous returns from their growth.</p>
<p>Moreover, investing in index funds is very simple, transparent, and relatively low-cost, making it particularly suitable for ordinary investors to hold for the long term. Compared to actively managed funds that require a lot of time and effort for research, index funds often outperform in the long run.</p>
<p>The Nasdaq 100 index fund is more focused on the tech sector compared to other broad market indices, which means it has higher growth potential. If you believe that technology is the core driving force behind future development, then the Nasdaq 100 index fund is an investment choice you cannot afford to miss.</p>


<h3 class="relative group"><strong>A Simple but Not Easy Investment Path: Why, When We Understand the Logic, Do We Still Not Do Well?</strong> 
    <div id="a-simple-but-not-easy-investment-path-why-when-we-understand-the-logic-do-we-still-not-do-well" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#a-simple-but-not-easy-investment-path-why-when-we-understand-the-logic-do-we-still-not-do-well" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>The method of investing in index funds is really simple: choose a good index fund, such as the Nasdaq 100 index fund, and then buy in regularly, holding it for the long term. It&rsquo;s that simple. You don&rsquo;t need a background in finance, nor do you need to monitor the market every day. You can even leave it untouched for years.</p>
<p>But why is it that so few people are actually able to do this simple thing?</p>
<p>First, it requires you to have a long-term perspective and firm conviction. During market fluctuations, especially when the market is down, many people feel panic and anxiety, and even doubt their choice, eventually giving in and selling, and as a result? They often sell at the lowest point, missing out on the rebound that follows.</p>
<p>Second, it requires you to overcome your human weaknesses. In the course of investing, you&rsquo;ll encounter all sorts of temptations: today, this stock has hit its limit up, tomorrow, that concept is hot, the day after tomorrow, experts predict the market will plummet… this noise will interfere with your judgment, leading you to deviate from your original investment plan.</p>
<p>Many people, even those who have learned this simple investment method, still cannot do it well. Some investors are impatient to sell as soon as the market rises slightly, missing out on the big gains that come later; some investors, although they have set a fixed investment plan, are always unable to stick to it, going at it haphazardly; and other investors, because they hold other types of stocks or investments, are unable to make up their minds to switch to index funds.</p>
<p>What does all of this show? It shows that the success of investing depends not only on the method, but also on your mindset, whether you can overcome your human weaknesses, and whether you can steadfastly execute your investment plan.</p>
<p>Investing in index funds requires &ldquo;patience&rdquo; and &ldquo;waiting,&rdquo; the determination to &ldquo;stay the course&rdquo;, which is what most people lack.</p>


<h3 class="relative group"><strong>&ldquo;Pits&rdquo; on the Investment Path: Don&rsquo;t Let These Traps Swallow Your Wealth</strong> 
    <div id="heading" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#heading" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>The path of investment is full of all sorts of &ldquo;pits,&rdquo; and one wrong step can lead to total ruin.</p>
<ol>
<li><strong>The &ldquo;Financial Expert&rdquo; Scam:</strong> Many so-called &ldquo;financial experts&rdquo; are actually just salespeople for financial products. In order to earn commissions, they will recommend various complex financial products to you, such as insurance, bonds, annuities, etc. These products often come with high fees and less-than-ideal long-term returns. Annuity products in particular, are not only low-yielding and high-risk, but also severely impact your asset allocation and tax planning. Remember, truly good investments are often simple, and those complicated products are often traps.</li>
<li><strong>Noise from the Media and &ldquo;Experts&rdquo;:</strong> Many media outlets and so-called &ldquo;investment experts,&rdquo; in order to grab attention, publish all sorts of sensational market predictions. One minute they&rsquo;re saying a bull market is coming, the next a bear market is coming, and the next, that a certain industry is about to explode… This noise severely interferes with your judgment, making you unable to focus on long-term investment. Remember, what really matters is the long-term trend, not the short-term fluctuations.</li>
<li><strong>The Temptation of Short-Term Trading:</strong> Many people dream of getting rich overnight, so they like to buy and sell frequently, trying to capture every market fluctuation. However, short-term trading not only requires you to have superb skills and keen market intuition, but also to bear enormous risks. For ordinary investors, short-term trading is often not worth the effort, and can even lead to serious losses. Frequent trading is like a gambler in a casino, often eventually losing it all.</li>
<li><strong>The Risks of High Leverage:</strong> Some investors, in order to pursue higher returns, use excessive leverage, such as margin accounts. However, leverage is a double-edged sword, it can amplify your returns, but also amplify your losses. If used improperly, it can easily lead to total ruin, and even bankruptcy. Remember, the first priority of investment is to control risk, not to pursue high returns. Never put your fate in the hands of luck, especially not with leveraged fate.</li>
<li><strong>The Risk of Not Learning:</strong> Many people know nothing about investment. They don&rsquo;t understand the essence of investment, nor their own risk tolerance, nor the characteristics of the products they are investing in. Such blind investment is like crossing the road with your eyes closed, full of risks.</li>
</ol>


<h3 class="relative group"><strong>The Wisdom of &ldquo;Buy When You Have Money&rdquo;: Simple, Crude but Effective</strong> 
    <div id="the-wisdom-of" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#the-wisdom-of" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>&ldquo;Buy when you have money.&rdquo; These four words sound very simple, even a bit &ldquo;silly,&rdquo; right? But they are based on a deep understanding and insight into the long-term trends of the market.</p>
<p>We all know that the long-term trend of the market is upwards, driven by economic development and technological progress, and it&rsquo;s an unstoppable historical trend. Although the market will fluctuate in the short term and even fall sharply, these are all temporary. In the long run, the market will always return to the upward trend and continue to reach new highs.</p>
<p>Many people always want to buy at the lowest point and sell at the highest point. But ask yourself, do you really have the ability to do this? Not to mention ordinary investors, how many professional fund managers can actually do it?</p>
<p>Trying to choose the best time to buy is often futile, even foolish, because no one can accurately predict market bottoms and tops. Instead of wasting a lot of time and energy researching market trends, it&rsquo;s better to adopt a &ldquo;buy when you have money&rdquo; strategy, and use that time and energy to work and live life, enjoying life to the fullest.</p>


<h3 class="relative group"><strong>The Determination to &ldquo;Never Sell&rdquo;: The Secret to Enduring Market Cycles</strong> 
    <div id="the-determination-to" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#the-determination-to" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>&ldquo;Never sell,&rdquo; these four words, don&rsquo;t they sound a bit extreme? But they are the secret to enduring market cycles, the essence of long-term investing.</p>
<p>The essence of investing is to share in the growth dividends of excellent companies, not to gamble, in a casino, diving in and out. The logic behind &ldquo;never sell&rdquo; is actually very simple: as long as you are investing in excellent companies, and as long as you believe that these companies can continue to grow, then you should hold them for the long term, sharing in the dividends that their growth brings.</p>
<p>Frequent buying and selling will not only increase your transaction costs, but will also cause you to miss out on the compounding effect of long-term holding. More importantly, it will expose you to human weaknesses.</p>
<p>When the market is falling, you will feel panicked and will want to sell; when the market rises, you will become greedy and will want to chase after the price increases. As a result? You are often buying high and selling low, and are constantly harvested by the market.</p>
<p>The &ldquo;never sell&rdquo; strategy can help you overcome fear and greed, and allow you to always stay in the market, sharing in the dividends of economic growth.</p>


<h3 class="relative group"><strong>Market Downturns: Be Greedy When Others are Fearful</strong> 
    <div id="market-downturns-be-greedy-when-others-are-fearful" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#market-downturns-be-greedy-when-others-are-fearful" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>Market downturns, for many people, are a nightmare, a disaster. But for true investors, they are a once-in-a-lifetime opportunity.</p>
<p>Why is that? Because when the market is down, the stock prices of many high-quality companies will be severely undervalued, like a discounted sale, and buying at this time is like picking up a bargain.</p>
<p>Warren Buffett once famously said, &ldquo;Be fearful when others are greedy, and be greedy when others are fearful.&rdquo; This quote is about this very principle.</p>
<p>Market downturns are temporary, while the market&rsquo;s long-term trend is upward. As long as you can overcome your fear and stick to your long-term investment strategy, you will be able to seize opportunities during market downturns, buy undervalued high-quality assets, and lay a solid foundation for future wealth growth.</p>


<h3 class="relative group"><strong>&ldquo;Stock Pledges&rdquo;: Make Your Assets More Flexible</strong> 
    <div id="heading-1" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#heading-1" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>The strategy of &ldquo;living off stock pledges&rdquo; can help you address your daily capital needs without selling your stock. This is a smarter way to manage finances.</p>
<p>Many people might ask, what is a stock pledge? Simply put, it is using your stock as collateral to borrow money from a financial institution. In this way, you can gain access to liquidity without selling your stock, and you can continue to enjoy the long-term appreciation of your stock.</p>
<p>Through stock pledges, you can avoid being forced to sell stocks with long-term growth potential due to temporary funding shortages. Furthermore, in many countries and regions, the capital gains tax rate is usually higher than the borrowing interest rate. Through stock pledges, you can also reasonably reduce your tax burden.</p>
<p>Of course, stock pledges also carry some risks. If the stock price drops sharply, you may need to provide additional collateral or face the risk of forced liquidation. Therefore, when using stock pledges, you must control your leverage ratio, and it is generally recommended that the pledge ratio not exceed 20% of your total assets.</p>


<h3 class="relative group"><strong>Independent Thinking: Stay Clear-Headed in the Noisy Market</strong> 
    <div id="independent-thinking-stay-clear-headed-in-the-noisy-market" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#independent-thinking-stay-clear-headed-in-the-noisy-market" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>In this age of information overload, we are bombarded daily with all sorts of information, especially in the field of investment. The opinions of various &ldquo;experts,&rdquo; various media reports, and various rumors, are difficult to distinguish between true and false, making people dizzy.</p>
<p>If you don&rsquo;t have the ability to think independently, you can easily be swayed by this information and make wrong investment decisions.</p>
<p>Independent thinking is key to investment success. It means having your own judgment, not blindly following trends, not blindly believing in authority, and not being swayed by market sentiment.</p>
<p>The basis for independent thinking is learning and research. You need to continuously learn investment knowledge, study market laws, and understand the investment target. Only in this way can you form your own investment system and make correct decisions in the complex market environment.</p>
<p>Always remember that investment is your own business, and no one can make decisions for you.</p>
<hr>

<section class="space-y-10 w-full">
    
    
        
            






















  <a class="flex flex-wrap article " href="/en/posts/1728723295012-invest-qqq/">
    
        
        <div class="w-full md:w-auto h-full thumbnail nozoom thumbnailshadow md:mr-7" style="background-image:url(/posts/1728723295012-invest-qqq/featured_hu_6a34f16c918fab99.jpg);"></div>
        
      <div class=" mt-3 md:mt-0">
      <div class="items-center text-left text-xl font-semibold">
        
        <div class="font-bold text-xl text-neutral-800 decoration-primary-500 hover:underline hover:underline-offset-2 dark:text-neutral"
          href="/en/posts/1728723295012-invest-qqq/">How to Invest in NASDAQ 100</div>
        
        
        
      </div>
      <div class="text-sm text-neutral-500 dark:text-neutral-400">
        











  



















<div class="flex flex-row flex-wrap items-center">
  
  
  <time datetime="2024-10-12T00:00:00&#43;00:00">12 October 2024</time>
  

  
  
</div>





<div class="flex flex-row flex-wrap items-center">
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  <span style="margin-top:0.5rem" class="mr-2" onclick="window.open(&#34;/en/tags/investing/&#34;,'_self');">
    <span class="flex" style="cursor: pointer;">
  <span class="rounded-md border border-primary-400 px-1 py-[1px] text-xs font-normal text-primary-700 dark:border-primary-600 dark:text-primary-400">
    Investing
  </span>
</span>
  </span>
  
  <span style="margin-top:0.5rem" class="mr-2" onclick="window.open(&#34;/en/tags/finance/&#34;,'_self');">
    <span class="flex" style="cursor: pointer;">
  <span class="rounded-md border border-primary-400 px-1 py-[1px] text-xs font-normal text-primary-700 dark:border-primary-600 dark:text-primary-400">
    Finance
  </span>
</span>
  </span>
  
  <span style="margin-top:0.5rem" class="mr-2" onclick="window.open(&#34;/en/tags/qqq/&#34;,'_self');">
    <span class="flex" style="cursor: pointer;">
  <span class="rounded-md border border-primary-400 px-1 py-[1px] text-xs font-normal text-primary-700 dark:border-primary-600 dark:text-primary-400">
    QQQ
  </span>
</span>
  </span>
  
  <span style="margin-top:0.5rem" class="mr-2" onclick="window.open(&#34;/en/tags/securities/&#34;,'_self');">
    <span class="flex" style="cursor: pointer;">
  <span class="rounded-md border border-primary-400 px-1 py-[1px] text-xs font-normal text-primary-700 dark:border-primary-600 dark:text-primary-400">
    Securities
  </span>
</span>
  </span>
  
  <span style="margin-top:0.5rem" class="mr-2" onclick="window.open(&#34;/en/tags/account-opening/&#34;,'_self');">
    <span class="flex" style="cursor: pointer;">
  <span class="rounded-md border border-primary-400 px-1 py-[1px] text-xs font-normal text-primary-700 dark:border-primary-600 dark:text-primary-400">
    Account Opening
  </span>
</span>
  </span>
  
  <span style="margin-top:0.5rem" class="mr-2" onclick="window.open(&#34;/en/tags/nasdaq-100/&#34;,'_self');">
    <span class="flex" style="cursor: pointer;">
  <span class="rounded-md border border-primary-400 px-1 py-[1px] text-xs font-normal text-primary-700 dark:border-primary-600 dark:text-primary-400">
    Nasdaq 100
  </span>
</span>
  </span>
  
  
  
  
</div>




      </div>
      
    </div>
  </a>

        
    
</section>
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Early Retirement Extreme: Book Notes</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1728390192272/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1728390192272/</guid><description>This book offers an unconventional philosophical and practical guide to financial independence and early retirement, encouraging readers to break free from the traditional &amp;#39;work-consume&amp;#39; cycle. By cultivating diverse skills, reducing consumption, and investing wisely, readers can achieve financial independence within a few years and live a more free and balanced life. The book also delves into how &amp;#39;the system&amp;#39; influences individual decisions and how to escape its constraints.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[

<h2 class="relative group">I. Summary 
    <div id="i-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This book&rsquo;s core is to guide readers in constructing a mindset of financial independence and encourage them to challenge and break free from the constraints of societal &ldquo;systems.&rdquo; The author argues that modern society, through education, careers, consumerism, and other means, &ldquo;locks&rdquo; people into a preset track, making them work and consume continuously to maintain the system&rsquo;s operation. This book encourages readers to break this cycle by cultivating diverse skills, reducing dependence on a single income and material possessions, and ultimately achieving financial independence and early retirement to pursue a more meaningful life.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">II. Chapter Summaries 
    <div id="ii-chapter-summaries" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii-chapter-summaries" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<ul>
<li><strong>About the Book:</strong> Explains the purpose and core ideas, emphasizing that it&rsquo;s a philosophical book about strategy, aiming to help readers build a framework for financial independence.</li>
<li><strong>A Different Thinking Framework:</strong> Challenges the traditional &ldquo;work-consume&rdquo; model and society&rsquo;s pursuit of material possessions, status, and happiness. It encourages readers to think like a &ldquo;Renaissance person&rdquo; by developing diverse skills and points out the challenges of implementing change.</li>
<li><strong>Locked In:</strong> Delves into how modern people are &ldquo;locked in&rdquo; by consumerism, social norms, and &ldquo;the system.&rdquo; It analyzes how &ldquo;the system,&rdquo; through education, careers, advertising, media, etc., influences individual decisions, limits choices, and creates dependencies.  The book encourages readers to break free from the limitations of &ldquo;the system&rdquo; and re-examine their lifestyles and values. (Example: The allegory of Plato&rsquo;s Cave, illustrating how people are trapped in limited cognition and experience, mistaking shadows for reality).</li>
<li><strong>Degrees of Economic Freedom:</strong> Introduces four economic states: Salaryman, Wage Earner, Businessman, and Renaissance Person. It analyzes their financial characteristics, strengths, weaknesses, and interactions with &ldquo;the system.&rdquo;  The concepts of financial coupling and job dependence are emphasized.</li>
<li><strong>The Renaissance Ideal:</strong> Explains the versatility and independence of the &ldquo;Renaissance person&rdquo; and contrasts it with the modern &ldquo;system&rsquo;s&rdquo; emphasis on specialization.
<ul>
<li><strong>Human Capital and Necessary Personal Assets:</strong> Details the specific meanings and goals of seven areas of competence, emphasizing how these competencies help individuals break free from dependence on &ldquo;the system.&rdquo;</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Strategies, Tactics, and Guiding Principles:</strong> Provides strategic and tactical guidance for achieving financial independence.</li>
<li><strong>Tactical Principles:</strong> Offers more specific action guidelines, such as how to identify needs and wants, how to build a modular lifestyle, and how to maximize the use of existing resources.</li>
<li><strong>Economic and Financial Foundations:</strong> Explains the cash flow cycle and how to make money work for you instead of working for money through saving and investing.</li>
<li><strong>Financial Independence and Investing:</strong> Discusses important financial ratios and investment strategies, emphasizing the importance of understanding investment principles and risk management.  (Formulas: N=log[(1)/(1- (Po)/(p)(i)/(1+i))]/log(1+i) and P = (1+0.03/12)/(0.03/12) p = 401 р)</li>
<li><strong>The Renaissance Lifestyle:</strong>  Explores how to implement the Renaissance ideal in aspects such as food, clothing, shelter, transportation, health, relationships, etc., contrasting it with the modern consumerist lifestyle. Emphasizes how reducing dependence on products and services provided by &ldquo;the system&rdquo; can lower living costs and improve quality of life. (Examples: how to replace car ownership with walking, cycling, or other methods, how to repair and maintain items oneself, and how to reduce expenses through socializing and sharing resources).</li>
<li><strong>Conclusion:</strong>  Summarizes the core ideas and encourages readers to break free from the constraints of &ldquo;the system&rdquo; to live more free and autonomous lives.</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">III. Key Quotes 
    <div id="iii-key-quotes" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii-key-quotes" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>Independence is not something you have; it&rsquo;s something you are.</p></blockquote>
<p>Insight:  Independence is a way of thinking and behaving, not a state of being.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>You cannot solve a problem with the same mindset that created it.</p></blockquote>
<p>Insight: Achieving financial independence requires a shift from a consumerist mindset to a creative problem-solving approach.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Be the change that you wish to see in the world.</p></blockquote>
<p>Insight: Instead of complaining about the system, change yourself and your actions, and influence others by example.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The best prison has invisible bars.</p></blockquote>
<p>Insight: Modern society subtly confines us through social norms, consumerism, and the education system, making us unconsciously comply.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">IV.  Guidance 
    <div id="iv--guidance" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv--guidance" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This book provides a perspective that goes beyond traditional financial advice, helping readers re-examine their lifestyles, values, and relationship with societal &ldquo;systems.&rdquo; It encourages readers to achieve financial independence and early retirement through:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Critical thinking:</strong> Question social norms and consumerism to avoid being manipulated by &ldquo;the system.&rdquo;</li>
<li><strong>Developing diverse skills:</strong> Increase self-worth and competitiveness, and reduce dependence on a single income source.</li>
<li><strong>Smart consumption:</strong> Avoid unnecessary expenses and allocate resources to more valuable areas.</li>
<li><strong>Long-term planning and investing:</strong> Prepare for the future and make money work for you.</li>
<li><strong>Building a resilient lifestyle:</strong> Reduce dependence on the external environment and &ldquo;the system&rdquo; and increase the ability to adapt to change.</li>
<li><strong>Pursuing personal growth and self-realization:</strong> Live a more meaningful, autonomous, and free life.</li>
</ul>
<p>In conclusion, this book encourages readers to undertake a profound self-reflection and lifestyle transformation to ultimately break free from the constraints of &ldquo;the system&rdquo; and achieve financial independence and true freedom.
<br/>

  



<div
  
    class="flex px-4 py-3 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900"
  >

  <span
    
      class="text-primary-400 ltr:pr-3 rtl:pl-3 flex items-center"
    >

    

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512">
<path fill="currentColor" d="M288 32c0-17.7-14.3-32-32-32s-32 14.3-32 32V274.7l-73.4-73.4c-12.5-12.5-32.8-12.5-45.3 0s-12.5 32.8 0 45.3l128 128c12.5 12.5 32.8 12.5 45.3 0l128-128c12.5-12.5 12.5-32.8 0-45.3s-32.8-12.5-45.3 0L288 274.7V32zM64 352c-35.3 0-64 28.7-64 64v32c0 35.3 28.7 64 64 64H448c35.3 0 64-28.7 64-64V416c0-35.3-28.7-64-64-64H346.5l-45.3 45.3c-25 25-65.5 25-90.5 0L165.5 352H64zM432 456c-13.3 0-24-10.7-24-24s10.7-24 24-24s24 10.7 24 24s-10.7 24-24 24z"/></svg>
  </span>


  </span>

  <span
    
      class="dark:text-neutral-300"
    ><strong>Download:</strong> <a href="https://github.com/TianmingLi/early_retirement_extreme_cn/blob/main/src/earlyretirementextreme.pdf" target="_blank">Early Retirement Extreme</a></span>
</div>

<br/>
<a id="github-ca5909c42993317bda43c57784488179" target="_blank" href="https://github.com/TianmingLi/early_retirement_extreme_cn" class="cursor-pointer">
  <div
    class="w-full md:w-auto pt-3 p-5 border border-neutral-200 dark:border-neutral-700 border rounded-md shadow-2xl">

    <div class="flex items-center">
      <span class="text-2xl text-neutral-800 dark:text-neutral" style="margin-right:10px;">
        

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 496 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M165.9 397.4c0 2-2.3 3.6-5.2 3.6-3.3.3-5.6-1.3-5.6-3.6 0-2 2.3-3.6 5.2-3.6 3-.3 5.6 1.3 5.6 3.6zm-31.1-4.5c-.7 2 1.3 4.3 4.3 4.9 2.6 1 5.6 0 6.2-2s-1.3-4.3-4.3-5.2c-2.6-.7-5.5.3-6.2 2.3zm44.2-1.7c-2.9.7-4.9 2.6-4.6 4.9.3 2 2.9 3.3 5.9 2.6 2.9-.7 4.9-2.6 4.6-4.6-.3-1.9-3-3.2-5.9-2.9zM244.8 8C106.1 8 0 113.3 0 252c0 110.9 69.8 205.8 169.5 239.2 12.8 2.3 17.3-5.6 17.3-12.1 0-6.2-.3-40.4-.3-61.4 0 0-70 15-84.7-29.8 0 0-11.4-29.1-27.8-36.6 0 0-22.9-15.7 1.6-15.4 0 0 24.9 2 38.6 25.8 21.9 38.6 58.6 27.5 72.9 20.9 2.3-16 8.8-27.1 16-33.7-55.9-6.2-112.3-14.3-112.3-110.5 0-27.5 7.6-41.3 23.6-58.9-2.6-6.5-11.1-33.3 2.6-67.9 20.9-6.5 69 27 69 27 20-5.6 41.5-8.5 62.8-8.5s42.8 2.9 62.8 8.5c0 0 48.1-33.6 69-27 13.7 34.7 5.2 61.4 2.6 67.9 16 17.7 25.8 31.5 25.8 58.9 0 96.5-58.9 104.2-114.8 110.5 9.2 7.9 17 22.9 17 46.4 0 33.7-.3 75.4-.3 83.6 0 6.5 4.6 14.4 17.3 12.1C428.2 457.8 496 362.9 496 252 496 113.3 383.5 8 244.8 8zM97.2 352.9c-1.3 1-1 3.3.7 5.2 1.6 1.6 3.9 2.3 5.2 1 1.3-1 1-3.3-.7-5.2-1.6-1.6-3.9-2.3-5.2-1zm-10.8-8.1c-.7 1.3.3 2.9 2.3 3.9 1.6 1 3.6.7 4.3-.7.7-1.3-.3-2.9-2.3-3.9-2-.6-3.6-.3-4.3.7zm32.4 35.6c-1.6 1.3-1 4.3 1.3 6.2 2.3 2.3 5.2 2.6 6.5 1 1.3-1.3.7-4.3-1.3-6.2-2.2-2.3-5.2-2.6-6.5-1zm-11.4-14.7c-1.6 1-1.6 3.6 0 5.9 1.6 2.3 4.3 3.3 5.6 2.3 1.6-1.3 1.6-3.9 0-6.2-1.4-2.3-4-3.3-5.6-2z"/></svg>

  </span>


      </span>
      <div
        id="github-ca5909c42993317bda43c57784488179-full_name"
        class="m-0 font-bold text-xl text-neutral-800 decoration-primary-500 hover:underline hover:underline-offset-2 dark:text-neutral">
        TianmingLi/early_retirement_extreme_cn
      </div>
    </div>

    <p id="github-ca5909c42993317bda43c57784488179-description" class="m-0 mt-2 text-md text-neutral-800 dark:text-neutral">
      Early Retirement Extreme 中文翻译 Renaissance &amp; Liberty
    </p>

    <div class="m-0 mt-2 flex items-center">

      <span class="mr-1 inline-block h-3 w-3 rounded-full"
        style="background-color: #e34c26"></span>
      <div class="m-0 mr-5 text-md text-neutral-800 dark:text-neutral">
         HTML 
      </div>

      <span class="text-md mr-1 text-neutral-800 dark:text-neutral">
        

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 576 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M287.9 0C297.1 0 305.5 5.25 309.5 13.52L378.1 154.8L531.4 177.5C540.4 178.8 547.8 185.1 550.7 193.7C553.5 202.4 551.2 211.9 544.8 218.2L433.6 328.4L459.9 483.9C461.4 492.9 457.7 502.1 450.2 507.4C442.8 512.7 432.1 513.4 424.9 509.1L287.9 435.9L150.1 509.1C142.9 513.4 133.1 512.7 125.6 507.4C118.2 502.1 114.5 492.9 115.1 483.9L142.2 328.4L31.11 218.2C24.65 211.9 22.36 202.4 25.2 193.7C28.03 185.1 35.5 178.8 44.49 177.5L197.7 154.8L266.3 13.52C270.4 5.249 278.7 0 287.9 0L287.9 0zM287.9 78.95L235.4 187.2C231.9 194.3 225.1 199.3 217.3 200.5L98.98 217.9L184.9 303C190.4 308.5 192.9 316.4 191.6 324.1L171.4 443.7L276.6 387.5C283.7 383.7 292.2 383.7 299.2 387.5L404.4 443.7L384.2 324.1C382.9 316.4 385.5 308.5 391 303L476.9 217.9L358.6 200.5C350.7 199.3 343.9 194.3 340.5 187.2L287.9 78.95z"/></svg>
  </span>


      </span>
      <div id="github-ca5909c42993317bda43c57784488179-stargazers" class="m-0 mr-5 text-md text-neutral-800 dark:text-neutral">
        193
      </div>

      <span class="text-md mr-1 text-neutral-800 dark:text-neutral">
        

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 448 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M80 104c13.3 0 24-10.7 24-24s-10.7-24-24-24S56 66.7 56 80s10.7 24 24 24zm80-24c0 32.8-19.7 61-48 73.3V192c0 17.7 14.3 32 32 32H304c17.7 0 32-14.3 32-32V153.3C307.7 141 288 112.8 288 80c0-44.2 35.8-80 80-80s80 35.8 80 80c0 32.8-19.7 61-48 73.3V192c0 53-43 96-96 96H256v70.7c28.3 12.3 48 40.5 48 73.3c0 44.2-35.8 80-80 80s-80-35.8-80-80c0-32.8 19.7-61 48-73.3V288H144c-53 0-96-43-96-96V153.3C19.7 141 0 112.8 0 80C0 35.8 35.8 0 80 0s80 35.8 80 80zm208 24c13.3 0 24-10.7 24-24s-10.7-24-24-24s-24 10.7-24 24s10.7 24 24 24zM248 432c0-13.3-10.7-24-24-24s-24 10.7-24 24s10.7 24 24 24s24-10.7 24-24z"/></svg>
  </span>


      </span>
      <div id="github-ca5909c42993317bda43c57784488179-forks" class="m-0 mr-5 text-md text-neutral-800 dark:text-neutral">
        40
      </div>

    </div>

  </div>
  <script>
    fetch("https://api.github.com/repos/TianmingLi/early_retirement_extreme_cn", {
      headers: new Headers({
        'User-agent': 'Mozilla/4.0 Custom User Agent'
      })
    })
      .then(response => response.json())
      .then(data => {
        document.getElementById('github-ca5909c42993317bda43c57784488179-full_name').innerHTML = data.full_name;
        document.getElementById('github-ca5909c42993317bda43c57784488179-description').innerHTML = data.description;
        document.getElementById('github-ca5909c42993317bda43c57784488179-stargazers').innerHTML = data.stargazers_count;
        document.getElementById('github-ca5909c42993317bda43c57784488179-forks').innerHTML = data.forks;
      })
      .catch(error => console.error(error))
  </script>
</a></p>
<hr>

<section class="space-y-10 w-full">
    
    
        
            






















  <a class="flex flex-wrap article " href="/en/posts/1728295490690-book-list/">
    
        
        <div class="w-full md:w-auto h-full thumbnail nozoom thumbnailshadow md:mr-7" style="background-image:url(/posts/1728295490690-book-list/featured_hu_a14921d8ab66af4e.jpg);"></div>
        
      <div class=" mt-3 md:mt-0">
      <div class="items-center text-left text-xl font-semibold">
        
        <div class="font-bold text-xl text-neutral-800 decoration-primary-500 hover:underline hover:underline-offset-2 dark:text-neutral"
          href="/en/posts/1728295490690-book-list/">Recommended Reading List</div>
        
        
        
      </div>
      <div class="text-sm text-neutral-500 dark:text-neutral-400">
        











  



















<div class="flex flex-row flex-wrap items-center">
  
  
  <time datetime="2024-10-01T00:00:00&#43;00:00">1 October 2024</time>
  

  
  
</div>





<div class="flex flex-row flex-wrap items-center">
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  <span style="margin-top:0.5rem" class="mr-2" onclick="window.open(&#34;/en/tags/recommended/&#34;,'_self');">
    <span class="flex" style="cursor: pointer;">
  <span class="rounded-md border border-primary-400 px-1 py-[1px] text-xs font-normal text-primary-700 dark:border-primary-600 dark:text-primary-400">
    Recommended
  </span>
</span>
  </span>
  
  <span style="margin-top:0.5rem" class="mr-2" onclick="window.open(&#34;/en/tags/book/&#34;,'_self');">
    <span class="flex" style="cursor: pointer;">
  <span class="rounded-md border border-primary-400 px-1 py-[1px] text-xs font-normal text-primary-700 dark:border-primary-600 dark:text-primary-400">
    Book
  </span>
</span>
  </span>
  
  
  
  
</div>




      </div>
      
    </div>
  </a>

        
    
</section>
]]></content:encoded></item></channel></rss>