<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Investment and Financial Management on QQQ Investor</title>
    <link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/tags/investment-and-financial-management/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Investment and Financial Management on QQQ Investor</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 31 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jomonylw.github.io/en/tags/investment-and-financial-management/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>00516 The Middle-Class Dilemma and the Rich Mindset: The Truth Behind the Gaps in Happiness, Investment, and System Design</title>
      <link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1748740945878/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1748740945878/</guid>
      <description>In this session, Mr. James emphasizes the core philosophy of long-term investing, which is to ignore short-term market fluctuations and focus on quality assets (like the Nasdaq 100 Index Fund). He delves into strategies for personal wealth accumulation within the capitalist system, including correctly understanding risk, rationally using leverage (advising conservatism for most), and balancing wealth inheritance with life&amp;#39;s meaning. The core message is that through the right investment mindset and methods, ordinary people can achieve financial freedom and live a fulfilling life, rather than merely chasing money.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<lite-youtube videoid="-eZxijaGtcc" playlabel="-eZxijaGtcc" params=""></lite-youtube>



<h2 class="relative group">I. Main Theme of This Session 
    <div id="i-main-theme-of-this-session" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-main-theme-of-this-session" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>Mr. James&rsquo;s core viewpoints in this session revolve around <strong>long-term investing, ignoring market noise, understanding the essence of capitalism, and balancing wealth with life</strong>. He emphasizes that investors should focus on quality passive ETFs like the Nasdaq 100 Index Fund (QQQ) and possess the patience and optimism for long-term holding. Simultaneously, he deeply analyzes the impact of the capitalist system on different social classes, how to utilize capital markets to achieve personal and family financial freedom, and explores profound topics such as the relationship between wealth accumulation and life happiness, family relationships, children&rsquo;s education, elderly care for parents, and wealth inheritance.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">II. Briefing Content 
    <div id="ii-briefing-content" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii-briefing-content" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Market Volatility and Investment Mentality 
    <div id="market-volatility-and-investment-mentality" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#market-volatility-and-investment-mentality" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>No need to pay attention to market signals</strong>: Market disturbances (like tariffs, wars) are irrelevant to long-term investing; the market will eventually rise, and approaching or even setting new highs is normal. Investors need not worry about short-term signals.
<ul>
<li><em>Example:</em> The current market is full of turmoil, yet it&rsquo;s close to setting new highs, proving that short-term signals are inconsequential.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Learn from history, understand the present</strong>: The century-long history of the U.S. stock market shows that while it doesn&rsquo;t repeat, it rhymes astonishingly. Understanding history helps solidify long-term investment beliefs. Mr. James shares insights based on his 40 years of market experience and understanding of 200 years of U.S. market history.</li>
<li><strong>Optimism and patience</strong>: Investors should always be extremely optimistic and unaffected by external pessimism and fear-mongering. &ldquo;If you don&rsquo;t listen or look, it doesn&rsquo;t exist.&rdquo; Wealth is worth waiting for; investing requires patience.</li>
<li><strong>Technical analysis is ineffective</strong>: Those who believe technical analysis is effective haven&rsquo;t truly grasped investing. Market fluctuations can sometimes be like &ldquo;madness&rdquo;; no need to dance to its tune.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Core Investment Strategies and Tools 
    <div id="core-investment-strategies-and-tools" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#core-investment-strategies-and-tools" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Focus on the Nasdaq 100 Index Fund (QQQ)</strong>: This is currently the fastest-growing passive ETF globally, suitable for young investors to accelerate asset appreciation. Mr. James provides links to resources for investing in Nasdaq 100 Index Funds worldwide.</li>
<li><strong>Learning resources</strong>: Recommends watching a series of videos (e.g., 00451 &ldquo;Value Investing Lecture&rdquo; as a compulsory course for newcomers, as well as 398, 399, 400, etc.), learning them in conjunction with the market conditions at the time to achieve a solid grasp.</li>
<li><strong>Getting started for young professionals/small investors</strong>: It&rsquo;s advised to set aside an emergency fund for six months to a year before starting to invest in QQQ or 00662 (a Taiwanese ETF tracking Nasdaq 100). Buy whenever you have money, don&rsquo;t try to time the market, buy at market price.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">The Nature of Capitalism and How to Cope 
    <div id="the-nature-of-capitalism-and-how-to-cope" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#the-nature-of-capitalism-and-how-to-cope" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Systemic traps of capitalism</strong>: Mr. James quotes and agrees with a YouTuber&rsquo;s perspective that capitalism is designed to favor the rich, reflected in:
<ul>
<li><strong>Tax mechanisms</strong>: Investment income (e.g., U.S. Long-term Capital Gains, tax-free for singles up to $40k/couples up to $80k, with rates of 15%-20% above that) is taxed at much lower rates than labor income (up to 37%), benefiting long-term investors. Taiwan doesn&rsquo;t even have capital gains tax.</li>
<li><strong>Triple risks for the middle class</strong>: Job, company stock, and property near the company are highly intertwined. If the company has problems, one might lose their job, stock value, and property (or face mortgage pressure) simultaneously. Advice: Sell company stock promptly and reinvest in QQQ; buy a house only after achieving financial freedom (&ldquo;buying a house should be like buying slippers&rdquo;).</li>
<li><strong>Differences in borrowing</strong>: The rich borrow money to get richer (investment), while the middle class borrows money to become poorer (consumption).</li>
<li><strong>Differences in income growth</strong>: Income from physical labor struggles to keep pace with inflation and asset appreciation.</li>
<li><strong>Differences in offspring development</strong>: Middle-class children rely on &ldquo;involution&rdquo; (cram schools, prestigious universities, spending hundreds of thousands to get into private schools), while wealthy children can pursue their interests and grow up happily.</li>
<li><strong>Impact of financial bubbles</strong>: The middle class is forced to sell assets at low prices when bubbles burst because they can&rsquo;t hold on, while the rich have the money and opportunity to buy the dip.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Utilizing capitalism</strong>: Despite its pitfalls, the capital market is an important way for ordinary people to bridge the wealth gap and share the dividends of social progress.
<ul>
<li><strong>At the national level</strong>: If citizens all become capitalists, holding shares in globally competitive companies (like TSMC, Apple), they can enjoy the benefits of globalization while &ldquo;transferring&rdquo; negative externalities of production (like pollution). Citizens should ponder: Is it better to be proud of owning a factory, or proud of owning shares in that factory?</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>The &ldquo;Borrow 100 Million&rdquo; thought experiment</strong>: If someone were willing to lend you 100 million (any currency) at 5% interest, to be repaid in 40 years, would you dare to borrow it? Those who dare and know how to use it possess a rich mindset, because this money, through investment, can generate returns far exceeding the interest, potentially allowing for immediate retirement. The key is whether you have the credit or assets to borrow this sum.</li>
<li><strong>Inspiration from Trump&rsquo;s proposed &ldquo;Great Child America Act&rdquo;</strong>: Investing $1,000 annually for newborns from a young age cultivates financial literacy and long-term compound interest awareness, reflecting a nation&rsquo;s soft power. This is more meaningful than direct subsidies.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Life, Family, and Wealth Philosophy 
    <div id="life-family-and-wealth-philosophy" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#life-family-and-wealth-philosophy" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Beyond &ldquo;cost&rdquo; thinking</strong>: Falling in love, getting married, and having children should not be calculated as &ldquo;costs.&rdquo; With a long-term wealth perspective (e.g., 1 million becoming 1 billion in 40 years), money is meant to be spent, and family is for sharing love.
<ul>
<li><em>Example:</em> If you only think about the immediate 1 million not being enough, you miss the possibility of becoming a billionaire enjoying life in the future. By 60-70, even with money, you might not be able to make up for regrets from youth (like having children).</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>The &ldquo;Die with Zero&rdquo; philosophy</strong>: Life should be fully experienced, rather than dying with a huge fortune, which is the tragedy of &ldquo;having nothing but money.&rdquo; Money should be spent wisely to create beautiful memories.</li>
<li><strong>Financial wisdom for couples</strong>:
<ul>
<li><strong>Economic security</strong>: The higher-earning spouse should proactively transfer a portion of their funds (e.g., 50k from a 150k salary) to the other&rsquo;s account, giving them financial freedom and security, avoiding the need to &ldquo;report everything&rdquo; or &ldquo;ask for money.&rdquo;</li>
<li><strong>Common goals</strong>: Couples should have aligned financial views, invest together, and not bicker over money (like who does the dishes or takes out the trash). A home needs love.</li>
<li><strong>Improve oneself first</strong>: In a family, first make yourself &ldquo;worthy of being loved.&rdquo;</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Becoming the &ldquo;big tree&rdquo; of the family</strong>: Through long-term investment, everyone has the potential (hundreds of thousands becoming hundreds of millions, millions becoming billions) to become the family&rsquo;s economic pillar, providing shelter for loved ones.</li>
<li><strong>Elderly care for parents</strong>:
<ul>
<li><strong>Health is the biggest money-saver</strong>: Instead of worrying if pensions are sufficient, care more about parents&rsquo; health, manage their blood pressure and blood sugar, ensure they take medication on time, and have regular check-ups (e.g., for macular degeneration, joints, carotid artery stents). Healthy parents mean a lighter burden for children.</li>
<li><strong>Cost estimation</strong>: If parents are completely dependent, a caregiver plus basic expenses might cost NT$80,000-100,000 per month. Mr. James&rsquo;s mother cost about NT$10 million over 10 years.</li>
<li><strong>Plan early</strong>: When children are 30, parents are around 60. Significant expenses might arise after age 80. Regularly investing NT$1,000-2,000 per month for parents can accumulate a considerable pension fund after 20 years.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Investment Practice and Risk Management 
    <div id="investment-practice-and-risk-management" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#investment-practice-and-risk-management" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Simplify investing</strong>: Once asset allocation is done, you can set it to &ldquo;autopilot,&rdquo; no need to watch the market daily or analyze asset performance. Spending 5 minutes once a year for rebalancing is sufficient.</li>
<li><strong>Risk awareness</strong>:
<ul>
<li><strong>&ldquo;Market goes to zero&rdquo; test</strong>: Before any investment decision, ask yourself, &ldquo;If this investment goes to zero tomorrow, can I handle it? Even if I can&rsquo;t sell stocks for three years, can I survive?&rdquo; If not, the risk is too high.</li>
<li><strong>Liquidity risk</strong>: Some markets or specific situations (like some mainland China ETFs in 2022) may experience situations where you want to sell but cannot.</li>
<li><strong>Leverage risk</strong>: Margin loans (e.g., from a brokerage account) are extremely risky. A market downturn can lead to margin calls or even negative equity (e.g., stocks drop to $800k, but you borrowed $1 million, owing $200k). Personal loans (with stable income, used for investment) are relatively manageable because they are not directly tied to stock market value for forced liquidation.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>The essence of learning</strong>: It&rsquo;s not just about learning what works, but more importantly, learning that &ldquo;these things are useless&rdquo; (like technical analysis, economic analysis, business cycle indicators). This conclusion is reached after understanding these tools.</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">III. Q&amp;A Session 
    <div id="iii-qa-session" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii-qa-session" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">CADRE 
    <div id="cadre" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#cadre" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Observed some people nearing retirement with no stable income wanting to borrow money to invest. However, their understanding of investment philosophy and risk tolerance might be insufficient. Advised such individuals not to borrow easily; they should first build a solid foundation with their own funds and become mentally strong enough before considering advanced operations.
<ul>
<li>Mr. James&rsquo;s comments: Strongly agree. Investors first need to experience market volatility (e.g., a 10-15% correction) with their own funds to confirm they can tolerate it before considering borrowing. For retirees:
<ul>
<li>Personal loans: If there&rsquo;s no stable income for repayment, a market downturn will force selling stocks to repay debt, which is not recommended.</li>
<li>Mortgages: A home equity line of credit (HELOC, interest-only payments, like in the US) might be considered; however, mortgages requiring principal and interest payments are not recommended due to the large amounts involved.</li>
<li>Core principle: For any leveraged investment, consider, &ldquo;If the stock drops to zero, the loan still needs to be repaid. Can I handle it?&rdquo;</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Sams 
    <div id="sams" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#sams" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing 1: As a listener for over two years, he gradually shifted personal funds, private equity, trusts, and insurance products into QQQ and domestic Nasdaq ETFs. Due to excessive optimism, he used margin (brokerage account overdraft to buy) from late 2023 to early 2024, almost at 1:1 leverage. He then encountered the &ldquo;tariff war&rdquo; and liquidity issues in the domestic ETF market (e.g., 513100), where some ETFs hit their limit down and couldn&rsquo;t be sold. He was forced to significantly deleverage the next day, wiping out much of the previous year&rsquo;s profits. His father&rsquo;s account, with no leverage and regular investments, hit an all-time high. Profound realization: Don&rsquo;t rush to make money; slow is fast, and safety is more important. Personal cash flow and future income expectations are crucial when using leverage. Also, in panic, he cleared out QLD from his Hong Kong account, missing the subsequent rally. This experience reminded him of the 2015 A-share market crash, also involving margin calls and being unable to sell for three consecutive days.
<ul>
<li>Mr. James&rsquo;s comments: Sams&rsquo; experience is very typical. Markets have liquidity risks, and margin risks are enormous, potentially leading to margin calls or even owing the brokerage money. Repeatedly emphasized the importance of the &ldquo;market goes to zero test.&rdquo; Don&rsquo;t test human nature.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Sharing 2: Investing allows one to control their own destiny. He experienced his company being acquired, then another company he co-founded being acquired (sold to Evergrande, which later defaulted, and got entangled in lawsuits), and personally shutting down an underperforming branch (decided to close the Chongqing branch after a three-hour walk with his boss; employees were given N+1 severance the next day). Because he had investments as a backup, he was more composed when facing these changes. Colleagues without investments (like some branch managers) felt lost about their future. Insight: Whether in good times or bad, hold on to good assets.
<ul>
<li>Mr. James&rsquo;s comments: All things have unexpected events (companies go bankrupt, properties get damaged). When investing, first think about risk. Jobs and individual stocks carry high risks. QQQ will also drop significantly. Only invest money you won&rsquo;t need for 15-20-30 years. Retirees need to set aside about 15 years of cash for living expenses.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question: Mr. James once suggested 70% QQQ / 30% cash, and allocating 2% to leveraged funds (like QLD) in down years. He wanted to confirm:
<ol>
<li>Can mainland China and Hong Kong accounts be treated as one, with a synchronized 70/30 allocation?</li>
<li>Since transferring funds out of mainland China is troublesome, should more leveraged funds be allocated in Hong Kong?</li>
<li>If the market falls at year-end, is the 2% allocation to leveraged funds based on 2% of total assets or only 2% of Hong Kong assets?</li>
</ol>
<ul>
<li>Mr. James&rsquo;s reply:
<ol>
<li>For beginners or those sensitive to volatility, 70/30 (QQQ/cash) or even 60/40 is a safe starting point. No need to rush into leveraged funds. Because even if the overall drop isn&rsquo;t large, the violent fluctuations of leveraged funds themselves can cause anxiety (e.g., only focusing on QLD dropping 5%, not seeing that cash doesn&rsquo;t drop).</li>
<li>Beta can start at a lower level (e.g., 0.6-0.8) and gradually increase with experience and asset growth.</li>
<li>Regarding the 2% QLD allocation: It can be calculated based on Hong Kong assets or total assets. However, note that leveraged funds usually cannot be used as collateral for bank loans (e.g., at HSBC). If QLD proportion is too high, it might affect future collateralized financing plans.</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">DVA 
    <div id="dva" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#dva" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Listening to Mr. James&rsquo;s class is like learning life philosophy; investing is a battle against human nature. Experienced the recent market correction (what the teacher called a &ldquo;slap in the face&rdquo; market). Although he wanted to hold on, he was scared and sold half of his holdings, including some individual stocks like Nvidia.</li>
<li>Question: His Roth IRA account is small, and he&rsquo;s nearing retirement. He wants to know if an allocation of 60% QQQ + 10% TQQQ + 30% cash, or 70% QQQ + 20% TQQQ + 10% cash, resulting in an overall Beta of around 0.8, is robust enough while also providing growth.
<ul>
<li>Mr. James&rsquo;s reply: A 60/10/30 (QQQ/TQQQ/cash) configuration, with a Beta around 0.8, is very good. Beta will increase as the leveraged portion grows. For those afraid of volatility, an initial Beta of 0.6-0.8 is sufficient.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Yao 
    <div id="yao" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#yao" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Recently, watching news (Elon Musk leaving the White House after 130 days, under immense pressure, even relying on medication and games to de-stress) and movies (the heavy burden and helplessness of the protagonist in &ldquo;Oppenheimer&rdquo;), he realized &ldquo;uneasy lies the head that wears a crown.&rdquo; If ordinary people lack such talent and resilience, it&rsquo;s better to follow the teacher&rsquo;s philosophy, achieve wealth calmly and happily, without enduring those extreme pressures and risks. Investing slowly and waiting for the compounding effect is a good choice.
<ul>
<li>Mr. James&rsquo;s comments: Slow is fast. Don&rsquo;t use money you need to earn money you don&rsquo;t need. Life should be about reducing regrets, not chasing empty fame and fortune. Enjoy the fruits of enterprises (like Nvidia) through tools like QQQ, without bearing the immense pressure of the operators.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Ju 
    <div id="ju" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ju" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Introduced to Mr. James&rsquo;s philosophy by a friend in 2018/2019. As a stock market novice, he was deeply inspired and immediately adjusted his strategy, investing borrowed funds and continuing with regular contributions. He once participated in short-term trading studies (joined a stock reading club) but found it arduous and the ROE (Return on Equity) not high. He had to watch the market daily, research US stocks, Taiwan stocks, margin changes, aiming for a 10-20% annualized return, and only dared to invest a portion of his capital (e.g., 10-30%). So he gave up, focused on his main job and long-term investing, and now lives a peaceful and prosperous life (meditating morning and evening). When sharing his philosophy with friends and colleagues, he found they hesitated to invest for their own long-term (feeling 20-30 years is too long), but were more receptive to investing for their children, which might then lead them to participate themselves. Having experienced 00662 (a Taiwanese Nasdaq 100 ETF) dropping from over 50 to the 40s and persisting in buying, he is now calm about current market fluctuations.
<ul>
<li>Mr. James&rsquo;s comments: Many short-term traders only look at the ROI (Return on Investment) of individual trades, ignoring the ROE (Return on Equity) on their total assets. They might achieve a high ROI with a small amount of capital, but it contributes little to overall wealth growth. For example, with 1 million in capital, using 30,000 to make 30,000 is a 100% ROI, but only a 3% ROE. Whereas we aim for a 10% return on the entire 1 million, which is 100,000.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chen Hua 
    <div id="chen-hua" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chen-hua" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question 1: Noticed Mr. James recently emphasizing conservatism more, suggesting a 30% cash position (earlier it was 10-20%). Is this due to varying student experience levels or other considerations? He himself targets a Beta of 1.0, holds leveraged funds, has little cash, and would need to reduce leveraged funds to reach 30% cash.
<ul>
<li>Mr. James&rsquo;s reply: Yes, this is because students come from diverse backgrounds; many are novices or cannot withstand significant volatility. A 30% (or even 40%) cash position is a &ldquo;plain beef noodle soup&rdquo; style basic version, suitable for everyone to start with. Experienced investors who can tolerate risk can adjust it themselves, choosing a &ldquo;mildly spicy&rdquo; or &ldquo;extra spicy&rdquo; allocation. Asset allocation is very personal.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2: Regarding wealth inheritance. Warren Buffett&rsquo;s testamentary portfolio (90% S&amp;P 500 + 10% short-term bonds) is suitable due to his vast assets. For ordinary people whose descendants have no interest in investing, how should a &ldquo;permanent&rdquo; trust asset allocation plan be established? (Citing Anita Mui&rsquo;s trust case)
<ul>
<li>Mr. James&rsquo;s reply:
<ul>
<li>Firstly, children&rsquo;s moral character and values education (quoting Lin Zexu: &ldquo;If my descendants are like me, what&rsquo;s the use of leaving them money? If my descendants are not like me, what&rsquo;s the use of leaving them money?&rdquo;) is more important than wealth inheritance. Wealth should be the icing on the cake.</li>
<li>One can start considering gifting when their assets exceed 50 times their annual expenses.</li>
<li>It&rsquo;s not advisable to easily set up a private non-profit foundation unless the children are genuinely committed, otherwise, it might become a burden or a management problem.</li>
<li>Trust selection: Trust services from large financial institutions (like HSBC, Charles Schwab) are generally more stable than private family offices (even if the institution fails, assets are protected, like Credit Suisse being taken over by UBS), but offer less flexibility. One can set up a portfolio like 70% QQQ / 30% cash (or short-term bonds/money market funds), with a rule to withdraw 2% annually, achieving perpetuity. The key is simplicity and low management fees. Private family offices might offer comprehensive services, but institutional trusts focus more on asset management and distribution.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">IV. Key Quotes / Insightful Points 
    <div id="iv-key-quotes--insightful-points" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv-key-quotes--insightful-points" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>Market fluctuations have nothing to do with me anymore. The market might be full of turmoil, tariffs coming and going, wars still ongoing, but the market is already close to new highs. So this is why you don&rsquo;t need to care about market signals; they are not important, not important at all.
&ndash; Mr. James</p></blockquote>
<p>This view emphasizes that investors should ignore short-term market noise and focus on long-term trends.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>This capitalism is a systemic trap&hellip; it&rsquo;s advantageous to the rich, to wealthy people.
&ndash; Mr. James (quoting and agreeing with a YouTuber&rsquo;s perspective)</p></blockquote>
<p>This view reveals the inherent mechanisms of wealth distribution under the capitalist system.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Earning money through physical labor will never keep up with inflation, let alone the speed of asset appreciation.
&ndash; Mr. James</p></blockquote>
<p>This view highlights the fundamental difference between labor income and capital appreciation.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>If you calculate falling in love, getting married, and having children in terms of cost, then you&rsquo;re being too meticulous&hellip; We are rich people; money is meant to be spent. We&rsquo;ll have more money than we can spend in a lifetime, so if we get married and have children, let&rsquo;s have a few more to spend it together.
&ndash; Mr. James</p></blockquote>
<p>This view reminds people to look beyond utilitarian calculations in important life choices, focus on emotions and experiences, and view them from a long-term wealth perspective.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Slowly is fast. You will all become a big tree for your family.
&ndash; Mr. James (combining the &ldquo;slow is fast&rdquo; and &ldquo;become a big tree&rdquo; concepts)</p></blockquote>
<p>This view encourages long-term patient investing, believing in the power of compounding to enable individuals to become the economic pillars of their families.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>For any asset allocation, just ask yourself: what if the market goes to zero tomorrow, how would you fare? Ah, if you find out it&rsquo;s not okay, if I&rsquo;m finished if it goes to zero, then you should quickly adjust your asset allocation.
&ndash; Mr. James</p></blockquote>
<p>This view provides an ultimate test for measuring risk tolerance.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Everyone needs to know that in investing, all things can have unexpected outcomes. Your company can go bankrupt in an instant&hellip; So for any investment, the first thing to think about is what if this investment is destroyed, goes to zero, what will you do?
&ndash; Mr. James</p></blockquote>
<p>This view emphasizes risk awareness, that any investment should first consider the worst-case scenario.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Don&rsquo;t think about making this money too quickly; a bit slower and safer might be better.
&ndash; Sams</p></blockquote>
<p>Sams, after a severe setback with leverage, gained a profound understanding of prudent investing.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>What&rsquo;s the biggest advantage of investing well? It&rsquo;s that you can control your own destiny.
&ndash; Sams</p></blockquote>
<p>Sams shared how investing gave him more agency and security amidst career and life changes.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Spending five minutes a year is enough. There&rsquo;s absolutely no need to care about market fluctuations; it&rsquo;s completely meaningless&hellip; Living a good life is the purpose of life.
&ndash; Mr. James</p></blockquote>
<p>This view advocates for simplifying investment management and dedicating more energy to life itself.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">V. Summary 
    <div id="v-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#v-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>In this CLEC sharing session, Mr. James once again emphasized the importance of long-term holding of quality assets (especially the Nasdaq 100 Index Fund) and reminded investors to ignore market noise and focus on their own investment discipline. He deeply analyzed the operational mechanisms of capitalism, pointing out that ordinary people can achieve wealth growth through capital markets and escape the &ldquo;laborer mindset.&rdquo; The discussion covered several important topics, including risk management (especially a cautious attitude towards using leverage, advising most to start with a conservative cash ratio, and conducting the &ldquo;market goes to zero&rdquo; test), the wisdom of wealth inheritance (emphasizing children&rsquo;s moral education first and suggesting simple, sustainable trust solutions through financial institutions), elderly care for parents (prioritizing health management over financial worries), and balancing investment with life happiness (avoiding excessive calculation of &ldquo;costs&rdquo; in life, living in the present, and achieving the state of &ldquo;Die with Zero&rdquo;). Participants&rsquo; sharing also provided valuable practical experiences and lessons, particularly regarding leverage risks, market liquidity, and the profound impact of investment on personal control over one&rsquo;s destiny. Overall, this session aimed to help investors establish the correct investment mindset and methodology to achieve long-term financial health and a fulfilling life.</p>

  



<div
  
    class="flex px-4 py-3 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900"
  >

  <span
    
      class="text-primary-400 ltr:pr-3 rtl:pl-3 flex items-center"
    >

    

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M506.3 417l-213.3-364c-16.33-28-57.54-28-73.98 0l-213.2 364C-10.59 444.9 9.849 480 42.74 480h426.6C502.1 480 522.6 445 506.3 417zM232 168c0-13.25 10.75-24 24-24S280 154.8 280 168v128c0 13.25-10.75 24-23.1 24S232 309.3 232 296V168zM256 416c-17.36 0-31.44-14.08-31.44-31.44c0-17.36 14.07-31.44 31.44-31.44s31.44 14.08 31.44 31.44C287.4 401.9 273.4 416 256 416z"/></svg>

  </span>


  </span>

  <span
    
      class="dark:text-neutral-300"
    ><strong>Disclaimer:</strong> This article is for personal learning notes only and does not constitute any investment advice.</span>
</div>

]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>00504 Asset Allocation Wisdom: How to Build Financial Freedom with Leverage and Pledging? Cash is King? Investment Wisdom in a Volatile Market</title>
      <link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1740895441407/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1740895441407/</guid>
      <description>This episode of CLEC Investment and Financial Management Channel focuses on the concept of easy investing, emphasizing that international situations should not interfere with personal investment decisions, and investing in the United States remains a wise choice. It delves into index fund investment strategies, shares tips on using YouTube Music Podcast features, and interprets Buffett&amp;#39;s latest shareholder letter. In the Q&amp;amp;A session, students actively participated, and James provided detailed answers to questions on taxation, insurance, asset allocation, retirement planning, and the philosophy of life, encouraging everyone to stick to long-term investment and achieve both financial and spiritual freedom.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<lite-youtube videoid="pw6ORn1yTOI" playlabel="pw6ORn1yTOI" params=""></lite-youtube>



<h2 class="relative group">I. Current Theme 
    <div id="i-current-theme" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-current-theme" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This episode of the CLEC Investment and Financial Management Channel adopts the theme of &ldquo;Easy Chat on Investment,&rdquo; with the core idea that market chaos is irrelevant to personal investment, and reiterating the correctness of investing in the U.S. market. James emphasized that investors should adhere to their established index fund investment strategies and not pay excessive attention to international political and economic fluctuations. At the same time, he also introduced the new features of YouTube Music Podcast, recommended learning resources, and patiently answered students&rsquo; questions about taxation, insurance, asset allocation, and life planning, aiming to help everyone establish a more mature investment mindset and strategy.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">II. Briefing Content 
    <div id="ii-briefing-content" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii-briefing-content" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Market and Investment Philosophy 
    <div id="market-and-investment-philosophy" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#market-and-investment-philosophy" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Market Situation and Personal Investment:</strong> Emphasized that even in the face of international events such as the Wol War and Trump&rsquo;s election, personal investment decisions should not be changed as a result. These external factors are not directly related to long-term investment goals and should not be overemphasized, but rather focus on the execution of one&rsquo;s own investment plan.</li>
<li><strong>Investing in the United States:</strong> Reaffirmed that the U.S. economy remains strong in the long term, so investing in the United States is still the right choice. Even if the world situation is turbulent, long-term confidence in the U.S. economy should not be shaken.</li>
<li><strong>Easy Investment:</strong> Advocated a simplified approach to investment, choosing to buy index funds and then reducing attention to short-term market fluctuations, sticking to a long-term hold. This &ldquo;buy and hold&rdquo; strategy can reduce anxiety and operational errors.</li>
<li><strong>Risk Warning:</strong> Emphasized the inherent risks of investing, especially the risks associated with leveraged funds and stock pledging. James strongly recommends that new students listen to several episodes of videos and be sure to carefully study the relevant handouts before making any investment operations, especially to understand the operating mechanisms and potential risks of leveraged funds and pledging.</li>
<li><strong>Non-Profit and Personal Experience Sharing:</strong> Re-emphasized that the CLAC channel, as a non-profit organization, does not charge students any fees and will not ask for remittances. All sharing on the channel is based on personal experience and is not professional investment advice. Therefore, students need to think, research, and bear all investment risks on their own. At the same time, students are reminded to beware of external fraudulent information impersonating CLEC.</li>
<li><strong>Market Volatility is Normal:</strong> Pointed out that market volatility is normal, with declines possible every year, 20% declines every three to five years, and 50% declines every ten to fifteen years. Investors should recognize that this is normal and not panic excessively, and they will get used to it by staying in the market long enough.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Learning Resources and Tools 
    <div id="learning-resources-and-tools" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#learning-resources-and-tools" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Learning Resources:</strong> Suggested that new friends start by watching past videos from 2023, and then go back to review content from 2022 and earlier. At the same time, emphasized the importance of the handouts provided on the message board, with relevant links available on YouTube and the Cross House message board.</li>
<li><strong>Community Resources:</strong> Introduced the Taiwan 00662 Endurance Group and thanked the group administrator for their selfless contribution. Students can ask questions within the group, and the administrator will do their best to answer them, but emphasized that the group mainly answers basic questions from the handouts, such as what is 442, what is pledging, etc., to avoid off-topic discussions unrelated to the investment theme within the group. The group may have regional restrictions, and users in Asia may find it easier to join.</li>
<li><strong>NASDAQ 100 Index Funds:</strong> Recommended investing in NASDAQ 100 index funds, and pointed out that there are related products in many places around the world, including the United States, Taiwan, Hong Kong, Canada, Australia, the United Kingdom, Brazil, Japan, Malaysia, South Korea, etc. In Malaysia, it may be necessary to purchase through Phillip Securities.</li>
<li><strong>Best NASDAQ Document:</strong> Strongly recommended consulting the document titled &ldquo;World&rsquo;s Best NASDAQ United States NASDAQ 100 Index Fund Investment,&rdquo; which contains information on NASDAQ funds and leveraged funds in various countries, with links on the message board. The document contains local information provided by friends from various regions, helping investors find suitable investment targets.</li>
<li><strong>YouTube Music Podcast:</strong> Detailed instructions on how to use the YouTube Music Podcast feature. Parts of the CLEC channel content can be transferred to YouTube Music, allowing you to enjoy ad-free listening and offline downloads, and guiding users on how to operate on mobile phones and web pages. Emphasized the difference between YouTube Music and a regular YouTube account, and that after joining a Podcast playlist, it will be displayed in the YouTube Music APP.</li>
<li><strong>Buffett Shareholder Letter:</strong> Emphasized the importance of reading the latest Buffett shareholder letter, especially the part about paying taxes. Shared a YouTube link and encouraged everyone to learn from Buffett&rsquo;s investment wisdom and values.</li>
<li><strong>China NASDAQ 100 Index Fund:</strong> Introduced that there are already 12 NASDAQ 100 index funds in the Chinese market, and provided links to related ETFs to facilitate local purchases for Chinese investors. Even if there are purchase restrictions or premiums, these locally issued ETFs can be considered.</li>
<li><strong>Adlerian Purpose Theory:</strong> Strongly recommended watching videos related to Adlerian purpose theory as extracurricular homework to enhance happiness and self-awareness. Emphasized that understanding the purpose and meaning of life helps to maintain a peaceful state of mind in investing.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Asset Allocation and Pledging 
    <div id="asset-allocation-and-pledging" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#asset-allocation-and-pledging" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Asset Allocation Briefing:</strong> Mentioned the asset allocation briefing produced by Chen Feng and the 00662 group, mainly for investors participating in stock pledging, covering allocation schemes for different situations, such as different allocations with and without pledging (442, 80/20) and related Excel analysis tables. Recommended watching the relevant videos, and if you have any questions, you can ask them within the group.</li>
<li><strong>Stock Pledging Information:</strong> Shared information on stock pledging from E.SUN Securities, with the current interest rate at approximately 3%, which can be applied for online, and provided contact information for interested students to inquire.</li>
<li><strong>Leveraged Funds and Pledging:</strong> Re-emphasized that leveraged funds should not be used for pledging, and emphasized that U.S. leveraged funds should be placed in a retirement account (Roth IRA) and not pledged.</li>
<li><strong>Importance of Roth IRA:</strong> Emphasized that leveraged funds must be placed in a Roth IRA retirement account, rather than a Block 9 com account, to avoid unnecessary tax burdens and pledging risks.</li>
<li><strong>Rust IRA&rsquo;s Importance:</strong> Pointed out that even if a Rust IRA account has little initial capital, it should be gradually increased to eventually achieve a 442 allocation. Emphasized the importance of time accumulation and the benefits of long-term compounding.</li>
<li><strong>Retirement Fund Withdrawal:</strong> Discussed fund withdrawal strategies when there is no income after retirement. Emphasized that in the case of non-pledging, in order to cope with market risks, only a conservative 80/20 allocation can be used to avoid over-reliance on leverage.</li>
<li><strong>Other Income After Retirement:</strong> If there are other sources of income after retirement, such as rental income or side hustle income, leveraged funds can be held, and a more aggressive 433 allocation can be considered, but a 442 allocation is not recommended.</li>
<li><strong>Pledging and Asset Allocation:</strong> Whether retired or not, as long as pledging is carried out, it is recommended to use a 433 allocation and cooperate with a smart rebalancing strategy.</li>
<li><strong>Yuanta Securities Pledging:</strong> Reminded friends who pledge stocks at Yuanta Securities in Taiwan to pay attention to the need to renew their contracts every 18 months to avoid forced sale of stocks. Even if there is no borrowing, timely renewal is still required.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Investment Mentality and Insights 
    <div id="investment-mentality-and-insights" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#investment-mentality-and-insights" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Individual Stocks and Index Funds:</strong> Emphasized the advantages of investing in index funds, pointing out that individual stocks are more volatile than index funds, and cited the stock price fluctuations of NVIDIA and Tesla as examples to illustrate that index funds can avoid affecting the mentality due to large rises and falls in individual stocks.</li>
<li><strong>Value of Long-Term Investment:</strong> Shared a case of a student who started investing in index funds in 2020 and earned eight figures by 2024, emphasizing the huge returns of long-term investment, which is better than short-term operations.</li>
<li><strong>Avoid Sub-Entrustment:</strong> Reminded to avoid investing through sub-entrustment to avoid increasing the complexity of tax filing due to excessive profits.</li>
<li><strong>Investment Philosophy and Market Cognition:</strong> Shared the transformation of a student from initial unfamiliarity with the market to ultimately understanding the concept of long-term investment, emphasizing that the highest realm of investment is to not pay attention to short-term returns, focus on long-term value, and achieve a selfless investment state.</li>
<li><strong>No Selling Principle:</strong> Emphasized the strategy of using stock pledges to borrow money to live on, the core of which is not to sell assets to achieve sustainable wealth. Criticized the idea of needing to sell assets for profit as short-sighted and a lack of financial knowledge.</li>
<li><strong>Channel Purpose:</strong> Re-emphasized that the goal of the CLEC channel is to help everyone achieve financial peace of mind and improve the quality of life.</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">III. Q&amp;A Session 
    <div id="iii-qa-session" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii-qa-session" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Haoqing 
    <div id="haoqing" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#haoqing" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Share 1: Shared the evolution of the tax system in the United States and views on the current government&rsquo;s tax cut policy.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s comment: Future tax reforms will not be retroactive, and existing Traditional IRAs will still be taxed. Even if the Trump administration does succeed in implementing large-scale tax cuts, tariff revenues will not be able to fully compensate for the reduction in individual income taxes.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 1: The impact of the new U.S. government&rsquo;s tax cut policy on investment?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s reply: The world will not achieve a perfect tax-free state. Even if income tax is eliminated in the future, traditional retirement accounts (Traditional IRA) will still be taxed because the government needs alternative tax sources. Alternative tax sources such as tariffs may only be a transfer of the form of taxation, and the final tax burden may be comparable. The current retirement account investment strategy should not be adjusted based on future uncertain tax changes, but should be carried out according to the established plan. Even if there are adjustments in the future, there will be corresponding alternatives, so there is no need to worry too much. Don&rsquo;t bet on something that may not happen in the future.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2: Views on the U.S. health insurance system and the impact of future tax systems and AI development on investment strategies?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s reply: The U.S. health insurance system does have shortcomings, such as rejection of claims and delays, but health is very important and should not be sacrificed for the sake of saving money. Encourage everyone to have the ability to distinguish between minor and serious illnesses, and not to turn minor illnesses into major illnesses. Minor illnesses and pains can be observed on your own, but you must have the knowledge to judge major illnesses, and you must go to the hospital when necessary, and you cannot sacrifice your life in order to save money. Rich people can not rely on insurance and cover medical expenses through wealth. In the future, even if AI develops and the tax system changes, it will not have much impact on the current retirement account investment strategy, so there is no need to worry too much. Encourage looking at government taxation from a business perspective and understanding the logic of increasing revenue and reducing expenditure. If a zero tax rate is really implemented, then consider how the government can increase revenue, such as selling gold card immigration.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Summer 
    <div id="summer" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#summer" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question 1: A non-U.S. resident (NR) in mainland China, holding a U.S. dollar account, has purchased QQQM and QLD. Considering the risk of estate tax, wants to switch to EQQQ issued in Europe. Inquired about the reasons for the price difference between European and American market ETFs and suggestions for operation?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s reply: It is strongly not recommended to open an account with a brokerage firm outside the United States because there is a risk of estate tax. It is recommended to close the U.S. account as soon as possible and consider opening an account with a Hong Kong brokerage firm to purchase NASDAQ index funds listed in Hong Kong, such as 7261 (double leverage), 7266 (Southern NASDAQ). Emphasized that it is also feasible to purchase U.S. dollar-denominated funds in Hong Kong. You shouldn&rsquo;t care about the U.S. situation.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2: Regarding the understanding of whether holding non-U.S.-issued ETFs in a U.S. brokerage account can avoid estate tax?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s reply: Estate tax is related to where the brokerage account is located, not where the ETF is issued. As long as you open an account with a U.S. brokerage firm and fill out the W-8BEN form, you are subject to U.S. estate tax. Even if you purchase ETFs issued outside the United States, you still need to pay estate tax. U.S. tax residents have estate tax, and if they need to fill out a W-8BEN, they have to pay estate tax. It is recommended to consult IBKR to confirm specific tax issues, or consider brokers in other regions such as Phillip Securities in Singapore to avoid U.S. estate tax.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Brian 
    <div id="brian" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#brian" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Share 1: Shared that he has been under a lot of work pressure recently and feels slightly depressed, but feels comforted when spending time with his children, and said that CLEC content has been helpful to him.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s comment: Recommended watching videos related to Adlerian purpose theory, the focus should not only be on work, but should be shifted, work is not everything in life. Money will not bring happiness, it can only reduce worries and increase choices. The meaning of life lies in love and being loved, and success lies in how many people remember and love you after you pass away. Emphasized finding comfort in Lao Zhuang philosophy. It is common to run into walls at work, the important thing is to shift your focus away.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Sophia 
    <div id="sophia" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#sophia" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question 1: Retired, using an 80/20 allocation, QQQ holdings are less than 80%, some funds are in cash, considering converting some QQQ to QLD for long-term holding, is it feasible? Some of the money wants to be left to her grandchildren.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s reply: It is not recommended to transfer funds from a retirement account to QLD. QLD still needs to be converted back to QQQ in the end, which is suitable for young people or children&rsquo;s accounts with a long-term tax-free period. If your child is 5 years old, and has a hundred or two dollars, it is no problem to buy QLD. For retirement accounts, just maintain an 80/20 allocation, and don&rsquo;t pursue high risk. Emphasized that you must calculate clearly whether you can file your own taxes at age 18, and that children have $50,000 of long-term tax-free funds. For the money that is to be left to grandchildren, if the funds have reached more than 55 times the annual expenditure, the excess part can be considered to set up a custodial account for the grandchildren, and donate a certain amount each year, which can avoid estate tax and allow the grandchildren to get in touch with investment and financial management as early as possible. The key is that you must first be financially free.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Shufen 
    <div id="shufen" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#shufen" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Share 1: Shared the comparison between her mother&rsquo;s hospitalization experience in Taiwan and her friend&rsquo;s father&rsquo;s experience in a nursing home in the United States, reflecting on Taiwan&rsquo;s national health insurance and the U.S. (pension system/care system), hesitant about where to spend the future, and not knowing where home is.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s comment: The United States has a safety net of social security systems such as Medicare and Medicaid, which provide basic medical and pension security for low-income people, and the country will support those over 65 who have no money. Nursing home services in the United States are luxurious but expensive, while Taiwan&rsquo;s national health insurance benefits are good but may not be luxurious. The choice of where to spend your time should take into account personal financial status, comfort of life, and relationships with relatives and friends. If you don&rsquo;t have money, you can get Medicare. Emphasized that the meaning of life lies in connection, and encouraged young people to have children as early as possible to establish family connections. Wherever the children are, that is where the home is, and you should have children as soon as possible. Emphasized the importance of connections in old age, and encouraged having children even if you are not married.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">IAM 
    <div id="iam" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iam" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question 1: Regarding wealth awakening, early earning goals are easy to achieve, but larger wealth goals create doubt, how to understand this change in mentality?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s reply: After the early material desires are satisfied, a sense of emptiness will follow, and the happiness brought by material consumption is short-lived, and you should turn to spiritual consumption. The real happiness lies in having the ability to buy but choosing not to buy, and using money to improve your spiritual life, such as family gatherings, travel, etc. Material things should be reduced as much as possible. Wealth accumulation should look to the future and see the potential of long-term compounding. For example, the current 7 million assets may grow to hundreds of millions under long-term investment. You should not look at 7 million, but at 300 million. You see the present, he sees the future.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Jimmy 
    <div id="jimmy" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#jimmy" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Share 1: Supplemented the view on (jingjie tisheng - elevation of one&rsquo;s spiritual state), citing Zhuangzi philosophy, emphasizing the importance of mind state, and how to improve cognitive (jingjie - realm/state) through practice. Emphasized the Tao Te Ching, and the view of all things in the world.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s comment: Knowledge itself is simple, but it is not easy to improve cognitive (jingjie - realm/state). Practice is the key to improving (jingjie - realm/state), and encouraged everyone to try operations such as stock pledging, so that they can truly understand after experiencing it personally.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">IV. Highlighted Quotes 
    <div id="iv-highlighted-quotes" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv-highlighted-quotes" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>The market situation has nothing to do with us anymore.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>This view emphasizes that personal investment decisions should be independent of external market noise and focus on the execution of long-term investment strategies.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Investing in the United States is absolutely correct.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>Reiterated confidence in the U.S. economy and market, encouraging investors to stick to investing in the United States.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Investing in index funds is so simple, just buy them and don&rsquo;t pay attention to them.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>Emphasized simplifying the investment process, holding index funds for the long term, and reducing unnecessary market attention and operations.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The highest realm of investment is the view of no reward.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>Pointed out that true investment should transcend the obsession with short-term returns and focus on long-term value and asset accumulation.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Borrowing money and never selling, borrowing money to live on will never run out.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>Summarized the core idea of the stock pledging strategy, emphasizing the sustainability of assets and the liquidity of funds.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Money really won&rsquo;t bring you happiness, remember this thing forever, don&rsquo;t say that if I have money, I have everything, no, having money just eliminates a lot of worries or troubles, or adds more choices.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>Emphasized the limitations of money, true happiness comes from the spiritual level and interpersonal relationships, not material wealth itself.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>We can&rsquo;t please everyone, nor do we need to, but we shouldn&rsquo;t become someone who is annoying.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>Provided a guideline for interpersonal communication, not to deliberately please, but to avoid becoming an obnoxious person.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>What is (wu - enlightenment)? It&rsquo;s no past, no future.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>Explained the realm of &ldquo; (wu - enlightenment)&rdquo;, emphasizing the importance of living in the present and reducing worries about the past and future.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The world exists only in our hearts.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>Emphasized the importance of subjective consciousness, the impact of external things on individuals depends on inner cognition and attitude.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>People are selfish, I am here today to talk to you a lot, you think you have benefited, in fact I am selfish, I am satisfying my sense of accomplishment.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>Frankly shared the motivation for personal behavior, emphasizing that altruistic behavior also includes selfish elements, and encouraging treating yourself well.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">V. Summary 
    <div id="v-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#v-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This episode of the CLEC Investment and Financial Management Channel once again conveyed the core concepts of easy investing and long-term holding. James explained the index fund investment strategy in a simple and understandable way, and combined practical cases and philosophies of life to answer the questions of students in investment and life. He emphasized that investors should stick to long-term investment and not be shaken by short-term market fluctuations. At the same time, they should also pay attention to the spiritual level in life and pursue both financial and spiritual freedom. Through this exchange, students not only gained knowledge of investment and financial management, but also had a deeper understanding of the true meaning of life value and happiness.</p>

  



<div
  
    class="flex px-4 py-3 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900"
  >

  <span
    
      class="text-primary-400 ltr:pr-3 rtl:pl-3 flex items-center"
    >

    

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M506.3 417l-213.3-364c-16.33-28-57.54-28-73.98 0l-213.2 364C-10.59 444.9 9.849 480 42.74 480h426.6C502.1 480 522.6 445 506.3 417zM232 168c0-13.25 10.75-24 24-24S280 154.8 280 168v128c0 13.25-10.75 24-23.1 24S232 309.3 232 296V168zM256 416c-17.36 0-31.44-14.08-31.44-31.44c0-17.36 14.07-31.44 31.44-31.44s31.44 14.08 31.44 31.44C287.4 401.9 273.4 416 256 416z"/></svg>

  </span>


  </span>

  <span
    
      class="dark:text-neutral-300"
    ><strong>Disclaimer:</strong> This article is for personal study notes only and does not constitute any investment advice.</span>
</div>

]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Personal Investment Bible: Investment Iron Law </title>
      <link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1731056005968/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1731056005968/</guid>
      <description>This article explores common misconceptions in investment and financial management, particularly the reliance on forecasting and technical analysis. The author argues that technical analysis cannot consistently help investors achieve excess returns and instead often leads to the trap of short-term trading.  The article advocates a long-term investment strategy of &amp;#39;buy any stock, buy anytime, and don&amp;#39;t sell,&amp;#39; emphasizing that the key to successful investing lies in selecting the right investment targets and holding them for the long term, rather than attempting to predict short-term market fluctuations.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[

<h2 class="relative group">Investment Iron Law : Grasping the General Market Trend 
    <div id="investment-iron-law--grasping-the-general-market-trend" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#investment-iron-law--grasping-the-general-market-trend" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>Basing investment decisions on technical analysis<br>
often indicates a lack of experience.<br>
In most cases, it won&rsquo;t make you money.</p></blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">The Blind Spots of Forecasting and Analysis 
    <div id="the-blind-spots-of-forecasting-and-analysis" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#the-blind-spots-of-forecasting-and-analysis" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>The reason many investors engage in frequent short-term trading, besides being attracted by price fluctuations, is mainly due to the so-called &ldquo;experts&rdquo; who flood the investment market with constant analysis and forecasts, providing investors with specious advice. This leads investors to frantically chase the &ldquo;buy low, sell high&rdquo; principle.  Let&rsquo;s discuss whether forecasting and analysis are truly effective. Can they genuinely help investors make a fortune?</p>
<p><strong>Is Technical Analysis Effective?</strong></p>
<p>In April 1993, the Taiwan <em>Economic Daily</em> published an article titled, &ldquo;Success in Stocks Depends on Entry and Exit Timing.&rdquo; This led many to believe that the most crucial task in investment analysis is determining the right moments to buy and sell.</p>
<p>The average investor believes the golden rule for wealth in the stock market is &ldquo;buy low, sell high.&rdquo;  They also believe the key to success lies in accurately grasping these timing opportunities. Consequently, countless investors try every means to predict future stock price trends to determine optimal buying and selling points.  In their quest for the Midas touch, various methods, from the scientific to the absurd, and even the supernatural, such as astrology and market horoscopes, have emerged.  Currently, the most widely used method is &ldquo;technical analysis.&rdquo;</p>
<p>In the author&rsquo;s humble opinion, technical analysis&rsquo;s popularity in the global investment market, and its continued prevalence among Taiwanese investors, stems from the fact that it appears sophisticated yet not overwhelmingly complex, thus attracting many novice investors.  These beginners often believe they must possess some secret technique to navigate the stock market, leading them to prioritize learning technical analysis upon entering the market.</p>
<p>Technical analysis originated from the Dow Theory in the 1930s, after which various technical analysis methods sprung up like mushrooms.  From the 1940s to the 1960s, technical analysis was highly popular in the US stock market.  However, with the advent of the Random Walk Theory, and the observation that most users of technical analysis ended up worse off, its popularity began to wane.  By the 1980s, when the author was studying investment analysis in the US stock market, established investment analysts rarely mentioned technical analysis.  At the time, if an investor claimed to use technical analysis for investment decisions, it implied inexperience and a high probability of losing money.</p>
<p>Technical analysis involves studying and analyzing past price trends and volume data to determine buying and selling timings. Its fundamental assumption is that history repeats itself. Therefore, by identifying the patterns of stock price movements, one can accurately predict future trends.</p>
<p><strong>Beating the Market is a Pipe Dream</strong></p>
<p>Numerous empirical studies by scholars have revealed many problems and controversies surrounding technical analysis.  Briefly summarized:</p>
<ul>
<li>
<ol>
<li>Historical patterns don&rsquo;t always repeat. Even if technical analysis has been effective for decades, it doesn&rsquo;t guarantee future success.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol start="2">
<li>If a particular technical analysis method consistently succeeds, its widespread adoption will eliminate its potential profits.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol start="3">
<li>The collective actions of technical analysts can create price patterns.  This means the price isn&rsquo;t reflecting a correct prediction but rather the analysts&rsquo; actions.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol start="4">
<li>Some technical indicators rely on comparisons with past data.  These values can change due to time and environment, making past standards inapplicable to the present.</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ul>
<p>If you were given a past stock chart and asked to devise a profitable investment strategy, everyone would understand &ldquo;buy low, sell high.&rdquo;  Profiting from trading in such a scenario would be easy.  However, investing is about the future. Future price movements are complex and unpredictable; no one possesses a future stock chart.  So, is &ldquo;buy low, sell high&rdquo; still a suitable investment strategy?  The answer is no.  The reason is simple: no one can predict market highs and lows in advance.</p>
<p>Using previously successful technical analysis methods doesn&rsquo;t guarantee future success in beating the market, as excess returns can be random.  Furthermore, concluding that technical analysis is effective based on occasional or random excess returns is misleading. While technical analysis might yield short-term gains, it cannot consistently outperform the market in the long run.</p>
<p>A student once asked me, if the market follows a random walk and technical analysis is ineffective, why are some technical analysis methods accurate at times?  Claiming technical analysis is ineffective means it can&rsquo;t generate long-term excess profits, not that its predictions are always wrong.  Technical analysis can sometimes be accurate, just like random guesses can be accurate.  Therefore, technical analysis isn&rsquo;t necessarily inaccurate; its accuracy is comparable to guessing.</p>
<p><strong>The Trap of Short-Term Trading</strong></p>
<p>Another significant drawback of technical analysis is that its methods focus on identifying buy and sell points.  These points constantly emerge, forcing investors to frequently buy and sell, trapping them in short-term trading and eroding returns through transaction costs. The ineffectiveness of technical analysis means that, on average, it doesn&rsquo;t generate excess returns over the long term. In other words, while sometimes accurate, it ultimately underperforms the market&rsquo;s average return (buy-and-hold strategy).</p>
<p>You might have used technical analysis methods with seemingly good results.  I admit some methods can be effective, but investors often overlook transaction costs.  Considering these costs, returns from technical analysis are unlikely to be high.  Furthermore, the effectiveness of any technical analysis method is inconsistent, making long-term high returns improbable.</p>
<p>Technical analysis exhausts investors, leading to significant losses.  Investors should abandon it and adopt a long-term &ldquo;buy-and-hold&rdquo; strategy to benefit from long-term market growth.  It&rsquo;s crucial to understand that market risk is inherent in any investment strategy.  Investors should be mentally prepared and avoid excessive optimism about short-term returns.  Profitable investing relies on correctly judging the overall market direction.  Obsessively seeking investment rules from past data, even if profitable, will likely incur time and effort costs exceeding the returns.</p>
<p>If you still believe technical analysis can lead to riches, ask yourself: who has become wealthy solely through technical analysis?</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Blind faith in predictions is worse than no prediction at all.
Prediction is more art than science.</p></blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">The Only Certainty is Uncertainty 
    <div id="the-only-certainty-is-uncertainty" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#the-only-certainty-is-uncertainty" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>The biggest mistake in investment strategies is overconfidence in prediction. If you&rsquo;ve tirelessly searched for prediction methods without success, or your developed methods are unreliable and unprofitable, don&rsquo;t be discouraged. All predictions face the same challenges.</p>
<p>Like you, forecasting experts cannot predict the future.  If they possessed a crystal ball, they would be wealthy, not making a living from predictions.  If this logic isn&rsquo;t convincing, ask yourself: &ldquo;Which self-made millionaire or consistently successful long-term investor has relied solely on prediction?&rdquo;  The answer is none.</p>
<p><strong>Investment Performance is Unrelated to Predictive Ability</strong></p>
<p>People often assume investment success hinges on predictive ability.  Those who predict better supposedly perform better, while investment failures are attributed to poor prediction. However, this isn&rsquo;t true. Most successful investors admit their inability to predict the future. They have no preconceived notions, and their success stems from sound strategies, not accurate predictions.</p>
<p>During my studies in the US, when I first dabbled in the US stock market, I shared the common belief that Wall Street analysts were remarkable and highly skilled at predicting market trends. After graduating from UC Berkeley in 1987, I left academia for a position at a major US brokerage firm, largely driven by the desire to learn from renowned analysts at Merrill Lynch.</p>
<p>At Merrill Lynch, I witnessed these analysts firsthand. After numerous interactions, I realized they couldn&rsquo;t accurately predict future stock prices. Some didn&rsquo;t even invest in stocks themselves. I often called analysts, asking which stocks to buy and when the market would rise. One analyst, perhaps tired of my persistent inquiries, frankly told me, &ldquo;Think about it. If I knew which stocks would rise and when the market would go up, would I be stuck working as an analyst?&rdquo;  It was then I understood that analysts don&rsquo;t possess predictive powers.</p>
<p>Upon returning to Taiwan, I observed that local newspapers and magazines were filled with &ldquo;Expert Predictions&rdquo; or &ldquo;Analyst Market Forecasts.&rdquo;  I interacted with several well-known analysts, studying their predictions carefully. My conclusion: there were no superior predictions in the Taiwan stock market.  These analysts and experts couldn&rsquo;t accurately grasp the market&rsquo;s future direction.</p>
<p><strong>Analysts Rely on Hype</strong></p>
<p>Why do so many analysts and experts constantly make predictions in the media? The reason is simple: supply follows demand. Readers crave these predictions, prompting newspapers and magazines to create dedicated columns.  Experts often publish predictions not because they possess foresight but because readers believe experts have superior knowledge of the future and eagerly seek their opinions.  Newspapers cater to this demand by soliciting expert articles.  Similarly, why do brokerage firms employ so many analysts to interpret market trends for clients? To meet customer needs.  In a competitive environment, analyst insights are considered a crucial service. Brokerage firms readily provide this service because research indicates that investors guided by experts tend towards short-term trading, generating higher commissions for the firms.</p>
<p>This demonstrates investors&rsquo; heavy reliance on expert predictions, which arise from investor demand. The problem is that the stock market is unpredictable.  No one can make accurate predictions, a widely acknowledged fact.  Yet, most investors still believe in expert forecasts.</p>
<p>A US poll once asked, &ldquo;Who lies to the public the most?&rdquo; The results: weather forecasters, stock analysts, and economic commentators.  This reveals not that expert predictions are always inaccurate but the public&rsquo;s unwavering faith in them, leading to heightened expectations.  These professions often require making future predictions under the assumption that &ldquo;experts must be able to predict; those who can&rsquo;t predict aren&rsquo;t experts.&rdquo;  This pressure compels many researchers and analysts to publish future predictions, despite the inherent uncertainty.  Being wrong is inevitable, and being perceived as liars arises from the public&rsquo;s initial belief in their predictions, leading to feelings of deception when they prove incorrect.</p>
<p>You might question this, citing instances of analysts who made remarkably accurate predictions, causing stocks to surge upon their recommendations.  However, have you noticed that these seemingly prophetic &ldquo;experts&rdquo; are rarely the same person and often disappear after a while?  In reality, these experts, unless backed by market manipulators who profit from deceiving retail investors, are simply experiencing probability at play.  Occasional streaks of accuracy are possible but not sustainable.</p>
<p><strong>Strategies to Lure Retail Investors</strong></p>
<p>Market manipulators aiming to pump and dump a stock, besides securing cooperation from major shareholders, must create a forecasting &ldquo;expert&rdquo; who, through media appearances, convinces retail investors to buy in.  As major shareholders lock up their shares and more investors join, it creates the illusion that the &ldquo;expert&rsquo;s&rdquo; predictions are coming true, causing the stock price to surge.</p>
<p>Joseph Granville was a popular technical analyst in the early 1980s.  His remarkably accurate market predictions in the late 1970s made him famous.  His large following gave him considerable market influence; his words could move the market by tens of points.  However, in early 1982, he predicted a major market crash, advising his followers to sell all their stocks.  Instead, the market surged from around 700 to over 1200 points within five months.  Those who heeded his advice missed a significant bull market, and Granville faded into obscurity.</p>
<p>I advise investors to avoid stocks being manipulated. Even if you make small profits initially, one loss could wipe out all gains and more.  Another reason: manipulated stocks involve major shareholder intervention.  These shareholders, instead of focusing on business operations and profits, are interested in quick gains through market manipulation, indicating poor management.  Such companies aren&rsquo;t worth investing in. Their scheme relies on retail investors&rsquo; money; retail investors have little chance of winning.  If retail investors could profit from this game, what would be the point for the major shareholders?</p>
<p>Another possibility for accurate predictions is simply probability.  Predictions are often diverse and contradictory, with some bullish, some bearish, and some expecting consolidation.  Inevitably, someone will be right, purely due to luck or higher guessing probability.</p>
<p><strong>More Wrong Guesses Than Right</strong></p>
<p>However, most people don&rsquo;t think this way.  When experts make several consecutive correct predictions, they gain credibility and are hailed as &ldquo;prophets.&rdquo;  People easily forget past incorrect predictions, treating the &ldquo;prophet&rsquo;s&rdquo; words as gospel.  This is extremely dangerous. Investors overlook the possibility of future incorrect predictions.</p>
<p>I&rsquo;m not entirely dismissing analysts and experts.  In the unpredictable investment world, many investors need expert guidance.  Analyst data and forecasts can be valuable reference material. My point is, regardless of your attitude towards expert predictions, remember: the future is dynamic and unpredictable.  Investment risk is an unavoidable reality and must be managed.</p>
<p>In early 1990, as the market peaked, most experts predicted continued growth. A prominent &ldquo;market prophet&rdquo; confidently proclaimed the market would reach 15,000 points within six months and 20,000 within a year.  Major media outlets reported this prediction.  The reality was starkly different.  Within six months, the market plummeted 2,000 points, shocking all experts.  Did these experts disappear?  No.  Newspapers and magazines still feature expert market forecasts.  The reason is simple: investors are &ldquo;used to&rdquo; hearing these predictions and many remain captivated by them.</p>
<p>I don&rsquo;t advocate completely ignoring predictions.  Predictions have value, and good predictions are worth considering.  However, whether you believe in predictions or not, and regardless of the predictor&rsquo;s reputation, remember: the future is fluid and unpredictable.  Investment risk is an inherent part of investing and must be managed.</p>
<p>You don&rsquo;t need predictive abilities to invest well or make money in the market. In this complex and volatile market, the only certainty is uncertainty.  In the investment world, profits come from choosing the right investments and holding them long-term, not from predicting market movements.  In summary, consider expert predictions, but remember they are just predictions.  Don&rsquo;t blindly trust them.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>There are no experts in the stock market, only winners and losers.</p></blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">Trust Yourself, Not the Experts 
    <div id="trust-yourself-not-the-experts" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#trust-yourself-not-the-experts" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>Some believe that lacking professional expertise makes achieving wealth through investment incredibly difficult. Yet, many who don&rsquo;t understand stocks or real estate still achieve financial success through investing.  Most successful investors aren&rsquo;t investment professionals, and investment professionals aren&rsquo;t necessarily successful investors.  This shows that expertise isn&rsquo;t a prerequisite for wealth creation through investment.</p>
<p>Investment and financial management aren&rsquo;t inherently complex.  The perceived complexity and reliance on experts stem from investors&rsquo; inability to cope with uncertainty, overcomplicating simple matters and turning financial management into a source of anxiety and confusion.  This anxiety hinders rational decision-making, leading people to constantly seek external opinions.</p>
<p><strong>10 Experts, 11 Opinions</strong></p>
<p>The inability to handle uncertainty creates the illusion that foresight or profound analytical skills are necessary for successful investing, leading to the belief that only &ldquo;experts&rdquo; can manage finances effectively. Consequently, many entrust their financial decisions to experts, who often offer conflicting &ldquo;expert opinions.&rdquo; Ten experts can have eleven different views, further complicating the investment world and adding to investor confusion.</p>
<p>Basing your financial decisions solely on expert opinions is extremely dangerous. Ultimately, investment responsibility lies with the individual. Investors should enhance their financial literacy and become their own experts.  Financial management doesn&rsquo;t require extensive professional knowledge. By following a few basic principles outlined in this book and acting accordingly, you can achieve wealth without relying on experts.  With the right investment philosophy, you might even outperform them.</p>
<p>Therefore, I urge investors to take immediate action, start investing, and stop asking questions like &ldquo;When will the market rise?&rdquo; &ldquo;Which stock should I buy?&rdquo; or &ldquo;Should I sell my xxx stock now?&rdquo;  These questions are pointless; no one knows the correct answers.</p>
<p>In 1983, when I began my doctoral studies at UC Berkeley, I started helping Taiwanese entrepreneurs invest in US stocks.  To excel at this, I dedicated immense effort to stock analysis, often neglecting sleep and meals. For one to two years, I practically lived in the Berkeley Haas School of Business library, devouring every investment book and analyzing all available stock information. I learned various technical, fundamental, and market analysis techniques.  To develop my unique investment analysis and prediction methods, I utilized Berkeley&rsquo;s advanced computers and extensive stock databases, writing programs to simulate various investment approaches.  This proved futile; I couldn&rsquo;t find a satisfactory method.  It was all for naught.</p>
<p>If anyone truly knew when the market would rise or which stock to buy, they would be wealthy enough not to need a job as an analyst or expert.  I reiterate: even without knowing &ldquo;when the market will rise&rdquo; or &ldquo;which stock to buy,&rdquo; you can still achieve wealth through investing.  Stop wasting time on these questions. Countless people have dedicated their lives to researching them since the inception of the stock market. They became stock experts but didn&rsquo;t achieve wealth through investing.</p>
<p><strong>Inaction and Effortless Gains</strong></p>
<p>Financial management doesn&rsquo;t require excessive time. Those who spend less time on it often perform better.</p>
<p>Statistics show that Taiwanese stock investors spend an average of 3.12 hours daily on stock analysis and market watching. Is stock picking difficult? Is making money in the stock market challenging?  Constantly chasing price fluctuations, what are your returns?  Those who diligently study stocks often lose the most money.</p>
<p>A common investor mistake is giving up.  They eagerly enter during bull markets and become disheartened during bear markets, abandoning the market entirely.  Lacking patience and perseverance, they rarely succeed.  Conversely, those with less financial acumen, admitting their inability to time the market, often persevere and ultimately fare better.</p>
<p>The path to investment wealth is simple: effortless gains. The investment strategy presented&ldquo;buy any stock, buy anytime, don&rsquo;t sell&rdquo;can be summarized as &ldquo;do nothing, gain effortlessly.&rdquo;</p>
<p>Who wouldn&rsquo;t want effortless gains? Surprisingly, most investors can&rsquo;t achieve this.  &ldquo;There&rsquo;s no such thing as a free lunch&rdquo; is a widely known principle. Applying this to investment, people assume they must master complex techniques and work harder than others to profit.  Intuitively, they believe more knowledge and effort equate to higher returns. This might hold true in other areas, but in finance, the opposite is often true. Knowledge and effort don&rsquo;t significantly contribute to investment returns.  Knowing more and constantly monitoring the market encourages impulsive trading, leading to &ldquo;effort without gain.&rdquo;</p>
<p><strong>Inaction is Superior to Action</strong></p>
<p>Even investment gurus like Warren Buffett and Peter Lynch admit they can&rsquo;t predict market movements. Admitting ignorance might seem foolish, but it&rsquo;s the beginning of financial wisdom.  Being &ldquo;foolish&rdquo; enough to &ldquo;buy any stock, buy anytime, don&rsquo;t sell&rdquo; is the starting point of wealth creation. Confucius said, &ldquo;Great wisdom appears foolish.&rdquo;  This refers to highly learned individuals who achieve mastery through natural means, without contrivance or cunning.  They appear unintelligent but are truly wise.  Lao Tzu also said, &ldquo;Great skill appears clumsy,&rdquo; and advocated for &ldquo;governing by non-interference.&rdquo;  This strategy, applied to the volatile investment environment, is a sound approach. Unless you have strong conviction about future trends, it&rsquo;s better to ignore the chaos and remain inactive.</p>
<p>Therefore, you don&rsquo;t need to be an investment expert or possess sophisticated techniques.  &ldquo;Do nothing, gain effortlessly&rdquo; is the key to financial wealth. You might think this sounds too simple, even boring.  Indeed, it is. But this simplicity is the path to riches and becoming a millionaire.  Before acting, ask yourself: &ldquo;Do I want wealth or to be a stock market expert?&rdquo;  If you want wealth through stocks, emulate the many who became rich by simply investing and then ignoring the market.  Decades later, compounding will make you wealthy. You could also dedicate yourself to becoming a stock market expert, but this rarely leads to riches.</p>
<p>My point is, even without knowing &ldquo;when the market will rise&rdquo; or &ldquo;which stock to buy,&rdquo; you can still achieve wealth through investing. Short-term market fluctuations are unpredictable, but the long-term trend is upward. Long-term investing is the key to profit.</p>
<p>&ldquo;Buy any stock, buy anytime, don&rsquo;t sell&rdquo;so simple, effortless, and seemingly undeserved.  While it feels like unearned gain, don&rsquo;t feel guilty.  Investing in stocks contributes to economic development.  Constant trading harms individual wealth and offers no benefit to the overall economy or society.</p>
<p><strong>Easier Said Than Done</strong></p>
<p>Some worry and ask, &ldquo;You advise against saving money in banks.  If your book becomes a bestseller and this idea spreads, wouldn&rsquo;t it cause a nationwide bank run?&rdquo; This is an unnecessary concern. I&rsquo;ve been advocating against saving money in banks for three years, even before this book&rsquo;s publication. Many who hear this idea nod in agreement, as if enlightened, yet days, months, or years later, their money remains untouched in bank accounts.</p>
<p>Others question whether my &ldquo;buy any stock, buy anytime, don&rsquo;t sell&rdquo; theory, if widely adopted, would force brokerage firms to close, depriving the government of transaction taxes.  Again, there&rsquo;s no need for such concerns.  Those who frequently engage in short-term trading in stocks, futures, or margin accounts, even after understanding that it only benefits intermediaries, often can&rsquo;t resist continuing their behavior.  Like gambling, everyone knows the odds are stacked against them, yet gambling persists.</p>
<p><strong>I understand that &ldquo;don&rsquo;t save money in banks,&rdquo; &ldquo;avoid short-term trading,&rdquo; and &ldquo;diversify and hold long-term,&rdquo; are simple in theory but difficult in practice.  Nevertheless, I sincerely hope readers can integrate knowledge and action, diversifying most of their assets into stocks and real estate, holding them long-term. Achieving financial freedom is within reach.</strong></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Personal Investment Bible: Investment Iron Law III</title>
      <link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1731056005962/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1731056005962/</guid>
      <description>This article explores the importance of investing and managing finances, emphasizing the principle of &amp;#39;the sooner, the better.&amp;#39; It points out that procrastination is the primary cause of financial failure and encourages young people to start managing their finances early, rather than waiting until middle or old age.  The article uses the success stories of Warren Buffett and Jeffrey Koo Jr. to illustrate the power of long-term investment and compound interest. It also emphasizes that even with limited funds, one should start managing their finances and learn how to utilize high-return investment tools to grow their wealth.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[

<h2 class="relative group">Investment Iron Law III: Invest Sooner Rather Than Later 
    <div id="investment-iron-law-iii-invest-sooner-rather-than-later" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#investment-iron-law-iii-invest-sooner-rather-than-later" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>Invest first, then wait for the opportunity,<br>
rather than waiting for the opportunity to invest.</p></blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">Procrastination: The Primary Cause of Financial Failure 
    <div id="procrastination-the-primary-cause-of-financial-failure" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#procrastination-the-primary-cause-of-financial-failure" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>The mentality of &ldquo;things will work out&rdquo; and a passive approach to financial management is the most common obstacle to personal finance. It&rsquo;s also the main reason why many people struggle to achieve financial independence by retirement.  Many individuals adopt a passive attitude towards financial planning, believing that things will naturally fall into place. As they age and witness the rapid growth of others&rsquo; wealth, they finally realize the importance of financial management.  However, by then, time is often limited, the power of compound interest cannot be fully utilized, and it becomes too late, even if they understand the principles of financial management.</p>
<p><strong>Financial Management Is Not Just for the Middle-Aged</strong></p>
<p>Many young people believe that financial management is something for middle-aged or wealthy individuals, and that it&rsquo;s not too late to worry about it in old age.  Here, I want to remind readers that the ability to build wealth through financial management has little correlation with the amount of money one possesses, but a significant correlation with the length of time invested.  People often reach middle age, facing retirement with some savings, and only then start thinking about preparing for their financial future. However, at this point, it&rsquo;s often too late. The reason is insufficient time to allow compound interest to work its magic.  Turning small amounts of money into substantial wealth requires at least two to three decades.  Recall the previous example: 10 years is not enough time to see significant growth.  A much longer period is needed for remarkable results.</p>
<p>Since we know that building wealth through investment requires investing in high-return assets and leveraging the long-term effects of compound interest, our approach, besides enriching our investment knowledge and skills, should involve immediate action.  Financial planning should start as early as possible, cultivating patience and a long-term perspective.</p>
<p>The reason for many financial failures today is the lack of knowledge about how to utilize funds effectively to achieve the goal of making money work for you and building wealth through investment. This is a flaw in our education system. Schools dedicate significant time to teaching students how to earn a living but fail to teach them how to manage their earnings.  College students exploring financial management through stock investment are often viewed as engaging in speculative and greedy behavior. In a future dominated by finance, the lack of proper financial knowledge not only erodes the dream of wealth accumulation but also harms the financial operations of businesses and the overall prosperity of society.</p>
<p>Don&rsquo;t delay your financial plan using the excuse of uncertain future price trends.  Who can predict when real estate or stock prices will rise?  Past price surges always lead to regret for those who missed out. There are no clear signs before prices start to rise, and no one will announce it with fanfare. <strong>For investments that are unpredictable in the short term but offer high expected returns in the long term, the safest strategy is to invest first and then wait for the opportunity, not the other way around.</strong></p>
<p><strong>Warren Buffett Started Investing at Age 11</strong></p>
<p><em>I believe every business school graduate should sign a contract pledging to make no more than 20 major decisions in their lifetime. If your career spans 40 years, that&rsquo;s one decision every two years.</em></p>
<p>Warren Buffett, ranked the second richest man in America by Forbes magazine in 1996, is widely regarded as the god of stock investment. He claims that more than half of his net worth is attributed to about ten investment decisions. He believes the key to investment is to buy stocks of good companies at good prices and hold them for the long term. As long as these companies continue to perform well, don&rsquo;t sell their stocks.</p>
<p>Buffett, with a net worth of $9 billion, amassed his fortune entirely from the stock market.  At 68, he held an MBA from Columbia University and was the son of a stockbroker-turned-congressman.  Buffett made his first investment at the age of 11, putting his and his sister&rsquo;s small savings into the stock market. Initially, he lost money, and his sister criticized him, but he insisted that it would take three to four years to see profits. His sister sold her shares, while he held on, ultimately proving his point.</p>
<p>At 20, while studying at Columbia University, Buffett immersed himself in finance books and insurance industry statistics while his peers focused on leisure activities.  Lacking capital and disliking borrowing, he often sold stocks prematurely to reinvest in others. Despite the limitations of his funds, his wealth continued to grow.</p>
<p>In 1954, he joined Professor Graham&rsquo;s investment firm. Two years later, he raised $100,000 from family and friends and established his own firm. After its assets increased thirtyfold, he dissolved the company in 1969, returned the partners&rsquo; money, and focused on his own investments.</p>
<p>He is a true stock market tycoon and has been America&rsquo;s richest man for years. Other wealthy Americans, like Bill Gates and Henry Lea Hillman, built their fortunes through businesses, while Buffett focused on stock investment. As long as the US economy continues to grow, his wealth will continue to increase.</p>
<p>Buffett&rsquo;s immense wealth, accumulated through nearly 60 years of investing, is a testament to the power of compound interest.  His early experiences with trial and error played a crucial role in honing his investment acumen.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Financial management is like farming.<br>
A bountiful harvest in the future depends on diligent sowing and watering today.</p></blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">Start Investing Today 
    <div id="start-investing-today" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#start-investing-today" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>If time is an indispensable element of financial management, the best strategy is to act now. Start managing your finances today!</p>
<p><strong>Don&rsquo;t Wait Until Your Hair Turns White</strong></p>
<p>The earlier you start investing, the sooner you&rsquo;ll achieve your financial goals and enjoy the fruits of your labor with your family. Furthermore, starting early maximizes the time for compound interest to work, requiring smaller initial investments and making financial management easier and more enjoyable.</p>
<p>Starting later requires significantly higher monthly investments to reach the same goals. The following table is based on these assumptions: an annual return of 15%, a target amount of 100 million yuan, and a retirement age of 65. It calculates the required monthly investment for different starting ages.</p>
<p><em>Monthly Investment Required to Become a Millionaire, by Starting Age</em></p>
<table>
  <thead>
      <tr>
          <th>Starting Age</th>
          <th>Monthly Investment (Yuan)</th>
      </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
      <tr>
          <td>20</td>
          <td>2324</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>25</td>
          <td>4684</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>30</td>
          <td>9458</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>35</td>
          <td>19863</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>40</td>
          <td>39163</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>45</td>
          <td>81348</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>50</td>
          <td>175143</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>55</td>
          <td>410428</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>60</td>
          <td>1235959</td>
      </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>
<p>The table clearly demonstrates that youth is a valuable asset in wealth accumulation. The younger you are, the better positioned you are to achieve the dream of building wealth from small investments.  Starting financial planning in old age requires monthly investments that are beyond the reach of most people. In short, start saving for retirement early. Don&rsquo;t wait until your hair turns white; time waits for no one.</p>
<p>Your future financial well-being depends on your actions today. Don&rsquo;t let hesitation hold you back. Follow the principles outlined in this book, invest your funds in the stock market, real estate, or other high-return investment vehicles, and over time, you too can become wealthy.</p>
<p><em>1. The earlier you start investing, the longer the time for compound interest to work, and the sooner you&rsquo;ll achieve your wealth goals.</em></p>
<p><em>2. Only young people can dream of building wealth from small investments.</em></p>
<p><em>3. The best time to start managing your finances is as early as possible.</em></p>
<p><strong>Jeffrey Koo Jr.&rsquo;s Path to Wealth</strong></p>
<p>Jeffrey Koo Jr., the eldest son of Jeffrey Koo Sr., chairman of Chinatrust Commercial Bank in Taiwan, and current Vice President of Chinatrust, is actively uniting the third generation of Taiwanese entrepreneurs. He organized a luncheon club primarily for the third generation of prominent Taiwanese business families to network and exchange information. To expand its influence, Koo Jr. has also strengthened the luncheon club&rsquo;s connections with Southeast Asian politicians and the second and third generations of overseas Chinese business families.</p>
<p>Koo Jr. is a representative figure among Taiwan&rsquo;s third-generation entrepreneurs and the heir apparent to his father. Many assume his wealthy background afforded him a comfortable financial situation. However, Koo Sr. instilled frugal habits in his children and didn&rsquo;t provide excessive allowances.  Koo Jr. had to find his own ways to become financially independent.</p>
<p>Sent to Japan for his education by his father, Koo Jr. returned to Taiwan for university after graduating high school with only his accumulated New Year&rsquo;s money, around NT$100,000, in his bank account. In early 1987, as the weighted stock price index climbed from 1,000 points, many people invested in the stock market. Koo Jr., then a junior in college, followed suit, investing all his savings.  His grandmother&rsquo;s daily routine of asking him to recite the stock market index further influenced him.  His frequent interactions with entrepreneurs from various industries provided him with business opportunities, enabling him to grow his NT$100,000 capital to NT$10 million during the bull market.</p>
<p>When the stock market crashed from over 10,000 points in 1990, he was already pursuing his Master&rsquo;s degree at the Wharton School of Business in the US. His father, hoping for him to join the family business sooner, disapproved of his overseas studies and threatened to withhold financial support. Koo Jr. confidently assured his father that he could support himself financially. He successfully completed his studies in the US and even bought his dream car, a Porsche, with his own money.  Koo Jr.&rsquo;s knack for investment and financial management from a young age made his dreams a reality. If you aspire to be wealthy, start now!</p>
<p><strong>Youth Is the Greatest Asset for Financial Success</strong></p>
<p>Successful people have a habit: they delay, but don&rsquo;t give up, the enjoyment of the fruits of their labor.</p>
<p>In Louis Cha&rsquo;s novel <em>The Book and the Sword</em>, the Qianlong Emperor tells his sworn brother, &ldquo;I don&rsquo;t envy anything about you except your youth.&rdquo; Even the emperor envied youth.</p>
<p>Similarly, from a financial perspective, youth is the most important asset. I often tell college students, &ldquo;Young people, your name is wealth!&rdquo;  The compound interest formula clearly shows that time is money, and youth is wealth.</p>
<p>The compound interest chart provides a clear roadmap for financial planning: focus on increasing income and saving during your youth and start investing early. Money saved during youth contributes significantly to wealth in old age.  NT$10,000 saved in your youth can grow to over NT$2.3 million in 30 years.  The same amount saved in old age will only grow to NT$60,000 in 10 years. Whether the statement &ldquo;Young people, your name is wealth&rdquo; becomes a reality depends on whether young people manage their finances wisely. Poor financial management, even with the advantage of youth, will not bring wealth.</p>
<p>The prevalent notion among young people today is that it&rsquo;s fine to indulge in enjoyment while young and worry about financial planning later. This is a misguided perspective. Many young people believe retirement is far off and their funds are limited, so there&rsquo;s no need to consider investment. They often miss the opportunity to start early.</p>
<p>In reality, starting financial planning in old age, even with some savings, is often too late due to limited time. The correct approach is: <strong>investing and managing finances is the job of young people, while managing wealth is the job of old age.</strong>  However, many young people prioritize immediate gratification, spending their money on sports cars, high-end audio systems, or travel, believing they can enjoy life now and worry about finances later.</p>
<p>If you understand the role of time in financial management, it&rsquo;s easy to see why such individuals are destined for mediocrity.  Countless examples in society demonstrate how prioritizing enjoyment in youth leads to poverty in old age. The key is their neglect of the importance of early financial planning. By the time they realize it, it&rsquo;s often too late.</p>
<p>As Taiwan&rsquo;s population ages and smaller family structures become the norm, future generations will rely on their own financial resources for living expenses. Therefore, the concept of starting financial planning in youth becomes increasingly critical.</p>
<p><strong>Youth Is the Best Time for Taking Risks</strong></p>
<p>Young people possess the most valuable asset in financial management - time. Youth is also the best time to take risks because family responsibilities are generally lighter. Young people should embrace a risk-taking mindset because the cost of failure is lower.  You can recover from setbacks more easily. Moreover, with limited funds, potential losses are smaller, providing valuable learning experiences.  Most importantly, young people have ample time for compound interest to work its magic.</p>
<p>Before 50, one shouldn&rsquo;t adopt an overly conservative approach to investment and financial management. The best time to learn about financial management is as early as possible. Sound financial judgment comes from experience, and experience comes from mistakes. Since developing good judgment requires making some mistakes along the way, why not gain this experience while you&rsquo;re young and the stakes are lower?  By the time you have more capital, you can apply your honed financial judgment effectively.</p>
<p>Young people should not just spend money but also understand the importance of saving. Start saving, and once you have a few thousand or tens of thousands of yuan, consider long-term, high-return investments, even if they carry some risk.</p>
<p>Some may feel they are no longer young and their current income is low, leaving no surplus for investment. Indeed, older individuals have less time to benefit from compound interest. However, don&rsquo;t be discouraged. Money can buy time, and you might still have opportunities to catch up.  By following sound financial principles, you can achieve unexpected gains. If you are past 50, help your children by sharing these fundamental wealth-building concepts so they don&rsquo;t miss out on the opportunity to build wealth early in their lives.  Instead of giving your next generation money, teach them the knowledge of making money work for them.</p>
<p><em>1. Youth is the greatest asset for building wealth through financial management. 2. Young people should embrace risk-taking because the cost of failure is lower.</em> <em>3. Invest when you&rsquo;re young to maximize the benefits of compound interest over time.</em></p>
<blockquote>
<p>Playing a good hand well is nothing special; playing a bad hand well is what deserves admiration.</p></blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">Don&rsquo;t Neglect Financial Management Due to Limited Funds 
    <div id="dont-neglect-financial-management-due-to-limited-funds" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#dont-neglect-financial-management-due-to-limited-funds" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>Some believe that financial management is exclusive to the wealthy and high-income families, requiring substantial capital to even consider it.  Indeed, financial management is about making money work for you. It&rsquo;s not about turning stone into gold or creating something from nothing, so you need some initial capital. However, what many don&rsquo;t realize is that the most influential factors on future wealth, according to the compound interest formula, are the rate of return and the length of the investment period, not the current amount of capital or future contributions.</p>
<p><strong>Small Beginnings Can Lead to Great Fortunes</strong></p>
<p>With the right approach, even a small amount of money can generate significant wealth over time, as illustrated in previous examples.  Even someone with no initial capital, by investing 14,000 yuan annually, can become a millionaire in 40 years.  <strong>The principle of investment and financial management is this: understanding how to utilize high-return tools and the long-term effects of compound interest is more important than the amount of money invested.</strong></p>
<p>A common misconception is that financial planning is only necessary after accumulating a large sum of money. In reality, the key factors influencing future wealth are the rate of return and the length of investment period, not the amount of capital.  The key to successful financial management lies in maximizing returns and holding investments for the long term.  While having more capital can accelerate wealth accumulation, it&rsquo;s not the decisive factor.</p>
<p>Perhaps you&rsquo;ve considered investing but dismissed the idea due to limited funds. By doing so, you&rsquo;ve missed a valuable opportunity to enhance your investment skills.  The focus of investment should not be on &ldquo;how much money is earned&rdquo; but on &ldquo;the rate of return&rdquo; at which money is earned.  For example, earning 5,000 yuan on a principal of 100,000 yuan represents a 5% return, which is a poor investment. Earning 2,000 yuan on a principal of 10,000 yuan represents a 20% return, which is a good investment.  Over time, the latter will significantly outperform the former.  Therefore, the earlier you learn financial management, the better. It allows limited funds to leverage the power of compound interest and create substantial wealth.</p>
<p><strong>Those with Less Should Strive Harder</strong></p>
<p>Some may question how to invest with only a few thousand or tens of thousands of yuan. In today&rsquo;s developed financial markets, investment units are highly divisible. Around 10,000 yuan can buy a lower-priced stock, and a few thousand yuan can be invested in mutual funds.  Real estate is also moving towards securitization. In short, there will be more investment options for smaller amounts in the future.  Therefore, any idle funds not needed in the short term, even a few thousand yuan, should be invested.</p>
<p>Are people truly too poor to manage small amounts of money?  During the Chang Hwa Credit Cooperative bank run, many ordinary people withdrew hundreds of thousands of yuan.  Statistics also show that the average bank deposit is 600,000 yuan, which is more than enough for investment purposes.</p>
<p>Even those with no current savings or expecting limited future income shouldn&rsquo;t underestimate themselves and give up on financial planning. While wealthy or high-income individuals have a head start, those with fewer assets or lower incomes should understand the principles of financial management and leverage it to compensate for their financial disadvantages, ultimately improving their lifetime financial situation.</p>
<p>Moreover, individuals from humble beginnings and with modest incomes can achieve a greater sense of accomplishment by building wealth through diligent financial management.  As the saying goes, &ldquo;<strong>There&rsquo;s nothing remarkable about playing a good hand well; it&rsquo;s playing a bad hand well that deserves admiration.</strong>&rdquo; If you truly have no money, find ways to increase income and reduce expenses, save some money, and then start managing your finances. Remember, even a small amount of money is enough to begin. While the path to wealth may be longer and more challenging with limited initial funds, the goal is still achievable, and the journey itself is valuable.</p>
<p><em>1. Investment and financial management are not exclusive to the wealthy or high-income earners.</em></p>
<p><em>2. Those with limited assets or low incomes should leverage financial management to catch up.</em></p>
<p><em>3. The amount of money you have when you start doesn&rsquo;t matter. Less money might even be better, allowing you to experiment with smaller investments initially and gradually increase your investment as you become more comfortable with risk.</em></p>
<p><em>4. Leverage other people&rsquo;s money to accelerate wealth building.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
