<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Risk Management on QQQ Investor</title>
    <link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/tags/risk-management/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Risk Management on QQQ Investor</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 19 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jomonylw.github.io/en/tags/risk-management/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Most Important Thing：Book Notes</title>
      <link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1729341470274/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1729341470274/</guid>
      <description>This book, by renowned investor Howard Marks, summarizes his investment experience, explaining his investment philosophy and analyzing key factors such as market environment, investor psychology, and risk control, aiming to help investors achieve above-market investment performance.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[

<h2 class="relative group">I. Summary 
    <div id="i-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>The core idea of this book is how to achieve investment returns that surpass the market average. The author argues that achieving this goal requires &ldquo;second-level thinking,&rdquo; which is deeper and more comprehensive than the thinking of ordinary investors. He emphasizes contrarian investing, being greedy when others are fearful, and fearful when others are greedy. The book elaborates on important concepts such as market efficiency, value assessment, risk identification and control, cyclical and pendulum awareness, investor psychology, and diversified investment. It also provides a wealth of practical experience and case studies, aiming to help investors establish a sound thinking framework and control the impact of emotions on investment decisions.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">II. Chapter Summaries 
    <div id="ii-chapter-summaries" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii-chapter-summaries" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<ol>
<li>
<p><strong>Second-Level Thinking:</strong> To outperform the market, one must engage in second-level thinking, which requires investors to think more deeply and comprehensively, not being satisfied with simple conclusions, but considering various possibilities, probabilities, market consensus, and their own cognitive biases. For example, first-level thinking might conclude, &ldquo;This is a good company, so I should buy it,&rdquo; while second-level thinking would consider, &ldquo;While it&rsquo;s a good company, has the market already overreacted, pushing the price too high?&rdquo;</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Understanding Market Efficiency and Its Limitations:</strong> Markets are not perfectly efficient; there are opportunities for mispricing. However, due to the large number of investors competing, beating the market remains very difficult. Markets are efficient at incorporating information, but they don&rsquo;t always interpret that information correctly. Investors should focus on relatively inefficient markets, such as those that are less followed, have opaque information, or are controversial.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Value Assessment:</strong> The foundation of value investing is accurate estimation of intrinsic value, which requires considering factors such as a company&rsquo;s financial position, management capabilities, profitability, competitive advantages, and future growth prospects. The author emphasizes that value investing focuses more on present value, while growth investing emphasizes future value, but both require considering the future.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>The Relationship Between Price and Value:</strong> Successful investing is not about &ldquo;buying good things,&rdquo; but about &ldquo;buying things well,&rdquo; which means buying at a price below intrinsic value. Price is influenced by value, psychology, and technical factors. Investors need to understand the relationship between these three to make sound investment decisions. Buying a good company at a high price can still lead to losses, while buying a lower-quality asset at a low price can yield high returns.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Understanding Risk:</strong> Risk is not volatility, but the possibility of permanent loss of capital. It&rsquo;s crucial to understand the various forms of risk, such as failing to meet objectives, underperformance, career risk, and liquidity risk. Risk is subjective and difficult to quantify, depending on the investor&rsquo;s specific circumstances and goals.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Recognizing Risk:</strong> Risk often increases when market optimism is high and prices are inflated. Be wary of the &ldquo;no risk&rdquo; narrative and recognize signs of an overheated market, such as high P/E ratios, narrow credit spreads, and loose credit conditions.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Controlling Risk:</strong> Risk control is more important than taking risks. Control risk through diversification, limiting risk exposure, adhering to a margin of safety, and avoiding excessive leverage. The results of risk control are often invisible because they manifest in losses avoided.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Focusing on Cycles:</strong> Everything is cyclical. Recognize the inevitability of cyclical fluctuations and look for opportunities at cyclical extremes. The author uses the credit cycle as an example to illustrate how cycles are self-correcting and how investors can find opportunities within them.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Pendulum Awareness:</strong> Investor psychology swings like a pendulum between optimism and pessimism, greed and fear. Recognize the patterns of this swing and act contrarianly at extremes. Market extremes often represent turning points and opportunities.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Resisting Negative Influences:</strong> Resist the influence of negative emotions such as greed, fear, herd mentality, envy, and ego on investment decisions. Recognizing the existence of these psychological factors and striving to overcome them is crucial for making rational investment decisions.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Contrarian Investing:</strong> Be greedy when others are fearful, and fearful when others are greedy. Contrarian investing is not simply doing the opposite of the crowd; it requires independent thinking and judgment, as well as a deep understanding of value. Contrarian investing can be lonely and unsettling but is key to achieving superior returns.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Finding Bargains:</strong> Bargains often appear in unpopular and unfavored assets, such as those with apparent flaws, misunderstood by the market, or overlooked.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Waiting Patiently for Opportunities:</strong> Don&rsquo;t chase opportunities; wait patiently for them to come to you. Investors should be like baseball hitters, waiting for the perfect pitch instead of swinging blindly.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Recognizing the Limitations of Forecasting:</strong> Predicting the future is very difficult. Recognize the limitations of forecasting and focus on knowable factors, such as company fundamentals and industry trends.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Understanding Your Position in the Cycle:</strong> Understand your position within the market cycle and adjust your investment strategy accordingly. Investors can assess market conditions by observing investor behavior, the credit environment, and valuation levels.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Appreciating the Role of Luck:</strong> Investment outcomes are influenced by luck. Distinguish between skill and luck, and avoid being blinded by short-term success. Investors should focus on long-term performance and analyze the sources of returns, rather than just focusing on short-term gains.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Diversification:</strong> Diversification is an important risk management tool, but understand correlations and avoid ineffective diversification. True diversification means holding assets that behave differently under different market conditions.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Avoiding Mistakes:</strong> Avoiding major mistakes is more important than pursuing great success. Identify and avoid various types of errors, such as analytical errors, psychological errors, and failure to recognize cycles and market sentiment.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>The Significance of Value Creation:</strong> Value creation requires superior investment skill. Understand alpha and beta, and strive for asymmetric investment performance, meaning achieving higher returns when the market rises and suffering fewer losses when the market falls.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Reasonable Expectations:</strong> Set reasonable return expectations and avoid being misled by unrealistic expectations. Excessively high return expectations are often accompanied by excessive risk. Understand how returns are generated and the conditions required to achieve objectives.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>The Most Important Thing:</strong> Summarizes the core ideas of the book, emphasizing the importance of value assessment, risk control, contrarian investing, and psychological factors. Successful investing requires comprehensive consideration of these factors and the development of a complete investment framework.</p>
</li>
</ol>


<h2 class="relative group">III. Key Takeaways 
    <div id="iii-key-takeaways" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii-key-takeaways" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;There&rsquo;s a certain irony in the investing world: What&rsquo;s obvious to everyone else is likely to be wrong.&rdquo;</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Insight:  Consensus views often lead to average results, at best.  Superior returns require non-consensus views that prove to be correct.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;Remember, your goal in investing isn&rsquo;t to earn average returns; you want to do better than average.&rdquo;</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Insight:  Complacency is the enemy of superior performance.  Strive to exceed benchmarks, not simply match them.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;The widespread belief that there&rsquo;s no risk is the biggest risk of all.&rdquo;</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Insight:  When markets are universally optimistic, risk is often at its highest because prices don&rsquo;t reflect potential problems.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;Only when the tide goes out do you discover who&rsquo;s been swimming naked.&rdquo;</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Insight: Adverse market conditions reveal the weaknesses in portfolios and investment strategies that were hidden during favorable periods.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;It takes greatest courage, but provides the greatest profit, to buy when others are despondently selling and to sell when others are greedily buying.&rdquo;</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Insight: Contrarian investing is difficult because it requires going against the crowd, but it offers the potential for the highest rewards.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;One of the great things about investing is that you don&rsquo;t have to make a lot of good decisions to do well. What&rsquo;s essential is avoiding bad decisions.&rdquo;</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Insight:  Preserving capital is paramount.  Avoiding significant losses has a greater impact on long-term returns than occasional big wins.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;An investor needs do very few things right as long as he avoids big mistakes.&rdquo;</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Insight:  Risk management and capital preservation are the cornerstones of successful investing.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">IV. Practical Application 
    <div id="iv-practical-application" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv-practical-application" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This book provides a comprehensive investment framework to help investors:</p>
<ol>
<li><strong>Establish a sound investment philosophy:</strong> Emphasizes the importance of value investing, contrarian investing, and risk control.</li>
<li><strong>Improve investment skills:</strong> Learn how to assess value, identify risks, control emotions, and construct portfolios.</li>
<li><strong>Cultivate a healthy investment mindset:</strong> Remain rational, objective, patient, and think independently, avoiding being swayed by market sentiment.</li>
<li><strong>Achieve better investment performance:</strong> By applying the methods and techniques discussed in the book, improve the quality of investment decisions and ultimately achieve above-market returns.</li>
</ol>

  



<div
  
    class="flex px-4 py-3 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900"
  >

  <span
    
      class="text-primary-400 ltr:pr-3 rtl:pl-3 flex items-center"
    >

    

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 640 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M172.5 131.1C228.1 75.51 320.5 75.51 376.1 131.1C426.1 181.1 433.5 260.8 392.4 318.3L391.3 319.9C381 334.2 361 337.6 346.7 327.3C332.3 317 328.9 297 339.2 282.7L340.3 281.1C363.2 249 359.6 205.1 331.7 177.2C300.3 145.8 249.2 145.8 217.7 177.2L105.5 289.5C73.99 320.1 73.99 372 105.5 403.5C133.3 431.4 177.3 435 209.3 412.1L210.9 410.1C225.3 400.7 245.3 404 255.5 418.4C265.8 432.8 262.5 452.8 248.1 463.1L246.5 464.2C188.1 505.3 110.2 498.7 60.21 448.8C3.741 392.3 3.741 300.7 60.21 244.3L172.5 131.1zM467.5 380C411 436.5 319.5 436.5 263 380C213 330 206.5 251.2 247.6 193.7L248.7 192.1C258.1 177.8 278.1 174.4 293.3 184.7C307.7 194.1 311.1 214.1 300.8 229.3L299.7 230.9C276.8 262.1 280.4 306.9 308.3 334.8C339.7 366.2 390.8 366.2 422.3 334.8L534.5 222.5C566 191 566 139.1 534.5 108.5C506.7 80.63 462.7 76.99 430.7 99.9L429.1 101C414.7 111.3 394.7 107.1 384.5 93.58C374.2 79.2 377.5 59.21 391.9 48.94L393.5 47.82C451 6.731 529.8 13.25 579.8 63.24C636.3 119.7 636.3 211.3 579.8 267.7L467.5 380z"/></svg>

  </span>


  </span>

  <span
    
      class="dark:text-neutral-300"
    ><strong>Related Reading:</strong>  Howard Marks&rsquo; investment memos: <a href="https://www.oaktreecapital.com/insights/memos" target="_blank"><strong>Archived Memos</strong></a></span>
</div>

<hr>

<section class="space-y-10 w-full">
    
    
</section>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>00487 The Truth About Investing：Maximizing the Probability of Success, Not Returns; How to Navigate Market Volatility：Strategies to Avoid Interrupting Compound Growth</title>
      <link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1728777529388/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1728777529388/</guid>
      <description>James announces the discontinuation of short video updates, with content to be condensed into a Saturday briefing format. This session emphasizes the importance of risk control and how to maximize the success probability of an investment portfolio. James addresses audience questions on stock pledging, asset allocation, individual stock investments, and reiterates warnings about pump-and-dump schemes and scams. He also shares insights on market volatility, A-share market fluctuations, and investment psychology.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<lite-youtube videoid="ThLEX-IsszE" playlabel="ThLEX-IsszE" params=""></lite-youtube>



<h2 class="relative group">I. Main Topic 
    <div id="i-main-topic" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-main-topic" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>The most important thing in investing is <strong>maximizing the probability of success</strong>, not maximizing returns. Investors should <strong>control risks</strong>, <strong>avoid being forced to interrupt compounding due to market fluctuations</strong>, and choose investment portfolios that can be <strong>held for the long term</strong>. James emphasizes the importance of asset allocation, especially the role of cash, and the need to choose appropriate investment strategies based on different individuals (retired/not retired, different asset sizes).</p>


<h2 class="relative group">II. Briefing Content 
    <div id="ii-briefing-content" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii-briefing-content" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<ol>
<li><strong>The Most Important Thing in Investing:</strong>
<ul>
<li>The goal of investing is to maximize the probability of success, not to maximize the rate of return.</li>
<li>Risk management is to maximize the success of the investment portfolio and avoid interrupting compound growth due to being forced to sell because of market fluctuations.</li>
<li>Good investment assets must be able to withstand fear and panic. The best investment strategies are those that do not create fear and panic.</li>
<li>Sufficient cash is the best asset to help you sleep well and survive a sharp market decline.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Risks of Stock Pledging:</strong>
<ul>
<li>Stock pledging can easily lead to bankruptcy if asset allocation is not done properly.</li>
<li>Do not try stock pledging lightly if you do not understand the operating principles of stock pledging, otherwise, you will most likely go bankrupt.</li>
<li>Most people do not need to do stock pledging. Good asset allocation can make you rich without pledging.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Asset Allocation for Different Individuals:</strong>
<ul>
<li><strong>Individuals who are not retired and have salary income:</strong> Refer to the article &ldquo;Asset Allocation for Those Who Are Still Some Time Away from Retirement&rdquo;, with QQQ as the main investment.</li>
<li><strong>Individuals who are retired and have no income:</strong> Refer to the article &ldquo;Asset Allocation for Those Who Are Retired and Have No Income&rdquo;, and choose QQQ, SPY, or high-dividend ETFs for allocation based on asset size, and consider the withdrawal rate.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Investment and Life Philosophy:</strong>
<ul>
<li>Investing is like life. It requires continuous learning and experiencing different stages to find an investment strategy that suits you.</li>
<li>Resist temptation, avoid chasing short-term hotspots, and adhere to long-term investment.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>A-share Market Volatility:</strong>
<ul>
<li>The A-share market has recently experienced a surge and a plunge, with many investors being trapped due to chasing hotspots.</li>
<li>Market fluctuations are normal, especially in emerging markets. Investors need to be rational and adhere to long-term investment strategies.</li>
<li>The Chinese government&rsquo;s cooling measures are aimed at preventing further expansion of the bubble and protecting the interests of investors.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Beware of Pump and Dump Schemes:</strong>
<ul>
<li>Some online groups and &ldquo;teachers&rdquo; use market forecasts and insider information to induce investors to make trades and profit from them. Be wary of these pump and dump schemes.</li>
<li>The futures market, due to its smaller scale, is more susceptible to manipulation. Be wary of pump and dump schemes in the futures market as well.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>CLEC Investment and Financial Management Channel Update Plan:</strong>
<ul>
<li>Due to the time-consuming nature of producing short videos and the low viewership, we plan to stop updating short videos.</li>
<li>The content of the produced short videos will be condensed into a briefing format and shared with you on Saturdays for discussion.</li>
<li>It is recommended that you listen to long videos several times or listen to them in segments to achieve the same learning effect.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ol>


<h2 class="relative group">III. Q&amp;A Session 
    <div id="iii-qa-session" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii-qa-session" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p><strong>Ethan:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing:</strong> In China, a similar effect to stock pledging can be achieved through the margin financing function of securities firms.</li>
<li><strong>Sharing:</strong> The A-share market has recently experienced drastic fluctuations, and many investors have been influenced by the media to chase hotspots, resulting in heavy losses.</li>
<li><strong>Viewpoint:</strong> If you don&rsquo;t have the right understanding of the stock market, you are the victim.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Jackie:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing:</strong>  Her personal journey of investing in the Nasdaq, from skepticism to firm holding, and finally overcoming psychological barriers to achieve &ldquo;buy whenever you have money&rdquo;.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>H:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing:</strong>  Followed recommendations for meme stocks in 2021, resulting in heavy losses. Started gradually transferring funds to QQQ in 2023 and using leverage.</li>
<li><strong>Question:</strong>  The current proportions of QQQ, QLD, and SGOV have deviated from the initial 70%, 20%, and 10%. Is rebalancing needed? How should it be rebalanced?</li>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Reply:</strong>  It is recommended to adopt a smart rebalancing strategy. Transfer 30% of the QLD profits to SGOV. When the market falls, transfer 2% of the total assets in cash to QLD.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Im:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing:</strong>  Uses the mural story of Journey to the West as an analogy for the different stages of investment, reminding investors not to chase short-term gains and to adhere to long-term investment and continuous learning.</li>
<li><strong>Question:</strong>  How to persuade people who spend extravagantly to develop the habit of saving?</li>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Reply:</strong>  You can introduce them to the concept of long-term investment in index funds and the power of compound growth. Provide help within your means.</li>
<li><strong>Question:</strong>  If you also have the habit of spending extravagantly, how do you control it?</li>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Reply:</strong>  Live within your means. As your wealth grows, it is normal for your living standards to gradually improve within the scope of risk control, but avoid excessive consumption and spending beyond your means.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Sunny:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing:</strong>  The CLEC course not only teaches investment knowledge but also conveys life philosophy, helping everyone maintain a stable mindset in life and work.</li>
<li><strong>Viewpoint:</strong>  People with stable emotions are the most valuable. Investing in QQQ also brings peace of mind.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Beisen:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Background:</strong>  Assets of 70 million, monthly mortgage payment of 125,000.</li>
<li><strong>Question:</strong>  How to allocate assets to achieve early retirement?</li>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Reply:</strong>  Based on the current assets and expenses, immediate retirement is not possible. It is recommended to try the SPY asset allocation strategy, or use part of the funds to invest in high-dividend ETFs, and control the withdrawal rate.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Kevin:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Question:</strong>  Why has Tesla fallen so much?</li>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Reply:</strong>  Investing in individual stocks requires understanding the company better than the CEO to grasp the ups and downs of the stock price. If you don&rsquo;t understand Tesla&rsquo;s business model, you shouldn&rsquo;t invest in it.</li>
<li><strong>Question:</strong>  If you are very confident in Tesla, can you hold it for the long term?</li>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Reply:</strong>  If you truly understand and are optimistic about Tesla, you can hold it for the long term, but you must manage risks well.</li>
<li><strong>Question:</strong>  Does the teacher think the stock market will fall to zero?</li>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Reply:</strong>  &ldquo;Falling to zero&rdquo; is a figure of speech, which means that even if the stock does not completely fall to zero, it will not be able to be realized if it falls to a certain level, and cash is needed to maintain life.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Ming:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing:</strong>  I have invested in individual stocks before, and they all ended up going to zero in the end, so now I want to learn how to invest in index ETFs.</li>
<li><strong>Background:</strong>  Total assets of 3.3 million, of which 2 million are in a brokerage account, 300,000 are in a Roth account, and 1 million are in a traditional IRA account.  About to retire.</li>
<li><strong>Question:</strong>  How to allocate cash and index ETFs?</li>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Reply:</strong>  It is recommended to fully invest the brokerage account in SPY, the Roth account in TQQQ, and 60% of the traditional IRA account in money market funds and 40% in SPY.</li>
<li><strong>Question:</strong>  How to withdraw funds after retirement? Do you sell even in a loss state?</li>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Reply:</strong>  After retirement, you can withdraw 3% of your total assets for living expenses. You can sell SPY or obtain funds through stock pledging loans. You have to sell even in a loss state because you need cash to maintain your life.</li>
<li><strong>Question:</strong>  Is the risk of investing in TQQQ in a Roth account too high?</li>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Reply:</strong>  It is to maintain a certain cash ratio while obtaining relatively high returns. In extreme cases, you can transfer cash from the traditional IRA to the brokerage account or sell TQQQ to supplement cash.</li>
<li><strong>Question:</strong>  How to transfer funds from a traditional IRA to a Roth account?</li>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Reply:</strong>  Transfer out a portion of the money every year and use loans or salary to pay taxes.</li>
<li><strong>Question:</strong>  Why is the borrowing interest rate 5% and the cash interest rate only 2.5% when calculating interest in SPACE?</li>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Reply:</strong>  This is just a conservative estimate. The yield of money market funds is usually lower than the borrowing interest rate.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Sara:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing:</strong>  I have been investing in QQQ for three years and recently also invested in meme stocks.</li>
<li><strong>Question:</strong>  I plan to borrow money to invest. Should I buy QLD? How should cash be allocated?</li>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Reply:</strong>  Based on Sara&rsquo;s questions, it can be seen that she does not understand the concepts of stock pledging, leveraged ETFs, and asset allocation. Borrowing money to invest is not recommended. It is recommended to continue holding the 80% QQQ + 20% cash portfolio, and cash can be invested in BOXS.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Tom:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Question:</strong>  How to maintain the cash ratio and avoid excessive tax rates in the case of long-term borrowing to live?</li>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Reply:</strong>
<ul>
<li>Leveraged ETFs and cash should be placed in retirement accounts as much as possible.</li>
<li>Borrowing from a brokerage account should not exceed 70% of the account assets.</li>
<li>Invest Roth IRA in TQQQ and hold cash in a traditional IRA.</li>
<li>In extreme cases, the cash in the traditional IRA can be transferred to the brokerage account or TQQQ can be sold to supplement cash.</li>
<li>The borrowing amount should be controlled within a certain range, for example, not exceeding 2% of the total assets per year.</li>
<li>Taxes incurred by transferring a traditional IRA to a Roth IRA can be paid with loans or salary.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question:</strong>  Why is the borrowing interest rate 5% while the cash interest rate is only calculated as 2.5% in SPACE?</li>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Reply:</strong>  This is just a conservative estimate. Money market fund yields are usually lower than borrowing rates.</li>
<li><strong>Question:</strong>  How to handle it if funds in the Brokerage account need to be used before retirement?</li>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Reply:</strong>  You can use the funds in the Brokerage account for a pledge loan, but you need sufficient cash as a guarantee.</li>
<li><strong>Question:</strong>  What if the cash in the Brokerage account is insufficient to cover the loan in the event of an extreme stock market decline?</li>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Reply:</strong>  In extreme cases, you can transfer the cash in the Roth or Traditional IRA account to the Brokerage account, but this is an emergency measure and will incur penalties.</li>
<li><strong>Question:</strong>  Is investing TQQQ in a Roth IRA too risky?</li>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Reply:</strong>  Investing Roth IRA in TQQQ is to obtain higher returns while ensuring a certain cash ratio. If you are concerned about risks, you can appropriately reduce the proportion of TQQQ and increase the proportion of money market funds.</li>
<li><strong>Question:</strong>  In the long run, will borrowing from a Brokerage account lead to paying high taxes?</li>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Reply:</strong>  Borrowing itself does not increase the tax burden, but it can avoid the tax burden caused by selling stocks. However, if you transfer funds from a Traditional IRA to a Roth IRA, it will increase your taxable income for the year and you will need to pay additional taxes.</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">IV. Highlights 
    <div id="iv-highlights" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv-highlights" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p><strong>The most important thing in investing is maximizing the probability of success, not maximizing the rate of return.</strong>
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>To achieve long-term stable returns, control risks, avoid being forced to interrupt compound growth due to market fluctuations, and choose investment portfolios that can be held for the long term.</p>
<blockquote>
<p><strong>Don&rsquo;t try stock pledging lightly if you don&rsquo;t understand it.</strong>
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Stock pledging is very risky if not done properly and can lead to bankruptcy.</p>
<blockquote>
<p><strong>Most people don&rsquo;t need to do stock pledging and can still become wealthy without it.</strong>
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Good asset allocation and long-term investment can lead to financial freedom even without stock pledging.</p>
<blockquote>
<p><strong>If you don&rsquo;t have the right understanding of the stock market, you are the victim.</strong>
&ndash; Ethan</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Learn investment knowledge, understand market rules, and avoid becoming a韭菜 (leek, a metaphor for someone easily exploited in the stock market).</p>
<blockquote>
<p><strong>Investing is like life. You need to keep learning to find an investment strategy that suits you.</strong>
&ndash; Im</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Investing is a continuous learning process. You need to constantly improve your cognitive level to succeed in the market.</p>
<blockquote>
<p><strong>People with stable emotions are the most valuable. Investing in QQQ also brings peace of mind.</strong>
&ndash; Sunny</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Investing requires rationality and avoiding emotional trading to succeed in market volatility.</p>
<blockquote>
<p><strong>Rotten apples don&rsquo;t get better, and broken elevators don&rsquo;t fix themselves.</strong>
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>If the individual stocks you hold are not performing well, cut your losses in time and switch to more potential investment targets.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">V. Summary 
    <div id="v-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#v-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This episode emphasizes the importance of risk management and asset allocation and gives specific investment advice for different groups of people. James answers the audience&rsquo;s questions about stock pledging, asset allocation, individual stock selection, market fluctuations, pump and dump schemes, etc., to help everyone better understand the concept and methods of long-term investment. At the same time, James also announced the future update plan of the CLEC Investment and Financial Management Channel, which will stop updating short videos and condense the content of the short videos into a briefing format for sharing on Saturdays.</p>

  



<div
  
    class="flex px-4 py-3 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900"
  >

  <span
    
      class="text-primary-400 ltr:pr-3 rtl:pl-3 flex items-center"
    >

    

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M506.3 417l-213.3-364c-16.33-28-57.54-28-73.98 0l-213.2 364C-10.59 444.9 9.849 480 42.74 480h426.6C502.1 480 522.6 445 506.3 417zM232 168c0-13.25 10.75-24 24-24S280 154.8 280 168v128c0 13.25-10.75 24-23.1 24S232 309.3 232 296V168zM256 416c-17.36 0-31.44-14.08-31.44-31.44c0-17.36 14.07-31.44 31.44-31.44s31.44 14.08 31.44 31.44C287.4 401.9 273.4 416 256 416z"/></svg>

  </span>


  </span>

  <span
    
      class="dark:text-neutral-300"
    ><strong>Disclaimer:</strong> This article is for personal learning notes only and does not constitute any investment advice.</span>
</div>

]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>00484 Buying at the market price immediately when you have money is the best investment strategy:a market with an unbreakable asset allocation doesn&#39;t exist</title>
      <link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1728261371758/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1728261371758/</guid>
      <description>This live session focused on long-term investment strategies, delving into investment philosophy, risk management, and values.  James shared personal experiences and insights, offering valuable guidance on understanding the nature of investing and its inherent risks, emphasizing the importance of being rational, patient, and vigilant.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<lite-youtube videoid="UGUV4GIqKVg" playlabel="UGUV4GIqKVg" params=""></lite-youtube>



<h2 class="relative group">I. Topic of the Session 
    <div id="i-topic-of-the-session" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-topic-of-the-session" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>The session centered on the core principle of long-term investment strategies. James reiterated his investment philosophy: &ldquo;Buy QQQ whenever you have money and hold it for the long term.&rdquo; The discussion expanded to cover aspects like investment philosophy, risk management, and values, incorporating current events and questions from attendees. James also shared insights from legendary investors like Warren Buffett, encouraging attendees to cultivate a sound investment mindset.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">II. Briefing Highlights 
    <div id="ii-briefing-highlights" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii-briefing-highlights" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<ol>
<li><strong>Buying at the Dip vs. Buying When You Have Money:</strong> James cited research from ChatGPT, indicating that even with the ability to accurately predict and buy at market dips, the long-term returns differed minimally compared to simply buying when one has available funds. Over a 20-year period, the difference was merely 8%, translating to a difference in annualized returns of less than 0.2%. Hence, rather than expending time and effort predicting market bottoms, it&rsquo;s more effective to seize opportunities and buy QQQ when you have the money.</li>
<li><strong>Risks of Leveraged Funds:</strong>  Using the 2000 tech bubble as an example, James explained how leveraged funds can accelerate losses in bear markets, potentially leading to devastating financial setbacks, even bankruptcy. He simulated a scenario where an investor repeatedly buys more leveraged funds as the market declines, culminating in financial ruin. This served as a cautionary tale against the &ldquo;buy the dip&rdquo; strategy with leveraged funds, emphasizing the importance of risk management.</li>
<li><strong>Keys to Investment Success:</strong> James emphasized that the key to successful investment lies in overcoming human weaknesses. Maintaining a detached and &ldquo;unfeeling&rdquo; attitude towards invested capital and short-term market fluctuations is crucial for adhering to a long-term investment approach.</li>
<li><strong>Market Cycles:</strong> James stated he wouldn&rsquo;t teach attendees about predicting market cycles or any trading techniques. He considers these unimportant and prone to misinterpretation and misapplication, potentially leading to increased risks. He advocated for a long-term investment strategy, likening it to riding a cable car, a smooth and steady ascent to the summit of financial success.</li>
<li><strong>Money and Values:</strong> Acknowledging that individuals have different values regarding money, James advised understanding and respecting diverse values, discouraging attempts to impose one&rsquo;s own values upon others. He used the example shared by an attendee about a mother preferring a financial subsidy over a family trip to illustrate the diverse ways people assign value to things.</li>
</ol>


<h2 class="relative group">III. Q&amp;A Session 
    <div id="iii-qa-session" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii-qa-session" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p><strong>IIM:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Shared:</strong> A story about a deceased friend, leading to reflections on money and values, and expressing confusion about balancing personal values with those of others.</li>
<li><strong>Question 1:</strong>  How to understand some people&rsquo;s &ldquo;frugality&rdquo; with money while being &ldquo;generous&rdquo; towards their pets.
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response:</strong> People manage their finances differently based on what they consider important and valuable. What might be significant to one person may hold little value for another.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question 2:</strong> How to understand a mother who prioritizes money over a family trip? How to better understand the needs of others?
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response:</strong>  This mother might have certain unmet needs, possibly requiring material security before pursuing leisurely experiences. Understanding true needs involves offering more choices (e.g., money plus a trip). Avoid trying to change others&rsquo; values; focus on understanding and respecting them.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Brian:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Shared:</strong> Encountering a friend who suggested leveraging to purchase Nvidia stock, leading to questions about investment advice.</li>
<li><strong>Question:</strong> How to evaluate investment advice received from others?
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response:</strong>   The validity of investment advice depends on individual judgment and risk tolerance. It&rsquo;s important to avoid blindly following the advice of others and to think independently.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Iny:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Shared:</strong>  Experiencing a sense of calm and reduced anxiety after adopting James&rsquo;s investment approach.  This newfound peace of mind allows for dedicating more time to important matters like family, and interestingly, focusing on work has led to increased income.</li>
<li><strong>Question:</strong>  How to understand the phenomenon of increased income resulting from a dedicated focus on work?
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response:</strong> This exemplifies the principle that altruism ultimately benefits oneself. By focusing on serving clients and enhancing product or service quality, one ultimately gains client recognition and rewards, leading to higher income and a sense of accomplishment.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Haoqing:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Shared 1:</strong>  An experience with check fraud, prompting concerns about bank security and the risks of using checks.
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response:</strong>  Banks do not verify the identity of check depositors. Checks present security vulnerabilities, making it advisable to use safer online banking and digital payment methods like Apple Pay.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Shared 2:</strong> Thoughts on the decline of US manufacturing and the rise of Asia, attributing this to factors like US regulations, labor laws, and unions.
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response:</strong> The decline of US manufacturing and the rise of Asia are multifaceted issues stemming from a complex interplay of factors, including national policies, labor laws, and unions. While Asian countries might resort to suppressing labor rights and environmental regulations to gain a competitive edge, the US places a higher value on worker well-being and environmental protection. This divergence in values contributes to different developmental paths.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Becky:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Shared:</strong> Based on personal experience working in a digital payment company, Becky recommended that everyone stop using checks due to inherent security risks. Digital payment methods offer greater security and convenience, with features such as spending alerts that enable prompt response and recovery in case of issues.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Mike:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Shared:</strong> As a long-time follower of James, Mike witnessed the evolution of his investment philosophy, from initially holding 30% SPY to converting to 100% QQQ, and eventually incorporating leveraged funds. He also shared personal investment experiences, like selling NIO and allocating a portion of his portfolio to private market investments.</li>
<li><strong>Question 1:</strong> Is investing in Intel after its acquisition worthwhile?
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response:</strong>  James advised against investing in large companies that are acquisitive. Acquisitions often lack efficiency, posing integration challenges and potentially hindering productivity. While acquiring smaller companies for technological advantages makes sense, acquiring large companies is akin to amassing a pile of scrap metal.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question 2:</strong>  How to view the supply chain security concerns stemming from the US outsourcing 3C product manufacturing, citing examples like the BBB Call explosion and walkie-talkie incidents?
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response:</strong> Espionage is ubiquitous, and supply chain security is just one facet of this broader issue. Governments might implant spy codes in chips and software for surveillance purposes. Explosions are a relatively rudimentary form of espionage; more sophisticated methods can be extremely difficult to detect and prevent.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question 3:</strong> Is it possible to offer advanced courses for more experienced attendees? He suggested using portfolio sharing as a means to differentiate attendees&rsquo; learning progress.
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response:</strong> James stated he wouldn&rsquo;t differentiate between attendees nor offer advanced courses. Assessing whether a student is genuinely learning is primarily based on their attitude, not investment returns or holding duration. Even portfolio sharing can&rsquo;t truly gauge learning progress. James mentioned his personal sensitivity to words and language, enabling him to discern learning attitudes from attendees&rsquo; emails and the way they pose questions.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">IV. Noteworthy Insights 
    <div id="iv-noteworthy-insights" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv-noteworthy-insights" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>The best time to buy is when you have money.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Many obsess over finding the perfect entry point, but research indicates that even if you could perfectly time market dips, the long-term returns barely differ from simply buying when funds are available. Instead of wasting time trying to predict the market, seize the opportunity and act promptly.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>To succeed in investing, you must be indifferent to the money you invest and the fluctuations in stock prices.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Overcoming the human tendency to fixate on money and fear short-term market swings is essential for maintaining a long-term investment strategy and achieving stable returns.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>To achieve effortless investing, you need to be numb to money.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>When investing becomes a habit, free from emotional impulses and external distractions, you can achieve optimal results.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The concept of a &ldquo;benefactor&rdquo; is relative.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>People perceive and absorb information differently. Who you consider a benefactor might not be perceived as such by others.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Don&rsquo;t try to change other people&rsquo;s values.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Everyone has their own values and ways of life. It&rsquo;s important to understand and respect diverse choices.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Espionage is everywhere.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Information security is a growing concern. Be vigilant and protect your personal data.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Acquisitions of large companies are generally inefficient, and leaders who are fond of acquisitions usually have inflated egos.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Integration complexities and high management costs associated with mergers often outweigh the benefits gained.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The US excels in areas such as finance and technology design, while Asian countries can only substitute and supplement in specific aspects.
&ndash; Haoqing</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Within the global division of labor, different countries have distinct strengths and weaknesses, leading to divergent paths of development.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The best judgments are validated by facts.
&ndash; Mike</p>
</blockquote>
<p>The success of an investment philosophy is ultimately determined by its long-term returns, not short-term fluctuations or gut feelings.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Your attitude determines my response.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>James adjusts his responses based on the learning attitude of the attendees. Attendees who are truly dedicated to learning will receive greater guidance.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Investing in individual stocks will ultimately lead to bankruptcy; holding onto individual stocks will also ultimately lead to bankruptcy.<br>
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Companies have lifecycles.  Holding onto a single stock long term significantly increases the risk of encountering bankruptcy. Diversification is key in investing.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">V. Summary 
    <div id="v-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#v-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This live session once again emphasized the importance of long-term investing while reminding attendees to stay rational, patient, and vigilant. James addressed attendees&rsquo; questions regarding investment strategies, risk management, and the relationship between money and values, sharing personal experiences and insights. Key takeaways include avoiding market timing, leveraged funds, and individual stock investments, and embracing an attitude of indifference towards money. Attendees actively shared their own investment experiences and reflections, prompting deeper contemplation on investment, money, life, and more. The session also delved into the philosophies of renowned investors like Warren Buffett and discussed various social phenomena, creating a rich and informative experience.</p>

  



<div
  
    class="flex px-4 py-3 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900"
  >

  <span
    
      class="text-primary-400 ltr:pr-3 rtl:pl-3 flex items-center"
    >

    

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M506.3 417l-213.3-364c-16.33-28-57.54-28-73.98 0l-213.2 364C-10.59 444.9 9.849 480 42.74 480h426.6C502.1 480 522.6 445 506.3 417zM232 168c0-13.25 10.75-24 24-24S280 154.8 280 168v128c0 13.25-10.75 24-23.1 24S232 309.3 232 296V168zM256 416c-17.36 0-31.44-14.08-31.44-31.44c0-17.36 14.07-31.44 31.44-31.44s31.44 14.08 31.44 31.44C287.4 401.9 273.4 416 256 416z"/></svg>

  </span>


  </span>

  <span
    
      class="dark:text-neutral-300"
    ><strong>Disclaimer:</strong> This transcript serves as personal learning notes only and does not constitute investment advice.</span>
</div>

]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>00479 Three Easy Examples of Getting Rich, The Power of Starting Early and Compound Interest</title>
      <link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1728391134352/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1728391134352/</guid>
      <description>In this session, James reiterates the importance of long-term index fund investing, illustrating the power of compounding interest with multiple examples. He also explains how to avoid common investment pitfalls to achieve financial freedom.  Additionally, James addresses audience questions on asset allocation, real estate investment, trusts, and children&amp;#39;s education funds.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<lite-youtube videoid="1VSo2I6xqG0" playlabel="1VSo2I6xqG0" params=""></lite-youtube>



<h2 class="relative group">I. Main Topic 
    <div id="i-main-topic" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-main-topic" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This session focuses on long-term index fund investing. The core message is: hold index funds firmly, ignore market fluctuations, maintain a proper asset allocation, and leverage the compounding effect of time to achieve financial freedom.  James also warns against investment scams and emphasizes avoiding unnecessary risks, while offering advice on investing in children&rsquo;s education funds.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">II. Presentation Summary 
    <div id="ii-presentation-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii-presentation-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<ul>
<li><strong>Advantages of Index Funds:</strong> Long-term index fund investing eliminates the need to follow short-term market fluctuations, international affairs, financial reports, and economic data.  Focus on asset allocation and consistent investment.</li>
<li><strong>The Power of Compounding:</strong> James uses several examples to illustrate the magic of compounding:  A monthly investment of 1000 TWD can grow to 17.3 million TWD in 40 years; a lump-sum investment of 100,000 TWD can reach 18.8 million TWD in 40 years;  starting early is crucial, as a 10-year delay significantly impacts final returns; one share of QQQ at 500 USD will become 25,000 USD in 30 years and 94,000 USD in 40 years.</li>
<li><strong>Safe Asset Allocation:</strong> Asset allocation is more critical than any market commentary. James recommends deleveraging and reducing debt for those nearing retirement, holding a larger cash position.  For younger individuals with stable income, leveraging can be considered. He suggests using a beta of 1.0 as a benchmark, reducing beta when the market is overheated, and increasing it back to 1.0 during market downturns.  For cash allocation, he references Buffett and suggests a sample allocation (Scenario 3): 40% index funds, 30% 2x leveraged funds, and 30% cash.</li>
<li><strong>Beware of Investment Scams:</strong>  Don&rsquo;t trust investment information from unknown accounts or websites. Choose legitimate financial institutions.</li>
<li><strong>Don&rsquo;t Give Money Directly to Children:</strong> James uses personal anecdotes and case studies to caution against putting assets directly in children&rsquo;s names, as this may discourage their initiative or cause family conflicts.  However, investing children&rsquo;s &ldquo;lucky money&rdquo; (red envelopes) for them is recommended as an educational fund.</li>
<li><strong>Risks of Real Estate Investment:</strong> James reiterates his advice against early homeownership for young people, arguing that real estate is illiquid, high-risk, and ties up capital that could be used for other investments.  He highlights the added risk in Taiwan, where mortgage debt remains even after foreclosure.</li>
<li><strong>Recommended Learning Resources:</strong> He recommends a YouTube channel called &ldquo;什么值得读&rdquo; (What&rsquo;s Worth Reading) for valuable content on value investing.</li>
<li><strong>Emergency Fund:</strong> Maintain a cash reserve equivalent to six months of living expenses in a money market fund account. Investing this emergency fund in stocks is not recommended.</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">III. Q&amp;A Session 
    <div id="iii-qa-session" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii-qa-session" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p><strong>Jeff:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Shares:  Highlights misconceptions about investing held by two listeners and emphasizes the importance of carefully studying James&rsquo;s lecture notes, particularly the chart on page two.</li>
<li>James&rsquo;s response:  Affirms Jeff&rsquo;s points and re-emphasizes the importance of a solid investment philosophy to avoid being swayed by market noise.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Cat:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Shares: A listener holding 35 million TWD in 00662 still finds the 2% withdrawal rate insufficient. Discusses the spending needs and inheritance considerations of single individuals.</li>
<li>James&rsquo;s response: Different indices have different volatility and dividend yields, requiring adjustments to withdrawal rates. For higher withdrawals, consider ETFs with higher dividend yields, such as 0056, which yields around 4-5%.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>H:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Question:  High rental costs for young people, should they buy a house?  Mortgages offer tax deductions, while renting does not.  Concerned about insufficient funds for leveraged investing.</li>
<li>James&rsquo;s response:  Recommends watching the &ldquo;30 Years of Different Destinies&rdquo; video, which analyzes the pros and cons of renting versus buying.  Young people should prioritize investing in index funds to build wealth through compounding and consider buying a house later.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Yonglin:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Question: Should money be invested in children&rsquo;s names for long-term holding?  Should a mortgage-free house be sold to invest in index funds after retirement?</li>
<li>James&rsquo;s response:  Advises against putting money directly in children&rsquo;s names.  Retirees should deleverage, and selling a mortgage-free house to invest in index funds is a viable option.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Mike:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Shares: Success story of investing his children&rsquo;s education fund in QQQ.  Gives the example of Taoyuan Language in Taiwan, suggesting potential leveraged investment through real estate mortgages.</li>
<li>Question: How to establish a family trust and manage generational wealth like the Rockefeller family?</li>
<li>James&rsquo;s response:  Recommends contacting Lisa for trust advice when assets reach a certain level and age. For now, focus on investing. Trusts can be considered around 70-80 years old. Single individuals or those without children should rely on trusts, appointing guardians and executors.  Those with children can consider Trust 2.0, with the bank as executor and children as supervisors.  Family foundations managed by professional institutions are also an option.  Recommends the Walmart family&rsquo;s living trust as a model.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Becky, Jessie, and Other Participants:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Becky: Difficulties of renting at an older age.</li>
<li>Jessie: How to balance saving for an emergency fund, paying off a mortgage, and investing simultaneously.</li>
<li>Other Participants: Questions about real estate investment, cash management, insurance, Bitcoin, and Japanese government bonds.</li>
<li>James&rsquo;s response:  Addresses each question and reiterates his investment philosophy.  For example, young people should avoid real estate and insurance due to high risks; long-term bonds and municipal bonds are not suitable for emergency funds.</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">IV. Key Takeaways 
    <div id="iv-key-takeaways" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv-key-takeaways" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>Time is the source of all power.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>James uses examples like the evolution of Earth&rsquo;s ecosystem and human evolution to illustrate the power of time and emphasize the importance of long-term investing.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Don&rsquo;t casually help others with money.  People will resent you for it for a lifetime.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Cautions against testing human nature with money and emphasizes setting boundaries with financial assistance.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The earlier you invest, the better.  Keep enough emergency funds. The earlier you invest, the lower the risk.
&ndash; Jeff</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Emphasizes the importance of early investing and maintaining an emergency fund.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Laugh a little; how long a scammer can scam is determined by the fool.
&ndash; Mike</p>
</blockquote>
<p>A cynical comment on the prevalence of scammers and a reminder to stay vigilant.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">V. Conclusion 
    <div id="v-conclusion" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#v-conclusion" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>The core message of this session remains long-term index fund investing. James uses clear language and vivid examples to reiterate the power of compounding and the importance of starting early. He also addresses audience questions on asset allocation, real estate, trusts, emergency funds, and children&rsquo;s education funds, sharing advice on avoiding common investment traps and achieving financial freedom.  He further recommends learning resources and provides commentary on social phenomena.</p>

  



<div
  
    class="flex px-4 py-3 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900"
  >

  <span
    
      class="text-primary-400 ltr:pr-3 rtl:pl-3 flex items-center"
    >

    

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M506.3 417l-213.3-364c-16.33-28-57.54-28-73.98 0l-213.2 364C-10.59 444.9 9.849 480 42.74 480h426.6C502.1 480 522.6 445 506.3 417zM232 168c0-13.25 10.75-24 24-24S280 154.8 280 168v128c0 13.25-10.75 24-23.1 24S232 309.3 232 296V168zM256 416c-17.36 0-31.44-14.08-31.44-31.44c0-17.36 14.07-31.44 31.44-31.44s31.44 14.08 31.44 31.44C287.4 401.9 273.4 416 256 416z"/></svg>

  </span>


  </span>

  <span
    
      class="dark:text-neutral-300"
    ><strong>Disclaimer:</strong> This document is for personal learning notes only and does not constitute any investment advice.</span>
</div>

]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>00477 Eternal Freedom from Worry and Stress：Wisdom and Strategies for Long-Term Investing</title>
      <link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1728565408053/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1728565408053/</guid>
      <description>In this session, James shares his investment philosophy, emphasizing the importance of independent thinking and risk management. He also answers questions from students on topics such as TQQQ, emergency funds, MAGS fund, and real estate investment.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<lite-youtube videoid="CfFEQJkTCBw" playlabel="CfFEQJkTCBw" params=""></lite-youtube>



<h2 class="relative group">I. Main Theme 
    <div id="i-main-theme" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-main-theme" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This session focuses on the philosophy of long-term investing, emphasizing the importance of independent thinking and risk management. James reiterates his long-held investment philosophy: choose the right investment target (such as QQQ), buy in early and hold for the long term, ignoring short-term market fluctuations, and ultimately achieve steady wealth growth. In addition, he discusses how to maintain a positive mindset, deal with stress and anxiety that may arise during the investment process, and how to choose a reliable brokerage to ensure account security.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">II. Briefing Content 
    <div id="ii-briefing-content" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii-briefing-content" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<ul>
<li><strong>Wealth is accumulated slowly, and enjoying the process of wealth accumulation is the meaning of life.</strong> Getting rich overnight or quickly is not the best way. Slowly accumulating wealth and enjoying it allows you to experience the true meaning of life and learn and grow from it.</li>
<li><strong>Don&rsquo;t blindly pursue high returns while ignoring risks.</strong> Many people pursue quick riches and hope for super high returns, but often overlook the risks involved, which may ultimately lead to losses outweighing gains. Learn to assess risk and choose an investment strategy that matches your risk tolerance.</li>
<li><strong>Investing requires finding a definite eternity, ignoring market noise, and maintaining inner peace.</strong> Index fund investing is a definite and eternal strategy that does not require painstaking research and operation. Simply holding for the long term can yield considerable returns.</li>
<li><strong>Investment is a loser&rsquo;s game, not seeking to win, but seeking not to lose.</strong>  In investing, avoiding mistakes is more important than pursuing victory. Index fund investing can help investors reduce mistakes and ultimately achieve victory.</li>
<li><strong>Buying in a lump sum at any time and holding for the long term is superior to other investment methods.</strong> Investing early and holding for the long term maximizes returns and delivers the best investment returns.</li>
<li><strong>Learn to distinguish between what can be done, what is effective, what can be worried about, and what is not worth worrying about.</strong> Focus your energy on important and solvable issues, ignore those that are irrelevant or beyond your control to improve efficiency and reduce unnecessary anxiety.</li>
<li><strong>Don&rsquo;t work too hard, let your money work for you.</strong> Put your money into the market and let it create wealth for you instead of devoting all your energy to work. Learn to utilize investment tools to achieve passive wealth growth.</li>
<li><strong>All pressure comes from expectations, and all worries come from not having a solution.</strong> Lower your expectations and actively seek solutions to relieve stress and anxiety.</li>
<li><strong>Learn to transfer pressure to those who can bear it and think about solutions for the worst-case scenario.</strong> Don&rsquo;t bear the pressure alone, learn to seek help, and think in advance about solutions to the worst-case scenario to calmly deal with challenges.</li>
<li><strong>Maintain inner peace, focus on the important things, and ignore the insignificant things.</strong> Stick to simple things, don&rsquo;t get involved in complex things, to maintain inner peace and focus on what really matters in life.</li>
<li><strong>Account security is the primary issue in investing. Choose a large, reputable brokerage to open an account and avoid using online brokers.</strong> Online brokers have security risks, such as account theft and asset freezing. Choosing a large, reputable brokerage can better protect your account security.</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">III. Q&amp;A Session 
    <div id="iii-qa-session" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii-qa-session" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p><strong>Dave:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing:</strong>
Shared the results of James&rsquo; TQQQ simulation backtest and raised the question of how to avoid the risk of a sharp TQQQ drawdown.</li>
<li><strong>Question and James&rsquo;s Reply:</strong>
James believes that it is impossible to predict the market and avoid all risks completely. The important thing is to control risk exposure and avoid over-betting. If you are worried about the volatility of TQQQ, you can choose a more conservative investment strategy, such as QQQ. James also reminds everyone to distinguish between personal thinking and public advice, and not to be easily swayed by the thoughts of others.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Minjianlian:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing:</strong>
Shared his experience of investing in stocks through his company&rsquo;s savings association, as well as discussions about the MAGS fund and emergency funds.</li>
<li><strong>Question and James&rsquo;s Reply:</strong>
<ol>
<li>About the MAGS fund: James believes that it is uncertain whether the MAGS fund can outperform QQQ in the long term. Investment should choose targets that have been tested by time, such as QQQ or SPY.</li>
<li>About emergency funds: James believes that emergency funds are a personal responsibility and government policies cannot be relied upon entirely. Everyone should prepare sufficient emergency funds according to their own circumstances to cope with contingencies.</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Learn:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Question and James&rsquo;s Reply:</strong>
Regarding the performance of 00670L, James explained the performance difference caused by USD hedging and how to solve it by investing in QLD through sub-brokerage. He emphasized that Beta and ROI are different concepts. Beta represents volatility, not ROI. The investment model in Taiwan needs to be adjusted according to specific circumstances, such as  maintenance margin requirements and exchange rate fluctuations.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>JJU:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing:</strong>
Shared his insights on market unpredictability and the importance of mentors and friends. He believes that investing, in addition to selecting good targets, is more about maintaining inner peace and enhancing one&rsquo;s spiritual level.</li>
<li><strong>Question and James&rsquo;s Reply:</strong>
<ol>
<li>About the difference between reinvest and buy share: James explained the difference between reinvesting and buying shares. The former automatically invests dividends or capital gains into the investment target, while the latter uses new funds to buy shares.</li>
<li>About the fund ratio of Roth IRA and Individual Brokerage Account: It is recommended to maximize the Roth IRA limit if possible.</li>
<li>About real estate mortgage investment: It is recommended to sell the property if possible to reduce the risk of investing in real estate. Otherwise, consider a Home Equity Line of Credit (HELOC) for investment, but pay attention to risk control and ensure that you can repay the loan on time. HELOC is a revolving credit line, similar to a credit card, which can be withdrawn and repaid at any time.</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Draft down:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing:</strong>
Proposed the possibility of leveraging 0% interest credit cards for investment and using the box spread strategy to increase capital utilization.</li>
<li><strong>Question and James&rsquo;s Reply:</strong>
<ol>
<li>About credit card investment: James believes that credit card limits are limited and there is a risk of not being able to renew the loan, making it unsuitable as a main source of investment funds. It is only suitable for short-term turnover of small amounts of funds.</li>
<li>About the box spread strategy: James believes that the box spread strategy is too complex and risky and is not recommended for ordinary investors.</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Jason:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Question and James&rsquo;s Reply:</strong>
<ol>
<li>How to overcome short-term pain in the investment process: James suggested lowering expectations, not pursuing perfection or getting rich quickly, finding solutions to problems, and transferring the pressure to those who can bear it, such as superiors or more experienced individuals. Think about solutions for the worst-case scenario, such as job loss or investment losses, and maintain a positive mindset, believing that the problem will eventually be solved.</li>
<li>About non-US tax resident investing in US stocks: James believes that non-US tax residents can use their passports to open brokerage accounts in the US without a Social Security Number. It is recommended to choose large, reputable brokers, such as Charles Schwab, and avoid using online brokers, such as Webull and Robinhood, as online brokers have security risks and imperfect regulations.</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">IV. Key Insights 
    <div id="iv-key-insights" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv-key-insights" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>Investment is a loser&rsquo;s game, not seeking to win, but seeking not to lose.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>In investing, avoiding mistakes is more important than pursuing victory. Choosing the right investment target, formulating a reasonable investment strategy and strictly adhering to discipline can reduce mistakes and ultimately achieve long-term stable returns.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Buying in a lump sum at any time and holding for the long term is superior to other investment methods.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Investing early and holding for the long term maximizes returns and delivers the best investment returns. Time is a friend of investment. Starting early allows time to work its magic of compounding.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>All pressure comes from expectations, and all worries come from not having a solution.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Lower your expectations and actively seek solutions to relieve stress and anxiety. When facing challenges, maintain a positive attitude and believe that you can find a way to solve the problem.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Wealth is accumulated slowly, and enjoying the process of wealth accumulation is the meaning of life.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Getting rich overnight or quickly is not the best way. Slowly accumulating wealth and enjoying it allows you to experience the true meaning of life. Investing is a long-term process. Don&rsquo;t be impatient and enjoy the process of wealth accumulation, learning and growing from it.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Good teachers and helpful friends are important. You may not be right if you agree with someone.
&ndash; JJU</p>
</blockquote>
<p>In the investment process, be good at learning and thinking. Don&rsquo;t blindly believe anyone&rsquo;s point of view, including teachers and friends. Make your own independent thinking and judgment to make the right investment decisions.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Account security is the primary issue in investing.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Choosing a large, reputable brokerage to open an account, such as Charles Schwab, can better protect your account security. Avoid using online brokers as online brokers have security risks and imperfect regulations.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">V. Summary 
    <div id="v-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#v-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This session focuses on the long-term investment philosophy, risk control, and mindset management. James helps students better understand the essence of investment through vivid examples and in-depth explanations. He answers students&rsquo; various questions encountered in the investment process, such as the risks of TQQQ, the importance of emergency funds, and real estate investment strategies. At the same time, students also actively share their experiences and confusion, such as using credit cards for investment and using the box spread strategy, triggering deeper thinking and discussion. James emphasizes the importance of independent thinking, advising against blindly believing anyone&rsquo;s point of view. He encourages making independent thinking and judgment to make the right investment decisions. At the same time, he also reminds everyone to pay attention to account security, choose large, reputable brokers to open accounts, and avoid using online brokers.</p>

  



<div
  
    class="flex px-4 py-3 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900"
  >

  <span
    
      class="text-primary-400 ltr:pr-3 rtl:pl-3 flex items-center"
    >

    

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M506.3 417l-213.3-364c-16.33-28-57.54-28-73.98 0l-213.2 364C-10.59 444.9 9.849 480 42.74 480h426.6C502.1 480 522.6 445 506.3 417zM232 168c0-13.25 10.75-24 24-24S280 154.8 280 168v128c0 13.25-10.75 24-23.1 24S232 309.3 232 296V168zM256 416c-17.36 0-31.44-14.08-31.44-31.44c0-17.36 14.07-31.44 31.44-31.44s31.44 14.08 31.44 31.44C287.4 401.9 273.4 416 256 416z"/></svg>

  </span>


  </span>

  <span
    
      class="dark:text-neutral-300"
    ><strong>Disclaimer:</strong> This article is only for personal learning notes and does not constitute any investment advice.</span>
</div>

]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
