<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Retirement Planning on QQQ Investor</title>
    <link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/tags/retirement-planning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Retirement Planning on QQQ Investor</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jomonylw.github.io/en/tags/retirement-planning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>00499 Future Wealth Planning: Capital Allocation in the Age of AI. Cash, QQQ, and QLD: Three Steps to Optimal Asset Allocation</title>
      <link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1737246178555/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1737246178555/</guid>
      <description>This episode introduces and discusses the relationship between investing in US dollars and US stocks, the concept of long-term investing, asset balancing methods, and shares the impact of AI development on future work and retirement. It also emphasizes the importance of learning and cognition, asset allocation and balancing, and answers related questions.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<lite-youtube videoid="YOTy3Tveq74" playlabel="YOTy3Tveq74" params=""></lite-youtube>



<h2 class="relative group">I. Episode Theme 
    <div id="i-episode-theme" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-episode-theme" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>The main theme of this episode is that <strong>investing in US indices means holding US assets, not holding US dollars.</strong> The discussion revolves around the <strong>US balance sheet, the relationship between the US dollar and US stocks</strong>, and deeply explores <strong>the philosophy of long-term investment and methods of asset allocation</strong>. In addition, it shares the impact of <strong>AI development on future work, social structures, retirement planning, and national competition</strong>, emphasizing the importance of <strong>learning and cognition, and asset allocation and balance</strong>.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">II. Briefing Contents 
    <div id="ii-briefing-contents" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii-briefing-contents" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Market Volatility and Long-Term Investing 
    <div id="market-volatility-and-long-term-investing" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#market-volatility-and-long-term-investing" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Market Volatility Is Irrelevant to Long-Term Investors</strong>: Short-term market fluctuations are normal. Long-term investors should adhere to the principle of &ldquo;buy when you have money, hold long term, and never sell,&rdquo; and not be swayed by market sentiment. Utilize the power of compound interest to hold quality assets for the long term. For example, even if the market experiences a significant pullback, as long as you hold a Nasdaq 100 index fund for the long term, you will ultimately achieve substantial returns.</li>
<li><strong>Disclaimer</strong>: The COEC Investment and Finance Channel is a non-profit channel aimed at sharing investment experiences and philosophies. All content is for reference only and does not constitute any investment advice. Advertisements on YouTube are not initiated by the channel. Please be wary of any investment schemes online that claim to guarantee returns, especially those using celebrity endorsements or AI-synthesized voiceovers; many are scams. COEC does not charge anyone a fee nor does it recommend any paid investment services.</li>
<li><strong>Investment Risk Warning</strong>: Investing involves risk, and the stock market is highly volatile. Investors should be fully aware of investment risks. For example, investing in stock index funds such as QQQ may face a short-term loss of 50% or even more of their market value.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Learning and Cognition 
    <div id="learning-and-cognition" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#learning-and-cognition" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Investing Requires Continuous Learning</strong>: James emphasizes the importance of learning and encourages everyone to watch the value investing lecture series videos, recommending episodes 00451, 00398, and 00288. There are also condensed short films in the playlist to help everyone quickly grasp the core content and to share with friends and family. Only through continuous learning can we enhance our investment knowledge and judgment.</li>
<li><strong>Q&amp;A Only Refines Your Existing Knowledge, Not Establishes It</strong>: This means that the Q&amp;A session can only help you further understand what you have already learned, but cannot replace systematic study. For example, concerning how to specifically implement the 433 asset allocation strategy, you need to first watch relevant videos for a systematic understanding.</li>
<li><strong>Nasdaq 100 Index Funds</strong>: James recommends long-term investment in Nasdaq 100 index funds (such as QQQ and TQQQ) and provides a list of Nasdaq 100 index fund options around the world for investors in different regions to reference.</li>
<li><strong>Investor Optimism</strong>: Despite market fluctuations and uncertainties, investors should maintain an extremely optimistic mindset. Market declines should be seen as opportunities to buy quality assets at lower prices. In the long run, the economy and the stock market will always trend upwards.</li>
<li><strong>Wealth Growth Requires Time</strong>: Investing is a long-term process. Wealth growth needs time to realize the effects of compound interest. For example, by investing in a Nasdaq 100 index fund for the long term, waiting for ten or twenty years, assets could potentially grow to a scale of hundreds of millions.</li>
<li><strong>Advantages of Long-Term Investing</strong>:
<ul>
<li><strong>Compound Interest Effect</strong>: Long-term investing can fully utilize the effects of compound interest, achieving exponential growth of wealth.</li>
<li><strong>Avoid Emotional Trading</strong>: Long-term investing can avoid making poor investment decisions due to short-term market fluctuations.</li>
<li><strong>Reduce Transaction Costs</strong>: Long-term investing can reduce the frequency of trading, thereby lowering transaction costs.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Relationship Between US Dollar and US Stocks 
    <div id="relationship-between-us-dollar-and-us-stocks" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#relationship-between-us-dollar-and-us-stocks" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Analysis of the US Balance Sheet</strong>:
<ul>
<li><strong>Detailed Data</strong>: James provided detailed US balance sheet data, including:
<ul>
<li><strong>Total US Government and Private Borrowing</strong>: This refers to the total domestic debt of all forms in the United States.</li>
<li><strong>Total Assets</strong>: $202 trillion, representing the total value of all US assets.</li>
<li><strong>Deficit</strong>: $36 trillion, referring to the US government&rsquo;s fiscal deficit.</li>
<li><strong>Total Liabilities</strong>: $101 trillion, including the total debt of the government and the public, which is actually the amount of US currency issued.</li>
<li><strong>GDP</strong>: $28.57 trillion, representing the total value of all goods and services produced within the US in one year.</li>
<li><strong>Federal Tax Revenue</strong>: $12 trillion, referring to the US federal government&rsquo;s tax revenue.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Income Estimation</strong>: Based on an average tax rate of 15%, it is estimated that the total income of US individuals and companies is about $80 trillion. James pointed out that because corporate tax rates are usually higher than 20%, this estimate may actually underestimate the actual income of the US, and the real number might be close to $100 trillion.</li>
<li><strong>Debt-to-Income Ratio</strong>: By comparing total liabilities to income, the US debt-to-income ratio was calculated and compared with individual debt-to-income ratios, explaining that the US balance sheet is very healthy and will not experience a debt crisis or bankruptcy as some people fear.</li>
<li><strong>Example</strong>: The US was compared to an individual with $202 million worth of real estate, owing $100 million, and with an annual income of $80 million, illustrating that its financial situation is very healthy. In comparison, many people have an income far less than $80 million but carry huge mortgage debts, and their personal financial situation is much worse than that of the US.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Relationship Between the US Dollar and US Stocks</strong>:
<ul>
<li><strong>Holding Assets, Not Currency</strong>: Investing in US index funds is actually holding a portfolio of assets composed of excellent US companies, rather than holding the US dollar as a currency.</li>
<li><strong>Impact of US Dollar Depreciation</strong>: Even if the US dollar depreciates, as long as the assets held (such as stocks) have value, the price of assets denominated in US dollars will rise.</li>
<li><strong>The US Dollar Is Just a Unit of Account</strong>: The US dollar is only a unit for measuring asset value and can be exchanged for assets using any other form of currency or valuable item. For example, real estate can be used to exchange for Apple shares or QQQ assets, without needing to go through the US dollar.</li>
<li><strong>US Dollar Credit Backing</strong>: The US dollar, as a fiat currency, is backed by national credit. The US government can repay its debt by taxing companies and individuals. Therefore, as long as US companies and individuals can continue to generate income, the US can repay its debts, and the US dollar will not collapse.</li>
<li><strong>Borrowing Strategy</strong>: Since the US dollar may depreciate, it is advisable to borrow as much US dollars as possible to invest or consume. In the future, debt can be repaid using depreciated US dollars.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Refuting the Bankruptcy Theory</strong>:
<ul>
<li>Cited data and facts to refute the view that &ldquo;excessive US debt will lead to bankruptcy.&rdquo;</li>
<li>Emphasized that the US has vast assets and a continuous source of income, which is enough to repay its debts.</li>
<li>Pointed out that those who spread such statements may have ulterior motives, and investors should think independently and not blindly believe them.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Long-Term Holding of Quality Assets</strong>:
<ul>
<li>Emphasized the importance of long-term holding of high-quality US assets (such as the Nasdaq 100 index fund).</li>
<li>Even if the US dollar depreciates, the value of quality assets will continue to grow.</li>
<li>Example: If QQQ is currently $500, after a large US dollar depreciation, QQQ may rise to $10,000 because it represents the assets of 100 excellent US technology companies.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>No Need to Worry About the US Dollar</strong>:
<ul>
<li>Investors should focus on the value of the assets themselves, rather than fluctuations in the US dollar.</li>
<li>US dollar depreciation is actually a good thing for investors holding quality assets because they can buy the same assets with fewer US dollars.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Asset Allocation and Balance 
    <div id="asset-allocation-and-balance" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#asset-allocation-and-balance" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>433 Asset Allocation</strong>:
<ul>
<li><strong>Definition</strong>: The 433 asset allocation is an investment strategy that allocates 40% of total assets to QQQ (Nasdaq 100 index fund), 30% to TQQQ (3x leveraged Nasdaq 100 index fund), and 30% to cash or money market funds.</li>
<li><strong>Purpose</strong>: By allocating assets with different risk levels, balance risk and return.</li>
<li><strong>Operation</strong>: Conduct &ldquo;smart rebalancing&rdquo; according to market conditions, that is, when the market rises, transfer some of the profits from TQQQ to cash; when the market falls, transfer cash to TQQQ.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Smart Rebalancing</strong>:
<ul>
<li><strong>Mechanism</strong>:
<ul>
<li><strong>When the market rises</strong>: Convert some of the profits (usually 30%) from leveraged funds (such as TQQQ) into cash.</li>
<li><strong>When the market falls</strong>: Convert cash into leveraged funds in a certain proportion (usually 20% of the cash portion).</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Effects</strong>:
<ul>
<li><strong>At market highs</strong>: The cash level is high, reducing the risk of a high-level pullback.</li>
<li><strong>At market lows</strong>: The cash level is low, allowing for buying more assets at lower prices, thus achieving greater returns when the market rebounds.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Auto-Pilot</strong>: The smart rebalancing mechanism can automatically adjust asset allocation according to market conditions without manual intervention.</li>
<li><strong>Examples</strong>: The internet bubble in 2000 and the financial crisis in 2008 were used to illustrate how the 433 asset allocation and smart rebalancing mechanism protect investors&rsquo; assets during significant market volatility.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Necessity of Long-Term Investment</strong>: Citing Howard Marks&rsquo;s views, it is explained that predicting short-term market trends is almost impossible, and frequent trading will only increase costs and risks. For ordinary investors, holding passive funds (such as QQQ) for the long term is a wiser choice.</li>
<li><strong>Avoid Frequent Trading</strong>: Combining data on the losses of Taiwanese day traders, the risks and harms of short-term trading are explained.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Other 
    <div id="other" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#other" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Essence of the Financial Industry</strong>: The goal of the financial industry is to maximize its own interests and may &ldquo;empty&rdquo; investors&rsquo; pockets through various means. Investors must improve their financial literacy to recognize and resist the traps and temptations of the financial industry. For example, long-term bond products may appear stable in name, but still have the potential to lose 30% or more.</li>
<li><strong>Information Filter Bubble Effect</strong>: The development of the internet and social media makes it easier for people to access information that matches their own views, thus forming information filter bubbles and making it difficult to hear different opinions. This leads to biases in people&rsquo;s understanding of the world and even conflicting emotions.</li>
<li><strong>Australian 2x Leveraged Fund GNDQ</strong>: Introduced an Australian market 2x leveraged fund called GNDQ, for Australian investors to reference.</li>
<li><strong>International Situation and Investment</strong>: Although we may know nothing about the international situation, this does not affect our long-term investments. The important thing is to choose the right investment targets and stick to them for the long term.</li>
<li><strong>Allocation Strategies for Roth IRA and Traditional IRA</strong>: It is recommended to invest all the funds in Roth IRA in TQQQ to maximize tax-free returns. Traditional IRA can allocate a portion to cash and a portion to QQQ, with the specific ratio depending on individual circumstances.</li>
<li><strong>Risks of Labor and Real Estate</strong>: Labor is facing the risk of unemployment, especially with the rapid development of artificial intelligence. Real estate also has risks, such as natural disasters and market volatility.</li>
<li><strong>Impact of AI on the Future</strong>: The development of AI will have a huge impact on the job market, with a large number of jobs being replaced by AI. In the future, society may only be left with a small number of capitalists and people who can control AI, while others may become &ldquo;useless&rdquo; laborers. Therefore, one should no longer learn coding but should use AI to serve oneself.</li>
<li><strong>Predictions on Future High-Tech Returns</strong>: Some finance professionals predict that future high-tech returns will decrease. James refuted this view, believing that these predictions are baseless and pointed out that the investment performance of these predictors is also poor.</li>
<li><strong>Encourage Learning and Sharing</strong>: Encourage everyone to watch the short films of the investment lectures and share them with more people to help them build correct investment philosophies.</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">III. Q&amp;A Session 
    <div id="iii-qa-session" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii-qa-session" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Cat 
    <div id="cat" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#cat" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing</strong>:
<ol>
<li>The annualized return rate of long-term investment does not mean that fixed returns can be obtained every year. If the investment period is too short, the desired results may not be achieved due to market fluctuations. She cited a chart from a book called &ldquo;The Long View,&rdquo; which shows the highest and lowest returns for different investment periods. For example, investing for one year, the highest return might be 66%, but it could also result in a loss of 38%; investing for two years, the highest return is 39.4%, but it could also lead to a loss of 31.7%; investing for five years, the highest return is 27.3%, but it could also result in a loss of 11.9%. Only when the investment period is more than 20 years is it possible to obtain a return ranging from a minimum of 6% to a maximum of 17%. In summary, the longer the investment period, the more the return rate tends to approach the long-term average.</li>
</ol>
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Comment</strong>: The longer the investment period, the closer the return is to the average. For example, if you invest for 25 years, the return will increasingly approach 10%. This explains the significance of the 433 asset allocation: short-term cash needs can be met with the cash position, while long-term investment is not affected. For example, if an investment portfolio has 10 million in long-term investments and 1 million for school tuition, the 1 million can be combined with the 10 million for 433 allocation. This would mean 300,000 in cash, and even if the market declines, the 300,000 cash can cover tuition needs. It was also emphasized that stock pledging can further reduce risk, because low-interest funds can be borrowed to meet emergency needs.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Four Five 
    <div id="four-five" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#four-five" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Question 1</strong>: The company&rsquo;s 401K plan can deposit 30% of income, which is far more than the IRS limit. The extra funds are put into an after-tax account. If the principal of this part is transferred to Roth IRA, and the appreciated part is transferred to Regular IRA, are there any tax issues with such operations?
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response</strong>: The after-tax 401K plan you mentioned is actually a tax-deferred account, which allows investors to put their after-tax income into it and conduct tax-free trading, but still have to pay taxes when finally withdrawn. For short-term operators, this type of account can avoid tax liabilities caused by frequent trading. However, for long-term investors like us, we do not make frequent buying and selling transactions, so this type of account does not have much appeal to us. The disadvantage of participating in this plan is that it actually increases the size of your Traditional IRA, and we generally advise against having too large a Traditional IRA because you will have to pay income tax when you withdraw in the future. Therefore, I do not recommend that you continue to participate and put money into this after-tax 401K plan.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question 2</strong>: I am 60 years old, and my current asset allocation is 70% of my money in Traditional IRA, 10% in Roth IRA, and 15% in Regular IRA. How should I allocate my assets?
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response</strong>: Given that your Roth IRA ratio is low, it is recommended to invest all the funds in your Roth IRA into TQQQ (3x leveraged Nasdaq 100 index fund) to maximize its potential for tax-free growth. For your Traditional IRA, it is recommended to allocate 20% to cash and 80% to QQQ (Nasdaq 100 index fund). This will make your overall asset allocation closer to the target of 433 (40% QQQ, 30% TQQQ, 30% cash).</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question 3</strong>: I am already using asset-backed loans, borrowing about 1% of the funds each year for use. According to the asset allocation ratio recommended by the teacher, my current cash ratio is insufficient. What should I do?
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response</strong>: In this case, you don&rsquo;t need to specifically increase your cash ratio. You only need to allocate 20% of the cash in your Traditional IRA and the remaining 80% to QQQ, and all the money in your Roth IRA to TQQQ. Use asset-backed loans to meet your daily expenses and tax payments, so that you do not need to use your investment principal. Continue to maintain the annual borrowing and use the loan to cover some expenses, so that your investment portfolio can continue to grow.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Ling 
    <div id="ling" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ling" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing 1</strong>: The US government has a very complete retirement plan. In contrast, Taiwan has a big gap in guaranteeing its people&rsquo;s retirement. Taiwan&rsquo;s labor insurance retirement account requires employers to set aside 6% of employees&rsquo; salaries in accordance with the law, and employees can choose to self-allocate 0% to 6% of their salaries. When Ling first started working, there was only the 6% set aside by the employer. Later, following the advice of colleagues, she chose to self-allocate 6% to increase retirement savings and deduct income tax.
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Comment</strong>: There is no need to participate, because Taiwan&rsquo;s securities accounts are tax-free.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Sharing 2</strong>: After listening to James&rsquo;s concept of investing in QQQ in November last year, Ling decided to change the self-allocated portion to 0% and use all the funds for investing in QQQ. In addition, Ling&rsquo;s company provides two options, &ldquo;employee stock trust&rdquo; and &ldquo;employee savings trust,&rdquo; aimed at helping employees increase retirement funds. Previously, she did not know enough and chose the &ldquo;employee stock trust&rdquo; investing in company stocks, but the return in the past six years was only about 38%. If she had followed James&rsquo;s QQQ investment philosophy, the performance might be higher. Therefore, she has recently made adjustments and has chosen the &ldquo;employee savings trust&rdquo; starting this year. However, the investment targets of this &ldquo;employee savings trust&rdquo; are limited and cannot be directly invested in QQQ. Only funds can be chosen. Currently, Ling plans to invest the company&rsquo;s portion in US technology funds and the self-allocated portion in Taiwan stock funds. Although the monthly investment amount is not large, Ling believes it still needs to be further optimized.
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Comment</strong>: Taiwan&rsquo;s securities accounts are tax-free, which is equivalent to the US Roth IRA, and there is no contribution limit, which is a very big advantage. Therefore, Taiwanese investors can directly use their own securities accounts for investments, especially in index funds such as QQQ, and do not need to participate in any retirement plans of the government or companies. These plans often have various restrictions, and the performance may not be good either. Taiwanese investors should take full advantage of this and invest funds directly into their securities accounts to enjoy tax-free investment income.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Sharing 3</strong>: Since November last year, Ling has watched all of James&rsquo;s videos before 2024 and continues to learn from the following videos. Ling compares investing in QQQ to a &ldquo;big pool.&rdquo; As soon as funds become available, she immediately puts them in, and regards it as her &ldquo;real estate.&rdquo; This &ldquo;big pool&rdquo; will continue to grow over time and is safer than traditional real estate. There is no need to worry about risks such as earthquakes, windstorms, or floods. When money is needed, she borrows through asset pledging to obtain funds instead of selling assets.
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Comment</strong>: Taiwan&rsquo;s financial environment is very friendly. In addition to tax-free securities accounts, the interest on asset-backed loans is also very low, which is an advantage that other regions cannot compare. Taiwanese investors should take full advantage of these &ldquo;free bullets&rdquo; and &ldquo;sophisticated weapons,&rdquo; do a good job in asset allocation, and the future wealth growth potential is huge. Regarding pledging, there is no need to wait until assets reach 10 million TWD to start. It can be decided based on your own circumstances and knowledge of assets. Even with only 2 million TWD of assets, you can try pledging to borrow a small amount of money each year (for example, 40,000 TWD) for use. As experience accumulates and assets grow, the borrowing amount can gradually be increased.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Warm Heart 
    <div id="warm-heart" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#warm-heart" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing 1</strong>: He began learning James&rsquo;s investment courses in 2022 and created an investment discussion group on Line in Taiwan in 2023. He emphasized that this group is self-organized, has no affiliation with the CLEC official, and has not received authorization or any form of assistance from James. The original intention of creating this group was to find more like-minded people to discuss investments, especially about 00662 (Yuanta Baoshu Shenzhen) and James&rsquo;s investment philosophy. Currently, this group has developed into a learning community of more than 500 people.</li>
<li><strong>Sharing 2</strong>: He mentioned that he is also facing a situation where his family does not understand his investment methods. For example, his father would question why he doesn&rsquo;t sell at high points but chooses to hold for the long term. In order to make his family better understand his investment philosophy, he invited his family to join the Line group he created, hoping that through the discussions within the group, his family could understand the advantages and value of long-term investment and reduce their concerns.</li>
<li><strong>Sharing 3</strong>: He particularly thanked several core members of the group, including Brother Chen, Mark, Chris, and QQM, for their contributions to the group&rsquo;s development.</li>
<li><strong>Sharing 4</strong>: He revealed that Brother Chen in the group will be sharing his experiences from 2 PM to 7 PM tomorrow (January 19th) and provided a link for everyone to participate.
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Comment</strong>: James expressed support and encouragement for this kind of self-organized learning community, believing that this form can help more people learn and spread the correct investment philosophy. He also emphasized that he himself does not privately provide any special resources or guidance to anyone or any group. All sharing will be done on public platforms to ensure transparency and fairness of information. He also reminded everyone that although these self-organized groups are usually made with good intentions, they should be vigilant and pay attention to potential risks. He himself and CLEC will not be responsible for the operation and management of these groups.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Mike 
    <div id="mike" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#mike" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing</strong>: He went hiking with a friend, who is also a member of CLEC. The two talked about the recent layoffs at Google due to AI development. This triggered their thinking about the future development of AI, especially whether AI will threaten humans due to its own &ldquo;rationality,&rdquo; for example, whether AI will deliberately leave bugs in its programs to avoid being shut down by humans.</li>
<li><strong>Question</strong>: What is the future development direction of AI? What impact will it have on human work? In particular, will AI develop self-awareness and threaten humans?
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response</strong>: The development of AI will have a huge impact on the job market. In the future, most people will face the risk of unemployment, and only a few capitalists and those who can control AI will be able to survive. Therefore, everyone should start learning and mastering AI tools now, and use them as assistants to improve work efficiency. At the same time, every country should pay attention to the development of AI, especially a comprehensive AI strategy. Currently, the United States and China are at the forefront in this area, while Europe and Taiwan are relatively lagging behind. If Taiwan wants to remain competitive in the AI era, it needs to significantly increase the salary levels of engineers and increase the TWD exchange rate to attract top talent from around the world. As for whether AI will develop self-awareness and threaten humans, this is indeed a concern. In the future, there may be a confrontation between &ldquo;righteous AI&rdquo; and &ldquo;villainous AI,&rdquo; just like in the movie &ldquo;The Matrix.&rdquo; This is also one of the reasons why Elon Musk is committed to developing more powerful AI and trying to guide it toward goodness.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question</strong>: How does James view the practice of restricting certain countries from accessing certain advanced technologies (such as AI)? Is this a form of discrimination?
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response</strong>: This is a complex issue that can be discussed publicly, but it is necessary to avoid political stances and remain objective and rational. Efforts should be made to make information public and transparent.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question</strong>: What is China&rsquo;s current asset situation? In addition, what impact does AI have on the stock markets of various countries?
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response</strong>: Every country has its own problems. China&rsquo;s data is not completely transparent, and it is difficult to obtain accurate information. Currently, AI has the most significant impact on the stock markets of the United States and Taiwan, while other countries are relatively less affected.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Jenny 
    <div id="jenny" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#jenny" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Question 1</strong>: James previously suggested keeping cash in an IRA account rather than a Brokerage Account. Why is that?
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response</strong>: Because the capital gains in the SEP IRA account also needs to be taxed, in order to avoid its rapid growth, it is recommended to keep your existing funds in your SEP IRA account as is and no longer contribute to it. The funds in the Brokerage Account can be used for asset-backed loans. You can continue to use the annual quota to deposit funds into your SEP IRA and then transfer it to a ROTH IRA.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question 2</strong>: Do I need to keep some cash in my Brokerage Account?
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response</strong>: No, you do not. You can obtain emergency funds through asset-backed loans. For example, if you have $5 million in Brokerage Account assets, you can obtain a credit line of approximately $3.5 million, which is sufficient to deal with most emergencies. You can first apply to open the asset-backed loan function, even if you don&rsquo;t use it for the time being. When you need money, you can borrow from it at any time, for example, occasionally borrowing $100,000 to pay taxes.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question 3</strong>: You always emphasize that QQQ should &ldquo;never be sold.&rdquo; So should QLD or TQQQ in a Roth IRA account also &ldquo;never be sold?&rdquo; But doesn&rsquo;t TQQQ have various fees and losses?
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response</strong>: Yes, even QLD and TQQQ should be held for the long term and not bought and sold frequently. Although TQQQ has some management fees and fluctuation losses, these losses are acceptable in the long term considering its huge growth potential. We should focus on long-term results rather than short-term fluctuations. For example, if QQQ increases 200 times in 40 years, then TQQQ may increase 600 times, which is a very substantial return.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question 4</strong>: In a Roth IRA account, if I don’t buy QLD, can I buy TQQQ?
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response</strong>: I don’t give specific investment advice. Whether to buy TQQQ is your own choice. I can only tell you that the data we use for backtesting is based on QQQ. If you change the volatility, I will not be able to answer the questions you may encounter.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question 5</strong>: For a child&rsquo;s Roth IRA account, do you recommend buying QLD or QQQ?
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response</strong>: For children’s accounts, regardless of the account type, as long as the investment period is long enough, for example, 40 years, it is okay to consider investing in QLD as much as possible to maximize tax-free gains.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Brian 
    <div id="brian" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#brian" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing</strong>: He used James&rsquo;s 433 asset allocation simulator to verify his investment logic and made adjustments according to his own circumstances. His current asset allocation is 80/20 (80% QQQ, 20% TQQQ). He plans to gradually transition to 40/30 (40% QQQ, 30% TQQQ, 30% cash) after retirement. He also shared his work experience in the AI field, mainly responsible for AI applications in power systems. He agrees with James&rsquo;s view that AI will eventually replace most human jobs, but some jobs are still difficult to replace in the short term, such as the construction industry. He also mentioned that the degree of demand for AI varies from region to region due to differences in labor costs. Finally, he shared that he would choose to stay in better hotels when he travels for business to enjoy life, rather than just saving money.
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response</strong>: In the process of market uptrend, your cash ratio must be greater than your liabilities. This is the most important principle. The 433 asset allocation has been verified by backtesting and can cope with the worst market conditions. If you cannot achieve the 433 allocation for the time being, you must at least ensure that the cash ratio is higher than your liabilities. At the same time, you can re-allocate your new capital each month. Regarding AI, although AI will eventually replace most jobs, some jobs are still difficult to replace in the short term. For example, the construction industry still requires a lot of physical labor, and AI cannot completely replace it in the short term.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">IM 
    <div id="im" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#im" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing</strong>: He didn’t quite understand what James meant by &ldquo;always being optimistic&rdquo; and the relationship between &ldquo;risk control&rdquo; before, nor did he fully understand the advice on consumption behaviors such as buying houses and cars. After a period of reflection, he gradually understood the logic behind these concepts.
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response</strong>: At this stage, you can spend more money appropriately and enjoy life. The key is to learn to borrow money for consumption, rather than spending your own money. Investing and consumption are not contradictory; the important thing is to master the methods. For example, you can choose to take a taxi instead of spending time waiting for a bus. You can choose to spend money to buy a better car and enjoy a better driving experience, as long as you don’t spend your own money but pay through loans or other means. In 40 years, you will have 80 billion. Now, what you should be thinking about is how to spend money, not how to save money.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">IV. Key Quotes 
    <div id="iv-key-quotes" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv-key-quotes" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>Investing in US indices means holding US assets, not holding US currency.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Investing in US stock index funds is about holding the assets of excellent US companies. The value of these assets is not highly correlated with the value of the US dollar. Even if the US dollar depreciates, the value of quality assets will continue to increase.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The market always goes up. Investing requires patience. Wealth is worth the wait.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>In the long run, the market always goes up, and investors need to be patient and wait for wealth to grow. Short-term market fluctuations are normal and should not be overemphasized.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The financial industry wants to empty your pockets.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>The goal of the financial industry is to maximize its own interests and may use various methods to &ldquo;empty&rdquo; investors&rsquo; pockets. For example, they will design various complex financial products and use information asymmetry to induce investors to buy. Investors must improve their financial literacy to recognize and resist the traps and temptations of the financial industry.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>There are many walls in the world, but people inside the walls don’t know they are within the walls, because everyone thinks they are free and open-minded. Many who think they are outside the walls don’t know that they are inside the walls.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>The information filter bubble effect in the online world should make us realize that the world we perceive may not be the real world, and we should maintain an open mind. Everyone and every country has its own information barriers.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The least guaranteed are laborers, and the second least guaranteed is real estate.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Laborers face the risk of unemployment, especially in the current era of rapid AI development. Real estate also has risks, such as natural disasters and market fluctuations. In comparison, the risk of long-term investing in quality stock assets (such as QQQ) is lower.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>All laborers, regardless of whether you are young or old, remember that now artificial intelligence is sweeping the world, you will face unemployment.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>The development of AI will have a huge impact on the job market, and a large number of jobs will be replaced by AI. This is both a challenge and an opportunity.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>In the future, the future will be left with very few capitalists and very few people who know how to control AI; the rest will be useless laborers.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>The social structure of the future will undergo tremendous changes, and you must become a capitalist or someone who can control AI. This means we need to continuously learn and master new skills in order to stand firm in the future society.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>We don&rsquo;t need to have a purpose in life, we don&rsquo;t need to do anything in life, we just need to be happy.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Encourage everyone to enjoy life and not set too many goals and pressures for themselves. The meaning of life lies in experiencing and feeling, rather than pursuing material wealth or social status.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>We don&rsquo;t necessarily have to like capitalist society, but we need to know how it makes money. We must stand on the same side as it, and then we can make a lot of money.
&ndash; Cat</p>
</blockquote>
<p>We don&rsquo;t need to like capitalism, but we need to understand the rules of capitalism in order to profit from it. Only by understanding how capitalism works can we better use it to achieve our wealth goals.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>If I still criticize, it means I still care.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>The criticism of Taiwan is because of the love for this land and the hope that it will become better.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">V. Summary 
    <div id="v-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#v-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This episode is full of information and covers many aspects such as investment philosophy, market analysis, asset allocation, and future outlook. James explained the underlying logic of investing in US index funds in an easy-to-understand way, emphasized the importance of long-term investment and holding high-quality assets, and provided an in-depth analysis of hot topics such as the relationship between the US dollar and US stocks, and the impact of AI on the future, in conjunction with the current economic situation and technological development trends. In addition, James also shared many practical investment tips and operational methods, such as the 433 asset allocation, smart rebalancing, and how to use asset-backed loans.</p>
<p>In conclusion, this episode is of great value to listeners who want to improve their investment knowledge and practice, helping them to better understand the essence of investment, master scientific investment methods, and become more stable and forward-looking on their future investment journey.</p>

  



<div
  
    class="flex px-4 py-3 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900"
  >

  <span
    
      class="text-primary-400 ltr:pr-3 rtl:pl-3 flex items-center"
    >

    

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M506.3 417l-213.3-364c-16.33-28-57.54-28-73.98 0l-213.2 364C-10.59 444.9 9.849 480 42.74 480h426.6C502.1 480 522.6 445 506.3 417zM232 168c0-13.25 10.75-24 24-24S280 154.8 280 168v128c0 13.25-10.75 24-23.1 24S232 309.3 232 296V168zM256 416c-17.36 0-31.44-14.08-31.44-31.44c0-17.36 14.07-31.44 31.44-31.44s31.44 14.08 31.44 31.44C287.4 401.9 273.4 416 256 416z"/></svg>

  </span>


  </span>

  <span
    
      class="dark:text-neutral-300"
    ><strong>Disclaimer:</strong> This article is for personal learning notes only and does not constitute any investment advice.</span>
</div>

]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>00492 Navigating Market Volatility: A Safe and Prudent Investment Approach; Leveraged ETF Strategies and Risk Management</title>
      <link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1732456561528/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1732456561528/</guid>
      <description>This lecture primarily discusses investment philosophy, asset allocation, real estate investment, retirement account management, and personal financial planning. James emphasizes the importance of long-term holding and advises investors to maintain undamaged capital (cash) to cope with market fluctuations. He also answers questions from the audience regarding retirement planning, tax optimization, and real estate investment, sharing specific case studies.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<lite-youtube videoid="oLims_tjx7E" playlabel="oLims_tjx7E" params=""></lite-youtube>



<h2 class="relative group">I. Main Topic 
    <div id="i-main-topic" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-main-topic" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This lecture focuses on the importance of long-term investing and asset allocation, especially the significance of holding cash (undamaged capital). James reiterates the idea that &ldquo;the only constant in the market is volatility&rdquo; and advises investors to adopt a &ldquo;buy and hold&rdquo; strategy similar to Warren Buffett&rsquo;s, investing long-term in Nasdaq 100 index funds (QQQ or 00662). He uses a rent vs. buy case study to demonstrate the advantages of long-term index fund investing. He also explains in detail the importance of maintaining undamaged capital (cash) in asset allocation to buy the dip during market downturns, thereby achieving long-term stable investment returns.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">II. Summary 
    <div id="ii-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Investment Philosophy and Strategy 
    <div id="investment-philosophy-and-strategy" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#investment-philosophy-and-strategy" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Long-term Holding:</strong> Investing requires a timeframe of 20+ years, ideally forever, without worrying about short-term market fluctuations. James uses Warren Buffett as an example, emphasizing the importance of long-term holding, stating that if one isn&rsquo;t prepared to hold for the long term, they shouldn&rsquo;t even hold for 10 minutes.</li>
<li><strong>Invest in the US:</strong> The US is the best country for fairness, justice, and open innovation, so invest only in the US.</li>
<li><strong>Index Funds:</strong> Invest in Nasdaq 100 index funds (QQQ/00662), and recommends new viewers watch introductory videos 00451, 288, and 398.</li>
<li><strong>Market Volatility:</strong> The only constant in the market is volatility. Ignore market fluctuations and adhere to long-term holding. The 2022 market correction was just a financial event, not a bubble.</li>
<li><strong>Bubbles:</strong> Bubbles are rare, occurring only twice in the past 25 years. The best way to deal with them is to ignore them and continue holding index funds.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Asset Allocation and Cash Management 
    <div id="asset-allocation-and-cash-management" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#asset-allocation-and-cash-management" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Undamaged Capital:</strong> Having undamaged capital (cash) is crucial. It helps investors stay calm during market panics and buy the dip, just like wealthy individuals.</li>
<li><strong>The Significance of Cash:</strong> Cash is a stabilizing force that overcomes human flaws in investing (fear and greed), allowing the power of compounding to fully take effect.</li>
<li><strong>Cash Ratio:</strong> Recommends a cash allocation of at least 20% in the portfolio.</li>
<li><strong>Retirement Planning:</strong>  To withdraw $30,000 annually from an investment account after retirement, $1.5 million in cash is needed. James suggests withdrawing $50,000 annually, requiring $2.5 million in cash, approximately 20% of total assets.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Real Estate Investment 
    <div id="real-estate-investment" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#real-estate-investment" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Renting is Superior to Buying:</strong>  In the long run, renting and investing in index funds yields higher returns than buying a house. James shares a PC Excel spreadsheet example demonstrating the advantages of rental investment and encourages viewers to modify the parameters for simulation calculations.</li>
<li><strong>Selling Advice:</strong> Recommends selling real estate and land, investing the funds in the stock market. There&rsquo;s no real estate that can&rsquo;t be sold, only prices that are too high. Even if sold at a lower price, investment returns may quickly compensate for the difference.</li>
<li><strong>Short-term Rental Investment:</strong>  Short-term rental investments aren&rsquo;t worthwhile unless the annualized return is at least 20%.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Retirement Account Management 
    <div id="retirement-account-management" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#retirement-account-management" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Traditional IRA to Roth IRA Conversion:</strong> Recommends converting funds from traditional IRA accounts to Roth IRA accounts when tax rates are lower (below 24%).</li>
<li><strong>Roth IRA Investment:</strong> Recommends investing in leveraged ETFs (TQQQ) within Roth IRA accounts, while holding more cash in traditional retirement accounts. Shares a case study suggesting viewers invest Roth IRA funds in TQQQ and hold more cash in traditional retirement accounts to optimize asset allocation.</li>
<li><strong>Leveraged ETFs:</strong> Retirees should not hold leveraged ETFs. Leveraged ETFs should be held in Roth IRA accounts.</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">III. Q&amp;A Session 
    <div id="iii-qa-session" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii-qa-session" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Lora 
    <div id="lora" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#lora" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Question 1: How can I deduct the interest on a pledged loan against the interest earned on cash holdings?</strong>
<ul>
<li><strong>James:</strong> There&rsquo;s no deduction. If the interest earned on your cash is higher than the loan interest, you&rsquo;re effectively earning more. I recommend buying non-dividend-paying stocks in your personal account, like BOXX, to avoid paying taxes on interest income. Since you don&rsquo;t have a Roth IRA, you can only operate within a brokerage account and will incur some tax costs.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question 2: Which trading software do you recommend?</strong>
<ul>
<li><strong>James:</strong>  Just use your broker&rsquo;s website; no need for additional software. I only use the web version. The &ldquo;positions&rdquo; page on your brokerage website allows you to view the profit and loss of each transaction and manage them in batches.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Run 
    <div id="run" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#run" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Question 1: Can Roth IRA funds be pledged as collateral?</strong>
<ul>
<li><strong>James:</strong> Roth IRA funds cannot be directly pledged. However, they can be used as a credit guarantee to lower interest rates on other loans.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question 2: How should I invest after maxing out my Roth IRA contributions?</strong>
<ul>
<li><strong>James:</strong>  Max out your Roth IRA contributions first. Invest the remaining funds in QQQ within a regular brokerage account.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Zhan 
    <div id="zhan" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#zhan" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Question 1: How should I handle my properties in Canada and the US?</strong>
<ul>
<li><strong>James:</strong> I recommend selling your Canadian property as soon as possible. If your US property is your primary residence, I also suggest selling it and renting instead. It&rsquo;s more cost-effective, as demonstrated in the rent vs. buy case study in the presentation.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question 2: What should I do with my Canadian pension plan?</strong>
<ul>
<li><strong>James:</strong> I recommend withdrawing the money from your pension plan and investing it in QQQ within a brokerage account. Don&rsquo;t use the 403(b) and TDA accounts provided by your school, as their performance is poor. Stick to your own IRA account.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">IM 
    <div id="im" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#im" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Comment 1: There&rsquo;s a significant wealth gap among young people, and some try to fill it by borrowing money. How can I avoid this trap?</strong>
<ul>
<li><strong>James:</strong> First, cultivate strong mental fortitude, which can be achieved through reading. Second, don&rsquo;t lend money casually. Third, don&rsquo;t buy things you don&rsquo;t need. Even Warren Buffett, despite his wealth, doesn&rsquo;t buy unnecessary things.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Comment 2: I participated in an 11-day meditation retreat and gained insights into the relationship between meditation and investing, particularly the importance of focus.</strong>
<ul>
<li><strong>James:</strong> Avoid distractions outside the stock market and focus on your investment strategy.  Treat distractions like &ldquo;demons and monsters&rdquo;—don&rsquo;t listen, don&rsquo;t watch, don&rsquo;t engage—and you&rsquo;ll maintain composure.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question: Does focusing solely on my own investments lead to detachment from the world?</strong>
<ul>
<li><strong>James:</strong> There&rsquo;s no need to be overly connected to worldly affairs. Focus on your investments and avoid excessive external information. Important information will eventually reach you.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Lin 
    <div id="lin" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#lin" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Question: How should I rebalance my portfolio?</strong>
<ul>
<li><strong>James:</strong> Since you&rsquo;re still working, you don&rsquo;t need to engage in complex rebalancing.  Just rebalance annually, adjusting the proportions of leveraged ETFs (00670L/TQQQ/Q2D) and cash. You can leave your 00662/QQQ holdings untouched. Alternatively, during your monthly investments, maintain an 80% allocation to 00662/QQQ and 20% to 00864B/cash.  (He then provides a specific example of adjusting the ratio between 00670L and cash).</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Lizi 
    <div id="lizi" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#lizi" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Question: How can I reduce the tax burden from RMDs (Required Minimum Distributions)?</strong>
<ul>
<li><strong>James:</strong> I recommend withdrawing $600,000 annually from your IRA and transferring it to a Roth IRA over the next seven years. You can invest in leveraged ETFs within the Roth IRA and hold cash in your traditional retirement account to lower your overall return and tax burden.  Start converting to a Roth IRA as soon as possible; don&rsquo;t wait until RMDs begin.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">IV. Key Takeaways 
    <div id="iv-key-takeaways" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv-key-takeaways" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;If you&rsquo;re not investing for 20+ years, don&rsquo;t tell me you&rsquo;re investing.&rdquo; &ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Investing requires a long-term perspective. Short-term market fluctuations should not influence investment decisions.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;Undamaged capital is the elixir that keeps us calm.&rdquo; &ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Holding cash helps investors remain composed during market volatility and seize opportunities to buy low.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;Don&rsquo;t engage with demons and monsters. If you don&rsquo;t engage, you don&rsquo;t need to train your mind.&rdquo; &ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Staying away from market noise and focusing on one&rsquo;s own investment strategy is key to maintaining rational investment decisions.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">V. Conclusion 
    <div id="v-conclusion" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#v-conclusion" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This lecture reiterates the importance of long-term investing, value investing, and asset allocation, analyzing them with practical examples.  James advises investors to hold Nasdaq 100 index funds and maintain a certain percentage of cash to cope with market fluctuations. He answers questions about retirement account management, real estate investment, and personal financial planning, providing specific advice based on individual circumstances. He emphasizes the importance of choosing the right investment strategy and asset allocation according to one&rsquo;s situation.</p>

  



<div
  
    class="flex px-4 py-3 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900"
  >

  <span
    
      class="text-primary-400 ltr:pr-3 rtl:pl-3 flex items-center"
    >

    

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M506.3 417l-213.3-364c-16.33-28-57.54-28-73.98 0l-213.2 364C-10.59 444.9 9.849 480 42.74 480h426.6C502.1 480 522.6 445 506.3 417zM232 168c0-13.25 10.75-24 24-24S280 154.8 280 168v128c0 13.25-10.75 24-23.1 24S232 309.3 232 296V168zM256 416c-17.36 0-31.44-14.08-31.44-31.44c0-17.36 14.07-31.44 31.44-31.44s31.44 14.08 31.44 31.44C287.4 401.9 273.4 416 256 416z"/></svg>

  </span>


  </span>

  <span
    
      class="dark:text-neutral-300"
    ><strong>Disclaimer:</strong> This is a personal learning summary and does not constitute investment advice.</span>
</div>

]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>00490 Workers are just picking up trash; Mortgages are a risk for retirees; Buying a house won&#39;t make you rich.</title>
      <link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1730597712367/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1730597712367/</guid>
      <description>This session focuses on investment philosophy, asset allocation, lifestyle, and how to cope with market fluctuations. It emphasizes the importance of staying optimistic, continuous learning, and answers questions from the audience on Bitcoin, real estate, retirement planning, leveraged funds, and education funds.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<lite-youtube videoid="Ad9u7a-z6Ro" playlabel="Ad9u7a-z6Ro" params=""></lite-youtube>



<h2 class="relative group">I. Main Topic 
    <div id="i-main-topic" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-main-topic" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This session revolves around investment and life planning. The core ideas are: be optimistic about investment and keep learning, ignoring short-term market fluctuations; young people should focus on asset appreciation, with Nasdaq 100 index funds being the top choice; utilize leverage and allocate assets reasonably; retirees should plan carefully and avoid excessive debt; and one should stay optimistic and confident, avoid material comparisons, and pursue true freedom.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">II. Presentation Content 
    <div id="ii-presentation-content" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii-presentation-content" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Investment Philosophy and Market Analysis 
    <div id="investment-philosophy-and-market-analysis" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#investment-philosophy-and-market-analysis" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Market Fluctuations and Investment Mentality:</strong> The market is always fluctuating. Don&rsquo;t let short-term fluctuations affect your investment decisions. Stay optimistic.</li>
<li><strong>Currency Devaluation and Asset Appreciation:</strong> Money depreciates; only assets like stocks can preserve and increase in value. Currency devaluation is more severe in emerging countries, so it is advised to convert currency into assets. Taiwan&rsquo;s low wages and currency devaluation are related to the government&rsquo;s subsidy policies.</li>
<li><strong>Worker Mindset vs. Capitalist Mindset:</strong> Workers exchange labor for depreciating currency, while capitalists exchange currency for appreciating assets. Learn to invest and become a capitalist, exchanging &ldquo;trash&rdquo; (depreciating currency) for assets.</li>
<li><strong>Global Market Linkage:</strong> Global markets are highly interconnected, and diversifying investments into other regions has limited effectiveness. Focusing on the US stock market is recommended.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Asset Allocation Strategies 
    <div id="asset-allocation-strategies" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#asset-allocation-strategies" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Nasdaq 100 Index Funds:</strong> The preferred choice for young people. Long-term investment can yield substantial returns.  Global codes for purchasing Nasdaq 100 index funds were provided, and investing based on market conditions is recommended.</li>
<li><strong>The Importance of Cash:</strong> Cash reserves are crucial. 00864B and money market funds (like SWVXX, VOXX) are safeguards and should not be replaced with high-dividend products like SPHD, as principal safety is paramount.</li>
<li><strong>Smart Rebalancing:</strong> Suitable for those who use leveraged funds, are not retired, and have income.</li>
<li><strong>Risks of Real Estate Investment:</strong> Housing prices in the Bay Area are high, putting great pressure on young people to buy houses, which can easily lead to financial difficulties. Renting is recommended to maintain flexibility.</li>
<li><strong>Borrowing and Investment:</strong> Loans, mortgages, and car loans should be repaid with stable cash flow, not relying on stock market returns.</li>
<li><strong>Retirement Planning:</strong> Retirees should be cautious about borrowing and make plans based on the size of their retirement funds.  If retirement funds are 50 times the annual expenses, two options are available: 1. Keep the mortgage and car loan, using 2% of the retirement fund annually to cover all expenses; 2. Pay off the mortgage and car loan, invest 80% of the remaining funds in 00662, 20% in 00864B, and use 2% of the total funds annually for living expenses.</li>
<li><strong>Asset Allocation Case Study:</strong> A case study with 45 million Taiwan dollars illustrated asset allocation strategies when withdrawals are not needed. An 80/20 allocation or a combination of leveraged funds (60% 00662, 20% 00670L, 20% 00864B) is recommended.  For those with stable income and no need to withdraw from investments, 100% investment in QQQ can be considered.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Other Matters 
    <div id="other-matters" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#other-matters" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Class Suspension Notice:</strong> Class is suspended on November 9th and resumes on November 16th. After daylight saving time ends, the class time will be changed to 6:00 AM Pacific Time and 10:00 PM Taiwan time.</li>
<li><strong>Stay Optimistic:</strong> Maintain an optimistic mindset; the market will reward you. Like, subscribe, and leave comments on various platforms to benefit more people.</li>
<li><strong>Contact Information:</strong> Two email addresses were provided for contact.</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">III. Q&amp;A Session 
    <div id="iii-qa-session" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii-qa-session" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Brian: 
    <div id="brian" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#brian" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing 1: Read &ldquo;Investing is Asset Allocation, What You Don&rsquo;t Know,&rdquo; agreeing with the importance of accumulating the first pot of gold early; learning investment allows for more focus on work and personal improvement, spending time each day learning new skills and increasing self-worth.  Investment enables people to be more motivated to improve their professional skills rather than &ldquo;lying flat.&rdquo;</li>
<li>Sharing 2: Individuals can improve their earning potential through learning, even if their investment assets are reduced to zero, they can still rely on professional skills to make a comeback.</li>
<li>Question 1: What should I do if the Beta value is very low when the asset value plummets in the Excel sheet?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: The sheet is designed for acceleration during market rises and deceleration during falls. A low Beta value is normal and a reflection of risk control; no adjustment is needed.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2: Even knowing that investment should be mindless, I still worry when the Beta value drops. How should I cope?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: Deceleration during declines is the purpose of the investment strategy. Don&rsquo;t worry, stick to the plan, just like autopilot.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">LU: 
    <div id="lu" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#lu" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question 1: What is the impact of Trump&rsquo;s potential return to office on Bitcoin?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: The US has abandoned the gold standard and will not adopt a Bitcoin standard. Bitcoin is similar to gold and has an anti-inflationary function, but its future development is limited.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2: Can QQQ break through its previous high?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: It definitely can. The current market is bullish; there&rsquo;s no need to worry.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Wendy: 
    <div id="wendy" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#wendy" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing 1: Learned James&rsquo;s investment philosophy and successfully recouped the income lost during unemployment. Started reading recommended books such as &ldquo;The Richest Man in Babylon&rdquo; and &ldquo;The Most Important Thing.&rdquo;</li>
<li>No Questions</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Peter: 
    <div id="peter" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#peter" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing 1: Agrees with James&rsquo;s philosophy and has increased the investment proportion of QQQ, but some individual stocks have not been completely sold due to tax reasons.</li>
<li>Question 1: Advantages and disadvantages of converting 401K to Roth 401K?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: Just put new contributions into Roth 401K; don&rsquo;t convert existing funds. Convert at retirement.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2:  How to use HSA and 529 accounts?  Is there any problem with using a credit card to pay medical bills from an HSA?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply:  HSA, 529, and college fund accounts are not recommended because they lead to a loss of control over the funds. Using your own funds or loans is recommended.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 3: Are there any suggestions for increasing income and saving money besides a full-time job?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: Excessive saving is not recommended. Plan for retirement funds first, and the remaining money can be freely used and enjoyed.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Yi Jie (First Sister): 
    <div id="yi-jie-first-sister" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#yi-jie-first-sister" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing 1: Previously followed the advice of online influencers and invested in US stocks and treasury bonds, currently converting to QQQ.  Has a modest salary and one child.</li>
<li>Question 1: Can the 20% cash in the 80/20 allocation be replaced with Fubon 50 2X leverage?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply:  QQQ 2X leverage (00670L) is recommended. He explained the use of leveraged funds.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2: Is it feasible to regularly invest equal amounts in QQQ and 2X leverage?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: Feasible, but pay attention to cash reserves. A Beta of 1.1 or 1.2 allocation is recommended, adjusting according to market conditions.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 3: Can a child&rsquo;s Lunar New Year money be all-in on 2X leverage?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: If you can guarantee continuous regular investment for more than 30 years, it&rsquo;s worth considering, but be aware of the risks and be able to withstand significant asset shrinkage.  In the long run, the returns can be substantial, but psychological barriers must be overcome.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 4: Are the views of online influencers recommending treasury bonds correct? Are treasury bonds more valuable during a market crash?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: Incorrect. During market downturns, bond declines can be even greater.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">IAM: 
    <div id="iam" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iam" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing 1: Reflecting on the value of money, learning gratitude, and paying attention to community articles, realizing that spending money is spending one&rsquo;s life energy.</li>
<li>Sharing 2: Made 100 pages of notes and calculated the return on an 80,000 loan invested for 40 years; the result was shocking.</li>
<li>Question 1: Why are people not accustomed to borrowing for investment?  Confused about the phenomenon of young people being afraid to borrow for investment but willing to use installment plans for consumption.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: This is due to cultural influences.  Change your mindset and recognize that good debt can help accumulate wealth. Shared personal experiences and spending philosophy, emphasizing the freedom of spending after becoming wealthy.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">YJ Yuanlin: 
    <div id="yj-yuanlin" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#yj-yuanlin" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing 1: Investing boosts confidence, enabling focus on work and hobbies.</li>
<li>Question 1: In a down year, can TQQ replace QLD in smart rebalancing?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: Both are possible, but pay attention to risk control and avoid excessive pursuit of high risk. TQQ has greater volatility and requires a stronger psychological capacity.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">T: 
    <div id="t" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#t" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question 1: What are your thoughts on Elon Musk supporting Trump?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: Politicians&rsquo; decisions are the result of weighing pros and cons. Elon Musk&rsquo;s support for Trump stems from personal interests and positions, such as opposing certain liberal policies.  Entrepreneurs also have to choose between different political forces.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Yi Ni: 
    <div id="yi-ni" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#yi-ni" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question 1: How to invest and use Canadian education fund accounts?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: It&rsquo;s recommended to thoroughly research the specific rules of the account and consider methods like pledged loans to avoid locking up funds. Inquired about whether it&rsquo;s possible to withdraw all funds and the limitations, suggesting consulting with professionals.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Meng: 
    <div id="meng" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#meng" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing 1: In the high-tech era, privacy and freedom are difficult to have both.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Peter: 
    <div id="peter-1" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#peter-1" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing 1: It can be difficult for beginners to invest in QQQ, etc. It&rsquo;s suggested to start by buying one share and gradually build confidence.  James&rsquo;s explanations are very patient and benefit everyone.</li>
<li>Question 1: How to strengthen mental and psychological well-being?  James&rsquo;s experience sharing on meditation and hypnosis.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: Recommended Rachel&rsquo;s hypnosis channel and shared personal methods of using hypnosis and positive psychological suggestions. Suggested listening to hypnotic audios every night before sleep.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">IV. Key Takeaways 
    <div id="iv-key-takeaways" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv-key-takeaways" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>Rise faster, fall slower.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This is one of James&rsquo;s core investment philosophies. Through smart rebalancing strategies, increase investment during market rises to accelerate profits, and reduce investment during market downturns to mitigate losses.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Money is the least valuable thing when it has no value.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This reflects James&rsquo;s unique view on wealth. When wealth accumulates to a certain extent, the value of money itself is no longer important; what matters more is pursuing freedom and happiness.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>If you want freedom, and you want privacy, you will not have freedom. In the future world, if you want privacy, you will not have freedom.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This shows James&rsquo;s insight into future social trends. In the high-tech era, one needs to make trade-offs between privacy and freedom.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The more daring one is to borrow money, the broader their perspective.
&ndash; YJ Yuanlin</p>
</blockquote>
<p>YJ Yuanlin&rsquo;s sharing led to James&rsquo;s views on borrowing: good debt can help wealth growth.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>If you want freedom, you cannot care.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Echoing the topic of Elon Musk supporting Trump and the entrepreneurial spirit, true freedom is not caring about external opinions and focusing on one&rsquo;s goals.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>If you don&rsquo;t use ChatGPT now, you are outdated and will be eliminated.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>James advocates for new technologies and maintains an open attitude towards learning new things.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">V. Summary 
    <div id="v-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#v-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This session covered various aspects of investment philosophy, asset allocation, lifestyle, and how to cope with market fluctuations.  James answered the audience&rsquo;s questions with easy-to-understand language and rich examples, sharing his life experiences and insights, and encouraging everyone to stay optimistic, continue learning, and pursue true freedom and happiness.</p>

  



<div
  
    class="flex px-4 py-3 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900"
  >

  <span
    
      class="text-primary-400 ltr:pr-3 rtl:pl-3 flex items-center"
    >

    

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M506.3 417l-213.3-364c-16.33-28-57.54-28-73.98 0l-213.2 364C-10.59 444.9 9.849 480 42.74 480h426.6C502.1 480 522.6 445 506.3 417zM232 168c0-13.25 10.75-24 24-24S280 154.8 280 168v128c0 13.25-10.75 24-23.1 24S232 309.3 232 296V168zM256 416c-17.36 0-31.44-14.08-31.44-31.44c0-17.36 14.07-31.44 31.44-31.44s31.44 14.08 31.44 31.44C287.4 401.9 273.4 416 256 416z"/></svg>

  </span>


  </span>

  <span
    
      class="dark:text-neutral-300"
    ><strong>Disclaimer:</strong> This article is for personal learning notes only and does not constitute any investment advice.</span>
</div>

]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>00489 US Dollar Hegemony and the Sorrow of Trade Surplus Countries; Investing in QQQ Outperforms SPY</title>
      <link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1730069768515/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1730069768515/</guid>
      <description>In this session, James begins by analyzing the current investment market, pointing out that it&amp;#39;s poised to hit new highs. He advises listeners to solidify their investment confidence and enter the market sooner rather than later. James then delves into a research paper discussing asset portfolios comprising leveraged funds, cash, QQQ, and SPY. He analyzes the risks and returns associated with various investment portfolios, emphasizing the critical role of cash allocation. He addresses questions from participants regarding asset allocation, stock pledges, retirement planning, investment strategies, and the US dollar&amp;#39;s global dominance. He also shares his personal views on marriage and having children. </description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<lite-youtube videoid="eOh-hu1X0jo" playlabel="eOh-hu1X0jo" params=""></lite-youtube>



<h2 class="relative group">I. Topic of the Day 
    <div id="i-topic-of-the-day" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-topic-of-the-day" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>The session focuses on the impending new highs anticipated in the investment market. James encourages everyone to bolster their investment confidence and enter the market early. He elaborates on various asset allocation strategies, particularly the use of leveraged funds and the significance of cash reserves. Additionally, James dives into the nature of US dollar hegemony and its implications for the global economy. He also shares his thoughts on marriage and childbearing.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">II. Briefing Content 
    <div id="ii-briefing-content" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii-briefing-content" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<ol>
<li>
<p><strong>The Market is About to Hit New Highs:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>The market is on the verge of reaching new highs. Entering early is more advantageous than waiting for the new highs to materialize.</li>
<li>Earnings reports from AI and high-tech sectors are projected to surpass expectations. Market funds and corporate profits are also expected to exceed projections.</li>
<li>The market consistently trends upward. Investment requires patience; wealth is worth the wait.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Interpreting the Asset Portfolio Research Paper:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Long-term bonds carry higher risks than stocks while yielding lower returns. Investment in them is not recommended.</strong></li>
<li><strong>QQQ offers superior returns and risk resistance compared to SPY.</strong></li>
<li><strong>Leveraged funds (e.g., QQQ2D) are characterized by high volatility, substantial downside risk, but also significant upside potential.</strong></li>
<li><strong>Intelligent asset allocation can achieve returns equivalent to a 100% QQQ portfolio while providing greater cash security.</strong></li>
<li><strong>Retirees or individuals without income are advised against using leveraged funds. An 80/20 asset allocation strategy is recommended.</strong></li>
<li><strong>Cash is the cornerstone ensuring investors can continue investing.</strong></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Additional Investment Advice and Experience Sharing:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Retirees should claim their social security benefits as early as possible and utilize them for investments.</li>
<li>Real estate is a liability; selling property for investment purposes is recommended. Avoiding mortgage loans against real estate is advised.</li>
<li>Young individuals can leverage credit loans for investments, accelerating wealth accumulation.</li>
<li>Exercise prudence in investments. Avoid excessive diversification or venturing into unfamiliar domains such as real estate or REITs.</li>
<li><strong>Investing in individual stocks is not advised. Opt for market capitalization-based index funds like QQQ.</strong></li>
<li>Experiencing substantial losses is a prerequisite to appreciating the allure of high returns. The market always presents risks, and one must learn to navigate them.</li>
<li>Short-term safe assets (e.g., treasury bills) are essential components of an investment portfolio, aiding investors in weathering market fluctuations.</li>
<li><strong>The higher the proportion of cash or cash-equivalent assets, the greater the risk tolerance of the investment portfolio.</strong></li>
<li><strong>Refrain from self-managing stock portfolios. The returns from most stocks fall short of those from treasury bills.</strong></li>
<li><strong>Stock index funds constantly face future risks. Embrace risk tolerance; only by weathering the storms can one see the sunshine.</strong></li>
<li><strong>Don&rsquo;t put faith in market predictions. During market downturns, &ldquo;stock gurus&rdquo; often emerge, but their predictions are frequently inaccurate.</strong></li>
<li><strong>Adhere to long-term investment principles. Avoid being swayed by short-term market fluctuations.</strong></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Marriage and Childbearing:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Marriage serves the purpose of creating life to carry on the universe&rsquo;s legacy. Loving one&rsquo;s partner as one would love their own child is paramount to a successful marriage.</li>
<li>Childbearing lies at the heart of life&rsquo;s meaning. Young individuals should marry and have children early, unburdened by financial pressures.</li>
<li>Even without marriage, childbearing should be considered. A life spent single and childless will ultimately lead to profound loneliness.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ol>


<h2 class="relative group">III. Q&amp;A Session 
    <div id="iii-qa-session" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii-qa-session" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p><strong>Mike:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing:</strong>
<ul>
<li>Mentions the Chinese government&rsquo;s strong push for policies akin to MMT (Modern Monetary Theory).</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question 1:</strong> Taiwan Semiconductor Manufacturing Company (TSMC) is not included in the Nasdaq 100 index, and the NYSE has extended its trading hours to 22 hours, while Nasdaq hasn&rsquo;t followed suit. Why?
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response:</strong> Nasdaq&rsquo;s trading hours are already standard. Extending trading hours only affects after-hours trading, holding little significance for ordinary investors. TSMC&rsquo;s exclusion from the Nasdaq 100 index is linked to factors such as trading costs.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question 2:</strong> How can MMT be explained to someone without financial expertise?
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response:</strong> James uses simple language to elucidate the relationship between government deficits and currency issuance. He asserts that governments can cover deficits by printing money without facing national bankruptcy. Using early American history and ancient barter systems as examples, he illustrates how governments utilize currency issuance to purchase goods and services, and how taxation maintains currency value. James emphasizes the essence of US dollar hegemony, highlighting that the US leverages its control over vital resource trading, like oil, to sustain the dollar&rsquo;s global dominance, citing Russia&rsquo;s forced use of dollars for oil purchases as an example. He also points out that the core nature of fiat currency is a representation of national sovereignty, enabling governments to mandate its use through legal means.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>IAM:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing:</strong>
<ul>
<li>Questions whether investing in QQQ also implies supporting &ldquo;rogue&rdquo; entities.</li>
<li>After comparing returns from QQQ and its top ten constituent stocks, IAM observed higher returns from the latter, leading to confusion about the role of the remaining 90 companies.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question 1:</strong> Does investing in QQQ equate to supporting &ldquo;rogue&rdquo; entities?
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response:</strong> We, as investors, are contributors. Through our investment in QQQ, we allocate capital to the 100 companies making the most significant contributions to humanity, propelling societal progress.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question 2:</strong> The top ten constituent stocks of QQQ generate higher returns; what is the purpose of the other 90 companies?
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response:</strong> The composition of QQQ&rsquo;s top ten holdings changes annually. Examining solely the past decade&rsquo;s data is insufficient. Companies previously ranked lower have the potential to enter the top ten, underscoring the vital role played by the remaining 90 companies.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question 3:</strong> Are companies ranked lower in QQQ&rsquo;s constituents at risk of being removed due to a decrease in their market capitalization percentage?
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response:</strong> Typically not, but QQQ mandates that the percentage of any individual constituent stock cannot exceed a specific threshold. Adjustments are made if this limit is surpassed.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question 4:</strong> How can one view the complete list of QQQ&rsquo;s constituent companies?
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response:</strong> This information can be accessed on websites like Yahoo Finance, which displays QQQ&rsquo;s holdings, or on QQQ&rsquo;s official website.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Chunxia:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing:</strong>
<ul>
<li>Shares a friend&rsquo;s investment story. This friend works at Apple and previously held steadfast belief in real estate and cash investments. However, recent issues like property taxes have awakened them to the importance of QQQ. Concerns about Apple stock&rsquo;s risk have led them to hesitate about stock pledges.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question:</strong> This friend holds a large quantity of Apple stock. How can they convert it into QQQ, and how should they approach a stock pledge?
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response:</strong>
<ul>
<li>The maximum long-term capital gains tax is 20%, regardless of income. James recommends that this friend sell a portion of their Apple stock sooner rather than later, converting it into QQQ to mitigate individual stock risk and reduce future tax burdens.</li>
<li>A gradual sale of Apple stock is advised, such as selling 10% or 20% each year or only selling the appreciated portion to minimize tax liability.</li>
<li>A stock pledge can be utilized for tax payments, for instance, borrowing 20% for tax obligations while reinvesting the remaining funds to enhance investment efficiency.</li>
<li>James suggests experimenting with a stock pledge, such as borrowing 2% for personal use, to gain firsthand experience with the convenience of borrowing.</li>
<li>He emphasizes the critical role of cash. A higher proportion of cash or cash-equivalent assets translates to greater risk tolerance for the investment portfolio.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Jenny:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing:</strong>
<ul>
<li>Owns multiple properties but has refrained from selling due to tax deductions and rising rental income.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question 1:</strong> Should she sell her properties?
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response:</strong> Real estate investments lack the return and liquidity offered by QQQ and potentially face substantial inheritance taxes in the future. Selling the properties is advised. Property taxes, maintenance costs, insurance fees, and more erode the returns from real estate investments. Moreover, real estate is illiquid, requiring time for liquidation. Properties, as inheritance, subject heirs to hefty inheritance taxes, potentially creating an insurmountable financial burden.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question 2:</strong> How can she convert to a Roth IRA?
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response:</strong> A Backdoor Roth IRA conversion is an option, involving initially depositing funds into a Traditional IRA and subsequently converting them to a Roth IRA.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question 3:</strong> Can property tax deductions and rising rental income offset the costs associated with real estate investment?
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response:</strong> The deductible amount for property taxes is limited. Moreover, income from rent increases is subject to income tax and cannot fully offset the costs tied to real estate investment.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question 4:</strong> Concerns about mortgages and trusts.
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response:</strong> If a mortgage is obtained under an individual&rsquo;s name, even placing the property within a trust cannot circumvent inheritance taxes. Using an LLC (Limited Liability Company) for property purchase from the outset is recommended, or transferring the property into an irrevocable trust before death to avoid inheritance tax liabilities.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Professor Zhou:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing:</strong>
<ul>
<li>Shares personal and sibling investment experiences. His sister, after experiencing investment losses, is hesitant to redeem her insurance policy. Jenny, due to returns from real estate investment, is reluctant to sell her properties. This illustrates how investors often fall prey to sunk cost and opportunity cost fallacies.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question:</strong> How can we enlighten ourselves and those around us to avoid such investment pitfalls?
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response:</strong> Understanding the concepts of sunk cost and opportunity cost is essential. Losses from investments should be cut promptly, avoiding attachment to past investments. Seek superior investment opportunities. While Jenny&rsquo;s real estate investment generates cash flow, its return is low, and it may face high inheritance taxes in the future. Therefore, she should consider selling the property and investing in higher-yielding assets like QQQ.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Bart:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Question:</strong> Issues connecting to the room.
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response:</strong> Recommends force-quitting the app and re-entering the room before raising a hand.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Daisy253:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing:</strong>
<ul>
<li>New to financial management, past investments were haphazard, primarily focused on real estate and insurance.</li>
<li>45 years old, with an 18-year-old daughter and a 14-year-old son, can invest NT$80,000 monthly. NT$10,000 is allocated to children&rsquo;s savings, with the remaining NT$70,000 for personal investment, aiming for rapid asset accumulation to reach NT$10 million.</li>
<li>Owns a rental property generating NT$30,000-40,000 in net monthly income, with principal invested ranging from NT$2 to 3 million, and the property valued at NT$3 to 4 million.</li>
<li>Children lean towards a &ldquo;non-marriage&rdquo; ideology, expressing no desire for offspring.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question:</strong> How should assets be allocated, and how can children be guided towards sound financial management principles?
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response:</strong>
<ul>
<li>Suggests referencing the article James provided, titled &ldquo;Individuals Still Some Time Away from Retirement,&rdquo; and adopting a BETA 1.2 asset allocation strategy.</li>
<li>Advises against giving children excessive funds at present. Instead, encourage them to save independently once they have a stable income, guiding them to establish proper financial management habits.</li>
<li>Proposes incentivizing children to marry and have children by offering NT$1 million annually in the future.</li>
<li>Emphasizes that 00864B cannot be replaced by 0056. Cash is cash and should not be substituted with stocks.</li>
<li>Underscores the significance of marriage and childbearing, advising early marriage and parenthood, urging them not to be bound by financial anxieties.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Xie Weiya:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing:</strong>
<ul>
<li>Recounts the story of a friend working at Apple. This friend steadfastly believed in real estate and cash as investments but recently recognized the importance of QQQ due to concerns like property taxes. However, they remain apprehensive about the risks associated with Apple stock and hesitate to engage in stock pledges.</li>
<li>This friend maintains a high spending level but undoubtedly possesses the financial capacity for retirement. They simply derive great enjoyment from work.</li>
<li>The friend has already contacted Lisa and is preparing for a stock pledge.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question:</strong>  This friend holds a substantial amount of Apple stock. How can they convert it into QQQ, and how should they approach a stock pledge?
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response:</strong>
<ul>
<li>The maximum long-term capital gains tax is 20%, independent of income. James recommends selling a portion of their Apple stock as soon as possible, converting it to QQQ to mitigate individual stock risk and reduce future tax burdens.</li>
<li>A gradual sale of Apple stock is advised, such as 10% or 20% each year, or selling only the appreciated portion to minimize tax liability.</li>
<li>Utilizing a stock pledge for tax payments is suggested, such as borrowing 20% for tax obligations while reinvesting the remaining funds to enhance investment efficiency.</li>
<li>James encourages them to experiment with a stock pledge, perhaps borrowing 2% for personal use, to experience the convenience of borrowing firsthand.</li>
<li>He highlights the vital role of cash. A higher proportion of cash or cash-equivalent assets translates to greater risk tolerance for the investment portfolio.</li>
<li>James advises this friend to learn from investment approaches employed by individuals like Warren Buffett and Wei Ying-ch’ung, leveraging credit for investment purposes.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Sunny:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Question:</strong> How should labor pension funds be withdrawn?
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response:</strong> If proficient in investment, withdrawing the entire labor pension fund at once and investing it in high-yielding assets like QQQ is recommended.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Wu Liyun:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Question:</strong> Is NT$5 million in stocks and cash sufficient for retirement?
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response:</strong>  NT$5 million in assets is insufficient to support a comfortable retirement. Withdrawing a labor pension monthly to supplement retirement income is recommended.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Nana:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Question:</strong> Concerns regarding genetic screening.
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response:</strong> Genetic screening is recommended to identify any potential genetic defects.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>College Student:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Question:</strong> Concerns about Backdoor Roth IRA.
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response:</strong> College students, lacking income, do not require a Backdoor Roth IRA. Directly depositing funds into a Roth IRA is suitable.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Jessie:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing:</strong> Has 1099 income.</li>
<li><strong>Question:</strong> Can 1099 income be deposited into a Traditional IRA?
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response:</strong>  Yes, 1099 income is eligible for deposit into a Traditional IRA. Additionally, a Backdoor Roth IRA can be executed using a spouse&rsquo;s W2 income.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">IV. Key Takeaways 
    <div id="iv-key-takeaways" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv-key-takeaways" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p><strong>Young individuals should be bold in using borrowed funds for investment to accelerate wealth accumulation.</strong>
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Young people are in their prime earning years, with steadily increasing income. They can utilize tools like credit loans to access low-cost capital for investing in high-return assets like QQQ, thereby speeding up their wealth-building journey.</p>
<blockquote>
<p><strong>Cash is the cornerstone ensuring investors can continue investing.</strong>
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Market volatility is a constant. Maintaining sufficient cash or cash-equivalent assets helps investors navigate market fluctuations with ease, preventing panic-driven asset sales, ultimately achieving long-term investment objectives.</p>
<blockquote>
<p><strong>Exercise prudence in investments. Avoid excessive diversification or venturing into unfamiliar domains.</strong>
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Focus investments within familiar areas. Refrain from blindly pursuing diversification or investing in unfamiliar domains, such as real estate or REITs.</p>
<blockquote>
<p><strong>The essence of US dollar hegemony lies in the US leveraging its control over vital resource trading, like oil, to sustain the dollar&rsquo;s global dominance.</strong>
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>By mandating US dollar settlements for global oil transactions, the US compels other nations to hold dollar reserves, solidifying its global currency dominance.</p>
<blockquote>
<p><strong>Marriage serves the purpose of creating life to carry on the universe&rsquo;s legacy. Loving one&rsquo;s partner as one would love their own child is paramount to a successful marriage.</strong>
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>The significance of marriage lies in procreation and the continuation of life. Loving one&rsquo;s partner deeply, treating them as one would treat their own child, is crucial for a lasting and fulfilling marriage.</p>
<blockquote>
<p><strong>Childbearing lies at the heart of life&rsquo;s meaning. Young individuals should marry and have children early, unburdened by financial pressures.</strong>
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Childbearing is inherent to human nature and the perpetuation of life. Young people should courageously embrace the responsibility of parenthood, refusing to be deterred by financial concerns.</p>
<blockquote>
<p><strong>Investors often fall prey to sunk cost and opportunity cost fallacies.</strong>
&ndash; Professor Zhou</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Sunk costs refer to incurred expenses that are irretrievable, such as purchased stocks or real estate. Opportunity cost represents the potential gains foregone by choosing one investment over other available options. During decision-making, investors should not be swayed by sunk costs; instead, they should prioritize opportunity cost, selecting investments offering higher returns.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">V. Conclusion 
    <div id="v-conclusion" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#v-conclusion" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This session revolves around the anticipated new highs in the investment market. James encourages listeners to solidify their investment confidence and enter the market promptly. He meticulously explains various asset allocation strategies, emphasizing the use of leveraged funds and the paramount importance of cash reserves. He also delves into the nature of US dollar hegemony and its global economic implications, sharing his personal views on marriage and childbearing. The Q&amp;A segment addresses questions encompassing asset allocation, stock pledges, retirement planning, investment strategies, and more, making it a content-rich and insightful session.</p>

  



<div
  
    class="flex px-4 py-3 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900"
  >

  <span
    
      class="text-primary-400 ltr:pr-3 rtl:pl-3 flex items-center"
    >

    

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M506.3 417l-213.3-364c-16.33-28-57.54-28-73.98 0l-213.2 364C-10.59 444.9 9.849 480 42.74 480h426.6C502.1 480 522.6 445 506.3 417zM232 168c0-13.25 10.75-24 24-24S280 154.8 280 168v128c0 13.25-10.75 24-23.1 24S232 309.3 232 296V168zM256 416c-17.36 0-31.44-14.08-31.44-31.44c0-17.36 14.07-31.44 31.44-31.44s31.44 14.08 31.44 31.44C287.4 401.9 273.4 416 256 416z"/></svg>

  </span>


  </span>

  <span
    
      class="dark:text-neutral-300"
    ><strong>Disclaimer:</strong> This article is for personal learning purposes only and does not constitute any investment advice.</span>
</div>

]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>00486 Market Trends and Future Investment Strategies: Navigating the New Economic Era</title>
      <link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1728231523948/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1728231523948/</guid>
      <description>In this session, James shares his analysis of the current market situation and investment advice. He also answers questions from the audience on topics like asset allocation, retirement planning, children&amp;#39;s education, handling stock options, leverage, and tax planning.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<lite-youtube videoid="mwchPrvkFMA" playlabel="mwchPrvkFMA" params=""></lite-youtube>



<h2 class="relative group">I. Main Topic 
    <div id="i-main-topic" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-main-topic" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>The theme of this session is <strong>Embrace the New Bull Market and Invest Long-Term.</strong> James believes that the global monetary easing policy and the rapid development of AI technology herald the arrival of a new bull market. He advises everyone to invest in the Nasdaq 100 index fund (QQQ or 00662) and view market fluctuations with a long-term perspective.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">II.  Content Summary 
    <div id="ii--content-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii--content-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<ul>
<li><strong>A new bull market is coming:</strong>  The world has entered an era of loose monetary policy with the start of a rate cut cycle, which will drive the stock market up. This bull market may be a slow one but will continuously rise.</li>
<li><strong>Invest confidently in the Nasdaq 100 index fund:</strong> QQQ could increase by 50 times in the next 20 years, with an annualized return of over 20%, making it the best investment target.</li>
<li><strong>Individual stocks are unreliable:</strong> Individual stock investment is risky, and in the long run, almost all of them will disappear. They are very difficult to outperform the market in the long term. It is recommended not to waste time and energy on stock selection.</li>
<li><strong>Do not invest in the Chinese stock market:</strong> The Chinese stock market is not mature enough; consider investing in it after 30 years.</li>
<li><strong>Comparison of household asset allocation in the US and Taiwan:</strong>  American families invest most of their assets in securities to create social value, while Taiwanese families prefer cash, insurance, and real estate, locking up funds in non-appreciating areas.</li>
<li><strong>Leveraging through stock pledges:</strong> Using stock pledges to borrow increases liquidity and allows for continued investment to enjoy the benefits of compound growth. With an understanding of asset allocation, the interest cost of borrowing can be almost negligible.</li>
<li><strong>Plan for retirement early:</strong> Young people are advised to invest in 00662, and retirees can choose 00646 (SPY) or 0056 according to their fund size.</li>
<li><strong>Emphasize family education:</strong> Parents should cultivate their children&rsquo;s financial management concepts from an early age, guide them to make long-term investments, stay away from bad habits such as short-term speculation and gambling, and lead by example.</li>
<li><strong>Don&rsquo;t blindly trust high-yield investment products:</strong> Any investment product promising high returns may be a scam. It is important to understand its operating mechanism and learn to discern between true and false.</li>
<li><strong>The dangers of short-term trading:</strong> Short-term trading will miss the best investment opportunities. Long-term investment in index funds will yield more stable returns.</li>
<li><strong>The purpose of cash allocation:</strong> It is not for profit, but for dealing with emergencies like unemployment or a market crash. It is advisable to keep more than 10% of your assets in cash.</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">III. Q&amp;A Session 
    <div id="iii-qa-session" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii-qa-session" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<ul>
<li>
<p><strong>Retired Doctor Poch:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: After learning about James&rsquo; investment philosophy, he found a more relaxing and suitable investment method.</li>
<li>Question: How to obtain a stable cash flow after retirement? Is it necessary to adjust the investment strategy of 00662?
<ul>
<li>Answer:  The investment target can be adjusted according to the size of the retirement fund. Choose 00646 (SPY) or 0056 with lower volatility to guarantee cash flow.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>IM:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: He tried to guide his child to invest by matching contributions and increased his vigilance against high-yield traps.</li>
<li>Question 1: How to guide a child to invest and prevent them from spending investment income?
<ul>
<li>Answer: Emphasize that investment is a long-term behavior. Income cannot be withdrawn for consumption. Funds should grow continuously through compound interest.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2: How to choose a safe and reliable trust company? How to avoid the traps of high-yield trust products?
<ul>
<li>Answer: Any trust company that promises high returns may be a scam. You should take control of your own investment and financial management rights, clearly stipulate investment in index funds in the trust clause, and set up a regulatory unit to ensure fund security.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Rose:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: She frankly talked about her past investment failures and the process of gradually establishing the correct investment concept under the guidance of James.</li>
<li>Question 1: What are the differences and pros and cons of Margin Loan and Pledge Loan?  The interest rate of Margin Loan from IB is relatively low. Is it necessary to transfer to Charles Schwab for Pledge Loan?
<ul>
<li>Answer:  Margin Loan is riskier, and Pledge Loan is relatively safe. If the interest rate of IB&rsquo;s Margin Loan is low, you can continue to use it, but pay attention to controlling the borrowing ratio, preferably no more than 20%.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2: The return on cash allocation will decrease in the interest rate cut cycle. Is it still necessary to allocate cash?
<ul>
<li>Answer: The purpose of cash allocation is not for profit but to deal with contingencies, such as unemployment or a market crash. It is advisable to keep more than 10% of your assets in cash.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 3: How to manage children&rsquo;s investment accounts? Under whose name should it be, yours or the child&rsquo;s?
<ul>
<li>Answer: It is recommended to open an account in the child&rsquo;s name to cultivate their financial management concept, but control the amount and provide proper investment guidance. Estate planning can be done after the child becomes an adult.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Phoenix:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: He shared his confusion about handling company stock options and finally adopted James&rsquo; suggestion.</li>
<li>Question 1: How to deal with the stock options of unlisted companies?
<ul>
<li>Answer: If the company has a high possibility of going public, it is recommended to sell it to an investment company before the listing to get cash and invest in QQQ.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2: What do you think of Bitcoin? Can I invest in it?
<ul>
<li>Answer: If you already hold a small amount of Bitcoin, you can continue to hold it, but do not invest any more capital. It is recommended to focus on investing in QQQ.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Allen:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: He shared his questions about 401k and stock investment and eventually made adjustments under James&rsquo; advice.</li>
<li>Question 1: What should I do if I have too much money in my 401k account?
<ul>
<li>Answer:  It is recommended to stop making further contributions to 401k and transfer some funds to the Roth IRA account through the Backdoor Roth IRA.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2: How to switch from holding Nvidia stock to QQQ?
<ul>
<li>Answer: Sell Nvidia stock as soon as possible, transfer funds to QQQ, and pledge stocks to borrow money to pay taxes.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Haoqing:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: He demonstrated the difficulty of stock selection through data analysis and illustrated the advantages of long-term investment in QQQ with practical examples.</li>
<li>Question: Can stock picking beat QQQ?
<ul>
<li>Answer: Stock selection is difficult to outperform QQQ in the long run. Even if it beats the market in the short term, transaction costs and taxes need to be considered.  Invest in index funds for the long term.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Xiang:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: He shared his confusion about saving for children&rsquo;s education and inheritance and finally found a solution under James&rsquo; advice.</li>
<li>Question 1: Is it better to use a 529 Education Fund or invest in QQQ for children&rsquo;s education savings?
<ul>
<li>Answer:  Investing in QQQ is recommended because it has higher long-term returns and is more flexible.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2: How to do estate planning?
<ul>
<li>Answer:  For larger estates, it is recommended to set up an irrevocable trust and consult an estate lawyer for planning.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Kevin:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Frankly admitted his past investment failures and regained confidence under the guidance of James, starting to embark on the road of steady investment.</li>
<li>Question: How many listeners are losing money on investments?
<ul>
<li>Answer: Past investment experience is not important. What is important is to establish the correct investment concept and believe in the value of long-term investment in index funds.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Julia:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Shared her lessons learned from investing in Chinese concept stocks and second-tier growth stocks, and how to guide children to make long-term investments.</li>
<li>Question 1: How to deal with losses caused by investment in Chinese concept stocks and second-tier growth stocks?
- Answer: It is advisable to &ldquo;cut your losses&rdquo; and switch funds to QQQ in a timely manner.</li>
<li>Question 2: How to guide children to make long-term investments?
- Answer: You can use an investment calculator to show children the power of compound interest and guide them with your own investment experience.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Peter:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Shared his experience working at Apple and confirmed that many high-income earners also choose to invest in index funds.</li>
<li>Question: How to balance family expenses and investment?
- Answer: It is recommended to use stock pledges to borrow money to meet living expenses and continue investing in QQQ, so that assets can continue to grow through compound interest.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Jason:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: He shared his confusion about company tax declaration and finally found a suitable solution under James&rsquo; advice.</li>
<li>Question: How to choose the tax filing method?
<ul>
<li>Answer: If your income is low, you can choose to file a 1099; if your income is high, you are advised to establish an S Corporation.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Cindy:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Shared her experience of guiding her child to invest in Roth IRA and keep away from gambling.</li>
<li>Question: How to guide children to invest in Roth IRA? How to guide children to stay away from gambling?
<ul>
<li>Answer: Open a Roth IRA account for the child and make matching contributions. Lead by example and educate your child with the experiences and stories of people around you.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">IV.  Highlights 
    <div id="iv--highlights" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv--highlights" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>Lending is more powerful than the atomic bomb; it&rsquo;s ten times the atomic bomb!
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>When encouraging people to use stock pledges for borrowing and investment, James used this analogy to vividly illustrate the power of leverage.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Investing should be easy and fun.
&ndash;  Hola</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This is what a listener said when she shared her investment experience. She also tried short-term trading, but finally found that long-term investment suited her better.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Each person has a different destiny when it comes to money.
&ndash; Peter</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Peter said this thought-provoking sentence when he shared his experience of persuading his father to invest in QQQ. This also reflects that investment and financial management should be combined with one&rsquo;s own situation to find a suitable way.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>All the money in the world is mine; you just need to take it and use it.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>James used humorous words to express his confidence in the market when encouraging everyone to invest, which also reflects his optimistic and positive attitude towards life.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">V. Conclusion 
    <div id="v-conclusion" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#v-conclusion" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>In this live broadcast, James once again emphasized the concept of long-term investment in index funds. He also provided specific investment advice for the audience based on the current market situation, covering asset allocation, retirement planning, children&rsquo;s education, stock options handling, leverage, and tax planning. The sharing from the students provided other listeners with valuable reference experience, showing their growth and earnings during the process of learning about investment and financial management.</p>

  



<div
  
    class="flex px-4 py-3 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900"
  >

  <span
    
      class="text-primary-400 ltr:pr-3 rtl:pl-3 flex items-center"
    >

    

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M506.3 417l-213.3-364c-16.33-28-57.54-28-73.98 0l-213.2 364C-10.59 444.9 9.849 480 42.74 480h426.6C502.1 480 522.6 445 506.3 417zM232 168c0-13.25 10.75-24 24-24S280 154.8 280 168v128c0 13.25-10.75 24-23.1 24S232 309.3 232 296V168zM256 416c-17.36 0-31.44-14.08-31.44-31.44c0-17.36 14.07-31.44 31.44-31.44s31.44 14.08 31.44 31.44C287.4 401.9 273.4 416 256 416z"/></svg>

  </span>


  </span>

  <span
    
      class="dark:text-neutral-300"
    ><strong>Disclaimer:</strong> This article is only for personal learning notes and does not constitute any investment advice.</span>
</div>

]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
