<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Retirement Planning on QQQ Investor</title>
    <link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/tags/retirement-planning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Retirement Planning on QQQ Investor</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jomonylw.github.io/en/tags/retirement-planning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>00490 Workers are just picking up trash; Mortgages are a risk for retirees; Buying a house won&#39;t make you rich.</title>
      <link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1730597712367/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1730597712367/</guid>
      <description>This session focuses on investment philosophy, asset allocation, lifestyle, and how to cope with market fluctuations. It emphasizes the importance of staying optimistic, continuous learning, and answers questions from the audience on Bitcoin, real estate, retirement planning, leveraged funds, and education funds.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<lite-youtube videoid="Ad9u7a-z6Ro" playlabel="Ad9u7a-z6Ro" params=""></lite-youtube>



<h2 class="relative group">I. Main Topic 
    <div id="i-main-topic" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-main-topic" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This session revolves around investment and life planning. The core ideas are: be optimistic about investment and keep learning, ignoring short-term market fluctuations; young people should focus on asset appreciation, with Nasdaq 100 index funds being the top choice; utilize leverage and allocate assets reasonably; retirees should plan carefully and avoid excessive debt; and one should stay optimistic and confident, avoid material comparisons, and pursue true freedom.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">II. Presentation Content 
    <div id="ii-presentation-content" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii-presentation-content" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Investment Philosophy and Market Analysis 
    <div id="investment-philosophy-and-market-analysis" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#investment-philosophy-and-market-analysis" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Market Fluctuations and Investment Mentality:</strong> The market is always fluctuating. Don&rsquo;t let short-term fluctuations affect your investment decisions. Stay optimistic.</li>
<li><strong>Currency Devaluation and Asset Appreciation:</strong> Money depreciates; only assets like stocks can preserve and increase in value. Currency devaluation is more severe in emerging countries, so it is advised to convert currency into assets. Taiwan&rsquo;s low wages and currency devaluation are related to the government&rsquo;s subsidy policies.</li>
<li><strong>Worker Mindset vs. Capitalist Mindset:</strong> Workers exchange labor for depreciating currency, while capitalists exchange currency for appreciating assets. Learn to invest and become a capitalist, exchanging &ldquo;trash&rdquo; (depreciating currency) for assets.</li>
<li><strong>Global Market Linkage:</strong> Global markets are highly interconnected, and diversifying investments into other regions has limited effectiveness. Focusing on the US stock market is recommended.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Asset Allocation Strategies 
    <div id="asset-allocation-strategies" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#asset-allocation-strategies" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Nasdaq 100 Index Funds:</strong> The preferred choice for young people. Long-term investment can yield substantial returns.  Global codes for purchasing Nasdaq 100 index funds were provided, and investing based on market conditions is recommended.</li>
<li><strong>The Importance of Cash:</strong> Cash reserves are crucial. 00864B and money market funds (like SWVXX, VOXX) are safeguards and should not be replaced with high-dividend products like SPHD, as principal safety is paramount.</li>
<li><strong>Smart Rebalancing:</strong> Suitable for those who use leveraged funds, are not retired, and have income.</li>
<li><strong>Risks of Real Estate Investment:</strong> Housing prices in the Bay Area are high, putting great pressure on young people to buy houses, which can easily lead to financial difficulties. Renting is recommended to maintain flexibility.</li>
<li><strong>Borrowing and Investment:</strong> Loans, mortgages, and car loans should be repaid with stable cash flow, not relying on stock market returns.</li>
<li><strong>Retirement Planning:</strong> Retirees should be cautious about borrowing and make plans based on the size of their retirement funds.  If retirement funds are 50 times the annual expenses, two options are available: 1. Keep the mortgage and car loan, using 2% of the retirement fund annually to cover all expenses; 2. Pay off the mortgage and car loan, invest 80% of the remaining funds in 00662, 20% in 00864B, and use 2% of the total funds annually for living expenses.</li>
<li><strong>Asset Allocation Case Study:</strong> A case study with 45 million Taiwan dollars illustrated asset allocation strategies when withdrawals are not needed. An 80/20 allocation or a combination of leveraged funds (60% 00662, 20% 00670L, 20% 00864B) is recommended.  For those with stable income and no need to withdraw from investments, 100% investment in QQQ can be considered.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Other Matters 
    <div id="other-matters" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#other-matters" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Class Suspension Notice:</strong> Class is suspended on November 9th and resumes on November 16th. After daylight saving time ends, the class time will be changed to 6:00 AM Pacific Time and 10:00 PM Taiwan time.</li>
<li><strong>Stay Optimistic:</strong> Maintain an optimistic mindset; the market will reward you. Like, subscribe, and leave comments on various platforms to benefit more people.</li>
<li><strong>Contact Information:</strong> Two email addresses were provided for contact.</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">III. Q&amp;A Session 
    <div id="iii-qa-session" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii-qa-session" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Brian: 
    <div id="brian" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#brian" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing 1: Read &ldquo;Investing is Asset Allocation, What You Don&rsquo;t Know,&rdquo; agreeing with the importance of accumulating the first pot of gold early; learning investment allows for more focus on work and personal improvement, spending time each day learning new skills and increasing self-worth.  Investment enables people to be more motivated to improve their professional skills rather than &ldquo;lying flat.&rdquo;</li>
<li>Sharing 2: Individuals can improve their earning potential through learning, even if their investment assets are reduced to zero, they can still rely on professional skills to make a comeback.</li>
<li>Question 1: What should I do if the Beta value is very low when the asset value plummets in the Excel sheet?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: The sheet is designed for acceleration during market rises and deceleration during falls. A low Beta value is normal and a reflection of risk control; no adjustment is needed.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2: Even knowing that investment should be mindless, I still worry when the Beta value drops. How should I cope?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: Deceleration during declines is the purpose of the investment strategy. Don&rsquo;t worry, stick to the plan, just like autopilot.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">LU: 
    <div id="lu" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#lu" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question 1: What is the impact of Trump&rsquo;s potential return to office on Bitcoin?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: The US has abandoned the gold standard and will not adopt a Bitcoin standard. Bitcoin is similar to gold and has an anti-inflationary function, but its future development is limited.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2: Can QQQ break through its previous high?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: It definitely can. The current market is bullish; there&rsquo;s no need to worry.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Wendy: 
    <div id="wendy" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#wendy" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing 1: Learned James&rsquo;s investment philosophy and successfully recouped the income lost during unemployment. Started reading recommended books such as &ldquo;The Richest Man in Babylon&rdquo; and &ldquo;The Most Important Thing.&rdquo;</li>
<li>No Questions</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Peter: 
    <div id="peter" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#peter" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing 1: Agrees with James&rsquo;s philosophy and has increased the investment proportion of QQQ, but some individual stocks have not been completely sold due to tax reasons.</li>
<li>Question 1: Advantages and disadvantages of converting 401K to Roth 401K?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: Just put new contributions into Roth 401K; don&rsquo;t convert existing funds. Convert at retirement.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2:  How to use HSA and 529 accounts?  Is there any problem with using a credit card to pay medical bills from an HSA?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply:  HSA, 529, and college fund accounts are not recommended because they lead to a loss of control over the funds. Using your own funds or loans is recommended.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 3: Are there any suggestions for increasing income and saving money besides a full-time job?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: Excessive saving is not recommended. Plan for retirement funds first, and the remaining money can be freely used and enjoyed.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Yi Jie (First Sister): 
    <div id="yi-jie-first-sister" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#yi-jie-first-sister" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing 1: Previously followed the advice of online influencers and invested in US stocks and treasury bonds, currently converting to QQQ.  Has a modest salary and one child.</li>
<li>Question 1: Can the 20% cash in the 80/20 allocation be replaced with Fubon 50 2X leverage?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply:  QQQ 2X leverage (00670L) is recommended. He explained the use of leveraged funds.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2: Is it feasible to regularly invest equal amounts in QQQ and 2X leverage?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: Feasible, but pay attention to cash reserves. A Beta of 1.1 or 1.2 allocation is recommended, adjusting according to market conditions.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 3: Can a child&rsquo;s Lunar New Year money be all-in on 2X leverage?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: If you can guarantee continuous regular investment for more than 30 years, it&rsquo;s worth considering, but be aware of the risks and be able to withstand significant asset shrinkage.  In the long run, the returns can be substantial, but psychological barriers must be overcome.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 4: Are the views of online influencers recommending treasury bonds correct? Are treasury bonds more valuable during a market crash?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: Incorrect. During market downturns, bond declines can be even greater.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">IAM: 
    <div id="iam" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iam" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing 1: Reflecting on the value of money, learning gratitude, and paying attention to community articles, realizing that spending money is spending one&rsquo;s life energy.</li>
<li>Sharing 2: Made 100 pages of notes and calculated the return on an 80,000 loan invested for 40 years; the result was shocking.</li>
<li>Question 1: Why are people not accustomed to borrowing for investment?  Confused about the phenomenon of young people being afraid to borrow for investment but willing to use installment plans for consumption.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: This is due to cultural influences.  Change your mindset and recognize that good debt can help accumulate wealth. Shared personal experiences and spending philosophy, emphasizing the freedom of spending after becoming wealthy.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">YJ Yuanlin: 
    <div id="yj-yuanlin" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#yj-yuanlin" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing 1: Investing boosts confidence, enabling focus on work and hobbies.</li>
<li>Question 1: In a down year, can TQQ replace QLD in smart rebalancing?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: Both are possible, but pay attention to risk control and avoid excessive pursuit of high risk. TQQ has greater volatility and requires a stronger psychological capacity.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">T: 
    <div id="t" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#t" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question 1: What are your thoughts on Elon Musk supporting Trump?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: Politicians&rsquo; decisions are the result of weighing pros and cons. Elon Musk&rsquo;s support for Trump stems from personal interests and positions, such as opposing certain liberal policies.  Entrepreneurs also have to choose between different political forces.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Yi Ni: 
    <div id="yi-ni" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#yi-ni" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question 1: How to invest and use Canadian education fund accounts?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: It&rsquo;s recommended to thoroughly research the specific rules of the account and consider methods like pledged loans to avoid locking up funds. Inquired about whether it&rsquo;s possible to withdraw all funds and the limitations, suggesting consulting with professionals.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Meng: 
    <div id="meng" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#meng" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing 1: In the high-tech era, privacy and freedom are difficult to have both.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Peter: 
    <div id="peter-1" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#peter-1" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing 1: It can be difficult for beginners to invest in QQQ, etc. It&rsquo;s suggested to start by buying one share and gradually build confidence.  James&rsquo;s explanations are very patient and benefit everyone.</li>
<li>Question 1: How to strengthen mental and psychological well-being?  James&rsquo;s experience sharing on meditation and hypnosis.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: Recommended Rachel&rsquo;s hypnosis channel and shared personal methods of using hypnosis and positive psychological suggestions. Suggested listening to hypnotic audios every night before sleep.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">IV. Key Takeaways 
    <div id="iv-key-takeaways" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv-key-takeaways" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>Rise faster, fall slower.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This is one of James&rsquo;s core investment philosophies. Through smart rebalancing strategies, increase investment during market rises to accelerate profits, and reduce investment during market downturns to mitigate losses.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Money is the least valuable thing when it has no value.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This reflects James&rsquo;s unique view on wealth. When wealth accumulates to a certain extent, the value of money itself is no longer important; what matters more is pursuing freedom and happiness.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>If you want freedom, and you want privacy, you will not have freedom. In the future world, if you want privacy, you will not have freedom.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This shows James&rsquo;s insight into future social trends. In the high-tech era, one needs to make trade-offs between privacy and freedom.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The more daring one is to borrow money, the broader their perspective.
&ndash; YJ Yuanlin</p>
</blockquote>
<p>YJ Yuanlin&rsquo;s sharing led to James&rsquo;s views on borrowing: good debt can help wealth growth.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>If you want freedom, you cannot care.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Echoing the topic of Elon Musk supporting Trump and the entrepreneurial spirit, true freedom is not caring about external opinions and focusing on one&rsquo;s goals.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>If you don&rsquo;t use ChatGPT now, you are outdated and will be eliminated.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>James advocates for new technologies and maintains an open attitude towards learning new things.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">V. Summary 
    <div id="v-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#v-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This session covered various aspects of investment philosophy, asset allocation, lifestyle, and how to cope with market fluctuations.  James answered the audience&rsquo;s questions with easy-to-understand language and rich examples, sharing his life experiences and insights, and encouraging everyone to stay optimistic, continue learning, and pursue true freedom and happiness.</p>

  



<div
  
    class="flex px-4 py-3 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900"
  >

  <span
    
      class="text-primary-400 ltr:pr-3 rtl:pl-3 flex items-center"
    >

    

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M506.3 417l-213.3-364c-16.33-28-57.54-28-73.98 0l-213.2 364C-10.59 444.9 9.849 480 42.74 480h426.6C502.1 480 522.6 445 506.3 417zM232 168c0-13.25 10.75-24 24-24S280 154.8 280 168v128c0 13.25-10.75 24-23.1 24S232 309.3 232 296V168zM256 416c-17.36 0-31.44-14.08-31.44-31.44c0-17.36 14.07-31.44 31.44-31.44s31.44 14.08 31.44 31.44C287.4 401.9 273.4 416 256 416z"/></svg>

  </span>


  </span>

  <span
    
      class="dark:text-neutral-300"
    ><strong>Disclaimer:</strong> This article is for personal learning notes only and does not constitute any investment advice.</span>
</div>

]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>00489 US Dollar Hegemony and the Sorrow of Trade Surplus Countries; Investing in QQQ Outperforms SPY</title>
      <link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1730069768515/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1730069768515/</guid>
      <description>In this session, James begins by analyzing the current investment market, pointing out that it&amp;#39;s poised to hit new highs. He advises listeners to solidify their investment confidence and enter the market sooner rather than later. James then delves into a research paper discussing asset portfolios comprising leveraged funds, cash, QQQ, and SPY. He analyzes the risks and returns associated with various investment portfolios, emphasizing the critical role of cash allocation. He addresses questions from participants regarding asset allocation, stock pledges, retirement planning, investment strategies, and the US dollar&amp;#39;s global dominance. He also shares his personal views on marriage and having children.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<lite-youtube videoid="eOh-hu1X0jo" playlabel="eOh-hu1X0jo" params=""></lite-youtube>



<h2 class="relative group">I. Topic of the Day 
    <div id="i-topic-of-the-day" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-topic-of-the-day" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>The session focuses on the impending new highs anticipated in the investment market. James encourages everyone to bolster their investment confidence and enter the market early. He elaborates on various asset allocation strategies, particularly the use of leveraged funds and the significance of cash reserves. Additionally, James dives into the nature of US dollar hegemony and its implications for the global economy. He also shares his thoughts on marriage and childbearing.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">II. Briefing Content 
    <div id="ii-briefing-content" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii-briefing-content" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<ol>
<li>
<p><strong>The Market is About to Hit New Highs:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>The market is on the verge of reaching new highs. Entering early is more advantageous than waiting for the new highs to materialize.</li>
<li>Earnings reports from AI and high-tech sectors are projected to surpass expectations. Market funds and corporate profits are also expected to exceed projections.</li>
<li>The market consistently trends upward. Investment requires patience; wealth is worth the wait.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Interpreting the Asset Portfolio Research Paper:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Long-term bonds carry higher risks than stocks while yielding lower returns. Investment in them is not recommended.</strong></li>
<li><strong>QQQ offers superior returns and risk resistance compared to SPY.</strong></li>
<li><strong>Leveraged funds (e.g., QQQ2D) are characterized by high volatility, substantial downside risk, but also significant upside potential.</strong></li>
<li><strong>Intelligent asset allocation can achieve returns equivalent to a 100% QQQ portfolio while providing greater cash security.</strong></li>
<li><strong>Retirees or individuals without income are advised against using leveraged funds. An 80/20 asset allocation strategy is recommended.</strong></li>
<li><strong>Cash is the cornerstone ensuring investors can continue investing.</strong></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Additional Investment Advice and Experience Sharing:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Retirees should claim their social security benefits as early as possible and utilize them for investments.</li>
<li>Real estate is a liability; selling property for investment purposes is recommended. Avoiding mortgage loans against real estate is advised.</li>
<li>Young individuals can leverage credit loans for investments, accelerating wealth accumulation.</li>
<li>Exercise prudence in investments. Avoid excessive diversification or venturing into unfamiliar domains such as real estate or REITs.</li>
<li><strong>Investing in individual stocks is not advised. Opt for market capitalization-based index funds like QQQ.</strong></li>
<li>Experiencing substantial losses is a prerequisite to appreciating the allure of high returns. The market always presents risks, and one must learn to navigate them.</li>
<li>Short-term safe assets (e.g., treasury bills) are essential components of an investment portfolio, aiding investors in weathering market fluctuations.</li>
<li><strong>The higher the proportion of cash or cash-equivalent assets, the greater the risk tolerance of the investment portfolio.</strong></li>
<li><strong>Refrain from self-managing stock portfolios. The returns from most stocks fall short of those from treasury bills.</strong></li>
<li><strong>Stock index funds constantly face future risks. Embrace risk tolerance; only by weathering the storms can one see the sunshine.</strong></li>
<li><strong>Don&rsquo;t put faith in market predictions. During market downturns, &ldquo;stock gurus&rdquo; often emerge, but their predictions are frequently inaccurate.</strong></li>
<li><strong>Adhere to long-term investment principles. Avoid being swayed by short-term market fluctuations.</strong></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Marriage and Childbearing:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Marriage serves the purpose of creating life to carry on the universe&rsquo;s legacy. Loving one&rsquo;s partner as one would love their own child is paramount to a successful marriage.</li>
<li>Childbearing lies at the heart of life&rsquo;s meaning. Young individuals should marry and have children early, unburdened by financial pressures.</li>
<li>Even without marriage, childbearing should be considered. A life spent single and childless will ultimately lead to profound loneliness.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ol>


<h2 class="relative group">III. Q&amp;A Session 
    <div id="iii-qa-session" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii-qa-session" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p><strong>Mike:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing:</strong>
<ul>
<li>Mentions the Chinese government&rsquo;s strong push for policies akin to MMT (Modern Monetary Theory).</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question 1:</strong> Taiwan Semiconductor Manufacturing Company (TSMC) is not included in the Nasdaq 100 index, and the NYSE has extended its trading hours to 22 hours, while Nasdaq hasn&rsquo;t followed suit. Why?
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response:</strong> Nasdaq&rsquo;s trading hours are already standard. Extending trading hours only affects after-hours trading, holding little significance for ordinary investors. TSMC&rsquo;s exclusion from the Nasdaq 100 index is linked to factors such as trading costs.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question 2:</strong> How can MMT be explained to someone without financial expertise?
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response:</strong> James uses simple language to elucidate the relationship between government deficits and currency issuance. He asserts that governments can cover deficits by printing money without facing national bankruptcy. Using early American history and ancient barter systems as examples, he illustrates how governments utilize currency issuance to purchase goods and services, and how taxation maintains currency value. James emphasizes the essence of US dollar hegemony, highlighting that the US leverages its control over vital resource trading, like oil, to sustain the dollar&rsquo;s global dominance, citing Russia&rsquo;s forced use of dollars for oil purchases as an example. He also points out that the core nature of fiat currency is a representation of national sovereignty, enabling governments to mandate its use through legal means.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>IAM:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing:</strong>
<ul>
<li>Questions whether investing in QQQ also implies supporting &ldquo;rogue&rdquo; entities.</li>
<li>After comparing returns from QQQ and its top ten constituent stocks, IAM observed higher returns from the latter, leading to confusion about the role of the remaining 90 companies.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question 1:</strong> Does investing in QQQ equate to supporting &ldquo;rogue&rdquo; entities?
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response:</strong> We, as investors, are contributors. Through our investment in QQQ, we allocate capital to the 100 companies making the most significant contributions to humanity, propelling societal progress.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question 2:</strong> The top ten constituent stocks of QQQ generate higher returns; what is the purpose of the other 90 companies?
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response:</strong> The composition of QQQ&rsquo;s top ten holdings changes annually. Examining solely the past decade&rsquo;s data is insufficient. Companies previously ranked lower have the potential to enter the top ten, underscoring the vital role played by the remaining 90 companies.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question 3:</strong> Are companies ranked lower in QQQ&rsquo;s constituents at risk of being removed due to a decrease in their market capitalization percentage?
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response:</strong> Typically not, but QQQ mandates that the percentage of any individual constituent stock cannot exceed a specific threshold. Adjustments are made if this limit is surpassed.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question 4:</strong> How can one view the complete list of QQQ&rsquo;s constituent companies?
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response:</strong> This information can be accessed on websites like Yahoo Finance, which displays QQQ&rsquo;s holdings, or on QQQ&rsquo;s official website.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Chunxia:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing:</strong>
<ul>
<li>Shares a friend&rsquo;s investment story. This friend works at Apple and previously held steadfast belief in real estate and cash investments. However, recent issues like property taxes have awakened them to the importance of QQQ. Concerns about Apple stock&rsquo;s risk have led them to hesitate about stock pledges.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question:</strong> This friend holds a large quantity of Apple stock. How can they convert it into QQQ, and how should they approach a stock pledge?
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response:</strong>
<ul>
<li>The maximum long-term capital gains tax is 20%, regardless of income. James recommends that this friend sell a portion of their Apple stock sooner rather than later, converting it into QQQ to mitigate individual stock risk and reduce future tax burdens.</li>
<li>A gradual sale of Apple stock is advised, such as selling 10% or 20% each year or only selling the appreciated portion to minimize tax liability.</li>
<li>A stock pledge can be utilized for tax payments, for instance, borrowing 20% for tax obligations while reinvesting the remaining funds to enhance investment efficiency.</li>
<li>James suggests experimenting with a stock pledge, such as borrowing 2% for personal use, to gain firsthand experience with the convenience of borrowing.</li>
<li>He emphasizes the critical role of cash. A higher proportion of cash or cash-equivalent assets translates to greater risk tolerance for the investment portfolio.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Jenny:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing:</strong>
<ul>
<li>Owns multiple properties but has refrained from selling due to tax deductions and rising rental income.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question 1:</strong> Should she sell her properties?
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response:</strong> Real estate investments lack the return and liquidity offered by QQQ and potentially face substantial inheritance taxes in the future. Selling the properties is advised. Property taxes, maintenance costs, insurance fees, and more erode the returns from real estate investments. Moreover, real estate is illiquid, requiring time for liquidation. Properties, as inheritance, subject heirs to hefty inheritance taxes, potentially creating an insurmountable financial burden.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question 2:</strong> How can she convert to a Roth IRA?
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response:</strong> A Backdoor Roth IRA conversion is an option, involving initially depositing funds into a Traditional IRA and subsequently converting them to a Roth IRA.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question 3:</strong> Can property tax deductions and rising rental income offset the costs associated with real estate investment?
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response:</strong> The deductible amount for property taxes is limited. Moreover, income from rent increases is subject to income tax and cannot fully offset the costs tied to real estate investment.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question 4:</strong> Concerns about mortgages and trusts.
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response:</strong> If a mortgage is obtained under an individual&rsquo;s name, even placing the property within a trust cannot circumvent inheritance taxes. Using an LLC (Limited Liability Company) for property purchase from the outset is recommended, or transferring the property into an irrevocable trust before death to avoid inheritance tax liabilities.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Professor Zhou:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing:</strong>
<ul>
<li>Shares personal and sibling investment experiences. His sister, after experiencing investment losses, is hesitant to redeem her insurance policy. Jenny, due to returns from real estate investment, is reluctant to sell her properties. This illustrates how investors often fall prey to sunk cost and opportunity cost fallacies.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question:</strong> How can we enlighten ourselves and those around us to avoid such investment pitfalls?
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response:</strong> Understanding the concepts of sunk cost and opportunity cost is essential. Losses from investments should be cut promptly, avoiding attachment to past investments. Seek superior investment opportunities. While Jenny&rsquo;s real estate investment generates cash flow, its return is low, and it may face high inheritance taxes in the future. Therefore, she should consider selling the property and investing in higher-yielding assets like QQQ.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Bart:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Question:</strong> Issues connecting to the room.
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response:</strong> Recommends force-quitting the app and re-entering the room before raising a hand.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Daisy253:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing:</strong>
<ul>
<li>New to financial management, past investments were haphazard, primarily focused on real estate and insurance.</li>
<li>45 years old, with an 18-year-old daughter and a 14-year-old son, can invest NT$80,000 monthly. NT$10,000 is allocated to children&rsquo;s savings, with the remaining NT$70,000 for personal investment, aiming for rapid asset accumulation to reach NT$10 million.</li>
<li>Owns a rental property generating NT$30,000-40,000 in net monthly income, with principal invested ranging from NT$2 to 3 million, and the property valued at NT$3 to 4 million.</li>
<li>Children lean towards a &ldquo;non-marriage&rdquo; ideology, expressing no desire for offspring.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question:</strong> How should assets be allocated, and how can children be guided towards sound financial management principles?
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response:</strong>
<ul>
<li>Suggests referencing the article James provided, titled &ldquo;Individuals Still Some Time Away from Retirement,&rdquo; and adopting a BETA 1.2 asset allocation strategy.</li>
<li>Advises against giving children excessive funds at present. Instead, encourage them to save independently once they have a stable income, guiding them to establish proper financial management habits.</li>
<li>Proposes incentivizing children to marry and have children by offering NT$1 million annually in the future.</li>
<li>Emphasizes that 00864B cannot be replaced by 0056. Cash is cash and should not be substituted with stocks.</li>
<li>Underscores the significance of marriage and childbearing, advising early marriage and parenthood, urging them not to be bound by financial anxieties.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Xie Weiya:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing:</strong>
<ul>
<li>Recounts the story of a friend working at Apple. This friend steadfastly believed in real estate and cash as investments but recently recognized the importance of QQQ due to concerns like property taxes. However, they remain apprehensive about the risks associated with Apple stock and hesitate to engage in stock pledges.</li>
<li>This friend maintains a high spending level but undoubtedly possesses the financial capacity for retirement. They simply derive great enjoyment from work.</li>
<li>The friend has already contacted Lisa and is preparing for a stock pledge.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question:</strong>  This friend holds a substantial amount of Apple stock. How can they convert it into QQQ, and how should they approach a stock pledge?
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response:</strong>
<ul>
<li>The maximum long-term capital gains tax is 20%, independent of income. James recommends selling a portion of their Apple stock as soon as possible, converting it to QQQ to mitigate individual stock risk and reduce future tax burdens.</li>
<li>A gradual sale of Apple stock is advised, such as 10% or 20% each year, or selling only the appreciated portion to minimize tax liability.</li>
<li>Utilizing a stock pledge for tax payments is suggested, such as borrowing 20% for tax obligations while reinvesting the remaining funds to enhance investment efficiency.</li>
<li>James encourages them to experiment with a stock pledge, perhaps borrowing 2% for personal use, to experience the convenience of borrowing firsthand.</li>
<li>He highlights the vital role of cash. A higher proportion of cash or cash-equivalent assets translates to greater risk tolerance for the investment portfolio.</li>
<li>James advises this friend to learn from investment approaches employed by individuals like Warren Buffett and Wei Ying-ch’ung, leveraging credit for investment purposes.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Sunny:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Question:</strong> How should labor pension funds be withdrawn?
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response:</strong> If proficient in investment, withdrawing the entire labor pension fund at once and investing it in high-yielding assets like QQQ is recommended.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Wu Liyun:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Question:</strong> Is NT$5 million in stocks and cash sufficient for retirement?
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response:</strong>  NT$5 million in assets is insufficient to support a comfortable retirement. Withdrawing a labor pension monthly to supplement retirement income is recommended.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Nana:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Question:</strong> Concerns regarding genetic screening.
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response:</strong> Genetic screening is recommended to identify any potential genetic defects.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>College Student:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Question:</strong> Concerns about Backdoor Roth IRA.
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response:</strong> College students, lacking income, do not require a Backdoor Roth IRA. Directly depositing funds into a Roth IRA is suitable.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Jessie:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing:</strong> Has 1099 income.</li>
<li><strong>Question:</strong> Can 1099 income be deposited into a Traditional IRA?
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response:</strong>  Yes, 1099 income is eligible for deposit into a Traditional IRA. Additionally, a Backdoor Roth IRA can be executed using a spouse&rsquo;s W2 income.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">IV. Key Takeaways 
    <div id="iv-key-takeaways" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv-key-takeaways" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p><strong>Young individuals should be bold in using borrowed funds for investment to accelerate wealth accumulation.</strong>
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Young people are in their prime earning years, with steadily increasing income. They can utilize tools like credit loans to access low-cost capital for investing in high-return assets like QQQ, thereby speeding up their wealth-building journey.</p>
<blockquote>
<p><strong>Cash is the cornerstone ensuring investors can continue investing.</strong>
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Market volatility is a constant. Maintaining sufficient cash or cash-equivalent assets helps investors navigate market fluctuations with ease, preventing panic-driven asset sales, ultimately achieving long-term investment objectives.</p>
<blockquote>
<p><strong>Exercise prudence in investments. Avoid excessive diversification or venturing into unfamiliar domains.</strong>
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Focus investments within familiar areas. Refrain from blindly pursuing diversification or investing in unfamiliar domains, such as real estate or REITs.</p>
<blockquote>
<p><strong>The essence of US dollar hegemony lies in the US leveraging its control over vital resource trading, like oil, to sustain the dollar&rsquo;s global dominance.</strong>
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>By mandating US dollar settlements for global oil transactions, the US compels other nations to hold dollar reserves, solidifying its global currency dominance.</p>
<blockquote>
<p><strong>Marriage serves the purpose of creating life to carry on the universe&rsquo;s legacy. Loving one&rsquo;s partner as one would love their own child is paramount to a successful marriage.</strong>
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>The significance of marriage lies in procreation and the continuation of life. Loving one&rsquo;s partner deeply, treating them as one would treat their own child, is crucial for a lasting and fulfilling marriage.</p>
<blockquote>
<p><strong>Childbearing lies at the heart of life&rsquo;s meaning. Young individuals should marry and have children early, unburdened by financial pressures.</strong>
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Childbearing is inherent to human nature and the perpetuation of life. Young people should courageously embrace the responsibility of parenthood, refusing to be deterred by financial concerns.</p>
<blockquote>
<p><strong>Investors often fall prey to sunk cost and opportunity cost fallacies.</strong>
&ndash; Professor Zhou</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Sunk costs refer to incurred expenses that are irretrievable, such as purchased stocks or real estate. Opportunity cost represents the potential gains foregone by choosing one investment over other available options. During decision-making, investors should not be swayed by sunk costs; instead, they should prioritize opportunity cost, selecting investments offering higher returns.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">V. Conclusion 
    <div id="v-conclusion" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#v-conclusion" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This session revolves around the anticipated new highs in the investment market. James encourages listeners to solidify their investment confidence and enter the market promptly. He meticulously explains various asset allocation strategies, emphasizing the use of leveraged funds and the paramount importance of cash reserves. He also delves into the nature of US dollar hegemony and its global economic implications, sharing his personal views on marriage and childbearing. The Q&amp;A segment addresses questions encompassing asset allocation, stock pledges, retirement planning, investment strategies, and more, making it a content-rich and insightful session.</p>

  



<div
  
    class="flex px-4 py-3 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900"
  >

  <span
    
      class="text-primary-400 ltr:pr-3 rtl:pl-3 flex items-center"
    >

    

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M506.3 417l-213.3-364c-16.33-28-57.54-28-73.98 0l-213.2 364C-10.59 444.9 9.849 480 42.74 480h426.6C502.1 480 522.6 445 506.3 417zM232 168c0-13.25 10.75-24 24-24S280 154.8 280 168v128c0 13.25-10.75 24-23.1 24S232 309.3 232 296V168zM256 416c-17.36 0-31.44-14.08-31.44-31.44c0-17.36 14.07-31.44 31.44-31.44s31.44 14.08 31.44 31.44C287.4 401.9 273.4 416 256 416z"/></svg>

  </span>


  </span>

  <span
    
      class="dark:text-neutral-300"
    ><strong>Disclaimer:</strong> This article is for personal learning purposes only and does not constitute any investment advice.</span>
</div>

]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>00486 Market Trends and Future Investment Strategies:Navigating the New Economic Era</title>
      <link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1728231523948/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1728231523948/</guid>
      <description>In this session, James shares his analysis of the current market situation and investment advice. He also answers questions from the audience on topics like asset allocation, retirement planning, children&amp;#39;s education, handling stock options, leverage, and tax planning.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<lite-youtube videoid="mwchPrvkFMA" playlabel="mwchPrvkFMA" params=""></lite-youtube>



<h2 class="relative group">I. Main Topic 
    <div id="i-main-topic" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-main-topic" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>The theme of this session is <strong>Embrace the New Bull Market and Invest Long-Term.</strong> James believes that the global monetary easing policy and the rapid development of AI technology herald the arrival of a new bull market. He advises everyone to invest in the Nasdaq 100 index fund (QQQ or 00662) and view market fluctuations with a long-term perspective.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">II.  Content Summary 
    <div id="ii--content-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii--content-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<ul>
<li><strong>A new bull market is coming:</strong>  The world has entered an era of loose monetary policy with the start of a rate cut cycle, which will drive the stock market up. This bull market may be a slow one but will continuously rise.</li>
<li><strong>Invest confidently in the Nasdaq 100 index fund:</strong> QQQ could increase by 50 times in the next 20 years, with an annualized return of over 20%, making it the best investment target.</li>
<li><strong>Individual stocks are unreliable:</strong> Individual stock investment is risky, and in the long run, almost all of them will disappear. They are very difficult to outperform the market in the long term. It is recommended not to waste time and energy on stock selection.</li>
<li><strong>Do not invest in the Chinese stock market:</strong> The Chinese stock market is not mature enough; consider investing in it after 30 years.</li>
<li><strong>Comparison of household asset allocation in the US and Taiwan:</strong>  American families invest most of their assets in securities to create social value, while Taiwanese families prefer cash, insurance, and real estate, locking up funds in non-appreciating areas.</li>
<li><strong>Leveraging through stock pledges:</strong> Using stock pledges to borrow increases liquidity and allows for continued investment to enjoy the benefits of compound growth. With an understanding of asset allocation, the interest cost of borrowing can be almost negligible.</li>
<li><strong>Plan for retirement early:</strong> Young people are advised to invest in 00662, and retirees can choose 00646 (SPY) or 0056 according to their fund size.</li>
<li><strong>Emphasize family education:</strong> Parents should cultivate their children&rsquo;s financial management concepts from an early age, guide them to make long-term investments, stay away from bad habits such as short-term speculation and gambling, and lead by example.</li>
<li><strong>Don&rsquo;t blindly trust high-yield investment products:</strong> Any investment product promising high returns may be a scam. It is important to understand its operating mechanism and learn to discern between true and false.</li>
<li><strong>The dangers of short-term trading:</strong> Short-term trading will miss the best investment opportunities. Long-term investment in index funds will yield more stable returns.</li>
<li><strong>The purpose of cash allocation:</strong> It is not for profit, but for dealing with emergencies like unemployment or a market crash. It is advisable to keep more than 10% of your assets in cash.</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">III. Q&amp;A Session 
    <div id="iii-qa-session" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii-qa-session" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<ul>
<li>
<p><strong>Retired Doctor Poch:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: After learning about James&rsquo; investment philosophy, he found a more relaxing and suitable investment method.</li>
<li>Question: How to obtain a stable cash flow after retirement? Is it necessary to adjust the investment strategy of 00662?
<ul>
<li>Answer:  The investment target can be adjusted according to the size of the retirement fund. Choose 00646 (SPY) or 0056 with lower volatility to guarantee cash flow.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>IM:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: He tried to guide his child to invest by matching contributions and increased his vigilance against high-yield traps.</li>
<li>Question 1: How to guide a child to invest and prevent them from spending investment income?
<ul>
<li>Answer: Emphasize that investment is a long-term behavior. Income cannot be withdrawn for consumption. Funds should grow continuously through compound interest.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2: How to choose a safe and reliable trust company? How to avoid the traps of high-yield trust products?
<ul>
<li>Answer: Any trust company that promises high returns may be a scam. You should take control of your own investment and financial management rights, clearly stipulate investment in index funds in the trust clause, and set up a regulatory unit to ensure fund security.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Rose:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: She frankly talked about her past investment failures and the process of gradually establishing the correct investment concept under the guidance of James.</li>
<li>Question 1: What are the differences and pros and cons of Margin Loan and Pledge Loan?  The interest rate of Margin Loan from IB is relatively low. Is it necessary to transfer to Charles Schwab for Pledge Loan?
<ul>
<li>Answer:  Margin Loan is riskier, and Pledge Loan is relatively safe. If the interest rate of IB&rsquo;s Margin Loan is low, you can continue to use it, but pay attention to controlling the borrowing ratio, preferably no more than 20%.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2: The return on cash allocation will decrease in the interest rate cut cycle. Is it still necessary to allocate cash?
<ul>
<li>Answer: The purpose of cash allocation is not for profit but to deal with contingencies, such as unemployment or a market crash. It is advisable to keep more than 10% of your assets in cash.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 3: How to manage children&rsquo;s investment accounts? Under whose name should it be, yours or the child&rsquo;s?
<ul>
<li>Answer: It is recommended to open an account in the child&rsquo;s name to cultivate their financial management concept, but control the amount and provide proper investment guidance. Estate planning can be done after the child becomes an adult.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Phoenix:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: He shared his confusion about handling company stock options and finally adopted James&rsquo; suggestion.</li>
<li>Question 1: How to deal with the stock options of unlisted companies?
<ul>
<li>Answer: If the company has a high possibility of going public, it is recommended to sell it to an investment company before the listing to get cash and invest in QQQ.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2: What do you think of Bitcoin? Can I invest in it?
<ul>
<li>Answer: If you already hold a small amount of Bitcoin, you can continue to hold it, but do not invest any more capital. It is recommended to focus on investing in QQQ.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Allen:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: He shared his questions about 401k and stock investment and eventually made adjustments under James&rsquo; advice.</li>
<li>Question 1: What should I do if I have too much money in my 401k account?
<ul>
<li>Answer:  It is recommended to stop making further contributions to 401k and transfer some funds to the Roth IRA account through the Backdoor Roth IRA.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2: How to switch from holding Nvidia stock to QQQ?
<ul>
<li>Answer: Sell Nvidia stock as soon as possible, transfer funds to QQQ, and pledge stocks to borrow money to pay taxes.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Haoqing:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: He demonstrated the difficulty of stock selection through data analysis and illustrated the advantages of long-term investment in QQQ with practical examples.</li>
<li>Question: Can stock picking beat QQQ?
<ul>
<li>Answer: Stock selection is difficult to outperform QQQ in the long run. Even if it beats the market in the short term, transaction costs and taxes need to be considered.  Invest in index funds for the long term.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Xiang:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: He shared his confusion about saving for children&rsquo;s education and inheritance and finally found a solution under James&rsquo; advice.</li>
<li>Question 1: Is it better to use a 529 Education Fund or invest in QQQ for children&rsquo;s education savings?
<ul>
<li>Answer:  Investing in QQQ is recommended because it has higher long-term returns and is more flexible.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2: How to do estate planning?
<ul>
<li>Answer:  For larger estates, it is recommended to set up an irrevocable trust and consult an estate lawyer for planning.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Kevin:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Frankly admitted his past investment failures and regained confidence under the guidance of James, starting to embark on the road of steady investment.</li>
<li>Question: How many listeners are losing money on investments?
<ul>
<li>Answer: Past investment experience is not important. What is important is to establish the correct investment concept and believe in the value of long-term investment in index funds.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Julia:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Shared her lessons learned from investing in Chinese concept stocks and second-tier growth stocks, and how to guide children to make long-term investments.</li>
<li>Question 1: How to deal with losses caused by investment in Chinese concept stocks and second-tier growth stocks?
- Answer: It is advisable to &ldquo;cut your losses&rdquo; and switch funds to QQQ in a timely manner.</li>
<li>Question 2: How to guide children to make long-term investments?
- Answer: You can use an investment calculator to show children the power of compound interest and guide them with your own investment experience.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Peter:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Shared his experience working at Apple and confirmed that many high-income earners also choose to invest in index funds.</li>
<li>Question: How to balance family expenses and investment?
- Answer: It is recommended to use stock pledges to borrow money to meet living expenses and continue investing in QQQ, so that assets can continue to grow through compound interest.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Jason:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: He shared his confusion about company tax declaration and finally found a suitable solution under James&rsquo; advice.</li>
<li>Question: How to choose the tax filing method?
<ul>
<li>Answer: If your income is low, you can choose to file a 1099; if your income is high, you are advised to establish an S Corporation.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Cindy:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Shared her experience of guiding her child to invest in Roth IRA and keep away from gambling.</li>
<li>Question: How to guide children to invest in Roth IRA? How to guide children to stay away from gambling?
<ul>
<li>Answer: Open a Roth IRA account for the child and make matching contributions. Lead by example and educate your child with the experiences and stories of people around you.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">IV.  Highlights 
    <div id="iv--highlights" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv--highlights" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>Lending is more powerful than the atomic bomb; it&rsquo;s ten times the atomic bomb!
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>When encouraging people to use stock pledges for borrowing and investment, James used this analogy to vividly illustrate the power of leverage.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Investing should be easy and fun.
&ndash;  Hola</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This is what a listener said when she shared her investment experience. She also tried short-term trading, but finally found that long-term investment suited her better.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Each person has a different destiny when it comes to money.
&ndash; Peter</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Peter said this thought-provoking sentence when he shared his experience of persuading his father to invest in QQQ. This also reflects that investment and financial management should be combined with one&rsquo;s own situation to find a suitable way.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>All the money in the world is mine; you just need to take it and use it.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>James used humorous words to express his confidence in the market when encouraging everyone to invest, which also reflects his optimistic and positive attitude towards life.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">V. Conclusion 
    <div id="v-conclusion" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#v-conclusion" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>In this live broadcast, James once again emphasized the concept of long-term investment in index funds. He also provided specific investment advice for the audience based on the current market situation, covering asset allocation, retirement planning, children&rsquo;s education, stock options handling, leverage, and tax planning. The sharing from the students provided other listeners with valuable reference experience, showing their growth and earnings during the process of learning about investment and financial management.</p>

  



<div
  
    class="flex px-4 py-3 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900"
  >

  <span
    
      class="text-primary-400 ltr:pr-3 rtl:pl-3 flex items-center"
    >

    

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M506.3 417l-213.3-364c-16.33-28-57.54-28-73.98 0l-213.2 364C-10.59 444.9 9.849 480 42.74 480h426.6C502.1 480 522.6 445 506.3 417zM232 168c0-13.25 10.75-24 24-24S280 154.8 280 168v128c0 13.25-10.75 24-23.1 24S232 309.3 232 296V168zM256 416c-17.36 0-31.44-14.08-31.44-31.44c0-17.36 14.07-31.44 31.44-31.44s31.44 14.08 31.44 31.44C287.4 401.9 273.4 416 256 416z"/></svg>

  </span>


  </span>

  <span
    
      class="dark:text-neutral-300"
    ><strong>Disclaimer:</strong> This article is only for personal learning notes and does not constitute any investment advice.</span>
</div>

]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
