<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Tax on QQQ Investor</title>
    <link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/tags/tax/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tax on QQQ Investor</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jomonylw.github.io/en/tags/tax/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>00496 Global Markets and the Tech Wave: How to Seize Opportunities for Wealth Growth Amidst Volatility. The Philosophy of Financial Freedom: From Personalized Investing to Exploring Life&#39;s Values</title>
      <link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1735482278058/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1735482278058/</guid>
      <description>At the end of 2024, with market fluctuations, Teacher James shared his insights on the current economic situation, financial markets, and investment strategies. In addition, several students asked questions online, covering asset allocation, business operations, health and wellness, tax planning, stock leveraging, and other areas.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Part One
<lite-youtube videoid="9F1rAWjCGX8" playlabel="9F1rAWjCGX8" params=""></lite-youtube>
</p>
<p>Part Two
<lite-youtube videoid="oPb4m81Nv24" playlabel="oPb4m81Nv24" params=""></lite-youtube>
</p>


<h2 class="relative group">I. Main Topic of the Session 
    <div id="i-main-topic-of-the-session" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-main-topic-of-the-session" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>Investment mindset and strategy adjustments amidst year-end market volatility, along with comprehensive reflections on personal life and financial health.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">II. Presentation Content 
    <div id="ii-presentation-content" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii-presentation-content" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Market Volatility and Investment Mindset 
    <div id="market-volatility-and-investment-mindset" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#market-volatility-and-investment-mindset" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>The only constant in the market is volatility. Investors should ignore market fluctuations, international situations, market analysis, financial reports, and economic situations, and focus on long-term investment.</li>
<li>Disclaimer: The content of the COC investment and financial management channel is for educational purposes only and does not constitute investment advice. Investment involves high risks, and proper asset allocation is necessary.</li>
<li>Newcomers should watch the YouTube episode 00451 &ldquo;Investment Lecture Worth 100 Million&rdquo; and also find related content on Bilibili and podcasts.</li>
<li>Investing requires independent thinking. Do not blindly follow advice or join any groups to avoid being deceived.</li>
<li>The Nasdaq 100 index fund is recommended as the only focused fund, with others being supplementary.</li>
<li>The handout includes information on Nasdaq 100 index funds worldwide, including leveraged funds, and information on retirement accounts in various regions, with content continuously updated.</li>
<li>The &ldquo;Investment Lecture Worth 100 Million&rdquo; video is the most important. Investors should always be extremely optimistic; the market will eventually rise and reach new highs.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">UK and European Financial Information 
    <div id="uk-and-european-financial-information" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#uk-and-european-financial-information" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Showcasing information provided by a UK friend regarding UK investments, loans, retirement accounts, ETFs, and insurance companies, particularly information on 2x leveraged funds on the PEA website.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">US-China Trade War and Globalization 
    <div id="us-china-trade-war-and-globalization" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#us-china-trade-war-and-globalization" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Issues like the US-China trade war and tariffs do not affect technological advancements and the innovation of American companies, thus having little impact on index investing.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Risks and Returns of Leveraged Funds 
    <div id="risks-and-returns-of-leveraged-funds" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#risks-and-returns-of-leveraged-funds" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>The risk of a 2x leveraged fund is not simply double, and the return is not twice the annualized rate of return, but approximately 1.4 times.</li>
<li>The annualized return of QQQ over 20 years is 14%, while QLD&rsquo;s is 19.6%. QLD&rsquo;s total return over 20 years is 2.6 times that of QQQ, far exceeding double.</li>
<li>Combining leveraged funds with cash can reduce risk and increase returns.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Investment Wisdom and Market Essence 
    <div id="investment-wisdom-and-market-essence" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#investment-wisdom-and-market-essence" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>The market is always smarter than individual investors. Stock picking and timing the market are futile.</li>
<li>In a bull market, many &ldquo;gurus&rdquo; emerge, but they disappear when the market falls; this is a market norm.</li>
<li>Controlling the major stocks on Wall Street means controlling the world.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Investment Sharing and Personal Insights 
    <div id="investment-sharing-and-personal-insights" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#investment-sharing-and-personal-insights" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Investment sharers need to provide clear, diverse, and universally applicable investment methods and benefit from them.</li>
<li>Buffett&rsquo;s investment philosophy emphasizes long-term investment, perfecting the investment system.</li>
<li>Understanding the essence of finance, economics, accounting, and logic helps resist external interference and adhere to index investing.</li>
<li>Asset allocation is simplified into two types: 433 (conservative) and 442 (aggressive), pursuing safety rather than high returns, with cash being a safe asset.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Finance and Monetary Theory 
    <div id="finance-and-monetary-theory" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#finance-and-monetary-theory" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>The foundation of capitalism is currency. Understanding monetary theory is crucial to understanding finance, investment, and the economy.</li>
<li>The status of the US dollar as the world&rsquo;s reserve currency determines the subordinate status of other countries, especially those holding large amounts of US dollar foreign exchange reserves.</li>
<li>China and other emerging countries are trying to break away from their dependence on the US dollar to escape US control.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Life&rsquo;s Meaning and Happiness 
    <div id="lifes-meaning-and-happiness" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#lifes-meaning-and-happiness" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>The happiest thing in life is giving. Happiness is a human right. Sharing and giving energy on a spiritual level can bring more happiness than material things.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Extremes of Capitalism and Social Issues 
    <div id="extremes-of-capitalism-and-social-issues" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#extremes-of-capitalism-and-social-issues" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Capitalism will lead to an expansion of the wealth gap. The development of robots will make spiritual education even more important.</li>
<li>Systemic discrimination exists in society, leading to a vicious cycle of poverty. Our goal is to help eliminate poverty as much as possible.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">US Accounting System and Social Phenomena 
    <div id="us-accounting-system-and-social-phenomena" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#us-accounting-system-and-social-phenomena" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>The US accounting system is very complete. Phenomena like &ldquo;zero-dollar shopping&rdquo; are the result of accounting costs and leftist thinking, and there is no need to over-interpret them.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Wealth and Government Relations 
    <div id="wealth-and-government-relations" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#wealth-and-government-relations" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Wealthy individuals escape government control by paying taxes, while the poor are trapped.</li>
<li>Legitimate tax avoidance is an important topic.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Personalization of Diet and Asset Allocation 
    <div id="personalization-of-diet-and-asset-allocation" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#personalization-of-diet-and-asset-allocation" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Both diet and asset allocation should be customized according to individual circumstances and cannot be generalized.</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">III. Q&amp;A Session 
    <div id="iii-qa-session" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii-qa-session" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Zhang Yong 
    <div id="zhang-yong" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#zhang-yong" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing</strong>: The chaos in the domestic insurance industry, where banks lure customers into buying insurance with high commissions, is even linked to the performance evaluations of customer managers. Many customers do not understand investments and choose low-yield or even risky insurance products to preserve their capital. He also shared a case of a friend who was defrauded of over 1.7 million in a romance scam, illustrating the complexity of the domestic financial environment.
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s comment</strong>: The US financial system strictly separates life insurance from other financial businesses, and there is no such thing as banks selling insurance. The financial supervision in China and Taiwan is problematic. Banks should focus on deposit and loan business and should not be involved in insurance and investment. This chaos will ultimately harm the interests of emerging countries.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question</strong>: Does Teacher James share content each week based on reflections on the same theme, or does he summarize viewpoints from reading many books?
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s reply</strong>: In addition to reading a lot of books, more importantly, independent thinking and critical thinking are involved. The formation of monetary theory stems from thinking about the nature of capitalism, and the content of the handouts mostly comes from students&rsquo; questions and his own reflections. This information is endless. To be an excellent sharer, one needs to have basic knowledge, thinking ability, and originality.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Xiao Cai 
    <div id="xiao-cai" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#xiao-cai" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing 1</strong>: Took over the family food business ten years ago when the company&rsquo;s assets and liabilities were zero. After ten years of operation, the company turned a profit, and its current value (including real estate) is about 300 million NTD. Over the past decade, he distributed about 200 million NTD of revenue to his family, retaining 100 million NTD for loan purposes. Currently, he has invested 80 million in 00662 (a 2x leveraged Nasdaq 100 index ETF) and 20 million in 00631L (Taiwan&rsquo;s 50 Positive 2 ETF).
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s comment</strong>: None</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question 1</strong>: The bank will allocate a loan of 60 million NTD on January 1st. Should this fund be used to buy 00662 all at once, or should he wait for a 20% market drop before buying? Also, if the market crashes and 00662 and 00631L go to zero, how will he deal with it?
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s reply</strong>: If the market goes to zero, the company can still make loan payments. The worst-case scenario is that the land is auctioned off, and he can still get tens of millions. Since the worst has been considered, how to buy the 60 million is not important. If it were me, I would buy it all on Monday. If you choose to wait for a 20% drop before buying, you can follow your plan and inform everyone when you buy.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question 2</strong>: How to maintain good health?
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s reply</strong>: Regular comprehensive physical examinations are necessary. I have been doing annual check-ups since my thirties. Wellness, like asset allocation, needs to be personalized. The advice I can give everyone now is to eat well, sleep well, and don&rsquo;t worry. What to eat specifically, what exercises to do, etc., need to be decided according to personal circumstances and cannot be given a unified recommendation.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question 3</strong>: What are your views on Taiwan&rsquo;s politics and how to support political parties?
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s reply</strong>: Regarding politics and religious beliefs, everyone has different positions and viewpoints. Discussing these issues in the classroom is meaningless and fruitless. It is recommended that students do not discuss these topics in the classroom and keep their opinions to themselves.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question 4</strong>: How to preserve assets in response to potential cross-strait issues? He currently has about 200 million NTD in assets in Taiwan and a house worth 8 million in Vietnam. How should he allocate his assets?
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s reply</strong>: If you can&rsquo;t sleep due to worries about cross-strait issues, it&rsquo;s recommended to immigrate as soon as possible. If you choose to stay in Taiwan, you need to make some decisions, such as whether to close the company. If the 40 employees are causing you distress, consider closing the company and compensating them. Life decisions should be decisive, not prolonged. Be responsible for your own happiness.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Additional question</strong>: How to get rid of the shackles of the family business?
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s reply</strong>: You have managed the company very well. The choice is your life. Do whatever makes you happy. If the family business makes you unhappy, shut it down and give the employees a good severance package. Consider your own life, not your father&rsquo;s. If your father&rsquo;s business is no longer your concern, and it&rsquo;s not bringing you happiness, then let it go.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Repeated emphasis</strong>: Believes that apart from investment and financial management, health is the most important asset in life, and cited the example of &ldquo;Yu (Yuan) Lingqi&rdquo; to emphasize the importance of regular health check-ups, hoping the channel will pay more attention to health issues.
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s reply</strong>: Health is very important. Everyone&rsquo;s health condition is different, and it is impossible to provide a unified recommendation. Everyone needs to pay attention to and manage their health according to their own situation.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Lare 
    <div id="lare" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#lare" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Question</strong>: Based in Canada, unable to leverage stocks. If income decreases in a certain year, and the tax rate drops from 32% to 24%, is it worth selling some stocks to increase income to the 32% tax bracket to improve the future cost basis?
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s reply</strong>: It is not recommended to sell stocks because selling incurs taxes. Canada&rsquo;s tax system is very unfavorable for stock investments. When immigrating, consider future generations and choose countries with development prospects. In Canada, you can consider using an IB account for loans, but this will face inheritance tax issues, possibly up to 40%. Therefore, when planning estates, minimize assets in IB accounts. In the long run, trusts can be used to avoid taxes. It is currently not recommended to sell stocks for short-term tax benefits. Consider selling after retirement when income is lower.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Additional explanation</strong>: IB accounts have a low financing ratio for Canadian stocks, only up to 50%.
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s addition</strong>: You can borrow 40% first, and add more if needed. But ultimately, there will still be inheritance tax issues.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Terry 
    <div id="terry" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#terry" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Question 1</strong>: How to transfer taxable accounts or retirement accounts to tax-free accounts, such as Roth IRA? What are the specific steps?
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s reply</strong>: If it&rsquo;s within the same brokerage, such as Charles Schwab, you can fill out a form online directly. If it&rsquo;s at different brokerages, you need to contact the brokerage to obtain and fill out a form. For specific steps, you can refer to the previously released video &ldquo;Investment and Financial Management Tips 26: How to Transfer from a Traditional Taxable Account to a Roth IRA Online at 722.&rdquo;</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question 2</strong>: What is your view on Crypto, and will QQQ include Crypto companies in the future?
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s reply</strong>: I don&rsquo;t know much about Crypto and am not sure if it will exist forever, so I won&rsquo;t answer.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">IM 
    <div id="im" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#im" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing</strong>: Through learning, I realized that my investment was too risky, and emergency funds should not all be invested in QQQ. Now I have withdrawn 36 months of emergency funds back to the Money Market Fund. When starting with small funds, one should focus on their main job and increase income sources. After investing in index funds, my mindset changed, and I began to focus on the importance of timing. Therefore, I started to focus on diet, fitness, and learning from the experiences of long-lived people around me. In addition, I learned from investing to avoid risks, such as giving up dangerous activities like diving.
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s comment</strong>: It is wise to learn from the experiences of others. Being overly aggressive is human nature, but it is important to realize and correct it in time. It is wrong to increase positions when the market is rising and to be fearful when it is falling. It should be the other way around. Emergency funds should not be added to.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question</strong>: How to judge whether you are being too adventurous? For example, increasing the leverage ratio of asset allocation from 1.0 to 1.8 when stocks are rising.
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s reply</strong>: This is also a necessary evil. Now that you realize it&rsquo;s not right, you can start to retreat, or when it rises, you buy in, and when it falls, you get scared. Oh, what to do? Then start to retreat. Once you have learned, don&rsquo;t do it again. So, as Buffett said, when others are greedy, you should be fearful, and when others are fearful, you should be greedy. That&rsquo;s the right pace. So, when you want to increase your position in the future, it should be when others are fearful. That&rsquo;s how I do it. This emergency fund should not be increased. Regardless of whether the market is rising or falling, you should not add to this cervical spine disease. How could you add to it? This is not allowed. Then, if you use our asset allocation, when the market falls, you automatically buy in for one year, and when the market rises, you automatically withdraw from the leveraged fund. This is passive, and this has already achieved the practice of being greedy when others are fearful and being fearful when others are greedy.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Patty 
    <div id="patty" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#patty" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Question</strong>: The relationship between the asset-backed ratio and cash reserves. If asset-backed financing is carried out, how to ensure that the cash on hand is greater than the pledged amount? For example, with assets of 1 million, allocated according to the 721 ratio, 200,000 is pledged, but 100,000 in cash cannot be moved. Is it necessary to balance for one or two years to accumulate 200,000 in cash before making a pledge?
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s reply</strong>: You cannot borrow 200,000 all at once; you can only borrow 2% per year. When conducting asset-backed financing, the asset allocation should be 433, not 721. Borrow 2% each year and conduct &ldquo;smart rebalancing.&rdquo; Even if the market falls, you will not be forced to liquidate. The cash ratio may be lower than the loan ratio in extreme cases (such as a continuous 10-year decline), but since the total asset value is still greater than the debt, there will be no problem.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Mike 
    <div id="mike" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#mike" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing</strong>: A friend&rsquo;s experience. The friend took over his father&rsquo;s family business and eventually had health problems due to overwork. He later sold the company for over 600 million and invested the funds in QQQ. He is now very happy.
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s comment</strong>: None</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question 1</strong>: Regarding 401k and RMD. Previously, company stock was placed in a 401k, and now it has a high value, facing the RMD issue. After Trump takes office, is it possible to abolish RMD and change it to a 15% capital gains tax?
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s reply</strong>: This possibility is extremely slim. The government is unlikely to give up the tax revenue brought by RMD.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question 2</strong>: Regarding the Debt to Equity Ratio of companies. It is found that there are large differences in the debt-to-equity ratios of Buffett and many technology companies. Is this related to the nature of the industry? For example, the debt-to-equity ratio of software companies is usually low, while that of hardware companies like Apple is high. So, for individuals, is it a healthy level to control the debt-to-equity ratio at 0.2?
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s reply</strong>: The higher the debt-to-equity ratio, the higher the ROE usually is, but this needs to be based on healthy debt. Healthy debt refers to debt that can be repaid through its own operating activities, such as credit, stock-backed loans (under safe circumstances), and mortgages (that can be repaid). Apple&rsquo;s debt-to-equity ratio is high because it borrows a lot of money to pay dividends and places assets overseas. In addition, it has a large amount of accounts payable. Therefore, it cannot be simply considered that a high debt-to-equity ratio is bad. It is necessary to analyze the nature and safety of the debt specifically.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question 3</strong>: What are your thoughts on the Jetson Orin product launched by Nvidia? This product is mainly for the personal AI market, is cheap, can use ChatGPT to generate code, and runs locally, thereby creating your own AI database.
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s reply</strong>: I don&rsquo;t know much about this product. Our AI is mainly trained using ChatGPT as a personal assistant. Currently, I don&rsquo;t use other devices for personal AI.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">IV. Highlighted Quotes 
    <div id="iv-highlighted-quotes" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv-highlighted-quotes" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>The only constant in the market is volatility.
&ndash; Teacher James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This viewpoint emphasizes the normality of market fluctuations. Investors should be mentally prepared and not be affected by short-term market fluctuations.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Investing requires independent thinking. Do not blindly follow advice or join any groups to avoid being deceived.
&ndash; Teacher James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This viewpoint emphasizes the importance of independent thinking in investing. Investors should make investment decisions based on their own judgment rather than blindly following others&rsquo; opinions or joining unreliable investment groups.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The happiest thing in life is giving. Happiness is a human right. Sharing and giving energy on a spiritual level can bring more happiness than material things.
&ndash; Teacher James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This viewpoint emphasizes that spiritual pursuits are more important than material ones. Giving and sharing can bring greater happiness.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>If you, as a commercial bank, do lending well, then focus on lending. Deposits are 2%. Then your lending is 3.5%, 4%. You just make that 2% difference. This is what a commercial bank should do. Commerce should not touch insurance.
&ndash; Teacher James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This viewpoint points out that commercial banks should focus on deposit and loan business instead of being involved in areas like insurance, which not only violates financial regulations but also harms the interests of customers.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Happiness is a human right. If you are alive, you should be happy. If you live so miserably, why bother?
&ndash; Teacher James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This viewpoint reminds everyone to pursue happiness and not sacrifice their happiness for money or other goals.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Impotence is also a kind of strength because accepting one&rsquo;s own impotence and acknowledging one&rsquo;s own impotence is also a kind of strength.
&ndash; Teacher James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This viewpoint expresses a broad-minded attitude towards life. Acknowledging one&rsquo;s limitations is not a bad thing; instead, it can make one more relaxed.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The truly wealthy are those who foresee a future eternally disconnected from government oversight, swiftly settling their dues to escape the clutches of authority.
&ndash; Teacher James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This perspective highlights how affluent individuals utilize legitimate tax avoidance strategies to minimize governmental control over their wealth.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Learning from the experiences of others is a wise approach.
&ndash; IM</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This viewpoint emphasizes the importance of learning and drawing lessons from others&rsquo; experiences, which can help us avoid making the same mistakes.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>When others are greedy, you should be fearful; when others are fearful, you should be greedy.
&ndash; Teacher James, quoting Buffett</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This is a very important principle in investing, namely, contrarian thinking, staying calm when the market is frenzied and looking for opportunities when the market is panicking.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Just be happy. There&rsquo;s nothing to it, nothing to fight for, no particular meaning, nothing that grand or great.
&ndash; Teacher James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This viewpoint expresses a detached attitude towards life. Don&rsquo;t put too much pressure on yourself; learn to enjoy life.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Don&rsquo;t wait until it&rsquo;s too late, leaving no time for regrets.
&ndash; Teacher James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Drawing on investment principles, this perspective underscores the importance of early health screenings, urging not to wait until problems arise before regretting, echoing Xiao Cai&rsquo;s shared viewpoint.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>We investors are always extremely optimistic. Market fluctuations should be ignored. The market will eventually rise and always reach new highs.
&ndash; Teacher James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This viewpoint emphasizes the optimistic attitude towards the long-term trend of the market and the neglect of short-term fluctuations, demonstrating the proper mindset for long-term investors.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">V. Summary 
    <div id="v-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#v-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>The content of this episode of the investment and financial management channel is rich. Teacher James not only shared his views on the current market and investment strategies but also answered the practical questions of many students, involving asset allocation, business operations, health and wellness, tax planning, and other aspects. In addition, he also emphasized the importance of happiness and health, as well as investment concepts such as independent thinking, long-term investment, and reasonable tax avoidance. In summary, the content of this episode provides valuable guidance and inspiration for investors, helping everyone make wise decisions in a complex market environment and have a healthier and happier life.</p>

  



<div
  
    class="flex px-4 py-3 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900"
  >

  <span
    
      class="text-primary-400 ltr:pr-3 rtl:pl-3 flex items-center"
    >

    

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M506.3 417l-213.3-364c-16.33-28-57.54-28-73.98 0l-213.2 364C-10.59 444.9 9.849 480 42.74 480h426.6C502.1 480 522.6 445 506.3 417zM232 168c0-13.25 10.75-24 24-24S280 154.8 280 168v128c0 13.25-10.75 24-23.1 24S232 309.3 232 296V168zM256 416c-17.36 0-31.44-14.08-31.44-31.44c0-17.36 14.07-31.44 31.44-31.44s31.44 14.08 31.44 31.44C287.4 401.9 273.4 416 256 416z"/></svg>

  </span>


  </span>

  <span
    
      class="dark:text-neutral-300"
    ><strong>Disclaimer:</strong> This article is only a personal study note and does not constitute any investment advice.</span>
</div>

]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>00495 Market Highs and Lows Don&#39;t Exist: The Only Truth in Long-Term Investing; The Privilege of the Rich and the Secret of Asset Appreciation</title>
      <link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1734846063547/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1734846063547/</guid>
      <description>In this session, James shares his year-end rebalancing strategy, investment philosophy, 433 asset allocation plan, and answers questions from students regarding QQQ, leveraged ETFs, ETNs, real estate, personal finance, and CLEC short video production.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<lite-youtube videoid="TCfozoZu0Hw" playlabel="TCfozoZu0Hw" params=""></lite-youtube>



<h2 class="relative group">I. Main Topic 
    <div id="i-main-topic" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-main-topic" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This session focuses on year-end investment strategies. James emphasizes the importance of rebalancing and delves into investment philosophy, asset allocation, handling market fluctuations, and other practical investment tips. The core message is: adopt a long-term investment approach, adhere to the &ldquo;buy whenever you have money, never sell&rdquo; strategy, and implement a suitable asset allocation and rebalancing plan based on individual circumstances.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">II. Briefing Content 
    <div id="ii-briefing-content" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii-briefing-content" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Year-End Rebalancing and Asset Allocation 
    <div id="year-end-rebalancing-and-asset-allocation" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#year-end-rebalancing-and-asset-allocation" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Importance of Rebalancing:</strong> James stresses the importance of rebalancing at the end or beginning of the year. He recommends passive rebalancing, which means rebalancing when the market is performing well, to avoid panic selling during market downturns. He points out that many investors are reluctant to rebalance during market rallies, hoping to earn more, but end up succumbing to losses during declines and selling at the bottom, resulting in greater losses.</li>
<li><strong>Pledging Stocks for Tax Payment:</strong> He advises individuals with pledged stocks to borrow money for tax payments instead of selling the stocks to avoid increasing capital gains tax and to better utilize their funds. He emphasizes that under the premise of sound asset allocation and risk management, the borrowed money can be used flexibly.</li>
<li><strong>Real Estate Investment:</strong>  James advises against buying real estate, believing it restricts personal freedom. He uses the example of a friend in the Bay Area selling their property to support this viewpoint, pointing out the high holding costs of real estate, including property taxes, maintenance fees, and insurance, which can put significant financial pressure on individuals.</li>
<li><strong>Children&rsquo;s Education and Wealth Perspective:</strong> He suggests parents support their children&rsquo;s choices, believing that happiness is more important than wealth. Children shouldn&rsquo;t live for the sake of glorifying their family but should pursue happiness, serve others, and do what they love.</li>
<li><strong>433 Asset Allocation Plan:</strong> James recommends the 433 asset allocation plan (40% QQQ, 30% TQQQ, 30% Cash) for the general public, adjustable based on individual circumstances. For retirees who are not pledging stocks, he suggests an 80/20 allocation (80% index funds, 20% cash). For investors unfamiliar with or averse to leveraged ETFs, he recommends 100% investment in QQQ or 00662.</li>
<li><strong>Taiwan&rsquo;s Investment Environment Advantage:</strong> James highly praises Taiwan&rsquo;s investment environment, believing it possesses cutting-edge financial tools, tax-free policies, and low interest rates, making it an ideal place for investment. He encourages Taiwanese investors to leverage this advantage.</li>
<li><strong>Mid-Life Investment Strategy:</strong> He advises middle-aged individuals, even with modest incomes, to persist in monthly investments, accumulating wealth gradually for retirement. He illustrates the returns of monthly investments of 5,000 and 10,000 at retirement with specific examples.</li>
<li><strong>Advantages of Nasdaq 100 Index Funds:</strong> James explains the rationale for investing in QQQ, stating that its constituent companies have strong profitability, focus on technology and innovation, and align with long-term human development trends. He also points out that the constituent companies of the Nasdaq 100 index have stronger profitability compared to the S&amp;P 500.</li>
<li><strong>Investment Philosophy:</strong>  He advocates for the &ldquo;buy whenever you have money, never sell&rdquo; strategy, ignoring short-term fluctuations and believing in the long-term upward trajectory of the market. He emphasizes that the purpose of investment is wealth appreciation, not short-term gains, and criticizes the drawbacks of short-term trading.</li>
<li><strong>The Difference Between the Rich and the Poor:</strong> James points out that the rich possess assets and credit, which they can use to &ldquo;print money&rdquo; through leverage for rapid wealth growth.  The poor, lacking investment knowledge, keep their money in banks, missing out on wealth growth opportunities. He uses the example of Warren Buffett issuing bonds to illustrate how the rich utilize credit for investment.</li>
<li><strong>Three Contributions of Investors:</strong>  First, allocating capital to the most efficient companies, promoting technological advancement; second, helping the government invest idle foreign exchange reserves; third, helping the poor activate their funds, maximizing their social value.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Other Investment Advice and Opinions 
    <div id="other-investment-advice-and-opinions" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#other-investment-advice-and-opinions" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Don&rsquo;t blindly trust the investment advice of financial advisors and banks, as they have profit motives and may recommend products beneficial to themselves, not necessarily to investors.</li>
<li>Don&rsquo;t believe in investment recommendations from so-called &ldquo;group leaders&rdquo; or random individuals. Think independently, make your own decisions, and be responsible for your investments.</li>
<li>Focus on investing in broad-market passive funds in the US, such as the Nasdaq 100 Index Fund (QQQ) and the S&amp;P 500 Index Fund (SPY). He provides codes for investing in Nasdaq 100 index funds globally.</li>
<li>Avoid investing in unfamiliar assets like Bitcoin. Focus on core investment strategies to avoid distractions.</li>
<li>Don&rsquo;t overemphasize short-term market fluctuations and various news. Maintain an optimistic mindset and firmly believe in the long-term upward trend of the market.</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">III. Q&amp;A Session 
    <div id="iii-qa-session" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii-qa-session" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Zhang Yong 
    <div id="zhang-yong" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#zhang-yong" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Expresses gratitude to James, shares his 15-year experience in the insurance industry, reflects on some existing problems within the industry, such as promoting low-yield financial insurance, and expresses admiration for the simplicity and effectiveness of the CLEC investment philosophy and how it can change his and his family&rsquo;s financial future. He also shares his desire to help friends and family learn the CLEC investment philosophy but acknowledges the challenges in promotion.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s comments: Affirms Zhang Yong&rsquo;s sharing and thanks Dr. Lao Chai for the recommendation. Emphasizes the power of word-of-mouth marketing and encourages Zhang Yong to continue promoting the CLEC investment philosophy.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Mike 
    <div id="mike" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#mike" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Shares a discussion with friends in Taiwan about QQQ&rsquo;s component stock adjustments and rebalancing mechanism, mentioning the Matthew effect and the idea that the strong get stronger. He also expresses surprise at the relatively small total market capitalization of QQQ.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s comments: Suggests focusing on long-term performance rather than short-term fluctuations and explains that QQQ&rsquo;s smaller market cap is due to the relatively low number of people who understand and invest in it.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 1:  The impact of QQQ component adjustments and rebalancing mechanisms on investments, and whether one should invest in the smaller 90 companies.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s reply:  Advises focusing on long-term performance and volatility, not short-term component adjustments. QQQ&rsquo;s adjustment mechanism ensures the inclusion of the best companies, illustrated by the performance of Mega 7 and MAGS. Points out the &ldquo;stronger get stronger&rdquo; phenomenon among large companies and explains QQQ&rsquo;s rebalancing mechanism.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2: James&rsquo;s methods, tools, and experience in creating short videos, and the application of AI technology.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s reply: Details the short video production process, including writing scripts, using speech recognition software, text-to-video conversion, and subtitle generation. He shares his experience with AI tools, emphasizing the importance of personal creation and the limitations of AI in emotional expression. Mentions using tools like speech recognition software, PowerDirector, and some Chinese and Taiwanese video production software.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Hui 
    <div id="hui" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#hui" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question 1:  FNGS has performed better than QQQ. Can FNGS replace QQQ?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s reply: No, because FNGS has excessive volatility and higher risk, illustrated by the 2000 tech bubble.  Emphasizes that asset allocation should consider volatility and maximum drawdown, not just performance. In the long run, QQQ offers better stability.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2: XLG has lower volatility than QQQ and decent returns.  Is it suitable for allocation?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s reply: No, because XLG&rsquo;s long-term performance is inferior to QQQ. He provides a performance comparison of QQQ and XLG from 2006 to the present, showing QQQ&rsquo;s significantly higher returns. Emphasizes focusing on long-term performance and avoiding investments with poor long-term track records despite low short-term volatility. Investments with less than 30 years of market history are not worth discussing.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Ethan 
    <div id="ethan" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ethan" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Shares his two-year experience learning and promoting the CLEC investment philosophy in China, highlighting the positive impact and challenges. He suggests domestic investors consider opening accounts in Hong Kong to invest in QQQ and shares the advantages of investing in Hong Kong.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s comments: Affirms Ethan&rsquo;s sharing and promotional efforts, agrees with his suggestion of opening accounts in Hong Kong, and adds to the advantages, such as access to leveraged ETFs and money market funds, making the 433 asset allocation plan more comprehensive.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Ling 
    <div id="ling" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ling" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Shares her experience and understanding of the CLEC investment philosophy and how she applies it to life, such as educating her children.  She shares a childhood story of collecting shells for money and her desire for investment.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s comments: Acknowledges Ling&rsquo;s sharing and praises her proactive approach.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question: How to pledge stocks after retirement?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s reply: Explains the process of pledging stocks after retirement and emphasizes the importance of asset allocation.  Suggests the 433 asset allocation plan, adjusted according to the value of the pledged stocks. Explains how to calculate borrowing limits based on the value of pledged stocks and how to add collateral.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Martin 
    <div id="martin" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#martin" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Shares his investment experience and observations in Europe and expresses envy for the US investment environment. Mentions issues such as strict regulations and heavy tax burdens in Europe.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s comments: Agrees with Martin&rsquo;s viewpoint, analyzes the disadvantages of the European investment environment, such as high taxes and restrictions on the tech industry, and explains his focus on the US market. Points out that European socialist ideology and wealth expropriation are detrimental to capital accumulation and economic development.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Ying 
    <div id="ying" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ying" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Reflects on some mistakes in his investment journey, such as missing a year of market gains for a 5% fixed deposit interest rate, and shares his experience and insights on all-in investing in QQQ and TQQQ, and how he persuaded his wife to start investing.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s comments: Affirms Ying&rsquo;s sharing and reiterates the &ldquo;buy whenever you have money, never sell&rdquo; strategy and the all-in investment philosophy. Points out the importance of overcoming human weaknesses for investment success.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Pamela 
    <div id="pamela" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#pamela" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Shares the story of her neighbor being scammed by an accountant, reminding everyone to be cautious of investment risks and not to trust others blindly, even friends or professionals.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s comments: Agrees with Pamela&rsquo;s point, emphasizes the importance of improving one&rsquo;s financial literacy, and advises against over-reliance on financial advisors and accountants.  Points out that an accountant&rsquo;s responsibility is tax filing, not financial planning, so investors should not solely rely on their investment advice.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Nick 
    <div id="nick" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#nick" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Shares his investment experience in Canada, recommends HQU, the Canadian equivalent of QQQ, and discusses using IBKR&rsquo;s margin account. Highlights the challenges of investing in Canada and how to utilize IBKR for leverage.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s comments: Thanks Macro for sharing and suggests that IBKR&rsquo;s margin account might be an option for investors in countries without stock pledging.  Recommends that investors from other countries try and provide feedback on their experience with IBKR&rsquo;s margin account.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Julie 
    <div id="julie" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#julie" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question 1: Will pledging stocks affect mortgage refinancing?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s reply: No, stock pledging does not appear on credit reports and will not affect mortgage refinancing rates. He advises Julie to pledge her stocks as soon as possible and not wait for interest rates to decline, as future interest rate movements are unpredictable.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2: How to use TQQQ for investment and how to balance returns and risks? How to invest the money set aside for property taxes?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s reply: Suggests the 433 asset allocation plan, adjustable based on individual circumstances.  Emphasizes the importance of Beta management and recommends holding leveraged ETFs in retirement accounts. He advises against investing property tax money in TQQQ, recommending instead to keep it in cash or money market funds for unexpected needs.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Other Q&amp;A 
    <div id="other-qa" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#other-qa" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>James answers audience questions on topics such as 20-year investment returns, Warren Buffett&rsquo;s cash holdings, account selection for funds, short video production, the impact of FNG&rsquo;s bankruptcy on QQQ, simulating investments in the top ten stocks, stock pledging in Taiwan, 50/25/25 asset allocation, money market fund selection, leveraged ETF investment ratios, investment time horizons, and investment options in Canada.</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">IV. Key Takeaways 
    <div id="iv-key-takeaways" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv-key-takeaways" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>Buy whenever you have money, never sell.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This is James&rsquo;s consistent investment philosophy and the core strategy of CLEC.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Taiwan is a country with well-equipped weapons and cheap bullets.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>James praises Taiwan&rsquo;s investment environment, believing its financial tools, tax benefits, and low interest rates are highly advantageous for investors.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The most important thing in life is happiness.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>James emphasizes that the meaning of life lies in happiness, not in working and making money for its own sake.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>AI creations lack warmth.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>James shares his experience using AI tools for short video production, highlighting the limitations of AI in conveying emotions.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>You can be a benefactor to others, but whether they benefit depends on their destiny and fate.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>James shares his understanding of wealth and life, believing that an individual&rsquo;s wealth accumulation is influenced by destiny, fate, and luck, in addition to hard work.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The market has no peak, only higher highs; the market has no bottom, only a perpetual absence of a top or bottom.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>James emphasizes the long-term upward trend of the market and advises against trying to predict market tops and bottoms.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">V. Summary 
    <div id="v-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#v-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This session covered year-end rebalancing strategies, investment philosophy, the 433 asset allocation plan, CLEC short video production methods, and addressed various questions from students. James emphasized the importance of long-term investing and encouraged participants to create a reasonable asset allocation and rebalancing plan based on their individual circumstances, ignore short-term market fluctuations, and adhere to the &ldquo;buy whenever you have money, never sell&rdquo; principle.  During the Q&amp;A, students shared their investment experiences and concerns, raising questions about investment environments in different countries and specific investment products.  James provided professional guidance and advice, helping students better understand and apply the CLEC investment philosophy.</p>

  



<div
  
    class="flex px-4 py-3 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900"
  >

  <span
    
      class="text-primary-400 ltr:pr-3 rtl:pl-3 flex items-center"
    >

    

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M506.3 417l-213.3-364c-16.33-28-57.54-28-73.98 0l-213.2 364C-10.59 444.9 9.849 480 42.74 480h426.6C502.1 480 522.6 445 506.3 417zM232 168c0-13.25 10.75-24 24-24S280 154.8 280 168v128c0 13.25-10.75 24-23.1 24S232 309.3 232 296V168zM256 416c-17.36 0-31.44-14.08-31.44-31.44c0-17.36 14.07-31.44 31.44-31.44s31.44 14.08 31.44 31.44C287.4 401.9 273.4 416 256 416z"/></svg>

  </span>


  </span>

  <span
    
      class="dark:text-neutral-300"
    ><strong>Disclaimer:</strong> This article is for personal learning notes only and does not constitute any investment advice.</span>
</div>

]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>00486 Market Trends and Future Investment Strategies: Navigating the New Economic Era</title>
      <link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1728231523948/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1728231523948/</guid>
      <description>In this session, James shares his analysis of the current market situation and investment advice. He also answers questions from the audience on topics like asset allocation, retirement planning, children&amp;#39;s education, handling stock options, leverage, and tax planning.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<lite-youtube videoid="mwchPrvkFMA" playlabel="mwchPrvkFMA" params=""></lite-youtube>



<h2 class="relative group">I. Main Topic 
    <div id="i-main-topic" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-main-topic" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>The theme of this session is <strong>Embrace the New Bull Market and Invest Long-Term.</strong> James believes that the global monetary easing policy and the rapid development of AI technology herald the arrival of a new bull market. He advises everyone to invest in the Nasdaq 100 index fund (QQQ or 00662) and view market fluctuations with a long-term perspective.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">II.  Content Summary 
    <div id="ii--content-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii--content-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<ul>
<li><strong>A new bull market is coming:</strong>  The world has entered an era of loose monetary policy with the start of a rate cut cycle, which will drive the stock market up. This bull market may be a slow one but will continuously rise.</li>
<li><strong>Invest confidently in the Nasdaq 100 index fund:</strong> QQQ could increase by 50 times in the next 20 years, with an annualized return of over 20%, making it the best investment target.</li>
<li><strong>Individual stocks are unreliable:</strong> Individual stock investment is risky, and in the long run, almost all of them will disappear. They are very difficult to outperform the market in the long term. It is recommended not to waste time and energy on stock selection.</li>
<li><strong>Do not invest in the Chinese stock market:</strong> The Chinese stock market is not mature enough; consider investing in it after 30 years.</li>
<li><strong>Comparison of household asset allocation in the US and Taiwan:</strong>  American families invest most of their assets in securities to create social value, while Taiwanese families prefer cash, insurance, and real estate, locking up funds in non-appreciating areas.</li>
<li><strong>Leveraging through stock pledges:</strong> Using stock pledges to borrow increases liquidity and allows for continued investment to enjoy the benefits of compound growth. With an understanding of asset allocation, the interest cost of borrowing can be almost negligible.</li>
<li><strong>Plan for retirement early:</strong> Young people are advised to invest in 00662, and retirees can choose 00646 (SPY) or 0056 according to their fund size.</li>
<li><strong>Emphasize family education:</strong> Parents should cultivate their children&rsquo;s financial management concepts from an early age, guide them to make long-term investments, stay away from bad habits such as short-term speculation and gambling, and lead by example.</li>
<li><strong>Don&rsquo;t blindly trust high-yield investment products:</strong> Any investment product promising high returns may be a scam. It is important to understand its operating mechanism and learn to discern between true and false.</li>
<li><strong>The dangers of short-term trading:</strong> Short-term trading will miss the best investment opportunities. Long-term investment in index funds will yield more stable returns.</li>
<li><strong>The purpose of cash allocation:</strong> It is not for profit, but for dealing with emergencies like unemployment or a market crash. It is advisable to keep more than 10% of your assets in cash.</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">III. Q&amp;A Session 
    <div id="iii-qa-session" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii-qa-session" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<ul>
<li>
<p><strong>Retired Doctor Poch:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: After learning about James&rsquo; investment philosophy, he found a more relaxing and suitable investment method.</li>
<li>Question: How to obtain a stable cash flow after retirement? Is it necessary to adjust the investment strategy of 00662?
<ul>
<li>Answer:  The investment target can be adjusted according to the size of the retirement fund. Choose 00646 (SPY) or 0056 with lower volatility to guarantee cash flow.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>IM:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: He tried to guide his child to invest by matching contributions and increased his vigilance against high-yield traps.</li>
<li>Question 1: How to guide a child to invest and prevent them from spending investment income?
<ul>
<li>Answer: Emphasize that investment is a long-term behavior. Income cannot be withdrawn for consumption. Funds should grow continuously through compound interest.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2: How to choose a safe and reliable trust company? How to avoid the traps of high-yield trust products?
<ul>
<li>Answer: Any trust company that promises high returns may be a scam. You should take control of your own investment and financial management rights, clearly stipulate investment in index funds in the trust clause, and set up a regulatory unit to ensure fund security.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Rose:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: She frankly talked about her past investment failures and the process of gradually establishing the correct investment concept under the guidance of James.</li>
<li>Question 1: What are the differences and pros and cons of Margin Loan and Pledge Loan?  The interest rate of Margin Loan from IB is relatively low. Is it necessary to transfer to Charles Schwab for Pledge Loan?
<ul>
<li>Answer:  Margin Loan is riskier, and Pledge Loan is relatively safe. If the interest rate of IB&rsquo;s Margin Loan is low, you can continue to use it, but pay attention to controlling the borrowing ratio, preferably no more than 20%.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2: The return on cash allocation will decrease in the interest rate cut cycle. Is it still necessary to allocate cash?
<ul>
<li>Answer: The purpose of cash allocation is not for profit but to deal with contingencies, such as unemployment or a market crash. It is advisable to keep more than 10% of your assets in cash.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 3: How to manage children&rsquo;s investment accounts? Under whose name should it be, yours or the child&rsquo;s?
<ul>
<li>Answer: It is recommended to open an account in the child&rsquo;s name to cultivate their financial management concept, but control the amount and provide proper investment guidance. Estate planning can be done after the child becomes an adult.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Phoenix:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: He shared his confusion about handling company stock options and finally adopted James&rsquo; suggestion.</li>
<li>Question 1: How to deal with the stock options of unlisted companies?
<ul>
<li>Answer: If the company has a high possibility of going public, it is recommended to sell it to an investment company before the listing to get cash and invest in QQQ.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2: What do you think of Bitcoin? Can I invest in it?
<ul>
<li>Answer: If you already hold a small amount of Bitcoin, you can continue to hold it, but do not invest any more capital. It is recommended to focus on investing in QQQ.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Allen:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: He shared his questions about 401k and stock investment and eventually made adjustments under James&rsquo; advice.</li>
<li>Question 1: What should I do if I have too much money in my 401k account?
<ul>
<li>Answer:  It is recommended to stop making further contributions to 401k and transfer some funds to the Roth IRA account through the Backdoor Roth IRA.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2: How to switch from holding Nvidia stock to QQQ?
<ul>
<li>Answer: Sell Nvidia stock as soon as possible, transfer funds to QQQ, and pledge stocks to borrow money to pay taxes.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Haoqing:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: He demonstrated the difficulty of stock selection through data analysis and illustrated the advantages of long-term investment in QQQ with practical examples.</li>
<li>Question: Can stock picking beat QQQ?
<ul>
<li>Answer: Stock selection is difficult to outperform QQQ in the long run. Even if it beats the market in the short term, transaction costs and taxes need to be considered.  Invest in index funds for the long term.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Xiang:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: He shared his confusion about saving for children&rsquo;s education and inheritance and finally found a solution under James&rsquo; advice.</li>
<li>Question 1: Is it better to use a 529 Education Fund or invest in QQQ for children&rsquo;s education savings?
<ul>
<li>Answer:  Investing in QQQ is recommended because it has higher long-term returns and is more flexible.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2: How to do estate planning?
<ul>
<li>Answer:  For larger estates, it is recommended to set up an irrevocable trust and consult an estate lawyer for planning.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Kevin:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Frankly admitted his past investment failures and regained confidence under the guidance of James, starting to embark on the road of steady investment.</li>
<li>Question: How many listeners are losing money on investments?
<ul>
<li>Answer: Past investment experience is not important. What is important is to establish the correct investment concept and believe in the value of long-term investment in index funds.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Julia:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Shared her lessons learned from investing in Chinese concept stocks and second-tier growth stocks, and how to guide children to make long-term investments.</li>
<li>Question 1: How to deal with losses caused by investment in Chinese concept stocks and second-tier growth stocks?
- Answer: It is advisable to &ldquo;cut your losses&rdquo; and switch funds to QQQ in a timely manner.</li>
<li>Question 2: How to guide children to make long-term investments?
- Answer: You can use an investment calculator to show children the power of compound interest and guide them with your own investment experience.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Peter:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Shared his experience working at Apple and confirmed that many high-income earners also choose to invest in index funds.</li>
<li>Question: How to balance family expenses and investment?
- Answer: It is recommended to use stock pledges to borrow money to meet living expenses and continue investing in QQQ, so that assets can continue to grow through compound interest.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Jason:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: He shared his confusion about company tax declaration and finally found a suitable solution under James&rsquo; advice.</li>
<li>Question: How to choose the tax filing method?
<ul>
<li>Answer: If your income is low, you can choose to file a 1099; if your income is high, you are advised to establish an S Corporation.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Cindy:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Shared her experience of guiding her child to invest in Roth IRA and keep away from gambling.</li>
<li>Question: How to guide children to invest in Roth IRA? How to guide children to stay away from gambling?
<ul>
<li>Answer: Open a Roth IRA account for the child and make matching contributions. Lead by example and educate your child with the experiences and stories of people around you.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">IV.  Highlights 
    <div id="iv--highlights" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv--highlights" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>Lending is more powerful than the atomic bomb; it&rsquo;s ten times the atomic bomb!
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>When encouraging people to use stock pledges for borrowing and investment, James used this analogy to vividly illustrate the power of leverage.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Investing should be easy and fun.
&ndash;  Hola</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This is what a listener said when she shared her investment experience. She also tried short-term trading, but finally found that long-term investment suited her better.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Each person has a different destiny when it comes to money.
&ndash; Peter</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Peter said this thought-provoking sentence when he shared his experience of persuading his father to invest in QQQ. This also reflects that investment and financial management should be combined with one&rsquo;s own situation to find a suitable way.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>All the money in the world is mine; you just need to take it and use it.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>James used humorous words to express his confidence in the market when encouraging everyone to invest, which also reflects his optimistic and positive attitude towards life.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">V. Conclusion 
    <div id="v-conclusion" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#v-conclusion" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>In this live broadcast, James once again emphasized the concept of long-term investment in index funds. He also provided specific investment advice for the audience based on the current market situation, covering asset allocation, retirement planning, children&rsquo;s education, stock options handling, leverage, and tax planning. The sharing from the students provided other listeners with valuable reference experience, showing their growth and earnings during the process of learning about investment and financial management.</p>

  



<div
  
    class="flex px-4 py-3 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900"
  >

  <span
    
      class="text-primary-400 ltr:pr-3 rtl:pl-3 flex items-center"
    >

    

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M506.3 417l-213.3-364c-16.33-28-57.54-28-73.98 0l-213.2 364C-10.59 444.9 9.849 480 42.74 480h426.6C502.1 480 522.6 445 506.3 417zM232 168c0-13.25 10.75-24 24-24S280 154.8 280 168v128c0 13.25-10.75 24-23.1 24S232 309.3 232 296V168zM256 416c-17.36 0-31.44-14.08-31.44-31.44c0-17.36 14.07-31.44 31.44-31.44s31.44 14.08 31.44 31.44C287.4 401.9 273.4 416 256 416z"/></svg>

  </span>


  </span>

  <span
    
      class="dark:text-neutral-300"
    ><strong>Disclaimer:</strong> This article is only for personal learning notes and does not constitute any investment advice.</span>
</div>

]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
