<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Education on QQQ Investor</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/tags/education/</link><description>Recent content in Education on QQQ Investor</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jomonylw.github.io/en/tags/education/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Millionaire Next Door：Book Notes</title><link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1728996298300/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1728996298300/</guid><description>This book reveals the true portrait of American millionaires through a survey, debunking myths about them and showcasing their common characteristics：frugality, diligence, self-discipline, and skillful investment. It also explores the definition of wealth, how to accumulate it, how to educate children, and how to distribute inheritance, providing a life textbook for readers.</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[

<h2 class="relative group">I. Summary 
    <div id="i-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This book unveils the real lives of American millionaires through a comprehensive survey, shattering the mystique surrounding them. The authors discovered that most American millionaires were not born with a silver spoon but built their wealth from scratch through frugality, hard work, self-discipline, and smart investing. The book also explores the definition of wealth, how to accumulate it, how to raise children, and how to distribute inheritance, offering a practical guide for those who aspire to build wealth.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">II. Chapter Summaries 
    <div id="ii-chapter-summaries" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii-chapter-summaries" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Chapter 1: Meet the Millionaire Next Door 
    <div id="chapter-1-meet-the-millionaire-next-door" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chapter-1-meet-the-millionaire-next-door" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>This chapter introduces the authors&rsquo; motivation and methodology for surveying millionaires and paints a typical picture of an American millionaire: they are mostly self-made entrepreneurs who live frugally and focus on investment rather than conspicuous consumption.</li>
<li>Through analyzing affluent individuals from diverse racial backgrounds and professions, the authors reveal the relationship between wealth accumulation and factors like racial origin and career choices, emphasizing the crucial role of &ldquo;frugality&rdquo; in wealth building.</li>
<li>The authors introduce the concept of &ldquo;Big Hat, No Cattle,&rdquo; referring to the phenomenon that many who appear to be millionaires are not truly wealthy, while many genuine millionaires live modest, frugal lives.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chapter 2: Frugality: The Cornerstone of Wealth Building 
    <div id="chapter-2-frugality-the-cornerstone-of-wealth-building" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chapter-2-frugality-the-cornerstone-of-wealth-building" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>This chapter delves into the theme of &ldquo;frugality,&rdquo; highlighting it as the foundation of wealth accumulation.</li>
<li>By comparing the lifestyles and consumption habits of &ldquo;Prodigious Accumulators of Wealth (PAWs)&rdquo; and &ldquo;Under Accumulators of Wealth (UAWs),&rdquo; the authors demonstrate the decisive impact of frugality on wealth accumulation. For instance, the contrasting cases of Mr. Ford, a lawyer with high spending habits, and Mr. Richards, a mobile home dealer who lived frugally, ultimately show that Mr. Richards accumulated almost five times the wealth of Mr. Ford.</li>
<li>This chapter points out that most American millionaires are first-generation affluent individuals who practice a lifestyle of saving more than they spend, refraining from splurging on luxury items like expensive clothing, watches, and cars. They accumulate wealth but maintain a moderately frugal lifestyle.</li>
<li>This chapter also introduces a crucial wealth formula: <em>Age multiplied by realized pretax annual household income, divided by 10, minus inherited wealth, equals your expected net worth.</em> Using this formula, readers can calculate their expected net worth and assess whether they are PAWs, UAWs, or &ldquo;Average Accumulators of Wealth (AAWs).&rdquo;</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chapter 3: Time, Energy, and Money 
    <div id="chapter-3-time-energy-and-money" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chapter-3-time-energy-and-money" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>This chapter explores the importance of efficiently allocating &ldquo;time, energy, and money&rdquo; for wealth accumulation.</li>
<li>By comparing how PAWs and UAWs allocate these three resources, the chapter illustrates that PAWs prioritize long-term planning, investment strategies, and risk management, while UAWs tend towards instant gratification, impulsive spending, and a lack of financial planning.</li>
<li>This chapter emphasizes the importance of household budgeting, stating that even high earners need to meticulously plan and control expenses to accumulate wealth.</li>
<li>The authors point out that PAWs spend significantly more time on financial planning than UAWs, and PAWs prefer to invest in appreciating assets like stocks and real estate, while UAWs tend to spend their money on consumer goods.</li>
<li>The authors advise readers to manage their household finances like a business, creating a budget, controlling expenses, and regularly reviewing investment plans.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chapter 4: You Aren&rsquo;t What You Drive 
    <div id="chapter-4-you-arent-what-you-drive" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chapter-4-you-arent-what-you-drive" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>This chapter uses the car-buying habits of millionaires as an example to further illustrate the principle that &ldquo;being financially independent is more important than displaying high social status.&rdquo;</li>
<li>The authors categorize millionaire car buyers into four types: &ldquo;New-Car Dealers&rsquo; Conservatives,&rdquo; &ldquo;New-Car Shoppers,&rdquo; &ldquo;Used-Car Dealers&rsquo; Conservatives,&rdquo; and &ldquo;Used-Car Shoppers.&rdquo;</li>
<li>By analyzing the purchasing behaviors of these four types, the authors find that &ldquo;Used-Car Shoppers&rdquo; are the most frugal, highly price-sensitive, and adept at leveraging various channels to find the best deals. This group is also the most likely to become PAWs.</li>
<li>This chapter also notes that most millionaires buy American-made cars, and many buy used cars. They believe that cars are depreciating assets and there&rsquo;s no need to spend excessively on new ones.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chapter 5: Economic Outpatient Care 
    <div id="chapter-5-economic-outpatient-care" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chapter-5-economic-outpatient-care" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>This chapter explores the phenomenon of &ldquo;Economic Outpatient Care,&rdquo; where parents provide substantial financial assistance to their adult children, often leading to the children&rsquo;s lack of financial independence and drive, ultimately hindering their ability to accumulate wealth.</li>
<li>By comparing the wealth accumulation of children who receive &ldquo;Economic Outpatient Care&rdquo; with those who don&rsquo;t, the authors illustrate the negative impact of this practice. For example, the case of Rama and Mary, a couple who received long-term financial support from Mary&rsquo;s parents, ultimately developed high spending habits and failed to accumulate wealth.</li>
<li>This chapter analyzes the causes of &ldquo;Economic Outpatient Care&rdquo; and offers suggestions to help affluent parents avoid the tragedy of &ldquo;shirtsleeves to shirtsleeves in three generations.&rdquo; For instance, parents should teach their children frugality and financial management instead of solely providing financial aid.</li>
<li>This chapter points out that adult children who receive gifts from their parents generally perform worse in wealth accumulation compared to those who don&rsquo;t. This is because receiving gifts can foster dependence and a tendency to spend the money on consumption rather than investment.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chapter 6: Rules of Thumb 
    <div id="chapter-6-rules-of-thumb" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chapter-6-rules-of-thumb" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>This chapter discusses how affluent parents distribute wealth to their adult children and how they choose heirs.</li>
<li>The authors note that affluent parents often distribute wealth based on their children&rsquo;s professions, gender, and contributions to the family, tending to leave more to children who need financial assistance. For instance, homemakers often receive more inheritance than working children.</li>
<li>This chapter also emphasizes the importance of choosing executors and suggests that affluent parents select an experienced professional as a co-executor to prevent inheritance disputes among children.</li>
<li>This chapter offers advice to help affluent parents avoid family conflicts when distributing inheritance. For example, affluent parents should establish estate plans early and communicate with their children to ensure their wishes are understood.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chapter 7: Affirmative Action, Family Style 
    <div id="chapter-7-affirmative-action-family-style" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chapter-7-affirmative-action-family-style" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>This chapter explores the business opportunities in providing products and services to the wealthy, noting that these opportunities will continue to grow with the increasing affluent population.</li>
<li>The authors list several businesses and professions that can benefit from serving the wealthy, including specialized lawyers, healthcare and dental specialists, estate liquidators, educational institutions and professionals, and real estate experts.</li>
<li>The authors also analyze the spending habits of the wealthy and point out that they are willing to spend on certain aspects, such as investment consulting, healthcare, and education, which provides significant business opportunities for many industries.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chapter 8: The Perfect Investment 
    <div id="chapter-8-the-perfect-investment" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chapter-8-the-perfect-investment" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>This chapter discusses the relationship between career choice and wealth accumulation, pointing out that self-employed business owners and professionals are more likely to build wealth.</li>
<li>By comparing the profitability and risks of different professions, the authors illustrate why self-employed business owners and professionals are more likely to accumulate wealth. For example, the average profit margin of a doctor&rsquo;s office is higher than that of a coal mining operation.</li>
<li>This chapter also analyzes why affluent parents often discourage their children from taking over family businesses and instead recommend pursuing careers as self-employed professionals. This is because self-employed professionals can leverage their knowledge and skills to generate sustainable income, and their careers tend to be more stable and less risky.</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">III. Key Quotes 
    <div id="iii-key-quotes" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii-key-quotes" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;Wealth is not the same as income. If you make a good income each year and spend it all, you are not getting wealthier. You are just living high. Wealth is what you accumulate, not what you spend.&rdquo;</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Analysis: This quote highlights the book&rsquo;s core message: wealth accumulation is not solely based on high income but also relies on frugal habits and smart investment skills. High income doesn&rsquo;t equate to wealth; only by converting income into assets can one achieve true financial freedom.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;Frugality is the cornerstone of wealth building.&rdquo;</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Analysis: This quote emphasizes the crucial role of frugality in wealth accumulation. Only by controlling consumption can one free up more funds for investment, leading to wealth growth. Frugality doesn&rsquo;t mean living an austere life but rather being a rational consumer and avoiding unnecessary waste.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;To build wealth, minimize your realized (taxable) income and maximize your unrealized income (wealth that is not taxed until it is converted to cash).&rdquo;</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Analysis: This quote reveals a vital strategy for wealthy individuals to accumulate wealth, namely, achieving wealth growth through investment rather than solely relying on salary income. One must skillfully utilize tax policies to convert income into tax-advantaged assets like stocks and real estate.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;If you&rsquo;re not yet wealthy but want to be someday, never purchase a home that requires a mortgage that is more than twice your household&rsquo;s total annual realized income.&rdquo;</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Analysis: This quote offers practical advice for those in the early stages of wealth accumulation: avoid excessive mortgage burdens and allocate more funds towards investment. When funds are limited, prioritize investment over consumption.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;Those who are financially independent are considerably happier than those in the same income/age cohort who are not financially secure.&rdquo;</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Analysis: This quote illustrates the importance of financial security for personal happiness. Possessing sufficient wealth allows individuals to face life&rsquo;s challenges with greater confidence. Economic independence is the foundation of personal freedom and a crucial guarantee of happiness.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;Never tell children that their parents are wealthy.&rdquo;</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Analysis: This quote provides valuable educational advice for affluent parents: avoid letting children know about the family&rsquo;s wealth too early to prevent them from developing dependence and a lack of initiative. Children need to understand that wealth is created through their own efforts.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;No matter how wealthy you are, teach your children to be self-sufficient and frugal.&rdquo;</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Analysis: This quote emphasizes the importance of frugality and self-discipline. Even children from affluent families should develop good habits to better adapt to future challenges. Children need to understand that frugality is a virtue and a prerequisite for success.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">IV. Significance 
    <div id="iv-significance" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv-significance" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<ol>
<li><strong>Importance of Frugality and Financial Management:</strong> This book highlights the importance of frugality and investment, helping readers establish a correct perspective on wealth and offering practical financial advice. There are no shortcuts to wealth creation; only through diligent saving and rational investment can one steadily accumulate wealth.</li>
<li><strong>Wisdom in Raising Children:</strong> This book explores how to raise children to be financially responsible individuals, providing insights into the educational experiences and methods of affluent parents and inspiring readers to reflect on their own parenting styles. Affluent parents should focus on cultivating their children&rsquo;s independence, responsibility, and financial management skills instead of solely providing financial assistance.</li>
<li><strong>Career Choices and Wealth Accumulation:</strong> This book analyzes the profitability and risks of different professions, helping readers better understand the relationship between career choices and wealth accumulation and providing guidance for individual career planning. Choosing a career with development potential that aligns with one&rsquo;s interests and abilities is a crucial prerequisite for achieving wealth accumulation.</li>
<li><strong>Business Opportunities in Serving the Wealthy:</strong> This book reveals the vast business opportunities in providing products and services to the wealthy, offering insights and inspiration for aspiring entrepreneurs. To succeed in this market, one must be adept at identifying the needs of the wealthy and providing high-quality products and services.</li>
<li><strong>Debunking Stereotypes about the Wealthy:</strong> This book debunks the myths surrounding millionaires through its survey of American affluent individuals, presenting a realistic portrait of their lives and prompting readers to contemplate the true meaning of wealth. True wealth encompasses more than just money; it also includes health, happiness, family, and a sense of accomplishment.</li>
</ol>
<p>In conclusion, &ldquo;The Millionaire Next Door&rdquo; is a timeless classic worth revisiting. It not only unveils the secrets to the success of the wealthy but also provides valuable insights and methods for ordinary readers to accumulate wealth, raise children, and plan their lives.</p>
<hr>

<section class="space-y-10 w-full">
    
    
        
            






















  <a class="flex flex-wrap article " href="/en/posts/1728295490690-book-list/">
    
        
        <div class="w-full md:w-auto h-full thumbnail nozoom thumbnailshadow md:mr-7" style="background-image:url(/posts/1728295490690-book-list/featured_hu4424409690304057825.jpg);"></div>
        
      <div class=" mt-3 md:mt-0">
      <div class="items-center text-left text-xl font-semibold">
        
        <div class="font-bold text-xl text-neutral-800 decoration-primary-500 hover:underline hover:underline-offset-2 dark:text-neutral"
          href="/en/posts/1728295490690-book-list/">Recommended Reading List</div>
        
        
        
      </div>
      <div class="text-sm text-neutral-500 dark:text-neutral-400">
        











  









  



  









<div class="flex flex-row flex-wrap items-center">
  
  
  <time datetime="2024-10-01T00:00:00&#43;00:00">1 October 2024</time><span class="px-2 text-primary-500">&middot;</span><span>
  
  
    
    
      
      
        
        
      
        
        
      
      
    
  
  <span id="views_posts/1728295490690-book-list/index.md" class="animate-pulse inline-block text-transparent max-h-3 rounded-full mt-[-2px] align-middle bg-neutral-300 dark:bg-neutral-400" title="views">loading</span>
  <span class="inline-block align-text-bottom">

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 576 512">
<path fill="currentColor" d="M288 32c-80.8 0-145.5 36.8-192.6 80.6C48.6 156 17.3 208 2.5 243.7c-3.3 7.9-3.3 16.7 0 24.6C17.3 304 48.6 356 95.4 399.4C142.5 443.2 207.2 480 288 480s145.5-36.8 192.6-80.6c46.8-43.5 78.1-95.4 93-131.1c3.3-7.9 3.3-16.7 0-24.6c-14.9-35.7-46.2-87.7-93-131.1C433.5 68.8 368.8 32 288 32zM432 256c0 79.5-64.5 144-144 144s-144-64.5-144-144s64.5-144 144-144s144 64.5 144 144zM288 192c0 35.3-28.7 64-64 64c-11.5 0-22.3-3-31.6-8.4c-.2 2.8-.4 5.5-.4 8.4c0 53 43 96 96 96s96-43 96-96s-43-96-96-96c-2.8 0-5.6 .1-8.4 .4c5.3 9.3 8.4 20.1 8.4 31.6z"/></svg>
  </span>

</span>
</span><span class="px-2 text-primary-500">&middot;</span><span>
  
  
    
    
      
      
        
        
      
        
        
      
      
    
  
  <span id="likes_posts/1728295490690-book-list/index.md"
    class="animate-pulse inline-block text-transparent max-h-3 rounded-full mt-[-2px] align-middle bg-neutral-300 dark:bg-neutral-400"
    title="likes">loading</span>
  <span class="inline-block align-text-bottom">

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512">
<path fill="currentColor" d="M47.6 300.4L228.3 469.1c7.5 7 17.4 10.9 27.7 10.9s20.2-3.9 27.7-10.9L464.4 300.4c30.4-28.3 47.6-68 47.6-109.5v-5.8c0-69.9-50.5-129.5-119.4-141C347 36.5 300.6 51.4 268 84L256 96 244 84c-32.6-32.6-79-47.5-124.6-39.9C50.5 55.6 0 115.2 0 185.1v5.8c0 41.5 17.2 81.2 47.6 109.5z"/></svg>
  </span>

</span>
</span>
  

  
  
</div>





<div class="flex flex-row flex-wrap items-center">
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  <span style="margin-top:0.5rem" class="mr-2" onclick="window.open(&#34;/en/tags/recommended/&#34;,'_self');">
    <span class="flex" style="cursor: pointer;">
  <span class="rounded-md border border-primary-400 px-1 py-[1px] text-xs font-normal text-primary-700 dark:border-primary-600 dark:text-primary-400">
    Recommended
  </span>
</span>
  </span>
  
  <span style="margin-top:0.5rem" class="mr-2" onclick="window.open(&#34;/en/tags/book/&#34;,'_self');">
    <span class="flex" style="cursor: pointer;">
  <span class="rounded-md border border-primary-400 px-1 py-[1px] text-xs font-normal text-primary-700 dark:border-primary-600 dark:text-primary-400">
    Book
  </span>
</span>
  </span>
  
  
  
  
</div>




      </div>
      
    </div>
  </a>

        
    
</section>
]]></content:encoded></item></channel></rss>