<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Children&#39;s Education on QQQ Investor</title>
    <link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/tags/childrens-education/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Children&#39;s Education on QQQ Investor</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jomonylw.github.io/en/tags/childrens-education/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>00493 Financial Risks and Investment Wisdom: How to Accumulate and Utilize Assets; Stock Pledge and Asset Allocation: Smart Choices for Risk Reduction</title>
      <link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1733026874385/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1733026874385/</guid>
      <description>In this episode, James reiterates the current market highs and advises investors to remain patient, adhere to long-term investment strategies, and avoid being swayed by short-term fluctuations. He also addresses questions from students regarding asset allocation, stock pledging, insurance, annuities, children&amp;#39;s education, and how to cope with market volatility, sharing his understanding of Modern Monetary Theory (MMT).</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<lite-youtube videoid="V0d8y8-Jl-w" playlabel="V0d8y8-Jl-w" params=""></lite-youtube>



<h2 class="relative group">I. Main Topic 
    <div id="i-main-topic" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-main-topic" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>The market continues to reach new highs.  Investing doesn&rsquo;t require constant attention; the key is to stick to a long-term investment strategy, maintain a well-diversified asset allocation, and remain patient. The real risk isn&rsquo;t short-term volatility, but the inability to accumulate sufficient wealth over the long term, and not knowing how to utilize accumulated wealth effectively.  Furthermore, it&rsquo;s crucial to be wary of various financial traps and maintain rational investment practices.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">II. Briefing Content 
    <div id="ii-briefing-content" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii-briefing-content" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Market Trends and Investment Strategies 
    <div id="market-trends-and-investment-strategies" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#market-trends-and-investment-strategies" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>The market is at a new high. Don&rsquo;t waste time over-analyzing; stick to long-term investing, buy and hold.  The market generally trends upwards; instead of predicting pullbacks, enter the market early.</li>
<li>Investing doesn&rsquo;t require excessive time. After placing your order, step away and let time work its magic through compounding.</li>
<li>Be wary of scams. Don&rsquo;t trust any investment advice that guarantees stable returns or daily gains.  Be extremely cautious of &ldquo;guaranteed profit&rdquo; schemes.</li>
<li>Ignore the advice of financial advisors and insurance agents. They rarely have the investor&rsquo;s best interests at heart and are often motivated by their own profits. Many financial products are designed to benefit the seller, not the investor.</li>
<li>Investing isn&rsquo;t simple. Even asset allocation within a Nasdaq 100 index fund requires in-depth research and adjustments based on individual circumstances.</li>
<li>Investors should always remain optimistic. The market will eventually rise. Patiently await wealth accumulation. Time is an investor&rsquo;s friend.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Risk Management and Wealth Goals 
    <div id="risk-management-and-wealth-goals" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#risk-management-and-wealth-goals" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>The biggest risks are not market fluctuations, but the failure to accumulate sufficient wealth over the long term and not knowing how to utilize accumulated wealth effectively. The ultimate goal of investing is to achieve financial freedom and enjoy life.</li>
<li>Avoid the instinctive reaction to short-term losses. Overcome fear and don&rsquo;t panic sell. Market downturns are normal and present buying opportunities.</li>
<li>View bear markets as opportunities. Buying low translates to higher future returns. Learn to think contrarily and utilize market fluctuations for mindless rebalancing.</li>
<li>The investment objective is to mitigate the risk of financial hardship, not to maximize returns. A sound investment strategy is more crucial than chasing high returns.</li>
<li>Choose a simple, low-cost, passive index investment strategy, such as a Nasdaq 100 index fund, and hold a portion in cash to maintain psychological balance and cope with market volatility.</li>
<li>Holding safe assets (like certificates of deposit and money market funds) can mitigate short-term risks, stabilize emotions during market fluctuations, and provide a sense of security.</li>
<li>The proportion of safe assets held should be adjusted based on age and risk tolerance. Retirees are advised to hold cash equivalent to 5 years of living expenses, while those yet to retire can hold more.</li>
<li>Young people should prioritize term life insurance to protect their families and avoid other types of insurance to prevent being misled by insurance companies.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Other Advice 
    <div id="other-advice" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#other-advice" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Be skeptical of all information, especially regarding money. Learn to think independently and don&rsquo;t blindly trust so-called &ldquo;experts.&rdquo;</li>
<li>Don&rsquo;t buy insurance or annuities for investment purposes. The essence of insurance is protection, not investment; annuities have high fees and low returns.</li>
<li>Don&rsquo;t disclose your wealth to your children. Encourage them to strive independently and create wealth through their own abilities.</li>
<li>Engage in rational discussions, view investments with a mathematical mindset, and analyze investment results with data.</li>
<li>Avoid over-investing in real estate. Maintain ample cash flow. Real estate has poor liquidity and is difficult to liquidate.</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">III. Q&amp;A Session 
    <div id="iii-qa-session" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii-qa-session" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Ke An 
    <div id="ke-an" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ke-an" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: 16 years old, living in the Netherlands.  Thanked James for his investment methods, which allowed her parents to take her on trips throughout Europe. She also shared that she finds her business management classes easier to understand than her classmates, thanks to James&rsquo;s teachings.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s comments: Praised Ke An&rsquo;s travel experiences and learning attitude, encouraging her to continue learning and explore her career interests.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question: Concerned about starting investing late, wants to open an account and start investing soon. Has saved NT$200,000 and plans to invest in 00662.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s reply: Affirmed the advantage of starting to invest at 16, emphasizing that time is the greatest asset.  Advised her to balance learning, life, and investment, and to enjoy her youth.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Ji Ya 
    <div id="ji-ya" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ji-ya" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question: Has savings equivalent to 8 years of living expenses. Working 40 hours a week only covers expenses. Driving for Uber could increase income but wants more free time. Unsure how to balance work and life and whether early retirement is possible. Is currently 42 years old.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s reply: In 15 years, the 8x annual expenses will grow to 50x due to compounding, enabling retirement. Suggested a BETA of 1.2 to increase investment returns, or driving for Uber a few hours a week to accelerate wealth accumulation and achieve early retirement.  Emphasized that pursuing early retirement shouldn&rsquo;t be the sole focus and that finding a balance between work and life is important. Health is paramount.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chun Xia 
    <div id="chun-xia" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chun-xia" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question 1: Plans to invest a loan of NT$7 million and aims for a return of NT$20-30 million within 10-15 years. Should the investment be lump-sum or staggered?  Has additional monthly income of NT$30,000-40,000.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s reply: Based on a 14% annualized return, there will be NT$67 million after 15 years, reaching the NT$20-30 million target within 10 years. Recommended a lump-sum investment to capitalize on market growth.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2: Wants to share investment philosophy with family in China.  Inquired about account opening procedures and trading software options in China.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s reply: Suggested Chun Xia email him for an introduction to a leader familiar with the Chinese market who can provide specific guidance on account opening and software selection.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Peter 
    <div id="peter" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#peter" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question: How to persuade family members to invest? They&rsquo;ve heard the advice but haven&rsquo;t acted, finding it difficult.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s reply: Acknowledged the &ldquo;familiarity bias&rdquo; that makes it difficult for family members to accept advice. Suggested Peter lead by example, sharing his investment philosophy and success stories. Encourage them to start with a small investment, like $100,000 in QQQ, and offer to cover any losses to build their confidence. He particularly recommended starting with retirement accounts and broad market index funds.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Ling 
    <div id="ling" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ling" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question:  Regarding children&rsquo;s education fund investment plan. Initially planned to invest all children&rsquo;s allowances in 00662 with monthly contributions, but has doubts after hearing James&rsquo;s lessons on children&rsquo;s education.  Should the plan be adjusted?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s reply: Advised prioritizing personal wealth accumulation and achieving financial freedom before focusing on children&rsquo;s education funds. Suggested redirecting the monthly contributions to personal investments to accelerate wealth growth.  Income like Lunar New Year red envelopes can continue to be invested for the children.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Dennis 
    <div id="dennis" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#dennis" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing 1: An insurance agent passed away due to financial problems, highlighting the importance of risk management, even for insurance professionals.</li>
<li>Sharing 2: Family recommended a video by an MIT professor about national debt, who argued that national debt is another form of taxation.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s reply: Explained Modern Monetary Theory (MMT).  U.S. national debt represents savings held by the public. The U.S. government&rsquo;s debt is repaid by Americans. The value of the dollar lies in its credit and the goods and services it can buy, not the level of debt. The government can stimulate the economy by issuing national debt without worrying about excessive debt.  Issuing national debt and lottery tickets are essentially providing investment channels, not just taxation.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Sharing 3: Wants to learn more about MMT.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s reply: Recommended Dennis search for books and materials on &ldquo;Modern Monetary Theory&rdquo; for a deeper understanding of its principles and applications.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Hao Xin 
    <div id="hao-xin" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#hao-xin" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question:  Are the P/E ratios of QQQ and SPY overvalued? How to deal with market fluctuations? Concerned that a prolonged stagnant market will cause borrowing interest to exceed cash reserves.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s reply: P/E ratios are unreliable and unpredictable. Recommended passive rebalancing.  Cash reserves will increase as the market rises; reinvest during downturns. Suggested simulating the 2000-2009 market scenario to test the robustness of the asset allocation strategy. If the market does stagnate for a long time, adjust lifestyle, reduce expenses, or consider other income sources. In the long run, the market will always go up; maintain confidence.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Sharing: Received a suspected scam call where the caller claimed to be from the bank and requested personal information verification.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s comments:  Commended Hao Xin&rsquo;s vigilance and reminded everyone to be cautious of calls requesting personal information to avoid being scammed.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">IV. Key Takeaways 
    <div id="iv-key-takeaways" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv-key-takeaways" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;The first investment earns the most; that performance can never be replicated.&rdquo;
&ndash; Monica</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Monica&rsquo;s statement highlights the importance of early investment and the difficulty of timing the market. Early investments enjoy higher returns, and over time, even with the same investment strategy, it&rsquo;s hard to replicate those early gains.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;The U.S. government&rsquo;s debt is the public&rsquo;s savings.&rdquo;
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This perspective challenges the traditional understanding of national debt, emphasizing the unique nature of U.S. Treasury bonds.  U.S. national debt represents dollar-denominated assets held by U.S. citizens and global investors, reflecting confidence in the American economy.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;Survival is key, not maximizing returns.&rdquo;
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This statement pinpoints the core goal of investing, reminding investors not to be tempted by high returns at the expense of risk management. Preserving capital is more important than chasing high returns during market fluctuations.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;Time is an investor&rsquo;s friend.&rdquo;
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Only long-term investments can fully benefit from the power of compounding. Time is an investor&rsquo;s best ally.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">V. Summary 
    <div id="v-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#v-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>In this episode, James once again emphasized the importance of long-term investing and risk management, offering personalized advice tailored to each student&rsquo;s circumstances. His clear explanations helped students better understand market trends, investment strategies, and the essence of wealth management. He also shared his understanding of Modern Monetary Theory (MMT) and awareness of various financial traps, reminding investors to remain rational and avoid blindly chasing high returns.</p>

  



<div
  
    class="flex px-4 py-3 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900"
  >

  <span
    
      class="text-primary-400 ltr:pr-3 rtl:pl-3 flex items-center"
    >

    

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M506.3 417l-213.3-364c-16.33-28-57.54-28-73.98 0l-213.2 364C-10.59 444.9 9.849 480 42.74 480h426.6C502.1 480 522.6 445 506.3 417zM232 168c0-13.25 10.75-24 24-24S280 154.8 280 168v128c0 13.25-10.75 24-23.1 24S232 309.3 232 296V168zM256 416c-17.36 0-31.44-14.08-31.44-31.44c0-17.36 14.07-31.44 31.44-31.44s31.44 14.08 31.44 31.44C287.4 401.9 273.4 416 256 416z"/></svg>

  </span>


  </span>

  <span
    
      class="dark:text-neutral-300"
    ><strong>Disclaimer:</strong> This article is for personal learning notes only and does not constitute any investment advice.</span>
</div>

]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>00479 Three Easy Examples of Getting Rich, The Power of Starting Early and Compound Interest</title>
      <link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1728391134352/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1728391134352/</guid>
      <description>In this session, James reiterates the importance of long-term index fund investing, illustrating the power of compounding interest with multiple examples. He also explains how to avoid common investment pitfalls to achieve financial freedom.  Additionally, James addresses audience questions on asset allocation, real estate investment, trusts, and children&amp;#39;s education funds.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<lite-youtube videoid="1VSo2I6xqG0" playlabel="1VSo2I6xqG0" params=""></lite-youtube>



<h2 class="relative group">I. Main Topic 
    <div id="i-main-topic" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-main-topic" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This session focuses on long-term index fund investing. The core message is: hold index funds firmly, ignore market fluctuations, maintain a proper asset allocation, and leverage the compounding effect of time to achieve financial freedom.  James also warns against investment scams and emphasizes avoiding unnecessary risks, while offering advice on investing in children&rsquo;s education funds.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">II. Presentation Summary 
    <div id="ii-presentation-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii-presentation-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<ul>
<li><strong>Advantages of Index Funds:</strong> Long-term index fund investing eliminates the need to follow short-term market fluctuations, international affairs, financial reports, and economic data.  Focus on asset allocation and consistent investment.</li>
<li><strong>The Power of Compounding:</strong> James uses several examples to illustrate the magic of compounding:  A monthly investment of 1000 TWD can grow to 17.3 million TWD in 40 years; a lump-sum investment of 100,000 TWD can reach 18.8 million TWD in 40 years;  starting early is crucial, as a 10-year delay significantly impacts final returns; one share of QQQ at 500 USD will become 25,000 USD in 30 years and 94,000 USD in 40 years.</li>
<li><strong>Safe Asset Allocation:</strong> Asset allocation is more critical than any market commentary. James recommends deleveraging and reducing debt for those nearing retirement, holding a larger cash position.  For younger individuals with stable income, leveraging can be considered. He suggests using a beta of 1.0 as a benchmark, reducing beta when the market is overheated, and increasing it back to 1.0 during market downturns.  For cash allocation, he references Buffett and suggests a sample allocation (Scenario 3): 40% index funds, 30% 2x leveraged funds, and 30% cash.</li>
<li><strong>Beware of Investment Scams:</strong>  Don&rsquo;t trust investment information from unknown accounts or websites. Choose legitimate financial institutions.</li>
<li><strong>Don&rsquo;t Give Money Directly to Children:</strong> James uses personal anecdotes and case studies to caution against putting assets directly in children&rsquo;s names, as this may discourage their initiative or cause family conflicts.  However, investing children&rsquo;s &ldquo;lucky money&rdquo; (red envelopes) for them is recommended as an educational fund.</li>
<li><strong>Risks of Real Estate Investment:</strong> James reiterates his advice against early homeownership for young people, arguing that real estate is illiquid, high-risk, and ties up capital that could be used for other investments.  He highlights the added risk in Taiwan, where mortgage debt remains even after foreclosure.</li>
<li><strong>Recommended Learning Resources:</strong> He recommends a YouTube channel called &ldquo;什么值得读&rdquo; (What&rsquo;s Worth Reading) for valuable content on value investing.</li>
<li><strong>Emergency Fund:</strong> Maintain a cash reserve equivalent to six months of living expenses in a money market fund account. Investing this emergency fund in stocks is not recommended.</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">III. Q&amp;A Session 
    <div id="iii-qa-session" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii-qa-session" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p><strong>Jeff:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Shares:  Highlights misconceptions about investing held by two listeners and emphasizes the importance of carefully studying James&rsquo;s lecture notes, particularly the chart on page two.</li>
<li>James&rsquo;s response:  Affirms Jeff&rsquo;s points and re-emphasizes the importance of a solid investment philosophy to avoid being swayed by market noise.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Cat:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Shares: A listener holding 35 million TWD in 00662 still finds the 2% withdrawal rate insufficient. Discusses the spending needs and inheritance considerations of single individuals.</li>
<li>James&rsquo;s response: Different indices have different volatility and dividend yields, requiring adjustments to withdrawal rates. For higher withdrawals, consider ETFs with higher dividend yields, such as 0056, which yields around 4-5%.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>H:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Question:  High rental costs for young people, should they buy a house?  Mortgages offer tax deductions, while renting does not.  Concerned about insufficient funds for leveraged investing.</li>
<li>James&rsquo;s response:  Recommends watching the &ldquo;30 Years of Different Destinies&rdquo; video, which analyzes the pros and cons of renting versus buying.  Young people should prioritize investing in index funds to build wealth through compounding and consider buying a house later.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Yonglin:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Question: Should money be invested in children&rsquo;s names for long-term holding?  Should a mortgage-free house be sold to invest in index funds after retirement?</li>
<li>James&rsquo;s response:  Advises against putting money directly in children&rsquo;s names.  Retirees should deleverage, and selling a mortgage-free house to invest in index funds is a viable option.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Mike:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Shares: Success story of investing his children&rsquo;s education fund in QQQ.  Gives the example of Taoyuan Language in Taiwan, suggesting potential leveraged investment through real estate mortgages.</li>
<li>Question: How to establish a family trust and manage generational wealth like the Rockefeller family?</li>
<li>James&rsquo;s response:  Recommends contacting Lisa for trust advice when assets reach a certain level and age. For now, focus on investing. Trusts can be considered around 70-80 years old. Single individuals or those without children should rely on trusts, appointing guardians and executors.  Those with children can consider Trust 2.0, with the bank as executor and children as supervisors.  Family foundations managed by professional institutions are also an option.  Recommends the Walmart family&rsquo;s living trust as a model.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Becky, Jessie, and Other Participants:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Becky: Difficulties of renting at an older age.</li>
<li>Jessie: How to balance saving for an emergency fund, paying off a mortgage, and investing simultaneously.</li>
<li>Other Participants: Questions about real estate investment, cash management, insurance, Bitcoin, and Japanese government bonds.</li>
<li>James&rsquo;s response:  Addresses each question and reiterates his investment philosophy.  For example, young people should avoid real estate and insurance due to high risks; long-term bonds and municipal bonds are not suitable for emergency funds.</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">IV. Key Takeaways 
    <div id="iv-key-takeaways" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv-key-takeaways" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>Time is the source of all power.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>James uses examples like the evolution of Earth&rsquo;s ecosystem and human evolution to illustrate the power of time and emphasize the importance of long-term investing.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Don&rsquo;t casually help others with money.  People will resent you for it for a lifetime.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Cautions against testing human nature with money and emphasizes setting boundaries with financial assistance.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The earlier you invest, the better.  Keep enough emergency funds. The earlier you invest, the lower the risk.
&ndash; Jeff</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Emphasizes the importance of early investing and maintaining an emergency fund.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Laugh a little; how long a scammer can scam is determined by the fool.
&ndash; Mike</p>
</blockquote>
<p>A cynical comment on the prevalence of scammers and a reminder to stay vigilant.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">V. Conclusion 
    <div id="v-conclusion" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#v-conclusion" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>The core message of this session remains long-term index fund investing. James uses clear language and vivid examples to reiterate the power of compounding and the importance of starting early. He also addresses audience questions on asset allocation, real estate, trusts, emergency funds, and children&rsquo;s education funds, sharing advice on avoiding common investment traps and achieving financial freedom.  He further recommends learning resources and provides commentary on social phenomena.</p>

  



<div
  
    class="flex px-4 py-3 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900"
  >

  <span
    
      class="text-primary-400 ltr:pr-3 rtl:pl-3 flex items-center"
    >

    

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M506.3 417l-213.3-364c-16.33-28-57.54-28-73.98 0l-213.2 364C-10.59 444.9 9.849 480 42.74 480h426.6C502.1 480 522.6 445 506.3 417zM232 168c0-13.25 10.75-24 24-24S280 154.8 280 168v128c0 13.25-10.75 24-23.1 24S232 309.3 232 296V168zM256 416c-17.36 0-31.44-14.08-31.44-31.44c0-17.36 14.07-31.44 31.44-31.44s31.44 14.08 31.44 31.44C287.4 401.9 273.4 416 256 416z"/></svg>

  </span>


  </span>

  <span
    
      class="dark:text-neutral-300"
    ><strong>Disclaimer:</strong> This document is for personal learning notes only and does not constitute any investment advice.</span>
</div>

]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
