<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Market Analysis on QQQ Investor</title>
    <link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/tags/market-analysis/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Market Analysis on QQQ Investor</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jomonylw.github.io/en/tags/market-analysis/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>00493 Financial Risks and Investment Wisdom: How to Accumulate and Utilize Assets; Stock Pledge and Asset Allocation: Smart Choices for Risk Reduction</title>
      <link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1733026874385/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1733026874385/</guid>
      <description>In this episode, James reiterates the current market highs and advises investors to remain patient, adhere to long-term investment strategies, and avoid being swayed by short-term fluctuations. He also addresses questions from students regarding asset allocation, stock pledging, insurance, annuities, children&amp;#39;s education, and how to cope with market volatility, sharing his understanding of Modern Monetary Theory (MMT).</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<lite-youtube videoid="V0d8y8-Jl-w" playlabel="V0d8y8-Jl-w" params=""></lite-youtube>



<h2 class="relative group">I. Main Topic 
    <div id="i-main-topic" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-main-topic" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>The market continues to reach new highs.  Investing doesn&rsquo;t require constant attention; the key is to stick to a long-term investment strategy, maintain a well-diversified asset allocation, and remain patient. The real risk isn&rsquo;t short-term volatility, but the inability to accumulate sufficient wealth over the long term, and not knowing how to utilize accumulated wealth effectively.  Furthermore, it&rsquo;s crucial to be wary of various financial traps and maintain rational investment practices.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">II. Briefing Content 
    <div id="ii-briefing-content" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii-briefing-content" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Market Trends and Investment Strategies 
    <div id="market-trends-and-investment-strategies" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#market-trends-and-investment-strategies" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>The market is at a new high. Don&rsquo;t waste time over-analyzing; stick to long-term investing, buy and hold.  The market generally trends upwards; instead of predicting pullbacks, enter the market early.</li>
<li>Investing doesn&rsquo;t require excessive time. After placing your order, step away and let time work its magic through compounding.</li>
<li>Be wary of scams. Don&rsquo;t trust any investment advice that guarantees stable returns or daily gains.  Be extremely cautious of &ldquo;guaranteed profit&rdquo; schemes.</li>
<li>Ignore the advice of financial advisors and insurance agents. They rarely have the investor&rsquo;s best interests at heart and are often motivated by their own profits. Many financial products are designed to benefit the seller, not the investor.</li>
<li>Investing isn&rsquo;t simple. Even asset allocation within a Nasdaq 100 index fund requires in-depth research and adjustments based on individual circumstances.</li>
<li>Investors should always remain optimistic. The market will eventually rise. Patiently await wealth accumulation. Time is an investor&rsquo;s friend.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Risk Management and Wealth Goals 
    <div id="risk-management-and-wealth-goals" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#risk-management-and-wealth-goals" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>The biggest risks are not market fluctuations, but the failure to accumulate sufficient wealth over the long term and not knowing how to utilize accumulated wealth effectively. The ultimate goal of investing is to achieve financial freedom and enjoy life.</li>
<li>Avoid the instinctive reaction to short-term losses. Overcome fear and don&rsquo;t panic sell. Market downturns are normal and present buying opportunities.</li>
<li>View bear markets as opportunities. Buying low translates to higher future returns. Learn to think contrarily and utilize market fluctuations for mindless rebalancing.</li>
<li>The investment objective is to mitigate the risk of financial hardship, not to maximize returns. A sound investment strategy is more crucial than chasing high returns.</li>
<li>Choose a simple, low-cost, passive index investment strategy, such as a Nasdaq 100 index fund, and hold a portion in cash to maintain psychological balance and cope with market volatility.</li>
<li>Holding safe assets (like certificates of deposit and money market funds) can mitigate short-term risks, stabilize emotions during market fluctuations, and provide a sense of security.</li>
<li>The proportion of safe assets held should be adjusted based on age and risk tolerance. Retirees are advised to hold cash equivalent to 5 years of living expenses, while those yet to retire can hold more.</li>
<li>Young people should prioritize term life insurance to protect their families and avoid other types of insurance to prevent being misled by insurance companies.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Other Advice 
    <div id="other-advice" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#other-advice" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Be skeptical of all information, especially regarding money. Learn to think independently and don&rsquo;t blindly trust so-called &ldquo;experts.&rdquo;</li>
<li>Don&rsquo;t buy insurance or annuities for investment purposes. The essence of insurance is protection, not investment; annuities have high fees and low returns.</li>
<li>Don&rsquo;t disclose your wealth to your children. Encourage them to strive independently and create wealth through their own abilities.</li>
<li>Engage in rational discussions, view investments with a mathematical mindset, and analyze investment results with data.</li>
<li>Avoid over-investing in real estate. Maintain ample cash flow. Real estate has poor liquidity and is difficult to liquidate.</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">III. Q&amp;A Session 
    <div id="iii-qa-session" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii-qa-session" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Ke An 
    <div id="ke-an" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ke-an" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: 16 years old, living in the Netherlands.  Thanked James for his investment methods, which allowed her parents to take her on trips throughout Europe. She also shared that she finds her business management classes easier to understand than her classmates, thanks to James&rsquo;s teachings.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s comments: Praised Ke An&rsquo;s travel experiences and learning attitude, encouraging her to continue learning and explore her career interests.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question: Concerned about starting investing late, wants to open an account and start investing soon. Has saved NT$200,000 and plans to invest in 00662.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s reply: Affirmed the advantage of starting to invest at 16, emphasizing that time is the greatest asset.  Advised her to balance learning, life, and investment, and to enjoy her youth.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Ji Ya 
    <div id="ji-ya" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ji-ya" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question: Has savings equivalent to 8 years of living expenses. Working 40 hours a week only covers expenses. Driving for Uber could increase income but wants more free time. Unsure how to balance work and life and whether early retirement is possible. Is currently 42 years old.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s reply: In 15 years, the 8x annual expenses will grow to 50x due to compounding, enabling retirement. Suggested a BETA of 1.2 to increase investment returns, or driving for Uber a few hours a week to accelerate wealth accumulation and achieve early retirement.  Emphasized that pursuing early retirement shouldn&rsquo;t be the sole focus and that finding a balance between work and life is important. Health is paramount.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chun Xia 
    <div id="chun-xia" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chun-xia" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question 1: Plans to invest a loan of NT$7 million and aims for a return of NT$20-30 million within 10-15 years. Should the investment be lump-sum or staggered?  Has additional monthly income of NT$30,000-40,000.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s reply: Based on a 14% annualized return, there will be NT$67 million after 15 years, reaching the NT$20-30 million target within 10 years. Recommended a lump-sum investment to capitalize on market growth.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2: Wants to share investment philosophy with family in China.  Inquired about account opening procedures and trading software options in China.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s reply: Suggested Chun Xia email him for an introduction to a leader familiar with the Chinese market who can provide specific guidance on account opening and software selection.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Peter 
    <div id="peter" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#peter" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question: How to persuade family members to invest? They&rsquo;ve heard the advice but haven&rsquo;t acted, finding it difficult.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s reply: Acknowledged the &ldquo;familiarity bias&rdquo; that makes it difficult for family members to accept advice. Suggested Peter lead by example, sharing his investment philosophy and success stories. Encourage them to start with a small investment, like $100,000 in QQQ, and offer to cover any losses to build their confidence. He particularly recommended starting with retirement accounts and broad market index funds.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Ling 
    <div id="ling" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ling" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question:  Regarding children&rsquo;s education fund investment plan. Initially planned to invest all children&rsquo;s allowances in 00662 with monthly contributions, but has doubts after hearing James&rsquo;s lessons on children&rsquo;s education.  Should the plan be adjusted?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s reply: Advised prioritizing personal wealth accumulation and achieving financial freedom before focusing on children&rsquo;s education funds. Suggested redirecting the monthly contributions to personal investments to accelerate wealth growth.  Income like Lunar New Year red envelopes can continue to be invested for the children.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Dennis 
    <div id="dennis" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#dennis" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing 1: An insurance agent passed away due to financial problems, highlighting the importance of risk management, even for insurance professionals.</li>
<li>Sharing 2: Family recommended a video by an MIT professor about national debt, who argued that national debt is another form of taxation.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s reply: Explained Modern Monetary Theory (MMT).  U.S. national debt represents savings held by the public. The U.S. government&rsquo;s debt is repaid by Americans. The value of the dollar lies in its credit and the goods and services it can buy, not the level of debt. The government can stimulate the economy by issuing national debt without worrying about excessive debt.  Issuing national debt and lottery tickets are essentially providing investment channels, not just taxation.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Sharing 3: Wants to learn more about MMT.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s reply: Recommended Dennis search for books and materials on &ldquo;Modern Monetary Theory&rdquo; for a deeper understanding of its principles and applications.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Hao Xin 
    <div id="hao-xin" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#hao-xin" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question:  Are the P/E ratios of QQQ and SPY overvalued? How to deal with market fluctuations? Concerned that a prolonged stagnant market will cause borrowing interest to exceed cash reserves.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s reply: P/E ratios are unreliable and unpredictable. Recommended passive rebalancing.  Cash reserves will increase as the market rises; reinvest during downturns. Suggested simulating the 2000-2009 market scenario to test the robustness of the asset allocation strategy. If the market does stagnate for a long time, adjust lifestyle, reduce expenses, or consider other income sources. In the long run, the market will always go up; maintain confidence.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Sharing: Received a suspected scam call where the caller claimed to be from the bank and requested personal information verification.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s comments:  Commended Hao Xin&rsquo;s vigilance and reminded everyone to be cautious of calls requesting personal information to avoid being scammed.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">IV. Key Takeaways 
    <div id="iv-key-takeaways" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv-key-takeaways" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;The first investment earns the most; that performance can never be replicated.&rdquo;
&ndash; Monica</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Monica&rsquo;s statement highlights the importance of early investment and the difficulty of timing the market. Early investments enjoy higher returns, and over time, even with the same investment strategy, it&rsquo;s hard to replicate those early gains.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;The U.S. government&rsquo;s debt is the public&rsquo;s savings.&rdquo;
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This perspective challenges the traditional understanding of national debt, emphasizing the unique nature of U.S. Treasury bonds.  U.S. national debt represents dollar-denominated assets held by U.S. citizens and global investors, reflecting confidence in the American economy.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;Survival is key, not maximizing returns.&rdquo;
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This statement pinpoints the core goal of investing, reminding investors not to be tempted by high returns at the expense of risk management. Preserving capital is more important than chasing high returns during market fluctuations.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;Time is an investor&rsquo;s friend.&rdquo;
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Only long-term investments can fully benefit from the power of compounding. Time is an investor&rsquo;s best ally.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">V. Summary 
    <div id="v-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#v-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>In this episode, James once again emphasized the importance of long-term investing and risk management, offering personalized advice tailored to each student&rsquo;s circumstances. His clear explanations helped students better understand market trends, investment strategies, and the essence of wealth management. He also shared his understanding of Modern Monetary Theory (MMT) and awareness of various financial traps, reminding investors to remain rational and avoid blindly chasing high returns.</p>

  



<div
  
    class="flex px-4 py-3 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900"
  >

  <span
    
      class="text-primary-400 ltr:pr-3 rtl:pl-3 flex items-center"
    >

    

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M506.3 417l-213.3-364c-16.33-28-57.54-28-73.98 0l-213.2 364C-10.59 444.9 9.849 480 42.74 480h426.6C502.1 480 522.6 445 506.3 417zM232 168c0-13.25 10.75-24 24-24S280 154.8 280 168v128c0 13.25-10.75 24-23.1 24S232 309.3 232 296V168zM256 416c-17.36 0-31.44-14.08-31.44-31.44c0-17.36 14.07-31.44 31.44-31.44s31.44 14.08 31.44 31.44C287.4 401.9 273.4 416 256 416z"/></svg>

  </span>


  </span>

  <span
    
      class="dark:text-neutral-300"
    ><strong>Disclaimer:</strong> This article is for personal learning notes only and does not constitute any investment advice.</span>
</div>

]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>00489 US Dollar Hegemony and the Sorrow of Trade Surplus Countries; Investing in QQQ Outperforms SPY</title>
      <link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1730069768515/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1730069768515/</guid>
      <description>In this session, James begins by analyzing the current investment market, pointing out that it&amp;#39;s poised to hit new highs. He advises listeners to solidify their investment confidence and enter the market sooner rather than later. James then delves into a research paper discussing asset portfolios comprising leveraged funds, cash, QQQ, and SPY. He analyzes the risks and returns associated with various investment portfolios, emphasizing the critical role of cash allocation. He addresses questions from participants regarding asset allocation, stock pledges, retirement planning, investment strategies, and the US dollar&amp;#39;s global dominance. He also shares his personal views on marriage and having children. </description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<lite-youtube videoid="eOh-hu1X0jo" playlabel="eOh-hu1X0jo" params=""></lite-youtube>



<h2 class="relative group">I. Topic of the Day 
    <div id="i-topic-of-the-day" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-topic-of-the-day" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>The session focuses on the impending new highs anticipated in the investment market. James encourages everyone to bolster their investment confidence and enter the market early. He elaborates on various asset allocation strategies, particularly the use of leveraged funds and the significance of cash reserves. Additionally, James dives into the nature of US dollar hegemony and its implications for the global economy. He also shares his thoughts on marriage and childbearing.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">II. Briefing Content 
    <div id="ii-briefing-content" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii-briefing-content" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<ol>
<li>
<p><strong>The Market is About to Hit New Highs:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>The market is on the verge of reaching new highs. Entering early is more advantageous than waiting for the new highs to materialize.</li>
<li>Earnings reports from AI and high-tech sectors are projected to surpass expectations. Market funds and corporate profits are also expected to exceed projections.</li>
<li>The market consistently trends upward. Investment requires patience; wealth is worth the wait.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Interpreting the Asset Portfolio Research Paper:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Long-term bonds carry higher risks than stocks while yielding lower returns. Investment in them is not recommended.</strong></li>
<li><strong>QQQ offers superior returns and risk resistance compared to SPY.</strong></li>
<li><strong>Leveraged funds (e.g., QQQ2D) are characterized by high volatility, substantial downside risk, but also significant upside potential.</strong></li>
<li><strong>Intelligent asset allocation can achieve returns equivalent to a 100% QQQ portfolio while providing greater cash security.</strong></li>
<li><strong>Retirees or individuals without income are advised against using leveraged funds. An 80/20 asset allocation strategy is recommended.</strong></li>
<li><strong>Cash is the cornerstone ensuring investors can continue investing.</strong></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Additional Investment Advice and Experience Sharing:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Retirees should claim their social security benefits as early as possible and utilize them for investments.</li>
<li>Real estate is a liability; selling property for investment purposes is recommended. Avoiding mortgage loans against real estate is advised.</li>
<li>Young individuals can leverage credit loans for investments, accelerating wealth accumulation.</li>
<li>Exercise prudence in investments. Avoid excessive diversification or venturing into unfamiliar domains such as real estate or REITs.</li>
<li><strong>Investing in individual stocks is not advised. Opt for market capitalization-based index funds like QQQ.</strong></li>
<li>Experiencing substantial losses is a prerequisite to appreciating the allure of high returns. The market always presents risks, and one must learn to navigate them.</li>
<li>Short-term safe assets (e.g., treasury bills) are essential components of an investment portfolio, aiding investors in weathering market fluctuations.</li>
<li><strong>The higher the proportion of cash or cash-equivalent assets, the greater the risk tolerance of the investment portfolio.</strong></li>
<li><strong>Refrain from self-managing stock portfolios. The returns from most stocks fall short of those from treasury bills.</strong></li>
<li><strong>Stock index funds constantly face future risks. Embrace risk tolerance; only by weathering the storms can one see the sunshine.</strong></li>
<li><strong>Don&rsquo;t put faith in market predictions. During market downturns, &ldquo;stock gurus&rdquo; often emerge, but their predictions are frequently inaccurate.</strong></li>
<li><strong>Adhere to long-term investment principles. Avoid being swayed by short-term market fluctuations.</strong></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Marriage and Childbearing:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Marriage serves the purpose of creating life to carry on the universe&rsquo;s legacy. Loving one&rsquo;s partner as one would love their own child is paramount to a successful marriage.</li>
<li>Childbearing lies at the heart of life&rsquo;s meaning. Young individuals should marry and have children early, unburdened by financial pressures.</li>
<li>Even without marriage, childbearing should be considered. A life spent single and childless will ultimately lead to profound loneliness.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ol>


<h2 class="relative group">III. Q&amp;A Session 
    <div id="iii-qa-session" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii-qa-session" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p><strong>Mike:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing:</strong>
<ul>
<li>Mentions the Chinese government&rsquo;s strong push for policies akin to MMT (Modern Monetary Theory).</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question 1:</strong> Taiwan Semiconductor Manufacturing Company (TSMC) is not included in the Nasdaq 100 index, and the NYSE has extended its trading hours to 22 hours, while Nasdaq hasn&rsquo;t followed suit. Why?
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response:</strong> Nasdaq&rsquo;s trading hours are already standard. Extending trading hours only affects after-hours trading, holding little significance for ordinary investors. TSMC&rsquo;s exclusion from the Nasdaq 100 index is linked to factors such as trading costs.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question 2:</strong> How can MMT be explained to someone without financial expertise?
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response:</strong> James uses simple language to elucidate the relationship between government deficits and currency issuance. He asserts that governments can cover deficits by printing money without facing national bankruptcy. Using early American history and ancient barter systems as examples, he illustrates how governments utilize currency issuance to purchase goods and services, and how taxation maintains currency value. James emphasizes the essence of US dollar hegemony, highlighting that the US leverages its control over vital resource trading, like oil, to sustain the dollar&rsquo;s global dominance, citing Russia&rsquo;s forced use of dollars for oil purchases as an example. He also points out that the core nature of fiat currency is a representation of national sovereignty, enabling governments to mandate its use through legal means.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>IAM:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing:</strong>
<ul>
<li>Questions whether investing in QQQ also implies supporting &ldquo;rogue&rdquo; entities.</li>
<li>After comparing returns from QQQ and its top ten constituent stocks, IAM observed higher returns from the latter, leading to confusion about the role of the remaining 90 companies.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question 1:</strong> Does investing in QQQ equate to supporting &ldquo;rogue&rdquo; entities?
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response:</strong> We, as investors, are contributors. Through our investment in QQQ, we allocate capital to the 100 companies making the most significant contributions to humanity, propelling societal progress.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question 2:</strong> The top ten constituent stocks of QQQ generate higher returns; what is the purpose of the other 90 companies?
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response:</strong> The composition of QQQ&rsquo;s top ten holdings changes annually. Examining solely the past decade&rsquo;s data is insufficient. Companies previously ranked lower have the potential to enter the top ten, underscoring the vital role played by the remaining 90 companies.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question 3:</strong> Are companies ranked lower in QQQ&rsquo;s constituents at risk of being removed due to a decrease in their market capitalization percentage?
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response:</strong> Typically not, but QQQ mandates that the percentage of any individual constituent stock cannot exceed a specific threshold. Adjustments are made if this limit is surpassed.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question 4:</strong> How can one view the complete list of QQQ&rsquo;s constituent companies?
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response:</strong> This information can be accessed on websites like Yahoo Finance, which displays QQQ&rsquo;s holdings, or on QQQ&rsquo;s official website.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Chunxia:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing:</strong>
<ul>
<li>Shares a friend&rsquo;s investment story. This friend works at Apple and previously held steadfast belief in real estate and cash investments. However, recent issues like property taxes have awakened them to the importance of QQQ. Concerns about Apple stock&rsquo;s risk have led them to hesitate about stock pledges.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question:</strong> This friend holds a large quantity of Apple stock. How can they convert it into QQQ, and how should they approach a stock pledge?
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response:</strong>
<ul>
<li>The maximum long-term capital gains tax is 20%, regardless of income. James recommends that this friend sell a portion of their Apple stock sooner rather than later, converting it into QQQ to mitigate individual stock risk and reduce future tax burdens.</li>
<li>A gradual sale of Apple stock is advised, such as selling 10% or 20% each year or only selling the appreciated portion to minimize tax liability.</li>
<li>A stock pledge can be utilized for tax payments, for instance, borrowing 20% for tax obligations while reinvesting the remaining funds to enhance investment efficiency.</li>
<li>James suggests experimenting with a stock pledge, such as borrowing 2% for personal use, to gain firsthand experience with the convenience of borrowing.</li>
<li>He emphasizes the critical role of cash. A higher proportion of cash or cash-equivalent assets translates to greater risk tolerance for the investment portfolio.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Jenny:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing:</strong>
<ul>
<li>Owns multiple properties but has refrained from selling due to tax deductions and rising rental income.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question 1:</strong> Should she sell her properties?
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response:</strong> Real estate investments lack the return and liquidity offered by QQQ and potentially face substantial inheritance taxes in the future. Selling the properties is advised. Property taxes, maintenance costs, insurance fees, and more erode the returns from real estate investments. Moreover, real estate is illiquid, requiring time for liquidation. Properties, as inheritance, subject heirs to hefty inheritance taxes, potentially creating an insurmountable financial burden.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question 2:</strong> How can she convert to a Roth IRA?
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response:</strong> A Backdoor Roth IRA conversion is an option, involving initially depositing funds into a Traditional IRA and subsequently converting them to a Roth IRA.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question 3:</strong> Can property tax deductions and rising rental income offset the costs associated with real estate investment?
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response:</strong> The deductible amount for property taxes is limited. Moreover, income from rent increases is subject to income tax and cannot fully offset the costs tied to real estate investment.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question 4:</strong> Concerns about mortgages and trusts.
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response:</strong> If a mortgage is obtained under an individual&rsquo;s name, even placing the property within a trust cannot circumvent inheritance taxes. Using an LLC (Limited Liability Company) for property purchase from the outset is recommended, or transferring the property into an irrevocable trust before death to avoid inheritance tax liabilities.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Professor Zhou:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing:</strong>
<ul>
<li>Shares personal and sibling investment experiences. His sister, after experiencing investment losses, is hesitant to redeem her insurance policy. Jenny, due to returns from real estate investment, is reluctant to sell her properties. This illustrates how investors often fall prey to sunk cost and opportunity cost fallacies.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question:</strong> How can we enlighten ourselves and those around us to avoid such investment pitfalls?
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response:</strong> Understanding the concepts of sunk cost and opportunity cost is essential. Losses from investments should be cut promptly, avoiding attachment to past investments. Seek superior investment opportunities. While Jenny&rsquo;s real estate investment generates cash flow, its return is low, and it may face high inheritance taxes in the future. Therefore, she should consider selling the property and investing in higher-yielding assets like QQQ.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Bart:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Question:</strong> Issues connecting to the room.
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response:</strong> Recommends force-quitting the app and re-entering the room before raising a hand.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Daisy253:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing:</strong>
<ul>
<li>New to financial management, past investments were haphazard, primarily focused on real estate and insurance.</li>
<li>45 years old, with an 18-year-old daughter and a 14-year-old son, can invest NT$80,000 monthly. NT$10,000 is allocated to children&rsquo;s savings, with the remaining NT$70,000 for personal investment, aiming for rapid asset accumulation to reach NT$10 million.</li>
<li>Owns a rental property generating NT$30,000-40,000 in net monthly income, with principal invested ranging from NT$2 to 3 million, and the property valued at NT$3 to 4 million.</li>
<li>Children lean towards a &ldquo;non-marriage&rdquo; ideology, expressing no desire for offspring.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question:</strong> How should assets be allocated, and how can children be guided towards sound financial management principles?
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response:</strong>
<ul>
<li>Suggests referencing the article James provided, titled &ldquo;Individuals Still Some Time Away from Retirement,&rdquo; and adopting a BETA 1.2 asset allocation strategy.</li>
<li>Advises against giving children excessive funds at present. Instead, encourage them to save independently once they have a stable income, guiding them to establish proper financial management habits.</li>
<li>Proposes incentivizing children to marry and have children by offering NT$1 million annually in the future.</li>
<li>Emphasizes that 00864B cannot be replaced by 0056. Cash is cash and should not be substituted with stocks.</li>
<li>Underscores the significance of marriage and childbearing, advising early marriage and parenthood, urging them not to be bound by financial anxieties.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Xie Weiya:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing:</strong>
<ul>
<li>Recounts the story of a friend working at Apple. This friend steadfastly believed in real estate and cash as investments but recently recognized the importance of QQQ due to concerns like property taxes. However, they remain apprehensive about the risks associated with Apple stock and hesitate to engage in stock pledges.</li>
<li>This friend maintains a high spending level but undoubtedly possesses the financial capacity for retirement. They simply derive great enjoyment from work.</li>
<li>The friend has already contacted Lisa and is preparing for a stock pledge.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question:</strong>  This friend holds a substantial amount of Apple stock. How can they convert it into QQQ, and how should they approach a stock pledge?
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response:</strong>
<ul>
<li>The maximum long-term capital gains tax is 20%, independent of income. James recommends selling a portion of their Apple stock as soon as possible, converting it to QQQ to mitigate individual stock risk and reduce future tax burdens.</li>
<li>A gradual sale of Apple stock is advised, such as 10% or 20% each year, or selling only the appreciated portion to minimize tax liability.</li>
<li>Utilizing a stock pledge for tax payments is suggested, such as borrowing 20% for tax obligations while reinvesting the remaining funds to enhance investment efficiency.</li>
<li>James encourages them to experiment with a stock pledge, perhaps borrowing 2% for personal use, to experience the convenience of borrowing firsthand.</li>
<li>He highlights the vital role of cash. A higher proportion of cash or cash-equivalent assets translates to greater risk tolerance for the investment portfolio.</li>
<li>James advises this friend to learn from investment approaches employed by individuals like Warren Buffett and Wei Ying-ch’ung, leveraging credit for investment purposes.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Sunny:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Question:</strong> How should labor pension funds be withdrawn?
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response:</strong> If proficient in investment, withdrawing the entire labor pension fund at once and investing it in high-yielding assets like QQQ is recommended.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Wu Liyun:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Question:</strong> Is NT$5 million in stocks and cash sufficient for retirement?
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response:</strong>  NT$5 million in assets is insufficient to support a comfortable retirement. Withdrawing a labor pension monthly to supplement retirement income is recommended.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Nana:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Question:</strong> Concerns regarding genetic screening.
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response:</strong> Genetic screening is recommended to identify any potential genetic defects.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>College Student:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Question:</strong> Concerns about Backdoor Roth IRA.
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response:</strong> College students, lacking income, do not require a Backdoor Roth IRA. Directly depositing funds into a Roth IRA is suitable.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Jessie:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing:</strong> Has 1099 income.</li>
<li><strong>Question:</strong> Can 1099 income be deposited into a Traditional IRA?
<ul>
<li><strong>James&rsquo;s Response:</strong>  Yes, 1099 income is eligible for deposit into a Traditional IRA. Additionally, a Backdoor Roth IRA can be executed using a spouse&rsquo;s W2 income.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">IV. Key Takeaways 
    <div id="iv-key-takeaways" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv-key-takeaways" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p><strong>Young individuals should be bold in using borrowed funds for investment to accelerate wealth accumulation.</strong>
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Young people are in their prime earning years, with steadily increasing income. They can utilize tools like credit loans to access low-cost capital for investing in high-return assets like QQQ, thereby speeding up their wealth-building journey.</p>
<blockquote>
<p><strong>Cash is the cornerstone ensuring investors can continue investing.</strong>
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Market volatility is a constant. Maintaining sufficient cash or cash-equivalent assets helps investors navigate market fluctuations with ease, preventing panic-driven asset sales, ultimately achieving long-term investment objectives.</p>
<blockquote>
<p><strong>Exercise prudence in investments. Avoid excessive diversification or venturing into unfamiliar domains.</strong>
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Focus investments within familiar areas. Refrain from blindly pursuing diversification or investing in unfamiliar domains, such as real estate or REITs.</p>
<blockquote>
<p><strong>The essence of US dollar hegemony lies in the US leveraging its control over vital resource trading, like oil, to sustain the dollar&rsquo;s global dominance.</strong>
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>By mandating US dollar settlements for global oil transactions, the US compels other nations to hold dollar reserves, solidifying its global currency dominance.</p>
<blockquote>
<p><strong>Marriage serves the purpose of creating life to carry on the universe&rsquo;s legacy. Loving one&rsquo;s partner as one would love their own child is paramount to a successful marriage.</strong>
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>The significance of marriage lies in procreation and the continuation of life. Loving one&rsquo;s partner deeply, treating them as one would treat their own child, is crucial for a lasting and fulfilling marriage.</p>
<blockquote>
<p><strong>Childbearing lies at the heart of life&rsquo;s meaning. Young individuals should marry and have children early, unburdened by financial pressures.</strong>
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Childbearing is inherent to human nature and the perpetuation of life. Young people should courageously embrace the responsibility of parenthood, refusing to be deterred by financial concerns.</p>
<blockquote>
<p><strong>Investors often fall prey to sunk cost and opportunity cost fallacies.</strong>
&ndash; Professor Zhou</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Sunk costs refer to incurred expenses that are irretrievable, such as purchased stocks or real estate. Opportunity cost represents the potential gains foregone by choosing one investment over other available options. During decision-making, investors should not be swayed by sunk costs; instead, they should prioritize opportunity cost, selecting investments offering higher returns.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">V. Conclusion 
    <div id="v-conclusion" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#v-conclusion" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This session revolves around the anticipated new highs in the investment market. James encourages listeners to solidify their investment confidence and enter the market promptly. He meticulously explains various asset allocation strategies, emphasizing the use of leveraged funds and the paramount importance of cash reserves. He also delves into the nature of US dollar hegemony and its global economic implications, sharing his personal views on marriage and childbearing. The Q&amp;A segment addresses questions encompassing asset allocation, stock pledges, retirement planning, investment strategies, and more, making it a content-rich and insightful session.</p>

  



<div
  
    class="flex px-4 py-3 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900"
  >

  <span
    
      class="text-primary-400 ltr:pr-3 rtl:pl-3 flex items-center"
    >

    

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M506.3 417l-213.3-364c-16.33-28-57.54-28-73.98 0l-213.2 364C-10.59 444.9 9.849 480 42.74 480h426.6C502.1 480 522.6 445 506.3 417zM232 168c0-13.25 10.75-24 24-24S280 154.8 280 168v128c0 13.25-10.75 24-23.1 24S232 309.3 232 296V168zM256 416c-17.36 0-31.44-14.08-31.44-31.44c0-17.36 14.07-31.44 31.44-31.44s31.44 14.08 31.44 31.44C287.4 401.9 273.4 416 256 416z"/></svg>

  </span>


  </span>

  <span
    
      class="dark:text-neutral-300"
    ><strong>Disclaimer:</strong> This article is for personal learning purposes only and does not constitute any investment advice.</span>
</div>

]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>00488 AI Demand and Market Future: Insights from TSMC and Investment Trends; Ever-Growing Assets and Smart Spending without Repaying Principal</title>
      <link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1729384159255/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1729384159255/</guid>
      <description>This session focuses on strategies for long-term investment in Nasdaq 100 index funds amidst market volatility and changing international landscapes.  It also covers leveraging investments, smart spending habits, and navigating the job market in the age of AI.  Additionally, the discussion touches upon comparing different types of economic crises, estate planning, the synergy between real estate and stock investments, the feasibility of long-term investing in Taiwanese and US stock markets, and government policies regarding economic stimulus and social welfare.  Specific advice for Chinese investors accessing US markets and related tax implications are also addressed.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<lite-youtube videoid="y6smxG48k4M" playlabel="y6smxG48k4M" params=""></lite-youtube>



<h2 class="relative group">I. Main Topic 
    <div id="i-main-topic" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-main-topic" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>Trust in the power of technology and maintain a long-term investment strategy focused on Nasdaq 100 index funds, learning how to utilize stock pledging and spend wisely, especially during market fluctuations and shifts in the international situation.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">II. Presentation Content 
    <div id="ii-presentation-content" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii-presentation-content" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<ol>
<li><strong>Market Trends and Investment Philosophy:</strong>
<ul>
<li><strong>AI Drives the Future:</strong> AI demand is not a bubble, but a genuine driving force behind technological advancement, promising a bull market spanning two decades.  We are currently in the early stages of this growth.  Morris Chang (TSMC Chairman)&rsquo;s perspective and TSMC&rsquo;s investments in AI corroborate this judgment. The long bull market has begun, seize the opportunity to join the wealth train.</li>
<li><strong>Market Volatility and Long-Term Investment:</strong> Market fluctuations are inherent to investing.  Downswings are followed by even greater upswings. Using historical data from the Taiwan Weighted Index, Nikkei Index, and the US stock market as examples, the session illustrates the long-term market development pattern: an initial period of rapid growth followed by a period of stagnation (e.g., 32 years in Taiwan, 35 years in Japan, 24 years in the US), before entering a phase of stable growth.  Therefore, overcoming panic caused by market volatility and adhering to a long-term investment strategy is crucial for ultimate success.</li>
<li><strong>Capitalism and Investment:</strong>  The side effects of capitalism are wealth disparity and the exploitation of labor. Learn to operate like a capitalist and profit from investment.  Hard work and saving money to buy government bonds will ultimately result in wealth erosion due to inflation.</li>
<li><strong>Benefits of Quantitative Easing:</strong> Quantitative easing is beneficial for investors, fostering a low-interest-rate environment and driving asset price appreciation.  Those who fail to understand quantitative easing and complain about government money printing are often victims of capitalism, missing out on the benefits of asset appreciation.</li>
<li><strong>Characteristics of a Mature Market:</strong> Mature markets are characterized by fair, just, and transparent regulatory mechanisms, companies focused on their core businesses, and a high proportion of long-term investors and institutional holdings. The Taiwanese market is gradually maturing.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Investment Strategies and Recommendations:</strong>
<ul>
<li><strong>Invest in Nasdaq 100:</strong>  The session recommends investing in Nasdaq 100 index funds (QQQ), with the option to allocate to S&amp;P 500 or high-dividend ETFs based on individual circumstances.  References to Nasdaq 100 index funds globally are provided for the convenience of investors worldwide.</li>
<li><strong>Avoid Penny Stocks:</strong>  Refrain from investing in penny stocks, as they generally offer low long-term returns.  Real investment opportunities lie in companies that demonstrate sustained growth and lead technological advancements.</li>
<li><strong>Advantages of Stock Pledging:</strong> Stock pledging offers advantages over real estate mortgages, as stocks, unlike real estate, do not depreciate and can be held long-term, potentially allowing for &ldquo;borrowing without repayment or interest&rdquo; (specific instructions are available in related videos).</li>
<li><strong>Avoid Flawed Rebalancing Strategies:</strong> Avoid a 50% principal + 50% leveraged ETF rebalancing strategy, as it carries high risk and can easily deplete cash reserves during market downturns.</li>
<li><strong>Estate Planning and Stock Pledging:</strong> When engaging in stock pledging, it is advisable to diversify assets across multiple brokerage firms, pledging a portion and keeping the rest as cash to facilitate estate handling for inheritors.  Cat supplemented this with a detailed explanation of the stock pledging inheritance process, emphasizing the importance of advance planning.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Other Important Matters:</strong>
<ul>
<li><strong>Risk Warning and Disclaimer:</strong>  The content is for informational purposes only and does not constitute investment advice.  Do not remit funds to unknown accounts.</li>
<li><strong>Program Format Adjustment:</strong>  The presentation content will be expanded to include material previously covered in short videos.</li>
<li><strong>QQQ Stock Selection Mechanism:</strong>  Addresses audience questions regarding the QQQ stock selection mechanism, explaining the advantages of the Nasdaq exchange and why technology companies prefer listing on Nasdaq.</li>
<li><strong>Stock Pledging for Non-US Residents:</strong> Explains the regulations for non-US residents engaging in stock pledging with US brokers.</li>
<li><strong>Learning to Spend:</strong> Shares the philosophy of spending after achieving investment success, emphasizing the importance of focusing on future wealth growth and utilizing financial leverage for consumption.  Don&rsquo;t let wealth sit idle; learn how to use it.  This point is illustrated with the example of a listener who has $4 million but doesn&rsquo;t know how to spend it, calculating their potential wealth growth over 40 years and a reasonable spending level.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ol>


<h2 class="relative group">III. Q&amp;A Session 
    <div id="iii-qa-session" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii-qa-session" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p><strong>IAM:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Shared:</strong>  Expressed confusion about different types of economic crises and how the 2020-2023 pandemic period compares to previous bubbles after reading a book about economic crises.</li>
<li><strong>Question 1:</strong>  Which historical economic crisis is most similar to the economic downturn during the 2020-2023 pandemic?</li>
<li><strong>Answer:</strong> The 2020-2023 pandemic was an economic shock caused by an external event, distinct from previous bubble economies. The 2000 dot-com bubble was an industry bubble with limited impact; the 2008 financial crisis resembled the 1929 Great Depression, both being asset bubble bursts, but the 2008 crisis recovered faster due to quantitative easing. The 2022 market decline was not a bubble burst, but a revaluation caused by central bank interest rate hikes.</li>
<li><strong>Question 2:</strong> What did the US do to stimulate the economy that other countries couldn&rsquo;t replicate?</li>
<li><strong>Answer:</strong> The US is less constrained by fiscal discipline and is willing to borrow and issue debt, allocating funds to social welfare programs for the elderly, children, and healthcare, while guiding domestic capital towards overseas investment to mitigate inflation.  Taiwan&rsquo;s government was advised to learn from the US&rsquo;s fiscal spending approach and guide capital towards investment, while also focusing on efficient capital utilization and building a social safety net.</li>
<li><strong>Question 3:</strong> Why are Chinese people so keen on buying houses?</li>
<li><strong>Answer:</strong> This is a vestige of the agrarian &ldquo;land is wealth&rdquo; mentality, which is no longer applicable today.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Eason (Doctor):</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Shared:</strong>  Points to consider for Chinese investors buying Nasdaq ETFs:
<ul>
<li>Different brokerage firms have different fee policies and financing rates; careful comparison is necessary.</li>
<li>Domestic Nasdaq ETFs have premiums; buying during periods of low or negative premiums is recommended.  There are no limits for buying ETFs on the exchange, but there are limits for off-exchange subscriptions.</li>
<li>Recommends allocating a portion of assets to USD-denominated investments like QQQ, which can be purchased by opening brokerage accounts in Singapore or Hong Kong.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Added:</strong>  Chinese residents have a $50,000 annual foreign exchange quota for overseas investments.  Hong Kong and mainland China identities have different withholding tax rates on US stock investments.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Dave:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Question 1:</strong> Will the Nasdaq 100 index become stagnant like the Dow Jones index?</li>
<li><strong>Answer:</strong> Currently, the Nasdaq 100 is the most competitive; excessive worry about the future is unnecessary.</li>
<li><strong>Question 2:</strong> Is it feasible to only buy the top 10 companies in the Nasdaq 100 index?</li>
<li><strong>Answer:</strong> The top ten companies change frequently; individual stock selection and portfolio adjustments are too cumbersome, and returns may not be higher.  Investing directly in index funds is more efficient.</li>
<li><strong>Question 3:</strong> How do VGT and XLK compare to QQQ?</li>
<li><strong>Answer:</strong> VGT and XLK track different indices than QQQ, with different constituent stocks and concentration. QQQ is more robust and has broader coverage.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Jiawen:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Question:</strong> Can an 80% leveraged ETF + 10% cash + 10% bond portfolio be directly pledged? How is this done?</li>
<li><strong>Answer:</strong> Yes, but a small-scale trial is recommended, for instance, borrowing $200,000 against $5 million in principal, or borrowing within $1 million against $10 million. Long-term borrowing strategies should be adjusted according to circumstances. It&rsquo;s possible to pledge only a portion of the stocks, leaving the remainder for additional purchases or other uses.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Peter:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Shared:</strong>  Personal investment journey, transitioning from real estate to stocks, learning about stock pledging and asset allocation.</li>
<li><strong>Question:</strong> Is there synergy between real estate and stock investment? How can real estate cash flow be used for stock investment?</li>
<li><strong>Answer:</strong>  Buying a house is not recommended for young people. Real estate investment returns are lower than stocks and come with various risks (e.g., natural disasters, property taxes).  Even with positive cash flow, opportunity costs should be considered; investing that capital in stocks might yield higher returns.  Used Texas real estate as an example to illustrate the drawbacks of real estate investment.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Qiu Xiao:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Question 1:</strong>  What are the Canadian equivalents of US retirement accounts like IRA, Roth IRA, and 401k? Which account should cash be held in?</li>
<li><strong>Answer:</strong> Roth IRA corresponds to Canada&rsquo;s TFSA, Traditional IRA to RRSP, and 401k to DCPP. The choice of retirement account for cash depends on the individual&rsquo;s balance between taxable and tax-free accounts and their asset allocation strategy.  One should choose to place cash in either a tax-free or taxable account based on their specific circumstances for tax optimization.</li>
<li><strong>Question 2 (Related to Eason&rsquo;s question):</strong> How can one invest in Nasdaq ETFs in China, and how can quota limitations be addressed?</li>
<li><strong>Answer:</strong> Off-exchange subscriptions have quota limits, while on-exchange ETF purchases do not, but premiums should be considered.  Opening multiple brokerage accounts or opening an account in Hong Kong for US stock investment can be considered.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Haoqing:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Shared:</strong>  Used the example of SpaceX launching rockets with a small team to highlight concerns about AI replacing human labor and the difficulties young people face in finding employment.</li>
<li><strong>Question:</strong> How can we address the challenge of youth unemployment in the AI era?</li>
<li><strong>Answer:</strong>  Young people need to acquire AI skills to adapt to the future job market.  Recommends that schools incorporate AI courses into their core curriculum, cultivating AI talent from a young age. Philosophy is an important foundational subject but should not be a primary career focus.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Jimmy:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Shared:</strong>  Discussed the changing times and the need for young people to adapt, sharing observations about the youthful demographics of Xiamen. Mentioned the importance of aligning investments with the times and shared some common misunderstandings about investing he had encountered.</li>
<li><strong>Question:</strong> What are your views on index fund investing? Is the long-term return of 0050 sufficient? What are your thoughts on individual stock investing (e.g., TSMC)?</li>
<li><strong>Answer:</strong> Index fund investing is a method accessible to the general public, but many don&rsquo;t understand it and require time and experience to appreciate it. In the long run, QQQ and SPY offer higher returns and are more suitable for long-term investment. Individual stock picking demands specialized knowledge and skills and carries higher risks; it is difficult for average investors to select and hold high-quality stocks like TSMC for the long term.  The key to investing is finding investment targets that can be held long-term and sticking with them.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Other Q&amp;A:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>TQQQ Pledging:</strong>  Learn about stock pledging and how to achieve interest-free borrowing through the recommended videos.</li>
<li><strong>Top 10 QQQ Holdings:</strong>  Frequent trading is discouraged; holding the index fund long-term is sufficient.</li>
<li><strong>BOX vs. SWVXX:</strong>  BOX is recommended for brokerage accounts to avoid dividend taxes.</li>
<li><strong>Conservative Investing:</strong>  Conservative investing can involve holding cash or holding index funds long-term.</li>
<li><strong>How to Spend Money:</strong>  Focus on future wealth growth and utilize financial leverage for consumption.</li>
<li><strong>Investing in US Stocks from within China:</strong>  Coming to the US to invest or remitting funds to the US for investment is recommended.  Consider opening an account in Hong Kong or using other compliant channels for investment.</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">IV. Key Takeaways 
    <div id="iv-key-takeaways" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv-key-takeaways" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>AI demand is not a bubble; technological advancements will drive a bull market lasting 20 years.  We are just at the beginning.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>James emphasizes his belief that AI is a long-term trend and encourages investors to recognize the current market as the starting point of a significant bull run.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>High returns are meaningless if the probability of success is low.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>James reiterates that a successful investment strategy prioritizes long-term holding and consistency over chasing high returns with low success rates.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Young people need to learn AI skills to adapt to the future job market. AI courses should be core curriculum in all departments.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>James stresses the importance of acquiring AI skills for future employment and advocates for integrating AI education into all academic disciplines.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Earning money is easy; spending it wisely is difficult.  Don&rsquo;t let your wealth sit idle; learn how to use it.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>James offers a unique perspective on wealth management, urging listeners to become skilled spenders and maximize their wealth&rsquo;s potential.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Governments should invest in the elderly and children, building a strong social safety net.
&ndash; James</p>
</blockquote>
<p>James underscores the importance of social welfare, suggesting that nations prioritize investing in the well-being of their youngest and oldest citizens.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">V. Summary 
    <div id="v-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#v-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This session centers on long-term investment in the Nasdaq 100 index fund, covering market trends, investment strategies, the use of financial leverage, and personal development in the AI era.  James not only shares professional investment concepts and techniques but also encourages listeners to shift their mindsets, embrace the opportunities presented by technological advancements, and learn how to better manage and utilize their wealth. He also emphasizes the government&rsquo;s responsibility in social welfare development, advocating for a more robust social safety net to protect the well-being of the elderly and children.  Furthermore, the session addresses the needs of Chinese investors by answering questions about accessing US markets from China and related tax implications.</p>

  



<div
  
    class="flex px-4 py-3 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900"
  >

  <span
    
      class="text-primary-400 ltr:pr-3 rtl:pl-3 flex items-center"
    >

    

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M506.3 417l-213.3-364c-16.33-28-57.54-28-73.98 0l-213.2 364C-10.59 444.9 9.849 480 42.74 480h426.6C502.1 480 522.6 445 506.3 417zM232 168c0-13.25 10.75-24 24-24S280 154.8 280 168v128c0 13.25-10.75 24-23.1 24S232 309.3 232 296V168zM256 416c-17.36 0-31.44-14.08-31.44-31.44c0-17.36 14.07-31.44 31.44-31.44s31.44 14.08 31.44 31.44C287.4 401.9 273.4 416 256 416z"/></svg>

  </span>


  </span>

  <span
    
      class="dark:text-neutral-300"
    ><strong>Disclaimer:</strong> This article is for personal learning notes only and does not constitute any investment advice.</span>
</div>

]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
