<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Scam Alert on QQQ Investor</title>
    <link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/tags/scam-alert/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Scam Alert on QQQ Investor</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jomonylw.github.io/en/tags/scam-alert/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>00542 A 2.5% retirement withdrawal rate is key; QQQ is not about tech, it&#39;s about the strongest companies! The investment focus isn&#39;t on industry classification, but on the correct logic for long-term wealth building</title>
      <link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1764465235759/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1764465235759/</guid>
      <description>In this session, Teacher James explains in detail the application scenarios of QQQI as a retirement cash flow tool and provides an in-depth analysis clarifying that QQQ is not purely a high-tech fund, but an investment in the current one hundred strongest companies. The Q&amp;amp;A session was lively, discussing asset allocation and stock pledging operations in different regions like Hong Kong, Canada, and Mainland China. Through long-term data comparison, the immense advantage of the &amp;#39;sell your house, rent, and invest in indexes&amp;#39; strategy was re-emphasized to help students overcome psychological barriers to investing.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<lite-youtube videoid="A65OoUXqteY" playlabel="A65OoUXqteY" params=""></lite-youtube>



<h2 class="relative group">I. Main Topic of the Session 
    <div id="i-main-topic-of-the-session" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-main-topic-of-the-session" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>The core of this class revolved around two key points: first, introducing the proper use of the high-dividend ETF <strong>QQQI</strong> for retirees and investors needing cash flow, emphasizing its role as a supplementary cash flow tool rather than a substitute for cash itself; second, through in-depth analysis, clarifying the common misconception about <strong>QQQ (Nasdaq 100 Index)</strong>, pointing out that its investment logic is to &ldquo;invest in the strongest companies of the moment,&rdquo; not limited to the &ldquo;high-tech&rdquo; sector. Teacher James used examples and a historical perspective to explain the dynamic adaptability of the index and reiterated the core investment philosophy of holding for the long term and ignoring market fluctuations.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">II. Briefing Content 
    <div id="ii-briefing-content" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii-briefing-content" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Reminder: Beware of Scams 
    <div id="reminder-beware-of-scams" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#reminder-beware-of-scams" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Teacher James once again reminded everyone that scam groups are continuously using his name and profile picture to impersonate him.</li>
<li>The teacher emphasized that he has over 4,000 followers, while the scammers only have a few dozen, making them easy to distinguish.</li>
<li>Initially, scammers may imitate the teacher&rsquo;s tone, even using AI tools to answer questions, but their ultimate goal is to defraud people of money or request to manage their accounts. Please be vigilant and do not engage in private chats or send money to any &ldquo;James Chan&rdquo; who actively contacts you offering investment advice.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Investment Philosophy: Simple, Firm, No Forecasting 
    <div id="investment-philosophy-simple-firm-no-forecasting" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#investment-philosophy-simple-firm-no-forecasting" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Market Irrelevance</strong>: Market volatility, international situations, economic data, and company earnings reports are all irrelevant to our investment decisions.</li>
<li><strong>Core Strategy</strong>: The only correct strategy is to &ldquo;buy whenever you have money, hold for the long term, and never sell.&rdquo;</li>
<li><strong>Investment Target</strong>: Do not invest in individual stocks; focus on broad-market index funds to avoid the risks associated with individual company earnings and operations.</li>
<li><strong>Risk Awareness</strong>: The market can drop by 50% or even 80% at any time. Investors must manage their own risk and ensure that the funds invested are for the long term and will not be needed.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">QQQI: A Cash Flow Tool for Retirees 
    <div id="qqqi-a-cash-flow-tool-for-retirees" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#qqqi-a-cash-flow-tool-for-retirees" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Target Audience</strong>: QQQI is suitable for those who are retired or need a stable cash flow, especially when your annual expenses exceed 2.5% of your total assets.</li>
<li><strong>Functional Positioning</strong>: QQQI is a tool to <strong>generate cash flow</strong>, but it <strong>cannot be equated with cash</strong>. Your emergency fund should still be kept in highly liquid assets like money market funds (e.g., 00865B).</li>
<li><strong>Allocation Scenario</strong>: If your retirement assets are less than 40 times your annual expenses (i.e., your withdrawal rate is higher than 2.5%), you can pair it with a portion of QQQI to increase overall cash flow yield to meet living expenses. Young people or investors still in the accumulation phase should continue to invest in growth-oriented index funds like QQQ, 00662, etc.</li>
<li><strong>Practical Application</strong>:
<ul>
<li>In the United States, QQQI can be held in both retirement and individual accounts.</li>
<li>In Taiwan, you can purchase QQQI through a sub-brokerage (such as Yuanta, Fubon, Cathay). Most of the dividends distributed can be reclaimed through tax refunds.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Case Study</strong>: A friend of the teacher followed his advice early on, sold his house, and went all-in on QQQ (00662). His assets grew by 1.5 times in five to six years, achieving financial freedom. He now enjoys a high-quality retired life. This stands in stark contrast to those who work their entire lives for a house, a car, and an insurance company.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Analyzing QQQ: Investing in the Strongest Companies, Not a Pure Tech Fund 
    <div id="analyzing-qqq-investing-in-the-strongest-companies-not-a-pure-tech-fund" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#analyzing-qqq-investing-in-the-strongest-companies-not-a-pure-tech-fund" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Dispelling the Misconception</strong>: Many believe that investing in QQQ is investing in &ldquo;American high-tech.&rdquo; This is not entirely accurate. Truly pure technology sector funds are like XLK or VGT, but we do not recommend investing in any sector-specific funds.</li>
<li><strong>The Essence of QQQ</strong>: QQQ invests in the <strong>100 strongest companies listed on the Nasdaq Stock Exchange</strong>. It is an index without a &ldquo;personality&rdquo;; its only criterion is &ldquo;strength.&rdquo;</li>
<li><strong>Dynamic Adaptability</strong>:
<ul>
<li>In the current era, the strongest companies happen to be mostly high-tech firms.</li>
<li>However, if we went back 40 years, the strongest companies might have been those making radios, televisions, or trains, and they would have been included in the index. The definition of &ldquo;high-tech&rdquo; changes with the times.</li>
<li>The index also includes companies like Costco and Starbucks, which are not high-tech but are extremely powerful.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Core Viewpoint</strong>: We invest in QQQ because we believe that human progress is driven by these strongest companies. We are investing in a <strong>mechanism that dynamically selects the strongest players</strong>, not betting on a specific industry. Obsessing over whether it is a &ldquo;high-tech fund&rdquo; is pointless; what matters is its excellent long-term performance.</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">III. Q&amp;A Session 
    <div id="iii-qa-session" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii-qa-session" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Momo 
    <div id="momo" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#momo" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Discussed the process of stock pledging at HSBC in Hong Kong. She found HSBC&rsquo;s loan-to-value ratios to be relatively conservative (70% for underlying stocks, 90% for cash, leveraged ETFs cannot be pledged), which is lower than in the US or Taiwan.</li>
<li>Question 1: She designed a low-risk allocation of 50% Nasdaq and 50% cash (Beta=0.5), with annual expenses accounting for about 3% of total assets. She wanted to confirm if this approach is safe and whether using the cash portion would create risk. Additionally, she heard that HSBC uses the entire account as collateral, rather than differentiating by asset type, and wanted to verify this.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: The pledging rules at HSBC Hong Kong are identical to those in the US. It&rsquo;s normal for leveraged funds to have no pledge value. She has two options: 1. If taxes are not a concern, she can build a 4-3-3 portfolio within HSBC, buying Hong Kong-listed leveraged ETFs and rebalancing. 2. To avoid domestic capital gains tax, she could, like other students, buy and sell leveraged ETFs through an overseas broker like IBKR, but she must be mindful of potential future US estate tax issues. The teacher emphasized that when you need money, you should &ldquo;borrow&rdquo; from your credit line, not &ldquo;sell assets.&rdquo; A single withdrawal should preferably not exceed 10% of total assets, and always ensure your cash position is greater than your total liabilities; this is very safe.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2: She is helping her mother with financial management and, to give her mother a sense of involvement, is debating whether to open a Joint Account or manage it herself and provide regular updates.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: There are several options, depending on her mother&rsquo;s preference. They could open a joint account; she could open an account in her mother&rsquo;s name, and her mother could sign a Power of Attorney for her to operate it; or she could open it in her name and just share the login details so her mother can view it anytime. The simplest way is to show her the monthly statement and discuss the account&rsquo;s status together.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Zhihua Wang 
    <div id="zhihua-wang" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#zhihua-wang" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question: Is the dividend yield of QQYI fixed? He observed it changed from 12% last week to 13.64% this week.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: The dividend yield is related to market volatility, so the amount paid out each month will vary slightly, but the annual total is generally stable between 10%-13%. It is not fixed. The teacher also demonstrated live how to use ChatGPT to calculate asset allocation ratios: by inputting the expected returns of different portfolios (e.g., 2.5% for a 4-3-3 portfolio, 11% for QQQI), the AI can help you calculate the capital proportions needed to achieve a target return rate (e.g., 4% or 6%).</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Jet 
    <div id="jet" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#jet" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question: Does the teacher have any recommended retirement locations in the US? The requirements are safety, good climate, and few natural disasters.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: (Jokingly) You&rsquo;re welcome to be my neighbor in Cupertino, California. It&rsquo;s next to Apple&rsquo;s headquarters, very safe, our area has no wildfire issues, and there are many excellent hospitals.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Tianluzhixia 
    <div id="tianluzhixia" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#tianluzhixia" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question: He is currently in South Korea and learned that the stock pledging interest rate is around 4.5%, which feels higher than in the US and Taiwan. Is it still worth doing?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: 4.5% is very cheap! The rates in the US are now up to 6%, so 4.5% is a very good rate and completely worth doing. South Korea has a well-developed financial system, and being able to buy 2x leveraged ETFs is also great.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Wendy 
    <div id="wendy" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#wendy" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question: She is a citizen of mainland China but has accounts and funds in mainland China, Hong Kong (Standard Chartered Bank), and IBKR (opened previously in Canada). She feels her asset allocation is chaotic and doesn&rsquo;t know how to distribute it.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: First, as a Chinese tax resident, it is not advisable to keep large assets in IBKR due to the risk of US estate tax; the funds should be consolidated into a Hong Kong account as soon as possible. Second, it&rsquo;s important to distinguish between &ldquo;margin financing&rdquo; at mainland brokers (borrowing money to buy stocks, cash cannot be withdrawn) and &ldquo;stock pledging&rdquo; at Hong Kong banks (collateralizing stocks to borrow cash for spending). He advised her to keep about 1 year of living expenses in China, 2-3 years of cash in Hong Kong, and invest the majority of the remaining funds in the Nasdaq 100 index. She could allocate a small portion (e.g., 10%) to a 2x leveraged ETF since she is still young and not yet retired.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Liang 
    <div id="liang" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#liang" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question 1: An internal staff member from a free tax filing software platform she uses in Canada contacted her, pointing out that her mutual fund fees were high and promoting investment advice to her. She felt this was a violation of her privacy.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: This is most likely because she agreed to the user agreement upon registration, which included a clause allowing the platform to use her data for internal marketing. This kind of investment advice is a &ldquo;scam&rdquo;; just ignore it. He re-emphasized the first rule of investing: stay away from any advice from financial advisors and banks.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2: She shared a news story from Canada where a couple passed away in the same year, leaving their children with a massive tax bill on their RRSP (Registered Retirement Savings Plan) and vacation home. This made her feel that estate planning in Canada is very difficult.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: The teacher expressed sympathy for Canada&rsquo;s high-tax environment and noted this is one reason he does not recommend immigrating there. This sparked a lively discussion about Canadian taxes (such as the deemed disposition at death, capital gains tax, gift tax, etc.), highlighting the complex realities of wealth planning in different countries.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Vicky 
    <div id="vicky" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#vicky" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question: She made an operational error during a trade. She intended to buy 12 shares of 00865B but ended up buying 12 lots (12,000 shares), forcing her to use her stock pledge loan to cover the funds, which raised her debt ratio to 14%. She asked if she should hold these extra bonds and pay back the money later.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: Absolutely not! In investing, once you make an operational mistake, you must correct it immediately and get back on your original planned track. You cannot let a mistake stand. This was an unplanned, passive borrowing act, which is wrong. She should sell the extra bonds as soon as possible and pay off the pledged loan.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Meihao Weilai 
    <div id="meihao-weilai" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#meihao-weilai" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question: She observed that during recent market volatility, her leveraged ETF portion deviated from its target allocation. She had an impulse to rebalance but resisted because it wasn&rsquo;t her scheduled annual rebalancing time (December/January). Now that the market has rebounded, she is wondering if she made a mistake. She wants to confirm if she should strictly adhere to the once-a-year discipline.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: Yes, you must adhere strictly. You absolutely cannot act based on short-term market fluctuations, or you will become a short-term trader. The discipline is to operate only once a year, pick a time (like December or January), get it done, and then you are finished until the next year. The practice of investing is to reach a state where you don&rsquo;t look at your account and are unaffected by market sentiment.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Jenny 
    <div id="jenny" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#jenny" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question 1: She plans to open an account at HSBC Hong Kong for pledging, using a 4-3-3 allocation. She wanted to confirm if she still needs to follow the principle that the &ldquo;total pledged loan amount should be less than the cash portion (30%)&rdquo;?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: Yes, for absolute safety, you should follow this principle.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2: She currently has an IBKR account in Canada. After opening an HSBC account, should she keep both accounts and operate them in parallel?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: Not recommended. She should consolidate all assets into the HSBC Hong Kong account. Keeping the IBKR account will always expose her to the risk of US estate tax. This &ldquo;leg&rdquo; is a &ldquo;lame leg&rdquo; that will need to be &ldquo;amputated&rdquo; sooner or later, so it&rsquo;s better to deal with it now. He suggested selling the assets directly in IBKR and transferring the cash, rather than attempting a complicated asset transfer.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Doris 
    <div id="doris" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#doris" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: No particular questions, just came on to wish the teacher and classmates a Happy Thanksgiving.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: Thank you, glad you came on.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Liuxiaojuan 
    <div id="liuxiaojuan" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#liuxiaojuan" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Accidentally pressed the button to come on stage and said hello to the teacher.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: Hello.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Rosemary 
    <div id="rosemary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#rosemary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Also pressed by accident, wished the teacher a Happy Thanksgiving.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: Okay, thank you.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Qing 
    <div id="qing" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#qing" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: He observed some investment bloggers on YouTube and found that they privately admit their most profitable business is actually &ldquo;teaching&rdquo; and &ldquo;memberships,&rdquo; not their own investment operations. He used this to comment on Teacher James&rsquo;s &ldquo;Buddha-like heart&rdquo; for teaching for free.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: Thanks for sharing.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Evelyn 
    <div id="evelyn" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#evelyn" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question: She has made up her mind to sell her primary residence to invest but is facing a huge psychological barrier. She calculated that the future rent would be about the same as her current mortgage payment, but her living space would shrink to one-third of its original size. This makes her feel like &ldquo;life is going backward,&rdquo; as if she is &ldquo;sacrificing today&rsquo;s quality of life for an imaginary tomorrow.&rdquo;
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: This is a matter of changing your perspective. By selling the house, you gain a large sum of cash to invest, which means your assets start working for you. A smaller living space means a simpler life, less cleaning, and you can spend your time and money on improving experiences. More importantly, this is a short-term &ldquo;sacrifice.&rdquo; Five or ten years from now, when your invested assets have doubled or grown, you can use the returns to rent a much larger and more luxurious place than the one you sold. This isn&rsquo;t &ldquo;enduring hardship&rdquo;; it&rsquo;s &ldquo;taking nourishment&rdquo; for the sake of exponential future freedom.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Suwei 
    <div id="suwei" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#suwei" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question: He saw an AI video on YouTube imitating Charlie Munger, claiming that QQQ and SPY are overvalued because too many people are buying them, and their prices have detached from the actual value of their constituent stocks, with future returns unlikely to exceed 10%. He is confused by this.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: This is typical nonsense. First, the source of the video is questionable; it&rsquo;s likely AI-generated. Second, the &ldquo;price is too high&rdquo; argument has been made every year for the past decade, yet the market keeps hitting new highs. In the long run, QQQ&rsquo;s annualized return will reach 15% or even higher. Investors need to have critical thinking skills. If you can&rsquo;t distinguish the authenticity of information, the safest approach is not to listen or watch, but to simply execute your established investment strategy.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Cherry 
    <div id="cherry" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#cherry" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: She is currently traveling in Barcelona, Spain, and shared her observations of the relaxed, enjoy-the-moment attitude she saw in Europe. She believes that Chinese culture often makes people too tense, only knowing how to work hard without relaxing. She encouraged everyone that money is a tool for improving quality of life and experiencing the world, not just for accumulating numbers. The brand new, high-quality hotel she stayed in locally cost only about $100 USD per night, proving that without being tied down by property, one can live very well all over the world.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: A very good sharing.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Unnamed Student (Singapore) 
    <div id="unnamed-student-singapore" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#unnamed-student-singapore" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question 1: She works in China and lives in Singapore and wanted to confirm her investment strategy. Should she adopt a leveraged strategy of 60% QQQ + 20% pledge + 20% cash, or since she still has an income, should she go all-in on QQQ and invest a fixed amount monthly?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: For an investor who is new to this concept and unfamiliar with stock pledging, it is recommended to use a simpler method: keep one to two years of living expenses as cash, and with the rest of the money, &ldquo;buy whenever you have money&rdquo; in QQQ. Do not engage in pledging.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2: Her child is 6 years old, and in Singapore&rsquo;s highly competitive environment, she feels very anxious. On one hand, she wants her child to become elite, but on the other, she feels that in the age of AI, children should be allowed to grow up happily.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: A 6-year-old child doesn&rsquo;t need to learn anything; their only job is to play. Don&rsquo;t worry about &ldquo;losing at the starting line&rdquo;; in both investing and life, you need to &ldquo;win at the finish line.&rdquo; Forcing a child to learn will not lead to success. You should take your child to experience the world (travel, museums, libraries) and let him discover his own interests. With hundreds of millions in assets, are you worried your child won&rsquo;t have food to eat? Letting him develop naturally is the best way.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Unnamed Student (House) 
    <div id="unnamed-student-house" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#unnamed-student-house" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question: He once again raised concerns about selling his house. He calculated his situation and believes that after selling the house, the principal invested in QQQ would need five to six years of &ldquo;hardship&rdquo; to double, by which time he might not even be able to buy back his current house.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: This is classic short-sightedness. The teacher did a 30-year calculation for him on the spot: assume he sells his house now and gets back 180,000 in principal, with the house valued at 300,000. In 30 years, at a 6% annualized growth rate, the house will be worth 1.7 million. But the 180,000 principal invested in QQQ, at a 15% annualized return, will become 12 million in 30 years. 1.7 million versus 12 million, which one do you choose? The so-called &ldquo;hardship&rdquo; is your own imagination. Renting can offer more freedom; you can rent a luxury apartment with a swimming pool and gym, and your quality of life might even be higher.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Unnamed Student (Property) 
    <div id="unnamed-student-property" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#unnamed-student-property" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: She discovered that flipping &ldquo;pre-construction properties&rdquo; in Singapore offers very high returns. With a 25% down payment, the profit from the property&rsquo;s appreciation in three to four years can exceed the principal, making the short-term return rate seem higher than QQQ&rsquo;s.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: If you don&rsquo;t believe it, you can go and try. But buying and selling property has transaction costs (6%) and taxes. Many people have already suffered this loss; buying a house will keep you poor for a lifetime. If you want to verify it for yourself, then go ahead.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Meng 
    <div id="meng" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#meng" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question (from the comment section): My assets are less than 10 million, my monthly income is 120,000, and my expenses are 100,000, leaving me with a monthly cash flow of 20,000. Can I, as soon as I receive my 120,000 income each month, immediately buy 100,000 of 00865B and 20,000 of 00662, and then immediately pledge them to borrow 100,000?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s Reply: No! Absolutely do not do this. You can&rsquo;t possibly invest 100,000 and expect to borrow 100,000 back; the risk is extremely high. Moreover, your allocation is 80% bonds, which has a very low Beta and poor returns. It&rsquo;s not worth borrowing money for at all.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">IV. Key Quotes 
    <div id="iv-key-quotes" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv-key-quotes" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>Selling your house isn&rsquo;t enduring hardship, it&rsquo;s taking nourishment! You&rsquo;ll understand in the future.
&ndash; James Chan
Context: In response to student Evelyn&rsquo;s psychological struggle about her living space shrinking and feeling a decline in quality of life after selling her house, Teacher James used this vivid metaphor to clarify that this is a short-term adjustment for massive future wealth growth, an act that nurtures the future.</p></blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>We don&rsquo;t need to win at the starting line; we just need to win at the finish line.
&ndash; James Chan
Context: When answering a student&rsquo;s question about how to educate her 6-year-old child in Singapore&rsquo;s fiercely competitive environment, the teacher emphasized the importance of letting children grow up happily and discover their interests, opposing premature, &ldquo;involution&rdquo;-style education.</p></blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>When you have money in the bank, the bank cares a lot about me. &hellip; I also owe the bank money, I owe them a lot. &hellip; (But) I&rsquo;m spending my equity.
&ndash; James Chan
Context: When discussing the relationship between property and banks with a student, the teacher clarified the correct relationship the wealthy have with banks: not as debtors passively repaying loans, but as asset owners actively using their assets (through pledging) to generate cash flow.</p></blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>In investing, once you make an operational mistake, you must correct it immediately and get back on your original planned track. You cannot let a mistake stand.
&ndash; James Chan
Context: When instructing student Vicky on how to handle the mistake of buying too many bonds, the teacher stated unequivocally the only correct principle for dealing with errors.</p></blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>You should listen to his philosophy, not his stock prices. If they ever talk about stock prices, that&rsquo;s nonsense.
&ndash; James Chan
Context: When commenting on the AI-generated &ldquo;Charlie Munger&rdquo; video circulating online, the teacher taught everyone how to selectively absorb information, focusing on learning the mindset and life wisdom of investment masters, rather than getting entangled in their (possibly fabricated) predictions of specific stock prices.</p></blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>Teaching is the most profitable.
&ndash; Qing
Context: Student Qing shared his observation of some investment bloggers, noting that they themselves admit their most profitable business is running courses and memberships, not their own investing, which highlighted the selflessness of Teacher James&rsquo;s free sharing.</p></blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>Your money allows you to stay in high-quality hotels all over the world. &hellip; You really have to slowly learn to adjust your energy, to truly treasure yourself a bit more, to love yourself a bit more.
&ndash; Cherry
Context: Student Cherry shared her insights while traveling in Europe, encouraging everyone to use their wealth to experience the world and improve their quality of life, rather than being shackled by material possessions (like a house).</p></blockquote>


<h2 class="relative group">V. Summary 
    <div id="v-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#v-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This session was rich in content and highly practical. Teacher James not only clearly defined the applicable scope of the tool QQQI, helping those planning for retirement to better construct their cash flow, but also once again clarified the fundamental investment logic of QQQ, strengthening everyone&rsquo;s confidence in long-term holding. The Q&amp;A interaction was particularly brilliant, ranging from specific cross-border account management to profound analyses of investment psychology. The repeated debates on &ldquo;selling a house to invest&rdquo; were especially notable, where the teacher, through firm logic and highly persuasive metaphors, helped students overcome the fear and doubt associated with transitioning from traditional concepts to a modern investment mindset. The entire discussion emphasized the critical role of discipline, critical thinking, and a long-term perspective for investment success.</p>

  



<div
  
    class="flex px-4 py-3 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900"
  >

  <span
    
      class="text-primary-400 ltr:pr-3 rtl:pl-3 flex items-center"
    >

    

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M506.3 417l-213.3-364c-16.33-28-57.54-28-73.98 0l-213.2 364C-10.59 444.9 9.849 480 42.74 480h426.6C502.1 480 522.6 445 506.3 417zM232 168c0-13.25 10.75-24 24-24S280 154.8 280 168v128c0 13.25-10.75 24-23.1 24S232 309.3 232 296V168zM256 416c-17.36 0-31.44-14.08-31.44-31.44c0-17.36 14.07-31.44 31.44-31.44s31.44 14.08 31.44 31.44C287.4 401.9 273.4 416 256 416z"/></svg>

  </span>


  </span>

  <span
    
      class="dark:text-neutral-300"
    ><strong>Disclaimer:</strong> This article is for personal study notes only and does not constitute any investment advice.</span>
</div>

]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>00520 [Stop Being a Sucker! The Truth About Investment Scams and the Right Mindset for Financial Management</title>
      <link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1751158103958/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1751158103958/</guid>
      <description>In this session, Teacher James emphasizes that market volatility is irrelevant to long-term investors and that the biggest risk is being out of the market. He reiterates the core philosophy of &amp;#39;buy whenever you have money, and never sell,&amp;#39; and delves into asset allocation, the use of leveraged funds, the principles of borrowing to invest, and how to debunk common investment myths like the Buffett Indicator. He also shares his unique perspective on capitalism and warns everyone to be vigilant against investment scams.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<lite-youtube videoid="GbkfZwvjqkU" playlabel="GbkfZwvjqkU" params=""></lite-youtube>



<h2 class="relative group">I. Topic of the Session 
    <div id="i-topic-of-the-session" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-topic-of-the-session" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>The core theme of this session is to emphasize that long-term investors should ignore short-term market volatility and firmly believe in the market&rsquo;s perpetual upward trend. Teacher James points out that having funds out of the market is the biggest risk, and investors should enter the market as soon as possible, adopting a &ldquo;buy whenever you have money, and never sell&rdquo; strategy. By debunking common market prediction indicators (like the Buffett Indicator) and analyzing asset allocation, he aims to help investors build a solid investment mindset to achieve long-term wealth growth.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">II. Briefing Content 
    <div id="ii-briefing-content" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii-briefing-content" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Core Investment Philosophy and Market Attitude 
    <div id="core-investment-philosophy-and-market-attitude" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#core-investment-philosophy-and-market-attitude" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Market Volatility Doesn&rsquo;t Concern Me</strong>: For long-term investors, daily market fluctuations, global situations, tariff wars, etc., should not influence investment decisions. The market hitting new highs for three consecutive days proves the importance of staying in the market.</li>
<li><strong>Being Out of the Market is the Biggest Risk</strong>: Many people exit the market fearing a downturn, but waiting for a correction might mean never getting back in. Keeping funds out of the market and missing out on gains is a far greater risk than a short-term decline.</li>
<li><strong>Predictions are Useless, Making Money is What Matters</strong>: There are many who make correct market predictions, but the ones who actually make money are those who ignore the predictions and stay invested.</li>
<li><strong>The Market Always Goes Up</strong>: This is the core belief a long-term investor must have. Historical data proves that in the long run, the market only goes up and will always reach new highs. Investors should always be extremely optimistic and face the sun.</li>
<li><strong>Review the Past, Preview the Future</strong>: The teacher advises students, especially new ones, to watch videos from the market crashes at the end of 2018, March 2020, and in 2022 to learn how to react correctly during times of panic and to mentally prepare for future market volatility.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Investment Discipline and Risk Management 
    <div id="investment-discipline-and-risk-management" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#investment-discipline-and-risk-management" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>No Risk in Long-Term Investing</strong>: Looking at a century of history, buying at any point and holding for the long term has always been profitable. However, short-term volatility can be immense, with potential drops of 50% or even 80%, so one must focus on long-term returns.</li>
<li><strong>The Nature of Your Funds Dictates Your Investment</strong>: Money needed for the short term (like tuition or a down payment for a house) must absolutely not be invested in the stock market; it should be kept as cash. Only long-term funds that you won&rsquo;t touch for 10-20 years are suitable for investment.</li>
<li><strong>The Importance of Asset Allocation</strong>:
<ul>
<li><strong>Seek Stability Before Returns</strong>: Investment allocation should prioritize psychological stability. It is inadvisable for people to switch from an aggressive allocation (e.g., 442) to a conservative one (e.g., 433) when they can&rsquo;t handle the pressure during a market drop (like in April of this year).</li>
<li><strong>A Conservative Beta Value</strong>: It is recommended that an investor&rsquo;s Beta value not exceed 1.0. If you think you can handle 1.0, it&rsquo;s better to subtract 0.2 and adopt a Beta of 0.8, which might be more suitable.</li>
<li><strong>Keep Sufficient Cash</strong>: It&rsquo;s advisable to keep at least 30% in cash. For example, a portfolio of 70% QQQ + 30% Cash.</li>
<li><strong>Gradual Increase in Leverage</strong>: Newcomers to the market can start without using leveraged funds. During a market dip, you can use a small amount of cash (e.g., 2% of assets) to buy a 2x leveraged fund, thereby gradually building a leveraged position and allowing the Beta value to increase naturally as the market rises. This is like riding a smooth, high-class train rather than a bumpy race car.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Specific Cases and Myth Debunking 
    <div id="specific-cases-and-myth-debunking" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#specific-cases-and-myth-debunking" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Case: Currency Exchange Impact on 00662 vs. QLD</strong>
<ul>
<li>A student asked if the performance of 00662 (Fubon NASDAQ-100) lagged behind QLD due to the appreciation of the Taiwan Dollar (TWD).</li>
<li><strong>Teacher&rsquo;s Analysis</strong>: Comparisons must be made in the same currency. Assuming the exchange rate was 33 when investing in QQQ and is now 29, the exchange loss is 12%. Over the past 5 years, QLD&rsquo;s performance was about 128%, and 00662&rsquo;s was about 114%. However, after deducting the 12% currency exchange loss from QLD&rsquo;s 128%, its performance becomes about 112%, which is actually lower than 00662&rsquo;s 114%. The conclusion is that their performances are essentially the same; don&rsquo;t be misled by nominal figures in different currencies.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Debunking the &ldquo;Buffett Indicator&rdquo; Myth</strong>:
<ul>
<li>Many people use the &ldquo;Total Stock Market Capitalization / GDP&rdquo; ratio to judge if the market is overheated, which is wrong.</li>
<li><strong>GDP is a flow concept</strong>: It only measures the new value added in the current year.</li>
<li><strong>Market Cap is a stock concept</strong>: It includes the value of all of a company&rsquo;s historical investments and accumulated value.</li>
<li>Comparing a changing flow metric to a cumulative stock metric is like comparing apples and oranges; it&rsquo;s completely illogical.</li>
<li>Warren Buffett himself rarely mentions this indicator and emphasizes not to use a single indicator to judge the market. Many &ldquo;pundits&rdquo; and bloggers on the market abuse this concept just to get attention, like mindless &ldquo;parrots.&rdquo;</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Scam Alert and Life Philosophy 
    <div id="scam-alert-and-life-philosophy" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#scam-alert-and-life-philosophy" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Beware of Investment Scams</strong>:
<ul>
<li>Teacher James <strong>solemnly declares</strong> that he provides <strong>completely free</strong> and <strong>voluntary teaching</strong>. He will never contact students privately, let alone offer financial services for a 1% fee or any other charge.</li>
<li>Anyone who uses his name on platforms like LINE or WeChat to contact you, claiming they can manage your finances for a fee, is a <strong>scammer</strong>.</li>
<li>In the US, it is illegal for an uncertified financial advisor to charge fees. The teacher stresses that no one cares more about your assets than you do; you must manage your investments yourself.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Awakening to Capitalism</strong>: Teacher James puts forward a sharp point: laborers who go to work in modern society are, in essence, &ldquo;slaves&rdquo; of capitalism. The purpose of his teaching is to awaken everyone&rsquo;s &ldquo;capitalist consciousness,&rdquo; to learn to use capitalism to become capitalists, rather than being enslaved by it. (Refer to video <code>00315</code>)</li>
<li><strong>Ultimate Goals in Life</strong>:
<ol>
<li><strong>Health and Longevity are Fundamental</strong>: Longevity is the path to wealth, and health is the mother of happiness. He reminds everyone to get health check-ups (like CT scans).</li>
<li><strong>Happiness is the purpose of life</strong>.</li>
<li><strong>Wealth is just the icing on the cake</strong>.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li><strong>The Principle of Borrowing to Invest</strong>:
<ul>
<li>For money borrowed according to proper principles, <strong>never think about paying it back</strong>.</li>
<li>Once you repay the loan, your risk (Beta value) will immediately increase. For example, an investor with 50% cash and 50% QQQ (Beta=0.5) who uses cash to repay a loan will see their Beta value skyrocket, greatly increasing their risk.</li>
<li>Having cash on hand gives you the confidence to face risks.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">III. Q&amp;A Session 
    <div id="iii-qa-session" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii-qa-session" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Zhao 
    <div id="zhao" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#zhao" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing</strong>: He is a 65-year-old veteran investor who lost tens of millions in the stock market twice. After starting to learn Teacher James&rsquo;s philosophy after the Chinese New Year, although he had doubts about some points (about 10-15%), he found through deeper study that the teacher&rsquo;s philosophy is continuously refined and has deep logic.</li>
<li><strong>Question 1</strong>: The market often says, &ldquo;If you miss the best few days of gains, your annualized return will drop significantly.&rdquo; What is the specific definition of this &ldquo;best time for gains&rdquo;?</li>
<li><strong>Question 2</strong>: Regarding &ldquo;smart rebalancing&rdquo; versus &ldquo;mindless rebalancing,&rdquo; if the market is still rising at the end of the year, will rebalancing then cause one to miss out on subsequent gains?
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s Reply</strong>:
<ol>
<li><strong>On Missing Up Days</strong>: This is precisely why it&rsquo;s important &ldquo;not to leave the market.&rdquo; Attempting to time the market will very likely cause you to miss the days with the biggest gains, leading to long-term returns far worse than those of an investor who &ldquo;never sells.&rdquo;</li>
<li><strong>On Rebalancing</strong>: Attempting &ldquo;smart,&rdquo; irregular rebalancing based on market movements is <strong>active investing</strong>, which cannot be taught because everyone&rsquo;s judgment criteria are different (add at a 10% drop? or 20%?). This approach can deplete your cash in an extreme market (like a three-year decline), leading to bankruptcy. Therefore, the simplest, safest, and most replicable method is to <strong>rebalance once a year</strong>. It doesn&rsquo;t matter that you didn&rsquo;t add more at the low point in April this year, because by the end of the year, your entire portfolio will still have appreciated significantly.</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Niu Ba 
    <div id="niu-ba" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#niu-ba" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing</strong>: Praised the NotebookLM system created by student &ldquo;Chen Feng&rdquo; and the teacher&rsquo;s ChatGPT tool as being very useful.</li>
<li><strong>Question 1</strong>: For a portfolio of 60% QQQ, 10% QLD, and 30% cash, what is the Beta value? (Teacher&rsquo;s reply: 0.6 + 0.1*2 = 0.8)</li>
<li><strong>Question 2</strong>: Can one use technical indicators (like the 200-day moving average) to assist in decision-makingbecoming conservative when the price is below the average and aggressive when it&rsquo;s above?</li>
<li><strong>Question 3</strong>: Are people like Apple CEO Tim Cook considered capitalists or laborers?
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s Reply</strong>:
<ol>
<li><strong>On Technical Indicators</strong>: Completely unnecessary. In the recent V-shaped recovery, using a 200-day moving average strategy would have had you sell and buy back at roughly the same point. Not only would you not have made a profit, you might have lost money on transaction fees, underperforming a &ldquo;do nothing&rdquo; strategy.</li>
<li><strong>On Tim Cook</strong>: He is a <strong>laborer</strong>, a very highly paid &ldquo;slave.&rdquo; His wealth comes from his salary (including stock options), not from returns on his own invested capital. True capitalists do not have to go to work.</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Inny 
    <div id="inny" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#inny" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing</strong>:
<ol>
<li>Influenced by family, she previously invested in real estate. Her property in Japan yielded poor returns due to the yen&rsquo;s major depreciation over the last decade.</li>
<li>Shared a success story: she took out a home loan of 8 million TWD four or five years ago and didn&rsquo;t pay it off early. Instead, she invested the funds in ETFs and made a profit of four to five million, deeply understanding the benefits of investing with borrowed money.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li><strong>Question 1</strong>: What should she do with the Japanese Yen she holds?</li>
<li><strong>Question 2</strong>: She has about $200,000 USD in cash (cost basis ~32 TWD/USD) and has already invested $100,000 in US stocks (QQQ/SPY/VT). Now she doesn&rsquo;t know what to do with the remaining cash because she heard the teacher say there are tax issues for Taiwanese people buying US stocks.
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s Reply</strong>:
<ol>
<li><strong>Handling the Yen</strong>: Immediately, right now, exchange it for TWD and buy 00662. Don&rsquo;t worry about the exchange rate loss, because the potential return from the stock market is far greater than currency fluctuations.</li>
<li><strong>Handling the USD Assets</strong>: Again, ignore the exchange rate. For Taiwanese investors, the best approach is to sell the holdings in the US brokerage, transfer the funds back to Taiwan, and buy 00662 with all of it to avoid future estate tax issues. In the long run, the exchange rates for entering and exiting the market will average out, so there&rsquo;s no need for excessive worry.</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Grace 
    <div id="grace" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#grace" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Question</strong>: She is in her 30s, and about 30-40% of her assets are in Bitcoin, with the rest in QQQ. How should she handle the Bitcoin?
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s Reply</strong>: Because you are still very young, you can continue to hold the Bitcoin. But <strong>do not add any more</strong>. All new funds in the future should be invested in QQQ. In the future, Bitcoin might be used as collateral like gold, so you may not need to sell it. At your age, if you persist for the long term, it&rsquo;s possible to have assets worth tens of billions or even hundreds of billions.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Ola 
    <div id="ola" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ola" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing</strong>: He is 65 and retired. During the recent downturn, his allocation was too aggressive (Beta 1.1), and he had no cash to add at the bottom. He has now adjusted to a Beta of 0.9 (70% QQQ, 10% QLD, 20% Cash).</li>
<li><strong>Question</strong>: Is there a mechanical rule for deploying cash during a major market drop? For example, investing one-third of the cash when the market drops 20%?
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s Reply</strong>: This falls under active management. If you must do it, you could consider this: when the market drops 10% (happens almost every year), you can add more once; when it drops 20% (happens every few years), you can add more again. If it continues to fall, you must be very cautious, as it could be a major bear market. At that point, you should switch to a defensive posture, not continue to add. The key is to <strong>never run out of cash</strong>, and the goal of adding to your position is to <strong>maintain your original Beta value (0.9)</strong>, not to raise it.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Wasi 
    <div id="wasi" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#wasi" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Question</strong>: QQQ has hit a new high, but her TQQQ position (about 10% of her portfolio) is still far from its high point. Why is that?
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s Reply</strong>: This is due to the <strong>volatility decay</strong> characteristic of leveraged ETFs. In volatile and declining markets, the drop in leveraged ETFs will be more than a multiple of the index&rsquo;s drop, and their recovery is also slower. This is why a full position in leveraged funds is not recommended. For those holding leveraged funds, adding to your position during a major market drop can help you break even faster. For those with a salary, you should normally buy QQQ and use your salary to buy TQQQ during major market dips.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Lu 
    <div id="lu" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#lu" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing</strong>:
<ol>
<li>She shared her observation of the debate in Taiwan between &ldquo;high-dividend ETFs&rdquo; and &ldquo;market-cap ETFs,&rdquo; believing that both are good as long as they attract people to participate in the capital market.</li>
<li>She shared her learning journey: after diligently listening to the teacher&rsquo;s past courses (especially the videos from the 2022 bear market), her conviction was established, many questions resolved themselves, and she became confident in managing minor &ldquo;variations&rdquo; in her portfolio without needing to ask the teacher about everything.</li>
<li>She shared her experience visiting relatives in Thailand and the joy of spending money on experiences. This was because after investing according to the teacher&rsquo;s method, she felt like she had more than enough money, leading to a more relaxed mindset.</li>
</ol>
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s Comment</strong>: I completely agree. There is no absolute right or wrong in investing and opinions; there&rsquo;s no need to debate. He himself has learned that it&rsquo;s better to understand the reasons behind the other person&rsquo;s viewpoint than to argue. He won&rsquo;t &ldquo;burn himself out&rdquo; trying to convince others but rather act as a light, allowing those who are destined to find it themselves.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Yao Nian 
    <div id="yao-nian" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#yao-nian" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Question</strong>: Regarding children&rsquo;s education, a friend&rsquo;s Chinese-American child was beaten at school for stopping a black classmate from cutting in line. The school handled it poorly due to &ldquo;political correctness.&rdquo; How should we teach our children to protect themselves when facing bullying and injustice, without losing faith in justice?
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s Reply</strong>: <strong>Safety is always the number one priority</strong>. He quoted a police officer&rsquo;s advice: when faced with a violent attack, the first reaction is to <strong>run</strong>, not to fight back. We must teach our children that defending justice cannot come at the cost of their own physical well-being; we are not martyrs. One can verbally intervene, but if the other person ignores it or shows violent tendencies, one must leave immediately and protect oneself. Society will teach them their lesson; our children don&rsquo;t need to take that risk.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">IV. Insightful Quotes 
    <div id="iv-insightful-quotes" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv-insightful-quotes" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>Being out of the market is actually the biggest risk.
&ndash; Teacher James</p></blockquote>
<p>This point was central to the entire session. The teacher repeatedly emphasized that compared to the risk of a short-term market decline, the risk of investors exiting out of fear and thereby missing out on huge long-term returns is far greater.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Today&rsquo;s laborers who go to work are like the cotton pickers brought from Africa to America in the past. All who work in factories today are slaves to capitalism.
&ndash; Teacher James</p></blockquote>
<p>This is a very sharp and thought-provoking view from the teacher, aimed at awakening people to the nature of capitalism and encouraging them to become capitalists through investment, thereby escaping the status of a &ldquo;laborer.&rdquo;</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Longevity is the path to wealth, happiness is the purpose of life, health is the mother of happiness, and wealth is just the icing on the cake.
&ndash; Teacher James</p></blockquote>
<p>The teacher shared his philosophy of life, emphasizing what is truly important. Wealth is meant to serve a better life, not be the ultimate goal.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>If someone says, &ldquo;Pay me 1% and I can be your investment advisor&rdquo;&hellip; that is a scam.
&ndash; Teacher James</p></blockquote>
<p>The teacher directly used the language of scammers as an example to strongly remind all students that anyone impersonating him and offering paid financial advice is a scam, urging everyone to protect their assets.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>You shouldn&rsquo;t defend justice with your own body; we are not martyrs.
&ndash; Teacher James</p></blockquote>
<p>This was the core advice given in response to the question about how a child should face school bullying. He stressed that under any circumstances, personal safety is the highest priority, teaching children to uphold their sense of justice while also learning to protect themselves wisely.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">V. Summary 
    <div id="v-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#v-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This session once again stressed the core discipline of long-term investing: ignore short-term market volatility and firmly believe in the market&rsquo;s long-term upward trend. By analyzing asset allocation, the use of leveraged funds, and debunking common myths like the Buffett Indicator, Teacher James pointed out a simple yet effective path to wealth growth. The Q&amp;A session was rich in content, covering profound discussions from specific investment strategies (like rebalancing timing and leveraged fund allocation) to life philosophies (such as dealing with bullying and the nature of capitalism). The central idea of the entire session is that investors should build a strong psychological foundation, focus on controllable investment principles, and simultaneously pursue a life of health, happiness, and longevity, viewing wealth as a tool for a better life, not the ultimate goal.</p>

  



<div
  
    class="flex px-4 py-3 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900"
  >

  <span
    
      class="text-primary-400 ltr:pr-3 rtl:pl-3 flex items-center"
    >

    

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M506.3 417l-213.3-364c-16.33-28-57.54-28-73.98 0l-213.2 364C-10.59 444.9 9.849 480 42.74 480h426.6C502.1 480 522.6 445 506.3 417zM232 168c0-13.25 10.75-24 24-24S280 154.8 280 168v128c0 13.25-10.75 24-23.1 24S232 309.3 232 296V168zM256 416c-17.36 0-31.44-14.08-31.44-31.44c0-17.36 14.07-31.44 31.44-31.44s31.44 14.08 31.44 31.44C287.4 401.9 273.4 416 256 416z"/></svg>

  </span>


  </span>

  <span
    
      class="dark:text-neutral-300"
    ><strong>Disclaimer:</strong> This article is for personal study notes only and does not constitute any investment advice.</span>
</div>

]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
