<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Finance on QQQ Investor</title>
    <link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/tags/finance/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Finance on QQQ Investor</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jomonylw.github.io/en/tags/finance/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>00496 Global Markets and the Tech Wave: How to Seize Opportunities for Wealth Growth Amidst Volatility. The Philosophy of Financial Freedom: From Personalized Investing to Exploring Life&#39;s Values</title>
      <link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1735482278058/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1735482278058/</guid>
      <description>At the end of 2024, with market fluctuations, Teacher James shared his insights on the current economic situation, financial markets, and investment strategies. In addition, several students asked questions online, covering asset allocation, business operations, health and wellness, tax planning, stock leveraging, and other areas.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Part One
<lite-youtube videoid="9F1rAWjCGX8" playlabel="9F1rAWjCGX8" params=""></lite-youtube>
</p>
<p>Part Two
<lite-youtube videoid="oPb4m81Nv24" playlabel="oPb4m81Nv24" params=""></lite-youtube>
</p>


<h2 class="relative group">I. Main Topic of the Session 
    <div id="i-main-topic-of-the-session" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-main-topic-of-the-session" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>Investment mindset and strategy adjustments amidst year-end market volatility, along with comprehensive reflections on personal life and financial health.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">II. Presentation Content 
    <div id="ii-presentation-content" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii-presentation-content" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Market Volatility and Investment Mindset 
    <div id="market-volatility-and-investment-mindset" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#market-volatility-and-investment-mindset" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>The only constant in the market is volatility. Investors should ignore market fluctuations, international situations, market analysis, financial reports, and economic situations, and focus on long-term investment.</li>
<li>Disclaimer: The content of the COC investment and financial management channel is for educational purposes only and does not constitute investment advice. Investment involves high risks, and proper asset allocation is necessary.</li>
<li>Newcomers should watch the YouTube episode 00451 &ldquo;Investment Lecture Worth 100 Million&rdquo; and also find related content on Bilibili and podcasts.</li>
<li>Investing requires independent thinking. Do not blindly follow advice or join any groups to avoid being deceived.</li>
<li>The Nasdaq 100 index fund is recommended as the only focused fund, with others being supplementary.</li>
<li>The handout includes information on Nasdaq 100 index funds worldwide, including leveraged funds, and information on retirement accounts in various regions, with content continuously updated.</li>
<li>The &ldquo;Investment Lecture Worth 100 Million&rdquo; video is the most important. Investors should always be extremely optimistic; the market will eventually rise and reach new highs.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">UK and European Financial Information 
    <div id="uk-and-european-financial-information" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#uk-and-european-financial-information" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Showcasing information provided by a UK friend regarding UK investments, loans, retirement accounts, ETFs, and insurance companies, particularly information on 2x leveraged funds on the PEA website.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">US-China Trade War and Globalization 
    <div id="us-china-trade-war-and-globalization" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#us-china-trade-war-and-globalization" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Issues like the US-China trade war and tariffs do not affect technological advancements and the innovation of American companies, thus having little impact on index investing.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Risks and Returns of Leveraged Funds 
    <div id="risks-and-returns-of-leveraged-funds" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#risks-and-returns-of-leveraged-funds" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>The risk of a 2x leveraged fund is not simply double, and the return is not twice the annualized rate of return, but approximately 1.4 times.</li>
<li>The annualized return of QQQ over 20 years is 14%, while QLD&rsquo;s is 19.6%. QLD&rsquo;s total return over 20 years is 2.6 times that of QQQ, far exceeding double.</li>
<li>Combining leveraged funds with cash can reduce risk and increase returns.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Investment Wisdom and Market Essence 
    <div id="investment-wisdom-and-market-essence" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#investment-wisdom-and-market-essence" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>The market is always smarter than individual investors. Stock picking and timing the market are futile.</li>
<li>In a bull market, many &ldquo;gurus&rdquo; emerge, but they disappear when the market falls; this is a market norm.</li>
<li>Controlling the major stocks on Wall Street means controlling the world.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Investment Sharing and Personal Insights 
    <div id="investment-sharing-and-personal-insights" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#investment-sharing-and-personal-insights" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Investment sharers need to provide clear, diverse, and universally applicable investment methods and benefit from them.</li>
<li>Buffett&rsquo;s investment philosophy emphasizes long-term investment, perfecting the investment system.</li>
<li>Understanding the essence of finance, economics, accounting, and logic helps resist external interference and adhere to index investing.</li>
<li>Asset allocation is simplified into two types: 433 (conservative) and 442 (aggressive), pursuing safety rather than high returns, with cash being a safe asset.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Finance and Monetary Theory 
    <div id="finance-and-monetary-theory" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#finance-and-monetary-theory" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>The foundation of capitalism is currency. Understanding monetary theory is crucial to understanding finance, investment, and the economy.</li>
<li>The status of the US dollar as the world&rsquo;s reserve currency determines the subordinate status of other countries, especially those holding large amounts of US dollar foreign exchange reserves.</li>
<li>China and other emerging countries are trying to break away from their dependence on the US dollar to escape US control.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Life&rsquo;s Meaning and Happiness 
    <div id="lifes-meaning-and-happiness" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#lifes-meaning-and-happiness" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>The happiest thing in life is giving. Happiness is a human right. Sharing and giving energy on a spiritual level can bring more happiness than material things.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Extremes of Capitalism and Social Issues 
    <div id="extremes-of-capitalism-and-social-issues" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#extremes-of-capitalism-and-social-issues" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Capitalism will lead to an expansion of the wealth gap. The development of robots will make spiritual education even more important.</li>
<li>Systemic discrimination exists in society, leading to a vicious cycle of poverty. Our goal is to help eliminate poverty as much as possible.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">US Accounting System and Social Phenomena 
    <div id="us-accounting-system-and-social-phenomena" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#us-accounting-system-and-social-phenomena" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>The US accounting system is very complete. Phenomena like &ldquo;zero-dollar shopping&rdquo; are the result of accounting costs and leftist thinking, and there is no need to over-interpret them.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Wealth and Government Relations 
    <div id="wealth-and-government-relations" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#wealth-and-government-relations" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Wealthy individuals escape government control by paying taxes, while the poor are trapped.</li>
<li>Legitimate tax avoidance is an important topic.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Personalization of Diet and Asset Allocation 
    <div id="personalization-of-diet-and-asset-allocation" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#personalization-of-diet-and-asset-allocation" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Both diet and asset allocation should be customized according to individual circumstances and cannot be generalized.</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">III. Q&amp;A Session 
    <div id="iii-qa-session" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii-qa-session" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Zhang Yong 
    <div id="zhang-yong" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#zhang-yong" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing</strong>: The chaos in the domestic insurance industry, where banks lure customers into buying insurance with high commissions, is even linked to the performance evaluations of customer managers. Many customers do not understand investments and choose low-yield or even risky insurance products to preserve their capital. He also shared a case of a friend who was defrauded of over 1.7 million in a romance scam, illustrating the complexity of the domestic financial environment.
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s comment</strong>: The US financial system strictly separates life insurance from other financial businesses, and there is no such thing as banks selling insurance. The financial supervision in China and Taiwan is problematic. Banks should focus on deposit and loan business and should not be involved in insurance and investment. This chaos will ultimately harm the interests of emerging countries.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question</strong>: Does Teacher James share content each week based on reflections on the same theme, or does he summarize viewpoints from reading many books?
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s reply</strong>: In addition to reading a lot of books, more importantly, independent thinking and critical thinking are involved. The formation of monetary theory stems from thinking about the nature of capitalism, and the content of the handouts mostly comes from students&rsquo; questions and his own reflections. This information is endless. To be an excellent sharer, one needs to have basic knowledge, thinking ability, and originality.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Xiao Cai 
    <div id="xiao-cai" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#xiao-cai" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing 1</strong>: Took over the family food business ten years ago when the company&rsquo;s assets and liabilities were zero. After ten years of operation, the company turned a profit, and its current value (including real estate) is about 300 million NTD. Over the past decade, he distributed about 200 million NTD of revenue to his family, retaining 100 million NTD for loan purposes. Currently, he has invested 80 million in 00662 (a 2x leveraged Nasdaq 100 index ETF) and 20 million in 00631L (Taiwan&rsquo;s 50 Positive 2 ETF).
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s comment</strong>: None</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question 1</strong>: The bank will allocate a loan of 60 million NTD on January 1st. Should this fund be used to buy 00662 all at once, or should he wait for a 20% market drop before buying? Also, if the market crashes and 00662 and 00631L go to zero, how will he deal with it?
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s reply</strong>: If the market goes to zero, the company can still make loan payments. The worst-case scenario is that the land is auctioned off, and he can still get tens of millions. Since the worst has been considered, how to buy the 60 million is not important. If it were me, I would buy it all on Monday. If you choose to wait for a 20% drop before buying, you can follow your plan and inform everyone when you buy.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question 2</strong>: How to maintain good health?
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s reply</strong>: Regular comprehensive physical examinations are necessary. I have been doing annual check-ups since my thirties. Wellness, like asset allocation, needs to be personalized. The advice I can give everyone now is to eat well, sleep well, and don&rsquo;t worry. What to eat specifically, what exercises to do, etc., need to be decided according to personal circumstances and cannot be given a unified recommendation.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question 3</strong>: What are your views on Taiwan&rsquo;s politics and how to support political parties?
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s reply</strong>: Regarding politics and religious beliefs, everyone has different positions and viewpoints. Discussing these issues in the classroom is meaningless and fruitless. It is recommended that students do not discuss these topics in the classroom and keep their opinions to themselves.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question 4</strong>: How to preserve assets in response to potential cross-strait issues? He currently has about 200 million NTD in assets in Taiwan and a house worth 8 million in Vietnam. How should he allocate his assets?
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s reply</strong>: If you can&rsquo;t sleep due to worries about cross-strait issues, it&rsquo;s recommended to immigrate as soon as possible. If you choose to stay in Taiwan, you need to make some decisions, such as whether to close the company. If the 40 employees are causing you distress, consider closing the company and compensating them. Life decisions should be decisive, not prolonged. Be responsible for your own happiness.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Additional question</strong>: How to get rid of the shackles of the family business?
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s reply</strong>: You have managed the company very well. The choice is your life. Do whatever makes you happy. If the family business makes you unhappy, shut it down and give the employees a good severance package. Consider your own life, not your father&rsquo;s. If your father&rsquo;s business is no longer your concern, and it&rsquo;s not bringing you happiness, then let it go.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Repeated emphasis</strong>: Believes that apart from investment and financial management, health is the most important asset in life, and cited the example of &ldquo;Yu (Yuan) Lingqi&rdquo; to emphasize the importance of regular health check-ups, hoping the channel will pay more attention to health issues.
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s reply</strong>: Health is very important. Everyone&rsquo;s health condition is different, and it is impossible to provide a unified recommendation. Everyone needs to pay attention to and manage their health according to their own situation.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Lare 
    <div id="lare" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#lare" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Question</strong>: Based in Canada, unable to leverage stocks. If income decreases in a certain year, and the tax rate drops from 32% to 24%, is it worth selling some stocks to increase income to the 32% tax bracket to improve the future cost basis?
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s reply</strong>: It is not recommended to sell stocks because selling incurs taxes. Canada&rsquo;s tax system is very unfavorable for stock investments. When immigrating, consider future generations and choose countries with development prospects. In Canada, you can consider using an IB account for loans, but this will face inheritance tax issues, possibly up to 40%. Therefore, when planning estates, minimize assets in IB accounts. In the long run, trusts can be used to avoid taxes. It is currently not recommended to sell stocks for short-term tax benefits. Consider selling after retirement when income is lower.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Additional explanation</strong>: IB accounts have a low financing ratio for Canadian stocks, only up to 50%.
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s addition</strong>: You can borrow 40% first, and add more if needed. But ultimately, there will still be inheritance tax issues.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Terry 
    <div id="terry" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#terry" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Question 1</strong>: How to transfer taxable accounts or retirement accounts to tax-free accounts, such as Roth IRA? What are the specific steps?
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s reply</strong>: If it&rsquo;s within the same brokerage, such as Charles Schwab, you can fill out a form online directly. If it&rsquo;s at different brokerages, you need to contact the brokerage to obtain and fill out a form. For specific steps, you can refer to the previously released video &ldquo;Investment and Financial Management Tips 26: How to Transfer from a Traditional Taxable Account to a Roth IRA Online at 722.&rdquo;</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question 2</strong>: What is your view on Crypto, and will QQQ include Crypto companies in the future?
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s reply</strong>: I don&rsquo;t know much about Crypto and am not sure if it will exist forever, so I won&rsquo;t answer.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">IM 
    <div id="im" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#im" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing</strong>: Through learning, I realized that my investment was too risky, and emergency funds should not all be invested in QQQ. Now I have withdrawn 36 months of emergency funds back to the Money Market Fund. When starting with small funds, one should focus on their main job and increase income sources. After investing in index funds, my mindset changed, and I began to focus on the importance of timing. Therefore, I started to focus on diet, fitness, and learning from the experiences of long-lived people around me. In addition, I learned from investing to avoid risks, such as giving up dangerous activities like diving.
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s comment</strong>: It is wise to learn from the experiences of others. Being overly aggressive is human nature, but it is important to realize and correct it in time. It is wrong to increase positions when the market is rising and to be fearful when it is falling. It should be the other way around. Emergency funds should not be added to.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question</strong>: How to judge whether you are being too adventurous? For example, increasing the leverage ratio of asset allocation from 1.0 to 1.8 when stocks are rising.
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s reply</strong>: This is also a necessary evil. Now that you realize it&rsquo;s not right, you can start to retreat, or when it rises, you buy in, and when it falls, you get scared. Oh, what to do? Then start to retreat. Once you have learned, don&rsquo;t do it again. So, as Buffett said, when others are greedy, you should be fearful, and when others are fearful, you should be greedy. That&rsquo;s the right pace. So, when you want to increase your position in the future, it should be when others are fearful. That&rsquo;s how I do it. This emergency fund should not be increased. Regardless of whether the market is rising or falling, you should not add to this cervical spine disease. How could you add to it? This is not allowed. Then, if you use our asset allocation, when the market falls, you automatically buy in for one year, and when the market rises, you automatically withdraw from the leveraged fund. This is passive, and this has already achieved the practice of being greedy when others are fearful and being fearful when others are greedy.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Patty 
    <div id="patty" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#patty" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Question</strong>: The relationship between the asset-backed ratio and cash reserves. If asset-backed financing is carried out, how to ensure that the cash on hand is greater than the pledged amount? For example, with assets of 1 million, allocated according to the 721 ratio, 200,000 is pledged, but 100,000 in cash cannot be moved. Is it necessary to balance for one or two years to accumulate 200,000 in cash before making a pledge?
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s reply</strong>: You cannot borrow 200,000 all at once; you can only borrow 2% per year. When conducting asset-backed financing, the asset allocation should be 433, not 721. Borrow 2% each year and conduct &ldquo;smart rebalancing.&rdquo; Even if the market falls, you will not be forced to liquidate. The cash ratio may be lower than the loan ratio in extreme cases (such as a continuous 10-year decline), but since the total asset value is still greater than the debt, there will be no problem.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Mike 
    <div id="mike" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#mike" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sharing</strong>: A friend&rsquo;s experience. The friend took over his father&rsquo;s family business and eventually had health problems due to overwork. He later sold the company for over 600 million and invested the funds in QQQ. He is now very happy.
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s comment</strong>: None</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question 1</strong>: Regarding 401k and RMD. Previously, company stock was placed in a 401k, and now it has a high value, facing the RMD issue. After Trump takes office, is it possible to abolish RMD and change it to a 15% capital gains tax?
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s reply</strong>: This possibility is extremely slim. The government is unlikely to give up the tax revenue brought by RMD.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question 2</strong>: Regarding the Debt to Equity Ratio of companies. It is found that there are large differences in the debt-to-equity ratios of Buffett and many technology companies. Is this related to the nature of the industry? For example, the debt-to-equity ratio of software companies is usually low, while that of hardware companies like Apple is high. So, for individuals, is it a healthy level to control the debt-to-equity ratio at 0.2?
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s reply</strong>: The higher the debt-to-equity ratio, the higher the ROE usually is, but this needs to be based on healthy debt. Healthy debt refers to debt that can be repaid through its own operating activities, such as credit, stock-backed loans (under safe circumstances), and mortgages (that can be repaid). Apple&rsquo;s debt-to-equity ratio is high because it borrows a lot of money to pay dividends and places assets overseas. In addition, it has a large amount of accounts payable. Therefore, it cannot be simply considered that a high debt-to-equity ratio is bad. It is necessary to analyze the nature and safety of the debt specifically.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>Question 3</strong>: What are your thoughts on the Jetson Orin product launched by Nvidia? This product is mainly for the personal AI market, is cheap, can use ChatGPT to generate code, and runs locally, thereby creating your own AI database.
<ul>
<li><strong>Teacher James&rsquo;s reply</strong>: I don&rsquo;t know much about this product. Our AI is mainly trained using ChatGPT as a personal assistant. Currently, I don&rsquo;t use other devices for personal AI.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">IV. Highlighted Quotes 
    <div id="iv-highlighted-quotes" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv-highlighted-quotes" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>The only constant in the market is volatility.
&ndash; Teacher James</p></blockquote>
<p>This viewpoint emphasizes the normality of market fluctuations. Investors should be mentally prepared and not be affected by short-term market fluctuations.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Investing requires independent thinking. Do not blindly follow advice or join any groups to avoid being deceived.
&ndash; Teacher James</p></blockquote>
<p>This viewpoint emphasizes the importance of independent thinking in investing. Investors should make investment decisions based on their own judgment rather than blindly following others&rsquo; opinions or joining unreliable investment groups.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The happiest thing in life is giving. Happiness is a human right. Sharing and giving energy on a spiritual level can bring more happiness than material things.
&ndash; Teacher James</p></blockquote>
<p>This viewpoint emphasizes that spiritual pursuits are more important than material ones. Giving and sharing can bring greater happiness.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>If you, as a commercial bank, do lending well, then focus on lending. Deposits are 2%. Then your lending is 3.5%, 4%. You just make that 2% difference. This is what a commercial bank should do. Commerce should not touch insurance.
&ndash; Teacher James</p></blockquote>
<p>This viewpoint points out that commercial banks should focus on deposit and loan business instead of being involved in areas like insurance, which not only violates financial regulations but also harms the interests of customers.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Happiness is a human right. If you are alive, you should be happy. If you live so miserably, why bother?
&ndash; Teacher James</p></blockquote>
<p>This viewpoint reminds everyone to pursue happiness and not sacrifice their happiness for money or other goals.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Impotence is also a kind of strength because accepting one&rsquo;s own impotence and acknowledging one&rsquo;s own impotence is also a kind of strength.
&ndash; Teacher James</p></blockquote>
<p>This viewpoint expresses a broad-minded attitude towards life. Acknowledging one&rsquo;s limitations is not a bad thing; instead, it can make one more relaxed.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The truly wealthy are those who foresee a future eternally disconnected from government oversight, swiftly settling their dues to escape the clutches of authority.
&ndash; Teacher James</p></blockquote>
<p>This perspective highlights how affluent individuals utilize legitimate tax avoidance strategies to minimize governmental control over their wealth.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Learning from the experiences of others is a wise approach.
&ndash; IM</p></blockquote>
<p>This viewpoint emphasizes the importance of learning and drawing lessons from others&rsquo; experiences, which can help us avoid making the same mistakes.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>When others are greedy, you should be fearful; when others are fearful, you should be greedy.
&ndash; Teacher James, quoting Buffett</p></blockquote>
<p>This is a very important principle in investing, namely, contrarian thinking, staying calm when the market is frenzied and looking for opportunities when the market is panicking.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Just be happy. There&rsquo;s nothing to it, nothing to fight for, no particular meaning, nothing that grand or great.
&ndash; Teacher James</p></blockquote>
<p>This viewpoint expresses a detached attitude towards life. Don&rsquo;t put too much pressure on yourself; learn to enjoy life.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Don&rsquo;t wait until it&rsquo;s too late, leaving no time for regrets.
&ndash; Teacher James</p></blockquote>
<p>Drawing on investment principles, this perspective underscores the importance of early health screenings, urging not to wait until problems arise before regretting, echoing Xiao Cai&rsquo;s shared viewpoint.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>We investors are always extremely optimistic. Market fluctuations should be ignored. The market will eventually rise and always reach new highs.
&ndash; Teacher James</p></blockquote>
<p>This viewpoint emphasizes the optimistic attitude towards the long-term trend of the market and the neglect of short-term fluctuations, demonstrating the proper mindset for long-term investors.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">V. Summary 
    <div id="v-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#v-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>The content of this episode of the investment and financial management channel is rich. Teacher James not only shared his views on the current market and investment strategies but also answered the practical questions of many students, involving asset allocation, business operations, health and wellness, tax planning, and other aspects. In addition, he also emphasized the importance of happiness and health, as well as investment concepts such as independent thinking, long-term investment, and reasonable tax avoidance. In summary, the content of this episode provides valuable guidance and inspiration for investors, helping everyone make wise decisions in a complex market environment and have a healthier and happier life.</p>

  



<div
  
    class="flex px-4 py-3 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900"
  >

  <span
    
      class="text-primary-400 ltr:pr-3 rtl:pl-3 flex items-center"
    >

    

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M506.3 417l-213.3-364c-16.33-28-57.54-28-73.98 0l-213.2 364C-10.59 444.9 9.849 480 42.74 480h426.6C502.1 480 522.6 445 506.3 417zM232 168c0-13.25 10.75-24 24-24S280 154.8 280 168v128c0 13.25-10.75 24-23.1 24S232 309.3 232 296V168zM256 416c-17.36 0-31.44-14.08-31.44-31.44c0-17.36 14.07-31.44 31.44-31.44s31.44 14.08 31.44 31.44C287.4 401.9 273.4 416 256 416z"/></svg>

  </span>


  </span>

  <span
    
      class="dark:text-neutral-300"
    ><strong>Disclaimer:</strong> This article is only a personal study note and does not constitute any investment advice.</span>
</div>

]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>00495 Market Highs and Lows Don&#39;t Exist: The Only Truth in Long-Term Investing; The Privilege of the Rich and the Secret of Asset Appreciation</title>
      <link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1734846063547/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1734846063547/</guid>
      <description>In this session, James shares his year-end rebalancing strategy, investment philosophy, 433 asset allocation plan, and answers questions from students regarding QQQ, leveraged ETFs, ETNs, real estate, personal finance, and CLEC short video production.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<lite-youtube videoid="TCfozoZu0Hw" playlabel="TCfozoZu0Hw" params=""></lite-youtube>



<h2 class="relative group">I. Main Topic 
    <div id="i-main-topic" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-main-topic" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This session focuses on year-end investment strategies. James emphasizes the importance of rebalancing and delves into investment philosophy, asset allocation, handling market fluctuations, and other practical investment tips. The core message is: adopt a long-term investment approach, adhere to the &ldquo;buy whenever you have money, never sell&rdquo; strategy, and implement a suitable asset allocation and rebalancing plan based on individual circumstances.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">II. Briefing Content 
    <div id="ii-briefing-content" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii-briefing-content" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Year-End Rebalancing and Asset Allocation 
    <div id="year-end-rebalancing-and-asset-allocation" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#year-end-rebalancing-and-asset-allocation" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Importance of Rebalancing:</strong> James stresses the importance of rebalancing at the end or beginning of the year. He recommends passive rebalancing, which means rebalancing when the market is performing well, to avoid panic selling during market downturns. He points out that many investors are reluctant to rebalance during market rallies, hoping to earn more, but end up succumbing to losses during declines and selling at the bottom, resulting in greater losses.</li>
<li><strong>Pledging Stocks for Tax Payment:</strong> He advises individuals with pledged stocks to borrow money for tax payments instead of selling the stocks to avoid increasing capital gains tax and to better utilize their funds. He emphasizes that under the premise of sound asset allocation and risk management, the borrowed money can be used flexibly.</li>
<li><strong>Real Estate Investment:</strong>  James advises against buying real estate, believing it restricts personal freedom. He uses the example of a friend in the Bay Area selling their property to support this viewpoint, pointing out the high holding costs of real estate, including property taxes, maintenance fees, and insurance, which can put significant financial pressure on individuals.</li>
<li><strong>Children&rsquo;s Education and Wealth Perspective:</strong> He suggests parents support their children&rsquo;s choices, believing that happiness is more important than wealth. Children shouldn&rsquo;t live for the sake of glorifying their family but should pursue happiness, serve others, and do what they love.</li>
<li><strong>433 Asset Allocation Plan:</strong> James recommends the 433 asset allocation plan (40% QQQ, 30% TQQQ, 30% Cash) for the general public, adjustable based on individual circumstances. For retirees who are not pledging stocks, he suggests an 80/20 allocation (80% index funds, 20% cash). For investors unfamiliar with or averse to leveraged ETFs, he recommends 100% investment in QQQ or 00662.</li>
<li><strong>Taiwan&rsquo;s Investment Environment Advantage:</strong> James highly praises Taiwan&rsquo;s investment environment, believing it possesses cutting-edge financial tools, tax-free policies, and low interest rates, making it an ideal place for investment. He encourages Taiwanese investors to leverage this advantage.</li>
<li><strong>Mid-Life Investment Strategy:</strong> He advises middle-aged individuals, even with modest incomes, to persist in monthly investments, accumulating wealth gradually for retirement. He illustrates the returns of monthly investments of 5,000 and 10,000 at retirement with specific examples.</li>
<li><strong>Advantages of Nasdaq 100 Index Funds:</strong> James explains the rationale for investing in QQQ, stating that its constituent companies have strong profitability, focus on technology and innovation, and align with long-term human development trends. He also points out that the constituent companies of the Nasdaq 100 index have stronger profitability compared to the S&amp;P 500.</li>
<li><strong>Investment Philosophy:</strong>  He advocates for the &ldquo;buy whenever you have money, never sell&rdquo; strategy, ignoring short-term fluctuations and believing in the long-term upward trajectory of the market. He emphasizes that the purpose of investment is wealth appreciation, not short-term gains, and criticizes the drawbacks of short-term trading.</li>
<li><strong>The Difference Between the Rich and the Poor:</strong> James points out that the rich possess assets and credit, which they can use to &ldquo;print money&rdquo; through leverage for rapid wealth growth.  The poor, lacking investment knowledge, keep their money in banks, missing out on wealth growth opportunities. He uses the example of Warren Buffett issuing bonds to illustrate how the rich utilize credit for investment.</li>
<li><strong>Three Contributions of Investors:</strong>  First, allocating capital to the most efficient companies, promoting technological advancement; second, helping the government invest idle foreign exchange reserves; third, helping the poor activate their funds, maximizing their social value.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Other Investment Advice and Opinions 
    <div id="other-investment-advice-and-opinions" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#other-investment-advice-and-opinions" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Don&rsquo;t blindly trust the investment advice of financial advisors and banks, as they have profit motives and may recommend products beneficial to themselves, not necessarily to investors.</li>
<li>Don&rsquo;t believe in investment recommendations from so-called &ldquo;group leaders&rdquo; or random individuals. Think independently, make your own decisions, and be responsible for your investments.</li>
<li>Focus on investing in broad-market passive funds in the US, such as the Nasdaq 100 Index Fund (QQQ) and the S&amp;P 500 Index Fund (SPY). He provides codes for investing in Nasdaq 100 index funds globally.</li>
<li>Avoid investing in unfamiliar assets like Bitcoin. Focus on core investment strategies to avoid distractions.</li>
<li>Don&rsquo;t overemphasize short-term market fluctuations and various news. Maintain an optimistic mindset and firmly believe in the long-term upward trend of the market.</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">III. Q&amp;A Session 
    <div id="iii-qa-session" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii-qa-session" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Zhang Yong 
    <div id="zhang-yong" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#zhang-yong" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Expresses gratitude to James, shares his 15-year experience in the insurance industry, reflects on some existing problems within the industry, such as promoting low-yield financial insurance, and expresses admiration for the simplicity and effectiveness of the CLEC investment philosophy and how it can change his and his family&rsquo;s financial future. He also shares his desire to help friends and family learn the CLEC investment philosophy but acknowledges the challenges in promotion.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s comments: Affirms Zhang Yong&rsquo;s sharing and thanks Dr. Lao Chai for the recommendation. Emphasizes the power of word-of-mouth marketing and encourages Zhang Yong to continue promoting the CLEC investment philosophy.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Mike 
    <div id="mike" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#mike" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Shares a discussion with friends in Taiwan about QQQ&rsquo;s component stock adjustments and rebalancing mechanism, mentioning the Matthew effect and the idea that the strong get stronger. He also expresses surprise at the relatively small total market capitalization of QQQ.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s comments: Suggests focusing on long-term performance rather than short-term fluctuations and explains that QQQ&rsquo;s smaller market cap is due to the relatively low number of people who understand and invest in it.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 1:  The impact of QQQ component adjustments and rebalancing mechanisms on investments, and whether one should invest in the smaller 90 companies.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s reply:  Advises focusing on long-term performance and volatility, not short-term component adjustments. QQQ&rsquo;s adjustment mechanism ensures the inclusion of the best companies, illustrated by the performance of Mega 7 and MAGS. Points out the &ldquo;stronger get stronger&rdquo; phenomenon among large companies and explains QQQ&rsquo;s rebalancing mechanism.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2: James&rsquo;s methods, tools, and experience in creating short videos, and the application of AI technology.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s reply: Details the short video production process, including writing scripts, using speech recognition software, text-to-video conversion, and subtitle generation. He shares his experience with AI tools, emphasizing the importance of personal creation and the limitations of AI in emotional expression. Mentions using tools like speech recognition software, PowerDirector, and some Chinese and Taiwanese video production software.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Hui 
    <div id="hui" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#hui" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question 1:  FNGS has performed better than QQQ. Can FNGS replace QQQ?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s reply: No, because FNGS has excessive volatility and higher risk, illustrated by the 2000 tech bubble.  Emphasizes that asset allocation should consider volatility and maximum drawdown, not just performance. In the long run, QQQ offers better stability.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2: XLG has lower volatility than QQQ and decent returns.  Is it suitable for allocation?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s reply: No, because XLG&rsquo;s long-term performance is inferior to QQQ. He provides a performance comparison of QQQ and XLG from 2006 to the present, showing QQQ&rsquo;s significantly higher returns. Emphasizes focusing on long-term performance and avoiding investments with poor long-term track records despite low short-term volatility. Investments with less than 30 years of market history are not worth discussing.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Ethan 
    <div id="ethan" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ethan" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Shares his two-year experience learning and promoting the CLEC investment philosophy in China, highlighting the positive impact and challenges. He suggests domestic investors consider opening accounts in Hong Kong to invest in QQQ and shares the advantages of investing in Hong Kong.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s comments: Affirms Ethan&rsquo;s sharing and promotional efforts, agrees with his suggestion of opening accounts in Hong Kong, and adds to the advantages, such as access to leveraged ETFs and money market funds, making the 433 asset allocation plan more comprehensive.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Ling 
    <div id="ling" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ling" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Shares her experience and understanding of the CLEC investment philosophy and how she applies it to life, such as educating her children.  She shares a childhood story of collecting shells for money and her desire for investment.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s comments: Acknowledges Ling&rsquo;s sharing and praises her proactive approach.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question: How to pledge stocks after retirement?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s reply: Explains the process of pledging stocks after retirement and emphasizes the importance of asset allocation.  Suggests the 433 asset allocation plan, adjusted according to the value of the pledged stocks. Explains how to calculate borrowing limits based on the value of pledged stocks and how to add collateral.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Martin 
    <div id="martin" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#martin" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Shares his investment experience and observations in Europe and expresses envy for the US investment environment. Mentions issues such as strict regulations and heavy tax burdens in Europe.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s comments: Agrees with Martin&rsquo;s viewpoint, analyzes the disadvantages of the European investment environment, such as high taxes and restrictions on the tech industry, and explains his focus on the US market. Points out that European socialist ideology and wealth expropriation are detrimental to capital accumulation and economic development.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Ying 
    <div id="ying" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ying" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Reflects on some mistakes in his investment journey, such as missing a year of market gains for a 5% fixed deposit interest rate, and shares his experience and insights on all-in investing in QQQ and TQQQ, and how he persuaded his wife to start investing.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s comments: Affirms Ying&rsquo;s sharing and reiterates the &ldquo;buy whenever you have money, never sell&rdquo; strategy and the all-in investment philosophy. Points out the importance of overcoming human weaknesses for investment success.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Pamela 
    <div id="pamela" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#pamela" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Shares the story of her neighbor being scammed by an accountant, reminding everyone to be cautious of investment risks and not to trust others blindly, even friends or professionals.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s comments: Agrees with Pamela&rsquo;s point, emphasizes the importance of improving one&rsquo;s financial literacy, and advises against over-reliance on financial advisors and accountants.  Points out that an accountant&rsquo;s responsibility is tax filing, not financial planning, so investors should not solely rely on their investment advice.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Nick 
    <div id="nick" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#nick" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Sharing: Shares his investment experience in Canada, recommends HQU, the Canadian equivalent of QQQ, and discusses using IBKR&rsquo;s margin account. Highlights the challenges of investing in Canada and how to utilize IBKR for leverage.
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s comments: Thanks Macro for sharing and suggests that IBKR&rsquo;s margin account might be an option for investors in countries without stock pledging.  Recommends that investors from other countries try and provide feedback on their experience with IBKR&rsquo;s margin account.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Julie 
    <div id="julie" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#julie" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Question 1: Will pledging stocks affect mortgage refinancing?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s reply: No, stock pledging does not appear on credit reports and will not affect mortgage refinancing rates. He advises Julie to pledge her stocks as soon as possible and not wait for interest rates to decline, as future interest rate movements are unpredictable.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Question 2: How to use TQQQ for investment and how to balance returns and risks? How to invest the money set aside for property taxes?
<ul>
<li>James&rsquo;s reply: Suggests the 433 asset allocation plan, adjustable based on individual circumstances.  Emphasizes the importance of Beta management and recommends holding leveraged ETFs in retirement accounts. He advises against investing property tax money in TQQQ, recommending instead to keep it in cash or money market funds for unexpected needs.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Other Q&amp;A 
    <div id="other-qa" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#other-qa" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>James answers audience questions on topics such as 20-year investment returns, Warren Buffett&rsquo;s cash holdings, account selection for funds, short video production, the impact of FNG&rsquo;s bankruptcy on QQQ, simulating investments in the top ten stocks, stock pledging in Taiwan, 50/25/25 asset allocation, money market fund selection, leveraged ETF investment ratios, investment time horizons, and investment options in Canada.</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">IV. Key Takeaways 
    <div id="iv-key-takeaways" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv-key-takeaways" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>Buy whenever you have money, never sell.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>This is James&rsquo;s consistent investment philosophy and the core strategy of CLEC.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Taiwan is a country with well-equipped weapons and cheap bullets.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>James praises Taiwan&rsquo;s investment environment, believing its financial tools, tax benefits, and low interest rates are highly advantageous for investors.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The most important thing in life is happiness.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>James emphasizes that the meaning of life lies in happiness, not in working and making money for its own sake.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>AI creations lack warmth.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>James shares his experience using AI tools for short video production, highlighting the limitations of AI in conveying emotions.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>You can be a benefactor to others, but whether they benefit depends on their destiny and fate.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>James shares his understanding of wealth and life, believing that an individual&rsquo;s wealth accumulation is influenced by destiny, fate, and luck, in addition to hard work.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The market has no peak, only higher highs; the market has no bottom, only a perpetual absence of a top or bottom.
&ndash; James</p></blockquote>
<p>James emphasizes the long-term upward trend of the market and advises against trying to predict market tops and bottoms.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">V. Summary 
    <div id="v-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#v-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This session covered year-end rebalancing strategies, investment philosophy, the 433 asset allocation plan, CLEC short video production methods, and addressed various questions from students. James emphasized the importance of long-term investing and encouraged participants to create a reasonable asset allocation and rebalancing plan based on their individual circumstances, ignore short-term market fluctuations, and adhere to the &ldquo;buy whenever you have money, never sell&rdquo; principle.  During the Q&amp;A, students shared their investment experiences and concerns, raising questions about investment environments in different countries and specific investment products.  James provided professional guidance and advice, helping students better understand and apply the CLEC investment philosophy.</p>

  



<div
  
    class="flex px-4 py-3 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900"
  >

  <span
    
      class="text-primary-400 ltr:pr-3 rtl:pl-3 flex items-center"
    >

    

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M506.3 417l-213.3-364c-16.33-28-57.54-28-73.98 0l-213.2 364C-10.59 444.9 9.849 480 42.74 480h426.6C502.1 480 522.6 445 506.3 417zM232 168c0-13.25 10.75-24 24-24S280 154.8 280 168v128c0 13.25-10.75 24-23.1 24S232 309.3 232 296V168zM256 416c-17.36 0-31.44-14.08-31.44-31.44c0-17.36 14.07-31.44 31.44-31.44s31.44 14.08 31.44 31.44C287.4 401.9 273.4 416 256 416z"/></svg>

  </span>


  </span>

  <span
    
      class="dark:text-neutral-300"
    ><strong>Disclaimer:</strong> This article is for personal learning notes only and does not constitute any investment advice.</span>
</div>

]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Personal Investment Bible - Investment Iron Law XIII</title>
      <link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1731056005972/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1731056005972/</guid>
      <description>This article explores the key to financial success, emphasizing that taking action is more important than knowledge. Through several stories, it illustrates that even with financial knowledge, wealth growth cannot be achieved without action.  The article encourages readers to overcome fear, dare to try, start with small investments, and learn from failures to ultimately achieve financial freedom.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[

<h2 class="relative group">Investment Iron Law XIII: Act Now 
    <div id="investment-iron-law-xiii-act-now" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#investment-iron-law-xiii-act-now" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>Those who require a fully justified reason for every action are never practitioners.</p></blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">Taking Action is Better Than Just Researching 
    <div id="taking-action-is-better-than-just-researching" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#taking-action-is-better-than-just-researching" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>A group of friends worked hard from sunrise to sunset, but their income remained meager.  They envied others who invested in stocks, real estate, or other ventures and became wealthy. They lamented, &ldquo;We toil all day, earning so little, while those investors make easy money.&rdquo;  Finally, they decided to seek guidance from an investment guru.</p>
<p><strong>Knowledge Without Action is Useless</strong></p>
<p>Touched by their sincerity, the guru agreed to teach them. The first lesson was &ldquo;Investment Principles,&rdquo; covering compound interest, returns, and risk management. The second lesson was &ldquo;Investment Practice,&rdquo; where the guru demonstrated how to invest in stocks, real estate, and other assets.  He then asked, &ldquo;Do you understand?&rdquo; They all replied, &ldquo;Yes!&rdquo; The guru said, &ldquo;Congratulations, you&rsquo;ve graduated!&rdquo;  The group rejoiced and returned to their jobs.</p>
<p>Decades later, at a reunion, they complained, &ldquo;Is there any way to make good money? Why do we always have to work so hard?&rdquo; They revisited the guru, who asked, &ldquo;Where did you put your earnings?&rdquo;  They answered, &ldquo;In bank savings accounts.&rdquo;</p>
<p>This story illustrates that education can change thinking but not necessarily behavior. <strong>Possessing knowledge and wisdom without action is no different from lacking them; you&rsquo;ll still rely on physical labor and skills for a living.</strong>  Wisdom without action is useless; one must be willing to act.</p>
<p>A survey of wealthy Americans revealed that one of their key traits is &ldquo;proactive action.&rdquo; In other words, financial success depends on what we do, not what we know.</p>
<p>Investment professors sometimes face student skepticism: &ldquo;If you know so much, why aren&rsquo;t you rich from investing?&rdquo;  A common response is, &ldquo;A teacher&rsquo;s duty is to impart knowledge, not necessarily to practice it. Just like the best coach isn&rsquo;t always the best athlete.&rdquo;</p>
<p>I often ponder this: Many teachers desire wealth.  Wealth accumulation and educating the next generation aren&rsquo;t mutually exclusive.  Why don&rsquo;t most investment professors, armed with financial knowledge, become wealthy?</p>
<p>Another common question is: &ldquo;Some uneducated, idle speculators get rich through investing without ever taking an investment course. How?&rdquo; The difference between professors and these speculators is simple: some professors know but don&rsquo;t act, while speculators act but don&rsquo;t necessarily know.  Financial knowledge alone doesn&rsquo;t guarantee wealth; action is key.</p>
<p><strong>Action is the Key to Investment Success</strong></p>
<p>Can investment skills be taught? No.  True skill comes from practice.  I often compare investing to ice skating, swimming, or cycling.  Can reading books on &ldquo;How to Ice Skate&rdquo; make you a skater? The best teacher is experience  falling hundreds of times, getting back up, and persevering.</p>
<p>Fear is the biggest obstacle to learning about investing.  A student once asked, &ldquo;What if I lose all my money before I learn how to invest?&rdquo;  I countered, &ldquo;Did you study fluid dynamics before learning to ride a bike, fearing you&rsquo;d crash before mastering it?&rdquo; Investors must understand that even extensive reading won&rsquo;t prevent losses; just like a perfect score in fluid dynamics doesn&rsquo;t guarantee perfect cycling.</p>
<p>Practice and experience are essential for practical skills.  Investing can&rsquo;t be taught. The key is to step away from books, enter the market, experiment, make mistakes, and learn from them.  Start small with a limited amount of money.</p>
<p>Achieving wealth through investing involves two stages: 1) acquiring correct investment knowledge, and 2) continuous practice and action. Both are essential.  Reading this book and understanding the principles is just the first step.</p>
<p><strong>Knowledge Becomes Power Through Action</strong></p>
<p>Knowledge is potential power.  Only through absorption, internalization, and action does it become real power.  &ldquo;Knowledge is power&rdquo; needs amending.</p>
<p>Correct understanding alone is insufficient.  Achieving wealth requires consistent action and practice. Otherwise, knowledge remains theoretical.  Investing is a skill honed through constant practice, like entrepreneur Wang Yung-ching, who continued massive investments in his 70s.</p>
<p><strong>We instinctively avoid risk; it&rsquo;s uncomfortable.  But investing for wealth requires calculated risks, learned through experience.</strong> Dear reader, action is paramount. Initial fear and anxiety are natural. The best way to overcome them is to act.</p>
<p><em>1. Those who put ideas and methods into action possess a competitive edge and grasp the opportunity for success.</em></p>
<p><em>2. In today&rsquo;s knowledge-rich world, the biggest obstacle to success is not knowing what to do, but doing what we know.</em></p>
<p><em>3. Many excel at thinking, analyzing, and identifying opportunities, but few act upon them.</em></p>
<p><strong>A Farmer Outperforms Market Veterans</strong></p>
<p>In early 1996, amid cross-strait tensions, Taiwan&rsquo;s stock market slumped. A farmer walked into a brokerage, placed a bag of cash (around 3-4 million NTD) on the counter, and said, &ldquo;I want to buy San Shang Yin.&rdquo;</p>
<p>The clerk, baffled, asked for his account number, which stock he wanted (San Shang Yin refers to three different bank stocks), and his desired price. He knew none of this, saying only, &ldquo;My friend said San Shang Yin is good. Here&rsquo;s the money.&rdquo;</p>
<p>The clerk explained the situation, helped him open an account, and bought 10 shares of each bank stock at around 90 NTD. Two months later, the prices rose to 160 NTD.</p>
<p>This farmer, lacking knowledge but daring to act, profited.  Meanwhile, market experts who thoroughly analyzed San Shang Yin missed out because they hesitated to act.</p>
<p>Does knowledge or action bring wealth? The farmer&rsquo;s lack of knowledge might have been his advantage, while overthinking paralyzed the experts. How much do analysis and knowledge truly contribute to wealth creation? It&rsquo;s worth pondering.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Active action makes dreams come true.  A strong desire for wealth fuels action.</p></blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">Your Future Wealth is in Your Hands 
    <div id="your-future-wealth-is-in-your-hands" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#your-future-wealth-is-in-your-hands" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>Many attendees at my seminars nod in agreement but fail to act. Remember, action, not knowledge, determines your future.  This book is useless unless you act upon it.</p>
<p><strong>Dreams Alone Won&rsquo;t Make You Rich</strong></p>
<p>Many dream of wealth, but few succeed.  It&rsquo;s not luck or intelligence, but the unity of thought and action. Success and wealth are earned through planning, action, and consistent effort.</p>
<p>For most, wealth is a fantasy. They think and talk, but don&rsquo;t act. Some lack the know-how, which is understandable.  Sadly, others know but don&rsquo;t act.  &ldquo;Knowing and not doing is not knowing.&rdquo;  Wealth won&rsquo;t come to those who only dream or accumulate knowledge without action.  People attribute wealth to luck, but does luck favor those dreaming at home or those actively seeking opportunities?</p>
<p>Reading this book won&rsquo;t magically make you rich.  Financial success depends on what we do.  We&rsquo;ve all seen seemingly unintelligent, not particularly hard-working, or frugal people who are wealthy.</p>
<p>The difference between self-made millionaires and us isn&rsquo;t intellect, effort, frugality, or knowledge, but where our money is placed.  They invest in high-return assets, while we often settle for low returns.  Most make excuses: not enough money, time, knowledge, or opportunity, or blaming age.  These are merely excuses preventing wealth accumulation.</p>
<p><em>1. The principles of financial management are simple; the difficulty lies in overcoming fear, greed, and laziness to do what we know we should.</em></p>
<p><em>2. Investing is an art and a science, but more art.  The best way to learn is by doing.</em></p>
<p><em>3. Without putting money to work, you&rsquo;ll rely on physical labor and skills your entire life.</em></p>
<p><strong>The First Step: Open a Brokerage Account and Buy Stocks</strong></p>
<p>An elderly British writer lamented, &ldquo;I&rsquo;ve seen many talented young people remain obscure, their potential unfulfilled because they lacked the courage to try.  Guidance and encouragement to take risks could have unleashed their talents and benefited society.&rdquo;</p>
<p>Over 13% of seniors in Taiwan rely on continued work or family support.  Many ended up this way because they didn&rsquo;t invest in risky assets like stocks or real estate in their youth.  Had they been guided to invest wisely, they could be enjoying retirement, reducing social inequality and promoting harmony.</p>
<p>Inspired by this writer, I now encourage my students to open brokerage accounts and buy stocks (or closed-end funds if unsure) on the first day of my investment courses.  I advise them to hold long-term, regardless of price fluctuations, aiming for practical experience over theoretical knowledge.</p>
<p><strong>Paying for Experience</strong></p>
<p>In 1983, while pursuing my PhD at UC Berkeley, a Wall Street analyst lectured at the university.  I asked him for book recommendations on stock investing.  He advised, &ldquo;The best way to learn is to invest. You&rsquo;ll learn more from one real investment than from several books.&rdquo; I followed his advice, lost money, and learned valuable lessons that shaped my future investment approach.</p>
<p>Financial management can&rsquo;t be learned solely in the classroom. Can attending ten lectures on swimming theory and reading ten books on &ldquo;Swimming Secrets&rdquo; make you a swimmer?  The first step is to get in the water.  Taiwan&rsquo;s education system overemphasizes book learning and neglects practical experience.</p>
<p>What&rsquo;s the first step in learning to invest?  Some suggest reading books, subscribing to financial magazines, or taking courses.  My advice: after reading this book, invest a small amount in stocks or mutual funds (especially index funds) if unsure.</p>
<p>Mutual funds offer diversification and professional management, generally performing close to market averages, minimizing potential losses and discouraging fear.</p>
<p>Outperforming mutual funds through individual stock picking is challenging.  Fund managers have experience, expertise, and research teams.  Consider mutual funds, especially index funds like CTBC Harmony Fund or China 100 Fund, in the initial stages.  &ldquo;Beating the index&rdquo; is every fund manager&rsquo;s dream, but most admit it&rsquo;s incredibly difficult.  If so, mirroring the market through index funds is a viable strategy.</p>
<p><strong>If you have savings and don&rsquo;t own property, consider buying a home as your first investment.</strong></p>
<blockquote>
<p>We learn more from failure than from success.  Success is built upon countless failures.</p></blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">Learning from Mistakes 
    <div id="learning-from-mistakes" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#learning-from-mistakes" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>Successful American investors share two traits: 1) they don&rsquo;t strive for perfection, and 2) they don&rsquo;t dwell on failures, focusing instead on future challenges.  High returns come with high risks.  Failure is inevitable and part of the learning process. Most successful investors have experienced multiple failures.</p>
<p><strong>No Success Without Failure</strong></p>
<p>Anyone claiming to have never lost money in investing is either lying or has never invested.  It&rsquo;s like a baseball player claiming to have never missed a swing.  Even the best hitters don&rsquo;t have a 100% batting average.</p>
<p>A top baseball player once attributed his success to &ldquo;missing more swings than others.&rdquo; To achieve a high batting average, he must have swung and missed more times than others.  Biographies of successful people often reveal that they&rsquo;ve experienced more failures than those less successful.  Failure is the mother of success, especially in investing.</p>
<p>Aspiring investors must withstand losses.  <strong>Those who haven&rsquo;t failed can&rsquo;t achieve greatness; those who haven&rsquo;t experienced losses can&rsquo;t expect to make a fortune.</strong>  Demanding a perfect track record leads to extreme conservatism and eliminates opportunities for success.</p>
<p><strong>The biggest failure is to never fail.</strong>  Avoiding mistakes eliminates chances for success. The best path to success is through failure and learning from it.  Never forget your losses; they are the keys to victory.  Successful investors analyze failures, learn from them, and improve their strategies.</p>
<p><strong>Reflect and Restart</strong></p>
<p>My failures have led to reflection, reassessment, and improved investment strategies.  Most failures bring unexpected benefits.  Treat failure as a necessary lesson, and your courage will grow.</p>
<p>Failure can&rsquo;t be learned secondhand.  You won&rsquo;t find books on &ldquo;How to Lose 10 Million in Investments.&rdquo;  People brag about successes, not failures.  Therefore, lessons from failure must come from personal experience.</p>
<p>Everyone makes mistakes in investing.  Even correct decisions can lead to losses.  Since losses and failures are inevitable, accepting them and learning from them is crucial.  Failure is not shameful or terrifying.  Face it, overcome it, and success will follow.</p>
<p><em>1. Take calculated risks for high rewards, be prepared for losses, and avoid undue self-blame.</em></p>
<p><em>2. Learn from every failure, identify flawed decision-making habits, and avoid repeating them.</em></p>
<p><em>3. Study valuable lessons from failures and discover opportunities for wealth creation.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Personal Investment Bible: Investment Iron Law X</title>
      <link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1731056005969/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1731056005969/</guid>
      <description>This article introduces three stock investment strategies: value investing, growth investing, and contrarian investing. Value investing emphasizes buying stocks when the price is below their intrinsic value and selling when the price is above. Growth investing focuses on the future earnings growth potential of companies, selecting companies with sustained high growth for investment. Contrarian investing suggests going against the general market sentiment, being greedy when others are fearful, and fearful when others are greedy.  The article analyzes the advantages, disadvantages, and suitability of each strategy, pointing out that although these three strategies are theoretically effective, they are difficult to implement in practice.  Ordinary investors are more suited to adopt a long-term buy-and-hold strategy of &amp;#34;buy any stock, buy at any time, and don&amp;#39;t sell.&amp;#34;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[

<h2 class="relative group">Investment Iron Law X: Mastering the Tools of Stock Market Offense and Defense 
    <div id="investment-iron-law-x-mastering-the-tools-of-stock-market-offense-and-defense" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#investment-iron-law-x-mastering-the-tools-of-stock-market-offense-and-defense" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>Buy when Value is higher than Price.
Sell when Value is lower than Price.</p></blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">Value Investing 
    <div id="value-investing" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#value-investing" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>The strategy of &ldquo;buy any stock, buy at any time, and don&rsquo;t sell&rdquo; sounds simple, but most people can&rsquo;t follow it. Even if they acknowledge its potential for wealth creation, they lack the courage to implement it because it seems to contradict common investment beliefs and principles. Therefore, the author presents three superior investment strategies: value investing, growth investing, and contrarian investing. Before investing, using these strategies, you must ask yourself: Does the investment target hold this value? What is its future growth potential? Is everyone investing in it? These three investment strategies can help you make better decisions.</p>
<p><strong>Verifying Value Ensures Profitability</strong></p>
<p>During the 1920s, Florida&rsquo;s real estate prices skyrocketed daily, triggering a buying frenzy. One fortunate investor managed to secure a plot of land. Most buyers didn&rsquo;t care about the land&rsquo;s quality, but this investor prudently asked a real estate agent to show him the purchased land. He was shocked to discover it was swampland.  &ldquo;Can anyone live here?&rdquo; he exclaimed. The agent calmly replied, &ldquo;Why worry about that? As long as the price goes up.&rdquo;</p>
<p>&ldquo;Human behavior and decision-making are perfectly rational&rdquo; is a fundamental assumption in academic research and theoretical development. Generally, consumers won&rsquo;t rush to buy unless a product offers exceptional value. For instance, no one would pay $5 million for a car worth $500,000 unless they were foolish. Investment decisions, involving money and future wealth, are even more critical than buying a car. Logically, people should be more rational and cautious, making decisions only after careful calculations.</p>
<p>However, are investors truly rational?  In July 1985, China Development Corporation&rsquo;s stock price was NT$14 per share. Four years later, in September 1989, it reached NT$1075, a nearly 80-fold increase.  Remarkably, in 1985, when the price was low, investors shunned the stock, resulting in low trading volume. Conversely, in 1989, when the price soared to over NT$1000, investors rushed in, fearing they would miss out, driving trading volume to its peak.</p>
<p>Are these investment behaviors rational?  Consider the difference between China Development Corporation at NT$14 in 1985, at over NT$1000 in 1989, or even at NT$50 in 1983.  Essentially, the difference was minimal; it was the same company, managed by practically the same people, with similar assets. Why such a drastic price difference? The answer lies not in the company&rsquo;s intrinsic changes but in investors&rsquo; behavioral and decision-making biases.</p>
<p>Between 1989 and 1990, during the Taiwan stock market&rsquo;s peak, investors continued pouring in. The author often asked friends and family, &ldquo;Do you think the stocks you&rsquo;re buying are worth the price?&rdquo;  Most found the question perplexing and avoided answering. Some reluctantly admitted, &ldquo;Probably not.&rdquo;  The author would then ask, &ldquo;Why buy them then?&rdquo;  Their confident reply: &ldquo;They&rsquo;ll go up!&rdquo;</p>
<p>Some also questioned the author&rsquo;s lack of participation in this lucrative market.  The response: &ldquo;I&rsquo;ll wait until after 4000 points to invest.&rdquo; The author believed the Taiwan stock market&rsquo;s true value was below 4000 points (in 1989).  Those who heard this scoffed, &ldquo;Keep waiting.&rdquo;  As it turned out, overvalued assets cannot rise indefinitely. In August 1990, the Taiwan stock index plummeted to around 2000 points, proving the author&rsquo;s point.  No investment&rsquo;s price can remain perpetually above or below its true value.</p>
<p><strong>Buy When Value Exceeds Price</strong></p>
<p>Value investing, introduced by Benjamin Graham in his 1933 book <em>Security Analysis</em>, was later championed by his students, including Warren Buffett and John Templeton.  In the 1980s, value investing gained prominence in the US, becoming the strategy of choice for many successful long-term investors.</p>
<p>Value investing posits that every stock has an intrinsic value.  Price fluctuations arise from investor trading.  Prices exceeding intrinsic value will eventually revert, and prices falling below will eventually recover.</p>
<p>The principle is simple: buy when the value is higher than the price, regardless of market fluctuations.  If it&rsquo;s cheap, buy it. Conversely, sell when the value is lower than the price.  In short, buy low, sell high.  Sell when prices significantly exceed value amidst widespread buying, minimizing holdings. Buy when prices fall drastically below value amidst widespread fear, increasing holdings.</p>
<p>Typically, investors focus solely on price appreciation, neglecting value.  People meticulously research cars, refrigerators, or stereos for months, comparing models, reading reviews, and seeking advice, constantly evaluating value for money.  They&rsquo;ll wait for a sale if the price is too high.  Yet, when buying stocks, often on a whim based on a tip or hearsay, they overlook value, making hasty decisions involving sums far exceeding appliance purchases.</p>
<p><strong>Invest with an Owner&rsquo;s Mindset</strong></p>
<p>Warren Buffett&rsquo;s investment philosophy emphasizes investing with an owner&rsquo;s mindset and a long-term perspective. This involves buying stocks of companies with stable earnings growth, positive prospects, high asset value, or simply when the intrinsic value exceeds the price.</p>
<p>Crowds flock to department stores during sales and clearances. The steeper the discounts, the larger the crowds.  Conversely, shopping is most pleasant when there are no sales, as stores are less crowded.  This is because consumers are motivated by value, buying when prices are below perceived worth.</p>
<p>However, in stock markets, the opposite occurs. Brokerage houses are deserted when stock prices are at their lowest.  Conversely, they are packed when prices are soaring. Investors are motivated by rising prices.  A stock falling from $100 to $50 attracts little interest, while rapid price increases fuel buying frenzy.</p>
<p>The assumption of rational economic behavior applies well to consumer choices but not to investment behavior.  As illustrated, investment decisions are often driven by irrational emotions, impulses, and intuition.</p>
<p>Value investing advises emulating consumer behavior: buy when stocks are &ldquo;on sale,&rdquo; and avoid the herd when prices are inflated.</p>
<p><strong>Developing the Ability to Calculate Asset and Earnings Value</strong></p>
<p>The key to successful value investing is the ability to calculate a company&rsquo;s intrinsic value, encompassing asset value and earnings value.  Asset value represents the liquidation value of the company&rsquo;s assets per share. Earnings value represents the present value of the company&rsquo;s projected future earnings.  Estimating future earnings is challenging, requiring the development of forecasting skills.</p>
<p>Calculating intrinsic value is not easy.  Investing in familiar companies simplifies this process.  Taiwanese businesswoman Shirley Wang, CEO of FIC Global, primarily invested in FIC and related IT and semiconductor companies.  Her familiarity with the industry allowed her to better grasp its dynamics.</p>
<p>Many successful investors adhere to Buffett&rsquo;s philosophy, investing only in familiar companies.  Li-Ching Hsu, former Taiwan head of ING Group, frequently advised investors to focus on companies in their own industry or related sectors.</p>
<p>Investment decisions should always involve value analysis. Buy when the value is present or the price is attractive; sell otherwise.  Value investing encourages adopting consumer-like behavior in the stock market, buying low and selling high.</p>
<p><em>1. When investing in stocks, ask &ldquo;Is it worth buying?&rdquo; not just &ldquo;Will it go up?&rdquo;</em></p>
<p><em>2.  Learn from consumer behavior: buy when prices are discounted.</em></p>
<blockquote>
<p>Choose a great company, and if it keeps growing, you&rsquo;ll almost never have to sell.</p></blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">Growth Investing 
    <div id="growth-investing" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#growth-investing" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>Valuing a company is challenging.  Some professional investors therefore focus on earnings growth rate, a primary driver of value, as their investment criterion. Growth investing has been successfully employed by renowned investors, notably Peter Lynch, former manager of Fidelity&rsquo;s Magellan Fund, who achieved the highest 15-year return among hundreds of US mutual funds.</p>
<p><strong>Investing in High-Growth Potential Stocks</strong></p>
<p>Simply put, growth investing involves buying stocks of companies with high future growth potential and selling when that potential diminishes.  A key characteristic is maintaining full investment, ideally diversified.  Growth investors acknowledge their inability to predict short-term market movements but believe in the long-term upward trend of stocks, especially those with high growth potential.</p>
<p>They invest all their capital in high-growth stocks.  Peter Lynch maintained a nearly 100% invested portfolio during his tenure at Magellan Fund, keeping minimal cash reserves for redemptions.</p>
<p>The key to successful growth investing lies in identifying companies with high growth potential.  This is the challenge: finding high-growth stocks.  Investing in IBM 30 years ago, Microsoft 15 years ago, or Cathay Life Insurance in Taiwan would have yielded multifold returns.</p>
<p>However, countless seemingly high-growth companies fizzle out. No one can predict the future with certainty. Even Peter Lynch admitted that only half of his stock picks were truly successful, but that was enough.  Therefore, diversification is crucial for mitigating the higher risks of growth investing.</p>
<p>Growth investing believes that a company&rsquo;s real growth drives stock price appreciation.  Investment returns depend on the earnings over the next few years. For high returns, choose investments with 5-10 year growth potential. Invest in companies in high-growth industries with excellent performance and a sustainable growth outlook. Their stock prices are likely to rise with the company&rsquo;s growth, offering substantial long-term gains.</p>
<p><strong>Choosing the Right Industry is More Important Than Choosing the Right Company</strong></p>
<p>Growth investors prioritize future earnings growth potential.  Industry growth is crucial for a company&rsquo;s earnings.  Choosing the right industry is therefore more important than choosing the right company.  Consider the future 5-10 year demand for the company&rsquo;s products, focusing on the industry&rsquo;s growth potential. Peter Lynch advised against selling good stocks prematurely for small profits and recommended selling stocks of companies with deteriorating growth prospects, even at a loss.  This approach allows gains from successful picks to offset losses from unsuccessful ones, resulting in overall profit.</p>
<p>Peter Lynch advocated for a &ldquo;common sense&rdquo; approach to investing, illustrated in his book <em>One Up On Wall Street</em>. He profited from observing his wife&rsquo;s preference for certain hosiery and dish soap brands, and his children&rsquo;s preference for certain sneakers, leading him to invest in those companies.  This approach can be explained by market efficiency theory.  Retailers and observant consumers are often the first to notice a product&rsquo;s popularity, before analysts.  By adopting a consumer perspective and noticing trends overlooked by experts, investors can gain an edge.</p>
<p>In early 1996, after a frugal, retired court clerk passed away, her family discovered her substantial wealth. She had consistently invested small amounts in Coca-Cola stock for decades, capitalizing on its growth and share price appreciation. This illustrates the power of long-term investment in growing companies.</p>
<p><strong>Don&rsquo;t Just Focus on Price Fluctuations</strong></p>
<p>Many investors are unclear about their investment rationale.  If you can&rsquo;t explain your investment&rsquo;s business and growth potential in five minutes, you shouldn&rsquo;t own it.  Focus on monitoring the validity of your investment thesis, not daily price fluctuations.</p>
<p>Many investors prefer startups or pre-IPO companies. However, established, profitable companies with growth potential are often better investments. Peter Lynch suggested capturing the middle five years of a company&rsquo;s 15-year growth trajectory, rather than the initial or mature phases.  If a stock has the potential to rise from $2 to $200, wait until it reaches $8 before buying. The potential gains are still substantial, and the risk is lower.  Losing money in the stock market is quick, but making money takes time. Most stocks take 3-5 years to rise significantly.</p>
<p>Regarding industry growth potential, in Taiwan, IT, communications, and semiconductors within the electronics industry are promising. Pharmaceuticals and biotechnology are also attractive due to increasing health consciousness. Taiwan&rsquo;s ten emerging industries (specialty chemicals, environmental protection, aerospace, telecommunications, semiconductors, IT, pharmaceuticals, precision machinery, etc.) offer future growth opportunities.  In the service sector, securities and investment trust, construction, and shipping also have good prospects.  <strong>Savvy investors should anticipate future trends, popular products, internet-driven products, and leverage their own consumer insights to identify investment opportunities.</strong></p>
<p>Growth investing is suitable for non-professional investors.  It requires no specialized training or constant monitoring.  To identify growth stocks, consider a company&rsquo;s potential performance over the next 5-10 years. Invest in companies with strong growth potential and hold them long-term, selling only when they transition from growth to maturity.  This strategy allows even amateur investors with limited time and expertise to achieve good results.</p>
<p><em>1. Real earnings growth drives stock price appreciation.</em></p>
<p><em>2. Diversify investments in companies with sustainable 5-10 year growth potential, patiently awaiting substantial returns.</em></p>
<blockquote>
<p>Don&rsquo;t follow the crowd; be rational. Figure out what most people are doing, then don&rsquo;t do it.</p></blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">Contrarian Investing 
    <div id="contrarian-investing" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#contrarian-investing" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>Many ask, &ldquo;Is there a better time to buy than &lsquo;any time&rsquo;?&rdquo; Research suggests there is: contrarian investing, a time-tested and remarkably effective strategy.</p>
<p><strong>Buy Straw Hats in Winter, Boats in a Drought</strong></p>
<p>A 19th-century American tycoon, when asked about his wealth-building secret, replied, &ldquo;Buy straw hats in winter.&rdquo;  Similarly, Fan Li, a wealthy merchant in ancient China, followed the principle of &ldquo;buying fur coats in summer, selling in winter; buying boats in a drought, selling when it rains.&rdquo;  These are examples of contrarian investing.</p>
<p>This investment concept originated in ancient China. According to <em>Records of the Grand Historian</em>, Ji Ran, an economist during the Warring States period, proposed the contrarian strategy of &ldquo;invest in boats during drought, invest in carts during floods.&rdquo;  He argued that during droughts, when everyone invests in cart production, one should invest in boats.  The oversupply of carts would lower prices and profits.  When the rains return, boat demand would surge, raising prices and profits.  Conversely, during floods, when everyone invests in boats, one should invest in carts.</p>
<p>Contrarian investing means investing when most people aren&rsquo;t and selling when everyone is eager to buy.  The concept is simple: go against the crowd.  However, implementing it is challenging. It requires overcoming human nature, resisting herd mentality, cultivating independent judgment, and enduring loneliness. Most investors follow the crowd, while contrarian investors look for opportunities when others are fearful.  This strategy relies on the belief that widespread consensus is often wrong and that reversals can be powerful.</p>
<p><strong>Don&rsquo;t Be Deceived by Net Buying or Selling</strong></p>
<p>Contrarian investing works because when most people are bullish, available capital is already invested, leading to overinflated prices.  With everyone already in the market, poised to sell, potential supply outweighs demand. Any negative news can trigger a sharp decline.</p>
<p>Conversely, when most people are bearish, selling pressure is minimal as most have already sold.  With potential buyers waiting on the sidelines, demand outweighs supply.  Any positive news can trigger a sharp rise.</p>
<p>Investors tend to extrapolate past trends, especially when reinforced by market sentiment. During initial market declines, most see it as temporary, while a few predict further declines. As the market continues falling, bears are rewarded, and bulls suffer.  At severely oversold levels, widespread pessimism creates buying opportunities.  Conversely, during initial market rallies, most see it as temporary, while a few predict further gains. As the market continues rising, bulls are rewarded, and bears suffer. At severely overbought levels, widespread optimism leads to overvaluation.</p>
<p><strong>Bullish When Rising, Bearish When Falling</strong></p>
<p>People tend to become more optimistic during optimistic periods and more pessimistic during pessimistic periods.  They rely on memory to predict the future.  A rising market breeds bullishness, and a falling market breeds bearishness.</p>
<p>At the peak of the Taiwan stock market in late 1989, the author taught an investment course. During one lecture, a student requested the author refrain from discussing stocks.  Surprised, the author asked why. The student explained that every class, from political science to calculus, included discussions about stocks.</p>
<p>Another anecdote from that period involves a professor asking his class the time. A student instinctively replied, &ldquo;9865 points, up 65 points.&rdquo;  Students were constantly monitoring stock prices during lectures. This illustrates the pervasive stock market mania at the time.  As it turned out, this widespread obsession was a harbinger of the impending crash.</p>
<p><strong>Great investments often involve defying conventional wisdom, selling when others are buying, and buying when others are selling.  Be bearish before others when everyone is bullish, and be bullish before others when everyone is bearish. As a Wall Street adage goes, &ldquo;Markets are born in despair, grow in skepticism, mature in optimism, and die in euphoria.&rdquo;</strong></p>
<p>Contrarian investing doesn&rsquo;t require constantly opposing the majority. It encourages resisting herd mentality and cultivating independent thinking.  The best buying opportunities may arise when most are afraid to buy, but buying solely for that reason is as foolish as following the crowd. The crowd isn&rsquo;t always wrong.  Develop independent judgment.  True contrarians don&rsquo;t blindly oppose the majority but wait for the dust to settle and buy when no one is paying attention.</p>
<p>Contrarian investing applies to stock selection. David Dreman, in his book <em>Contrarian Investment Strategies</em>, argued that unpopular companies often outperform expectations, while popular companies are susceptible to minor setbacks.</p>
<p>Timing the market is difficult. Mastering the principles of contrarian investing can be highly rewarding.</p>
<p><em>1. Invest when others aren&rsquo;t; sell when everyone is eager to invest.</em></p>
<p><em>2. Don&rsquo;t follow the crowd; buy when investor sentiment has cooled and no one is paying attention.</em></p>
<p><strong>Value, Growth, and Contrarian Strategies are Best Suited for Experts</strong></p>
<p>These seemingly disparate strategies are not mutually exclusive. Investors can choose or combine strategies based on their individual characteristics.  The most effective strategy is subjective and depends on individual circumstances. The author recommends value investing for those skilled in financial analysis, growth investing for those with foresight, and contrarian investing for independent, emotionally disciplined individuals.</p>
<p>Value investing is considered the most sophisticated technique, requiring strong financial knowledge and valuation skills. Most investors lack this expertise. Even among analysts, few truly understand valuation.  Growth investing requires foresight to identify high-growth industries and companies, which is also challenging.  Contrarian investing requires no specialized knowledge but is the hardest to implement due to its counterintuitive nature.  Most people are trend followers. Few can buy when everyone is selling or sell when everyone is buying.</p>
<p>These three strategies can enhance returns if mastered and applied correctly.  Countless self-proclaimed &ldquo;investment experts&rdquo; populate the market, but few consistently outperform using these strategies.  Misapplied, these strategies can lead to short-term speculation and losses.  Therefore, the author still recommends the simple, yet effective, long-term buy-and-hold strategy of &ldquo;buy any stock, buy at any time, and don&rsquo;t sell&rdquo; for most investors.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Personal Investment Bible: Investment Iron Law XI</title>
      <link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1731056005970/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1731056005970/</guid>
      <description>This article explains why short-term stock trading should be avoided. The core argument is that long-term holding is the key to gaining returns from the stock market.  It analyzes the disadvantages of short-term trading, including high transaction costs, profits being taken by market makers and large investors, and investment failures caused by human weaknesses. The article emphasizes that the primary source of profit from stock investment is the company&amp;#39;s earnings, not price fluctuations. It advises investors to adopt a buy-and-hold strategy of buy any stock, buy anytime, don&amp;#39;t sell to truly benefit from the stock market.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[

<h2 class="relative group">Investment Iron Law XI: Avoid Short-Term Trading 
    <div id="investment-iron-law-xi-avoid-short-term-trading" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#investment-iron-law-xi-avoid-short-term-trading" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>The greatest enemy of investment activity is human weakness: greed, fear, and herd mentality.</p></blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">The Pitfalls of Buying Low and Selling High 
    <div id="the-pitfalls-of-buying-low-and-selling-high" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#the-pitfalls-of-buying-low-and-selling-high" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>Stock prices fluctuate in the short term, leading many investors to intuitively believe that profits can be made by simply &ldquo;buying low and selling high.&rdquo; Undeniably, the allure of price differences is strong. A limit-up day can bring thousands of dollars in profit, and buying ten lots could cover a month&rsquo;s salary. However, once captivated by this temptation and engaging in the game of short-term trading, you unknowingly enter a losing battle. While luck might bring short-term gains, long-term losses are inevitable.</p>
<p><strong>Stock Profits Are More Than Just Price Differences</strong></p>
<p>Many stock investors hold the misconception that profits come solely from price fluctuations. In reality, the primary source of profit lies in sharing the company&rsquo;s earnings, not capitalizing on short-term price swings. Stock investments generate returns because the invested companies&rsquo; earnings are ultimately distributed to investors.  The immense time and effort spent researching entry and exit points, diligently watching the market, and constantly chasing trends contribute nothing to the company&rsquo;s earnings.</p>
<p>The Taiwan Weighted Stock Index rose from 100 points in early 1967 to 6200 points at the end of August 1996, a 62-fold increase.  Using the end of 1986 as a base period, when the index was around 700 points, the rise to 6200 points by the end of August 1996 represents an increase of over 8 times. The Taiwan stock market&rsquo;s astonishing growth and substantial returns should have made every investor wealthy.  However, the reality is quite the opposite. Few Taiwanese investors have profited from stocks, while countless have suffered losses. According to a 1988 survey by Professor Lin Quanyuan, 27% of investors experienced losses, and 78% earned returns below the market average.  Private surveys suggest even higher loss rates.  The question arises: &ldquo;Where did the substantial stock market profits go?&rdquo;</p>
<p><strong>Short-Term Trading is Gambling</strong></p>
<p>Short-term stock trading is speculation and gambling, both characterized by a high probability of loss. We often see short-term traders boastful after successful speculations but disappear or remain silent after losses. This creates the false impression that short-term trading is profitable. In truth, these traders usually end up losing money.</p>
<p>Long-term stock holding yields an average annual return of over 15%, but only if the stocks are held and not sold. The biggest problem with short-term trading is the transaction costs incurred with each trade.  Investors often overlook these costs, believing they are insignificant compared to potential price differences. In the Taiwanese securities market, the transaction cost for each round trip (buy and sell) is approximately 0.6% of the transaction amount. While a single transaction cost seems small, the cumulative effect is substantial. Imagine trading more than 25 times a year, or every two weeks. The 15% annual return would be almost entirely eroded, making it worse than keeping the money in a bank.  Moreover, short-term traders often exceed 25 trades per year.  Factor in a few losses, and the return becomes negative.  Frequent trading inevitably diminishes returns, and negative returns are no different from gambling.</p>
<p>Therefore, if you cannot resist the urge to chase short-term price differences, it&rsquo;s best to avoid stock investment altogether and keep your money in the bank.  While you may not become rich, it&rsquo;s better than losing it all in the stock market.</p>
<p>In 1989, the total after-tax earnings of all listed companies in Taiwan were 110.3 billion NTD.  In the same year, securities transaction taxes were 152.4 billion NTD, and transaction fees totaled 76.2 billion NTD. This means the combined earnings of listed companies were insufficient to cover these costs, leaving investors with an additional 118.3 billion NTD in transaction costs. It&rsquo;s no wonder most stock investors suffer losses. The solution is simple: adopt a long-term holding strategy and minimize unnecessary trading. Long-term stock market investment offers high returns and lower risk. By holding long term, there&rsquo;s no need for worry or fear, and wealth can be accumulated over one or two decades.</p>
<p><strong>Short-Term Trading Creates Wealth for Intermediaries</strong></p>
<p>To achieve investment success, one must overcome &ldquo;greed during market upswings and fear during downswings.&rdquo;</p>
<p>A book from the 1940s in the US, titled <em>Where Are the Customer&rsquo;s Yachts?</em>, tells the story of a stockbroker taking a major client to a marina. Pointing at the luxurious yachts, the broker says, &ldquo;These yachts belong to our firm&rsquo;s brokers.&rdquo; The client then asks, &ldquo;Are any of them owned by your clients?&rdquo; The broker is speechless, as none of the yachts belonged to clients. (Note: yachts were a status symbol of wealth in American society at that time).</p>
<p>It seems unlikely that valuable clients of brokerage firms would be wealthy. This story illustrates that while stock market profits are substantial, most are earned by intermediaries.  Those who frequently trade and generate significant profits for brokerage firms rarely become yacht owners themselves.</p>
<p>Merrill Lynch annually has a dozen or so brokers earning over a million dollars.  However, their truly valuable clients are not exceptionally wealthy individuals. Wealthy people are usually busy making money and don&rsquo;t have the time for frequent trading.  They wouldn&rsquo;t be considered valuable clients. Only those who constantly engage in short-term trading are the major contributors to transaction fees and the most loyal customers of brokerage firms.</p>
<p>In 1990, a scholar wrote a bestselling book on securities investment, earning about 1 million NTD.  He was overjoyed, as it was a considerable sum for a writer.  However, his friend at a brokerage firm mocked him, saying, &ldquo;Your three years of hard work only earned you the equivalent of one month&rsquo;s salary for a broker in our company.&rdquo;</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Retail investors, your name is weakness.</p></blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">A Losing Game 
    <div id="a-losing-game" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#a-losing-game" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>The stock market comprises four main participants: intermediaries, major shareholders, large investors, and retail investors. Intermediaries include brokerage firms, the government, and information providers like newspapers, magazines, financial channels, and software companies.  Regardless of market outcomes, intermediaries always profit, and their profits increase with trading volume and frequency. Major shareholders are company management or those with significant equity stakes.  They have ample capital, resources, and information, giving them a winning edge. Large investors have more capital than retail investors, affording them a higher probability of success.</p>
<p><strong>Intermediaries and Large Investors Are the Winners</strong></p>
<p>The original purpose of financial markets was to channel funds from the public to businesses, which then invest and share profits with investors.  However, based on the analysis above, listed companies&rsquo; earnings are insufficient to cover the costs of intermediaries, let alone distribute profits to retail investors. For retail investors to profit, they must outperform the other three players.  In short-term trading, retail investors face intermediaries who always win, major shareholders who are guaranteed to win, and large investors with a higher probability of winning.  In this game, retail investors have no chance.</p>
<p>Most short-term trading failures are attributed to lack of skill or bad luck. In reality, a calm analysis reveals a guaranteed losing game.</p>
<p><strong>How to Win Without Fighting</strong></p>
<p>As a retail investor, how can you navigate this game against major shareholders, intermediaries, and large investors? The simplest solution: &ldquo;Don&rsquo;t play!&rdquo;</p>
<p>Listed companies, on average, generate profits annually, and successful companies grow increasingly profitable.  Therefore, not investing idle funds means missing out on long-term gains. The &ldquo;don&rsquo;t play&rdquo; strategy doesn&rsquo;t advocate avoiding the stock market altogether. Instead, it encourages investing and then leaving it alone, minimizing short-term trading.</p>
<p>By consistently investing available funds and holding long-term, investors can benefit from both company earnings and overall economic growth. This long-term holding strategy, avoiding the trading game played by intermediaries and large investors, can dramatically shift the investment landscape.  If investors buy and hold, intermediaries and major shareholders lose their advantage.  Even with substantial capital and insider information, their attempts to manipulate prices won&rsquo;t lure disciplined retail investors into their traps, eliminating the disadvantage faced by smaller investors.  Major shareholders, large investors, and retail investors would then stand on equal footing, sharing the benefits of long-term market growth.</p>
<p>This &ldquo;immovable mountain&rdquo; strategy transforms retail investors&rsquo; disadvantage into an advantage, shifting the disadvantage to the other players, particularly intermediaries. If investors stop trading frequently, brokerage firms lose transaction fees, the government loses taxes, and financial information providers lose business.  With no one to &ldquo;feed&rdquo; them, they might be forced to become buy-and-hold investors themselves.</p>
<p><strong>The correct investment philosophy is to profit together, not to defeat others.</strong>  The truly intelligent strategy is to avoid the competition.  As Sun Tzu&rsquo;s <em>Art of War</em> states, &ldquo;The supreme art of war is to subdue the enemy without fighting.&rdquo;  The primary consideration in investment strategy should not be defeating others but maximizing profits.</p>
<p>How can everyone win? If every investor adopts the strategy presented in this book&ldquo;buy any stock, buy anytime, don&rsquo;t sell&rdquo;and adheres to this simple principle, a win-win situation for all can be achieved.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Futures markets make casinos pale in comparison.</p></blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">Avoid Futures and Margin Trading 
    <div id="avoid-futures-and-margin-trading" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#avoid-futures-and-margin-trading" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>In 1995, a single trader&rsquo;s mismanagement of futures trading resulted in a $1.1 billion loss, causing the collapse of Barings Bank, one of Britain&rsquo;s oldest banks. This is not an isolated incident. With the rise of derivative financial products like futures and margin trading (forex, bond margin trading, etc.), such incidents of company collapses or personal bankruptcies due to mismanagement have become increasingly common.  Several high-performing listed companies in Taiwan have also faced near-bankruptcy due to losses in futures or margin trading.</p>
<p><strong>Either Big Wins or Big Losses</strong></p>
<p>What makes futures and margin trading so dangerous?  The core issue is the margin trading system itself, which has a high degree of leverage, leading to either significant gains or devastating losses in the short term. The high risk also encourages frequent trading, often multiple times a day. These transaction costs, relative to the margin, are extremely high.  The combined effect of frequent trading and high transaction costs pushes the returns from futures and margin trading into significant negative territory.</p>
<p>A saying circulates in the US securities market: &ldquo;Futures markets make casinos pale in comparison.&rdquo;  In other words, futures markets are even more of a gamble than casinos. After paying substantial transaction costs to intermediaries, what profits are left for investors?  The author has extensively studied investment history across various countries and has personally participated in the securities market for over a decade.  I have never heard of any investor consistently profiting from long-term participation in futures or margin trading.  On the contrary, almost everyone I know involved in such activities has ultimately lost money.</p>
<p>The purpose of futures and margin trading markets is to provide hedging tools for businesses.  Individual investors rarely have such hedging needs.  For them, these markets become &ldquo;even more of a gamble than casinos&rdquo; due to the temptation of short-term trading. The author strongly advises readers to avoid futures and margin trading entirely. If reading this book leads you to stay away from these activities, then the book&rsquo;s price has already been repaid, and the author&rsquo;s efforts have been worthwhile.</p>
<p><strong>Often a Waste of Effort</strong></p>
<p>The biggest obstacle to successful financial management is not the difficulty of understanding but the difficulty of implementing what is understood.  The principles discussed above are easy to grasp, but understanding doesn&rsquo;t guarantee implementation.  In the volatile investment world, faced with fluctuating prices, investors are often tempted by greed to chase short-term gains or driven by fear to react to price swings. They unknowingly fall into the trap of short-term trading. While the process can be thrilling, it often ends in wasted effort. The true beneficiaries of this game are usually the brokerage firms and the major shareholders manipulating the stocks, leaving retail investors with losses.</p>
<p><strong>Many people invest in stocks not to build wealth but to prove their intelligence, knowledge, and predictive abilities to others.</strong> They constantly analyze and research, overemphasizing market trends and predictions. This leads to impatience, chasing rising prices and selling during dips, attempting to profit from short-term fluctuations.  However, this constant buying and selling consumes time, energy, and money in the form of hefty transaction costs, while also creating opportunities for major shareholders and large investors to manipulate stocks.  The ultimate result is often a waste of time and money. While knowledge and experience might increase, wealth does not.</p>
<p><strong>To succeed in the fast-paced and lucrative investment world, you must cultivate self-discipline.</strong> The secret to investment success lies not in knowledge or skill, nor in intelligence or luck, but in self-control. Your investment acumen allows your assets to generate returns, and your patience in long-term holding allows the power of compounding to take you to new levels of wealth. Before succumbing to the temptation of short-term trading, ask yourself: &ldquo;Which wealthy person achieved their fortune through continuous short-term trading?&rdquo; and &ldquo;Which successful stock market investor didn&rsquo;t rely on long-term holding?&rdquo;</p>
<p><strong>Temporary Glory Leads to Crushing Debt</strong></p>
<p>In the history of the Taiwan stock market, it&rsquo;s difficult to find examples of individuals who built wealth through short-term trading. There are many who gained fame through short-term speculation, like Lei Bolong, but they often ended up heavily in debt and even faced imprisonment.  This is not unique to Taiwan; the same holds true for the US stock market.  The author has studied renowned American investors and has never found a prominent figure whose strategy primarily involved short-term trading.  Long-term wealth accumulation through short-term trading is virtually unheard of.</p>
<p>Stock investment is a vital path to personal wealth creation and a crucial source of long-term capital for businesses. However, using the wrong approach can lead to financial ruin instead of prosperity. Listed companies issue stocks to raise capital, and if these funds are then misused in speculative games, it can be detrimental to individuals, society, and the nation.</p>
<p>Stockholders are company owners with the inherent rights to profit sharing and residual asset distribution.  Therefore, the company&rsquo;s profits will eventually be distributed to shareholders as dividends. With patience, the wealth generated by the company ultimately belongs to the investors.</p>
<p>Therefore, I urge all readers to avoid the game of short-term trading.  Throughout history, no renowned investor has achieved wealth through short-term speculation. Based on the author&rsquo;s observations, the vast majority of those who engage in short-term trading lose money, and many face financial ruin.</p>
<p><em>1. True profits come not from short-term trading skills but from the discipline of long-term holding.</em></p>
<p><em>2. In the long run, short-term traders inevitably lose. There are no exceptions.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Personal Investment Bible: Investment Iron Law I</title>
      <link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1731056005960/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1731056005960/</guid>
      <description>This article criticizes the traditional financial concept of saving money in the bank.  It points out that under inflation, low bank deposit interest rates struggle to withstand erosion from inflation, effectively resulting in the more you save, the less you have. This viewpoint is supported by examples from biblical stories, savings rate data, and the Nobel Prize Foundation&amp;#39;s case, encouraging readers to invest their funds in long-term, high-return investment tools like stocks and real estate to achieve wealth appreciation.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[

<h2 class="relative group">Investment Iron Law I: Don&rsquo;t Keep Your Money in the Bank 
    <div id="investment-iron-law-i-dont-keep-your-money-in-the-bank" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#investment-iron-law-i-dont-keep-your-money-in-the-bank" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>The vast majority of people who fail at financial management don&rsquo;t do so because they don&rsquo;t earn enough,
but because they put their assets in the wrong place.
Have you ever heard of anyone getting rich from bank savings?</p></blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">Saving Equals Wasting Resources 
    <div id="saving-equals-wasting-resources" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#saving-equals-wasting-resources" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>There&rsquo;s a parable in the Bible about financial stewardship. A landowner entrusted his property to three servants. He gave the first servant five units of money, the second two, and the third one. He told them to cherish and manage their wealth wisely, and he would return in a year to see how they had fared.</p>
<p><strong>Wasting Time and Money</strong></p>
<p>The first servant invested his money; the second bought raw materials and produced goods to sell; the third, for safety, buried his money under a tree. A year later, the landowner returned.  The first two servants had doubled their wealth, pleasing the landowner.  Only the third servant&rsquo;s money remained unchanged. He explained, &ldquo;Fearing loss through mismanagement, I kept the money safe. Today, I return it untouched.&rdquo;</p>
<p>The landowner was furious.  &ldquo;You lazy servant!&rdquo; he scolded. &ldquo;You didn&rsquo;t even try to utilize your wealth!&rdquo;  Wealth not utilized is wasted money and wasted potential. The third servant was rebuked not for misusing the money, nor for losing it through failed investments, but for keeping it &ldquo;safe&rdquo; and unproductive.</p>
<p>Keeping money in the bank is the most common approach to personal finance today, and also the biggest mistake people make.  Therefore, the first and most important financial rule this book offers is: <em>Don&rsquo;t keep your money in the bank.</em>  &ldquo;Bank&rdquo; here refers to post offices, commercial banks, and any other financial institution where money can be deposited.</p>
<p>Many believe that earning interest in a bank, benefiting from compound interest, constitutes sound financial planning. In reality, with inflation, the real rate of return is close to zero, meaning no real financial gain. Therefore, leaving money in the bank is equivalent to no financial management at all.</p>
<p>It&rsquo;s impossible to predict how much wealth each person will accumulate through financial management. The only certainty is that getting rich solely through bank savings is incredibly difficult.  Ask yourself, &ldquo;Have you ever heard of anyone getting rich purely from bank deposits?&rdquo;  Those who keep all their savings in the bank often find themselves not only failing to become wealthy in their old age but also struggling to maintain financial independence. Such stories are common.  Those who choose bank deposits as their primary financial management method do so primarily for safety. However, readers must understand:  <strong>&ldquo;Money in the bank is safest in the short term, but the most dangerous form of financial management in the long term.&rdquo;</strong></p>
<p><strong>Blind Spots in Personal Finance</strong></p>
<p><em>Most people manage their finances by keeping their money in the bank, so most people are not wealthy.</em></p>
<p>If accumulating immense wealth were as easy as the examples suggest, then most people over 65 today would be millionaires. However, this is far from reality.  Millionaires over 65 are few and far between, with many senior citizens facing financial hardship, relying on continued work or support from their children to make ends meet.</p>
<p>Surveys on the elderly in Taiwan reveal increasingly serious financial challenges for senior citizens.  Among approximately 1.48 million people aged 65 and above, about 13% rely on financial assistance from family and friends or social welfare.  This demonstrates a serious problem with most people&rsquo;s financial concepts and investment methods. How else could they reach old age not only without wealth but without even basic financial independence?</p>
<p>Taiwan&rsquo;s savings rate has historically been above 30%, currently hovering between 20% and 30%, consistently ranking among the highest globally. This indicates excellent performance in saving and budgeting. Consequently, we can deduce that flawed financial management is the primary reason for the lack of financial independence among ordinary people. To understand where they go wrong, we must first observe how they handle their assets. In various lectures, I often ask the audience, &ldquo;How are your assets stored?&rdquo;  The majority answer: &ldquo;In the bank.&rdquo;</p>
<p><strong>Prioritizing Security over Investment</strong></p>
<p>Surveys on Taiwanese household investment preferences reveal that the top three investment choices are demand deposits (72%), rotating savings and credit associations (53%), and time deposits (36%). Clearly, most people lean towards traditional financial methods.  Furthermore, when asked, &ldquo;If you had 10 million Taiwan dollars in savings, how would you use it?&rdquo;, about 41% of surveyed households said they would deposit it in a financial institution to earn interest. This illustrates the widespread preference for bank savings.</p>
<p>Indeed, people have high savings rates and a strong preference for depositing money in financial institutions to earn interest.  In early 1996, total deposits in Taiwanese financial institutions reached 12.6 trillion Taiwan dollars.  With a population of 21 million, this translates to an average deposit of 600,000 Taiwan dollars per person, regardless of age.  For an average family of four, this amounts to 2.4 million Taiwan dollars.  This demonstrates a strong inclination towards bank savings. However, this traditional and conservative approach is the primary reason why most people fail to achieve wealth through investment.</p>
<p>This phenomenon reveals an over-reliance on traditional bank deposits for financial management. People prioritize safety and convenience over the rate of return. However, focusing solely on earning and saving money, then depositing it in a bank, is often the first step towards financial mismanagement.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Keeping money in the bank is like having no financial plan at all.</p></blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">Deposit Interest Rates Lack True Compound Interest Benefits 
    <div id="deposit-interest-rates-lack-true-compound-interest-benefits" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#deposit-interest-rates-lack-true-compound-interest-benefits" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>What&rsquo;s wrong with bank deposits? The problem lies in the low interest rates (return on investment), making them unsuitable for long-term investment tools.</p>
<p>How much interest can bank deposits earn?  The salaries of average office workers are usually directly deposited into demand deposit accounts (current interest rates around 2%-4%). A portion serves as temporary funds or covers daily expenses, while the remainder is transferred to time deposits (current interest rates around 5%-8%) for investment purposes. Thus, the average interest rate earned on bank deposits is about 5%.</p>
<p><strong>5% Interest is Hardly a Path to Wealth</strong></p>
<p>Most people have a basic understanding of compound interest, believing that interest earned on bank deposits, accumulating over time, can create substantial wealth. This misconception arises from a superficial understanding of compounding.  The vast differences in final returns resulting from different rates of return on the same principal over the same period often come as a surprise.</p>
<p>Let&rsquo;s illustrate with an example. Suppose someone saves 14,000 Taiwan dollars annually at the end of each year for 40 years, depositing everything into a bank account with an average interest rate of 5%. How much will they accumulate after 40 years? Before answering, recall the similar example from the previous section, but with the money in a bank instead of invested in stocks or real estate with an average annual return of 20%.</p>
<p>You might guess 25 million, 10 million, or even a conservative 5 million Taiwan dollars.  The correct answer, however, is only 1.69 million.  This can be calculated using the future value of an annuity formula:</p>
<p><math xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" display="block"><mtable displaystyle="true" columnalign="right center left" columnspacing="0 thickmathspace" rowspacing="3pt"><mtr><mtd><mn>14,000</mn><mo></mo><mfrac><mrow><msup><mrow><mo stretchy="false">(</mo><mn>1</mn><mo>+</mo><mn>0.05</mn><mo stretchy="false">)</mo></mrow><mrow><mn>40</mn></mrow></msup><mo></mo><mn>1</mn></mrow><mn>0.05</mn></mfrac></mtd><mtd><mi></mi><mo>=</mo></mtd><mtd><mn>1,690,000</mn></mtd></mtr><mtr><mtd><mn>14,000</mn><mo></mo><mfrac><mrow><msup><mrow><mo stretchy="false">(</mo><mn>1</mn><mo>+</mo><mn>0.20</mn><mo stretchy="false">)</mo></mrow><mrow><mn>40</mn></mrow></msup><mo></mo><mn>1</mn></mrow><mn>0.20</mn></mfrac></mtd><mtd><mi></mi><mo>=</mo></mtd><mtd><mn>102,810,000</mn></mtd></mtr></mtable></math></p>
<p>Let&rsquo;s compare this with the 20% return scenario.  The only difference between the two formulas is the rate of return (5% vs. 20%). A 20% return over 40 years yields 102.81 million Taiwan dollars, while a 5% return over the same period yields only 1.69 million, less than a fraction of the former. The difference is over 60 times! This illustrates the power of compound interest.  Many assume they benefit from compound interest in a bank, but at a 5% return, even with compounding over a long period, the wealth creation effect is very limited.</p>
<p>This example demonstrates that one of the keys to successful financial management is the rate of return. The key is not just whether your assets are invested, but <em>where</em> they are invested and what the rate of return is.</p>
<ul>
<li>
<ol>
<li>The key to financial management lies in how your assets are allocated. The rate of return has a decisive impact on your future wealth.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol start="2">
<li>While bank savings provide interest income and the benefit of compounding,  you&rsquo;ll find that as you age, bank deposits contribute little to overall wealth growth.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol start="3">
<li>The first step towards building wealth through investment is to allocate assets to investments with high long-term rates of return.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol start="4">
<li>&ldquo;Financial Management&rdquo; is a significant factor contributing to wealth disparity in society.</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>Inflation makes money worth less and less.</p></blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">The Invisible Killer of Currency Value: Inflation 
    <div id="the-invisible-killer-of-currency-value-inflation" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#the-invisible-killer-of-currency-value-inflation" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>Forty years ago, a millionaire was truly wealthy.  Today, a millionaire might struggle to afford a house. Why?  Inflation.  Every investor must consider the impact of inflation.</p>
<p><em>Inflation reduces the purchasing power of money and lowers the real rate of return, diminishing the effect of wealth accumulation.</em></p>
<p>Over the past 30 years, the average annual inflation rate in Taiwan has been around 5%. What about the future?  Inflation and economic growth are closely linked. As Taiwan&rsquo;s economy continues to grow, inflation is expected to remain around 5% annually.</p>
<p>Inflation means continuously rising prices, which translates to decreasing purchasing power.  If you keep your money in a demand deposit account earning 4% interest with a 5% inflation rate, what happens?  Your purchasing power decreases.  The longer your money sits in a savings account, the less it&rsquo;s worth.  What used to cost 10 Taiwan dollars for a newspaper now costs 15. Your 10 dollars can now only buy two-thirds of a newspaper. With inflation, money in the bank shrinks like wool submerged in water.</p>
<p><strong>Saving Alone Won&rsquo;t Make You Rich, Not Even in Two Lifetimes</strong></p>
<p>With 5% inflation and a nominal interest rate of around 5% on bank deposits, your real rate of return is zero. In this scenario, the effect of compound interest is nullified.  Wealth accumulation relies solely on painstaking saving. Imagine someone saves 500,000 Taiwan dollars a year. How long would it take to become a billionaire?  200 years!</p>
<p>Saving 500,000 Taiwan dollars a year is difficult; living for 200 years is even harder!  Therefore, even with diligent saving and budgeting, if all the money is kept in the bank, this person won&rsquo;t become wealthy in this lifetime, and worse, not even in the next! The average lifespan is around 75 years, meaning two lifetimes total only 150 years.  It would take a third lifetime for someone relying solely on bank savings to potentially reach billionaire status.  If a family maintains the financial strategy of &ldquo;frugality and bank savings,&rdquo; it would take at least 200 years, or about seven generations, for them to potentially become wealthy.  Conversely, with proper financial management, wealth can be achieved in 40 years (half a lifetime).</p>
<p><strong>Money in the Bank Should Be Spent Sooner Rather Than Later</strong></p>
<p>I remember 30 years ago, when I was in second or third grade, a popsicle cost 20 cents, and a red bean ice cream cost 50 cents.  My parents gave me 50 cents each day for allowance, which I invariably spent on red bean ice cream after school. My parents constantly encouraged me to save, so my father opened a bank account for me. If I had been obedient and developed good saving habits from a young age, saving those 50 cents daily and earning 8% interest, it would have grown tenfold over 30 years, to 5 Taiwan dollars.  However, a red bean ice cream now costs 15 Taiwan dollars. Those 5 dollars can only buy one-third of a red bean ice cream. More importantly, for a 30 years ago, a red bean ice cream was precious.  Even a dozen red bean ice creams today couldn&rsquo;t compare to the value of one back then. Had I followed my parents&rsquo; financial advice and kept my money in the bank, I would regret it now.</p>
<p>Therefore, if you&rsquo;re going to keep money in the bank, my sincere advice is: &ldquo;Spend it sooner rather than later!&rdquo; This might sound shocking, but there&rsquo;s logic to it.  From an economic perspective, money has more value and higher utility when used sooner. We save money in the bank, delaying gratification for the sake of greater enjoyment in the future.  However, with inflation, money left in the bank often leads to <em>less</em> enjoyment.</p>
<p><strong>The Value of Money Decreases with Age</strong></p>
<p>My wife and her friends developed a financial philosophy: &ldquo;Money is most valuable when spent while young.&rdquo; This makes economic sense.  Their reasoning: &ldquo;When you&rsquo;re old, delicacies might harm your health, traveling becomes difficult, and most importantly, wearing beautiful clothes attracts unwanted attention and ridicule.&rdquo;</p>
<p>Thus, everyone managing their finances must be mindful of the dual pressures of inflation and the diminishing value of money with age. Bank deposit interest rates cannot compensate for these losses. In other words, <strong>money in the bank, while nominally increasing, actually decreases in value.</strong></p>
<p>Of course, I&rsquo;m not encouraging you to spend all your savings immediately.  Rather, I&rsquo;m highlighting that if you keep money in the bank, you must consider the declining purchasing power due to inflation and the reduced economic benefit as you age.  The fundamental solution is to withdraw your money from the bank and invest it in instruments with higher returns than bank deposit rates. <strong>Therefore, the best way to combat inflation is: Don&rsquo;t keep your money in the bank. Invest in long-term, high-return assets like stocks and real estate.</strong></p>
<p>Because inflation decreases real returns and hinders wealth accumulation, even saving 14,000 Taiwan dollars annually and investing in stocks or real estate for 40 years to become a billionaire won&rsquo;t carry the same weight as being a billionaire today.  Therefore, under inflation, consider using the <em>real</em> rate of return. If the return on investment is 20% and inflation is 5%, the real return is 15%.  So how much should you save annually, investing in stocks or real estate with a nominal return of around 20% (real return of 15%), to become a billionaire in 40 years?  The answer is 57,000 Taiwan dollars per year.</p>
<p><math xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" display="block"><mn>57,000</mn><mo></mo><mfrac><mrow><msup><mrow><mo stretchy="false">(</mo><mn>1</mn><mo>+</mo><mn>0.15</mn><mo stretchy="false">)</mo></mrow><mrow><mn>40</mn></mrow></msup><mo></mo><mn>1</mn></mrow><mn>0.15</mn></mfrac><mo>=</mo><mn>101,410,000</mn><mspace linebreak="newline"></mspace></math></p>
<blockquote>
<p>A small step today makes a world of difference tomorrow.</p></blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">The Path to Wealth of Chang Pin-san, Former Chairman of Chang Hwa Bank 
    <div id="the-path-to-wealth-of-chang-pin-san-former-chairman-of-chang-hwa-bank" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#the-path-to-wealth-of-chang-pin-san-former-chairman-of-chang-hwa-bank" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>Chang Po-hsin, the current standing director of Chang Hwa Bank, with assets exceeding tens of billions, inherited and expanded upon the fortune of his father, Chang Pin-san, the former chairman of Chang Hwa Bank, earning him a place among Taiwan&rsquo;s wealthiest individuals.</p>
<p><strong>Trading Bank Deposits for Stock Dividends</strong></p>
<p>Forty years ago, both Chang Pin-san and my father were from Nantun District, Taichung City.  They were not only fellow townsmen but also colleagues. Back then, Chang Pin-san was just a junior manager at Chang Hwa Bank, without much wealth.  However, he borrowed money to buy Chang Hwa Bank shares from colleagues who wanted to sell them. At the time, stock dividends were far lower than bank interest. Despite this, Chang Pin-san persisted in borrowing money to acquire shares, holding onto them for the long term.  Other colleagues deposited the proceeds from their stock sales into banks. Years later, Chang Pin-san, owning the most shares, became the largest shareholder and eventually the chairman of Chang Hwa Bank, laying the foundation for his immense wealth.</p>
<p>Chang Pin-san was also friends with Lien Chen-tung, father of Lien Chan, and encouraged him to buy Chang Hwa Bank shares. The Lien family&rsquo;s fortune also originated from those hundreds of Chang Hwa Bank shares.</p>
<p>It&rsquo;s hard to believe that the path to wealth could be so simple: borrow money to buy a few Chang Hwa Bank shares, invest in some real estate, hold them long-term, and essentially forget about them.  Decades later, great wealth is attained. Those who sold their shares and deposited the money in banks are still wondering how others became rich. Some might attribute this to luck, but financial management is not about luck.  It&rsquo;s about the method chosen and the investment tools selected.  Therefore, if you don&rsquo;t want to be poor, don&rsquo;t keep your money in the bank.</p>
<p><strong>Bank Savings Shouldn&rsquo;t Exceed Living Expenses</strong></p>
<p>Someone once jokingly asked me, &ldquo;You&rsquo;re telling us not to keep money in the bank.  Are we supposed to pay with stocks or real estate certificates at the supermarket or restaurant?&rdquo; Of course not!  Advising against keeping money in the bank doesn&rsquo;t mean you can&rsquo;t have any money in the bank at all. Bank deposits offer advantages: security and convenience. They are ideal for storing funds needed for daily expenses. However, you can&rsquo;t have your cake and eat it too.  Convenience comes at the cost of high returns.</p>
<p>The wise approach is to clearly divide funds into two categories: daily expenses and investments.  Keep enough for daily needs in the bank, enjoying the security and convenience it offers. Invest the rest in higher-return assets like stocks and real estate.</p>
<p>In my opinion, keeping the equivalent of two months&rsquo; living expenses in the bank is sufficient for an individual or family. Most individuals and families receive regular income, which is deposited into their bank accounts. Therefore, one month&rsquo;s expenses for immediate use and another month&rsquo;s worth as a safety net should be ample.  The remaining funds should be invested in higher-return assets like stocks and real estate.  In other words, if your monthly expenses average 50,000 Taiwan dollars, and your bank balance consistently exceeds 100,000, you are not managing your finances effectively.  Actively seek suitable investment opportunities to make your surplus funds work for you.</p>
<p><strong>The &ldquo;Two Big, One Small&rdquo; Approach to Flexible Fund Management</strong></p>
<p>Some believe in maintaining substantial emergency funds. However, even if unforeseen circumstances drain your bank savings, there&rsquo;s no need to panic. The high-return investments mentioned earlierstocks and real estateare not as illiquid as some might think.  Listed stocks in Taiwan&rsquo;s active stock market can be sold almost any day of the year (excluding holidays), providing quick access to cash within a few days.  Reluctant to sell? Stocks can also be used as collateral for loans.</p>
<p>Real estate is less liquid than stocks, but many Taiwanese banks now offer &ldquo;revolving mortgage loans,&rdquo; allowing property owners to convert fixed assets into liquid assets. These loans involve mortgaging a property to secure a credit line of up to 70%-75% of the property&rsquo;s value. Borrowers can draw and repay funds as needed, with interest accruing only on the outstanding balance. For example, a 10 million Taiwan dollar property could secure a 7.5 million credit line.  Borrowing 5 million leaves 2.5 million available without interest charges, with interest accruing only on the 5 million borrowed.  Any surplus funds can be used to repay the loan, reducing interest costs.</p>
<p>Many financial experts recommend a &ldquo;three-part&rdquo; approach, dividing assets equally among bank savings, real estate, and more speculative investments. I propose a &ldquo;two big, one small&rdquo; approach: allocate most of your assets to stocks and real estate, keeping a small portion in a bank for daily expenses.  This isn&rsquo;t my invention. In fact, this is the portfolio strategy employed by many who have achieved wealth through investments.</p>
<ul>
<li>
<ol>
<li>Keeping money in the bank is the riskiest form of financial management.  Inflation erodes returns, leaving real interest rates near zero.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol start="2">
<li>Banks offer convenience, not high returns.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol start="3">
<li>Keep only two months&rsquo; worth of living expenses in the bank.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol start="4">
<li>Trying to get rich with money in the bank is like trying to win a baseball game without swinging the bat.</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ul>
<p>If all this hasn&rsquo;t convinced you to reconsider keeping most of your money in a financial institution, perhaps the story of the Nobel Prize Foundation&rsquo;s success might change your mind.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Change your asset management perspective, change your financial destiny.</p></blockquote>


<h3 class="relative group">Lessons from the Nobel Prize Foundation 
    <div id="lessons-from-the-nobel-prize-foundation" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#lessons-from-the-nobel-prize-foundation" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>Every October, the Nobel Committee announces the Nobel laureates. The Nobel Prize attracts global attention not only for representing the highest academic honor but also because each laureate receives a substantial prize of 1 million US dollars.</p>
<p><strong>The Folly of Depleting Capital</strong></p>
<p>The Nobel Foundation awards several prizes annually, disbursing millions of dollars. This raises the question: How large is the Nobel fund to sustain such substantial payouts? The Nobel Foundation&rsquo;s success, besides the substantial initial donation by Alfred Nobel over a century ago, is largely attributed to its shrewd financial management.</p>
<p>Established in 1896 with a 9.8 million US dollar donation from Nobel, the foundation&rsquo;s purpose is to fund the prizes.  Flawless fund management was paramount.  Initially, its charter stipulated that investments be restricted to safe, fixed-income instruments like bank deposits and government bonds, explicitly excluding stocks and real estate to avoid market risks.</p>
<p>This capital preservation approach, prioritizing safety over returns, seemed prudent, preventing losses. However, sacrificing returns had consequences.  After 50 years of prize payouts and operating expenses, low returns depleted two-thirds of the Nobel fund, leaving only a little over 3 million US dollars by 1953.</p>
<p><strong>From 3 Million to 270 Million: The Secret</strong></p>
<p>Facing depletion, the Nobel Foundation&rsquo;s board recognized the importance of investment returns. In 1953, they made a groundbreaking change, amending the charter to shift from bank deposits and bonds to primarily stocks and real estate.  This shift in investment philosophy transformed the foundation&rsquo;s fate. Over the next 40 years, despite continued prize payouts and operating costs, the foundation not only recovered all previous losses but also grew its assets to 270 million US dollars by 1993.</p>
<p><em>Nobel Prize Foundation Asset Growth and Decline</em></p>
<table>
  <thead>
      <tr>
          <th>Year</th>
          <th>Total Assets (Million USD)</th>
          <th>Remarks</th>
      </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
      <tr>
          <td>1896</td>
          <td>9.8</td>
          <td>Foundation Established</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>1953</td>
          <td>3.3</td>
          <td>Investment Charter Amended</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>1993</td>
          <td>270</td>
          <td></td>
      </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>
<p>Had the Nobel Foundation not changed its approach 40 years ago, clinging to bank savings, it would have vanished, unable to fund the prizes.  Perhaps other wealthy individuals would have established new foundations with larger prizes, replacing the Nobel Prize.</p>
<p>The Nobel Foundation&rsquo;s history underscores the importance of financial management.  Even a substantial initial fund, if mismanaged, can be depleted. Conversely, even with significant spending, skillful management can generate rapid growth.</p>
<p>I once heard of a Taiwanese hometown association that established a foundation with 100,000 Taiwan dollars 40 years ago to provide scholarships for children from their hometown.  Forty years later, the fund remains at 100,000 Taiwan dollars. While a significant sum back then, today it barely covers administrative costs, threatening the foundation&rsquo;s existence.  The problem? Neglecting financial management.</p>
<p>Learning from the Nobel Foundation, many US foundations, pension funds, university endowments, and even personal trusts have shifted from bank deposits and bonds to primarily stocks and real estate. In contrast, few Taiwanese foundations grasp this concept, and university endowments rarely address financial management seriously.  The fate of these foundations, if they don&rsquo;t adapt, is clear.</p>
<p>I often participate in corporate training programs, where I habitually ask companies about the size and investment strategy of their employee welfare funds.  The answers are usually similar: small funds, mostly in bank deposits, rarely exceeding a few hundred thousand or a million Taiwan dollars. However, in 1990, during my time at China Development Corporation, the employee welfare fund exceeded 200 million Taiwan dollars. Why?  Because it was primarily invested in China Development Corporation&rsquo;s own stock.</p>
<ul>
<li>
<ol>
<li>The Nobel Foundation&rsquo;s course correction 40 years ago secured its status today.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol start="2">
<li>Prioritizing security above all else leads to asset depletion.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>
<ol start="3">
<li>The growth and decline of wealth for individuals, families, businesses, or other entities depends on their investment strategy.</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ul>
<p>Will your hard-earned wealth shrink like the early Nobel fund, or grow like the later one? The key lies in <em>how</em> you invest. If, like many, you keep most of your money in the bank, it&rsquo;s not too late to change. The Nobel Foundation&rsquo;s story shows how a change in investment philosophy can transform everything.  Should you reconsider your financial habits and prioritize investments in stocks and real estate? Let the Nobel Foundation inspire your financial thinking. A single change in mindset can lead to immense wealth decades from now!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Just Keep Buying: Book Notes</title>
      <link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1728914740948/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1728914740948/</guid>
      <description>This book answers the most common questions in the field of personal finance and investing. From saving to investing, it provides practical tips to teach you how to increase your income, invest in income-producing assets, manage your finances more wisely, and live a richer life.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[

<h2 class="relative group">I. Content Summary 
    <div id="i-content-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-content-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>This book is divided into two parts: saving and investing. The <strong>saving</strong> section covers all aspects of saving money, including how much to save, how to save more, and how to spend money without guilt. The <strong>investing</strong> section covers many aspects of making money with money, including why you should invest, what you should invest in, and how often you should invest. The author answers the most common questions in the field of personal finance and investing, with each chapter exploring a topic in depth and providing practical tips.  Using a large amount of data and empirical research as evidence, the author arrives at reliable ways to save money and build wealth.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">II. Chapter Summary 
    <div id="ii-chapter-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii-chapter-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Chapter 1. Where Should You Start? 
    <div id="chapter-1-where-should-you-start" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chapter-1-where-should-you-start" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>The poor should focus on saving, and the rich should focus on investing.</p>
<ul>
<li>Recent graduates should focus on increasing their income and savings rate, rather than obsessing over investment decisions, because the growth rate of savings far exceeds the growth rate of investment.</li>
<li>People who have accumulated a certain amount of wealth should spend more time thinking about the details of their investment plan.</li>
<li>The author proposes a &ldquo;Save-Invest continuum&rdquo; concept to help you determine your current financial focus: calculate your expected savings and expected investment growth. Focus on whichever is greater.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chapter 2. How Much Should You Save? 
    <div id="chapter-2-how-much-should-you-save" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chapter-2-how-much-should-you-save" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>You probably need to save less than you think.</p>
<ul>
<li>Many saving recommendations are based on false assumptions: that people&rsquo;s incomes are stable and that everyone has the ability to achieve the same savings rate.</li>
<li>In fact, incomes become more unstable over time, and the biggest determinant of an individual&rsquo;s savings rate is their income level.</li>
<li>The best saving advice is: <strong>save what you can save.</strong></li>
<li>A large body of evidence suggests that retirees generally don&rsquo;t spend enough, with many even increasing their financial assets after retirement.</li>
<li>Today&rsquo;s younger generation is not creating wealth any slower than previous generations, so there is no need to worry too much about running out of money after retirement.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chapter 3. How to Save More Money? 
    <div id="chapter-3-how-to-save-more-money" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chapter-3-how-to-save-more-money" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>The biggest lie in personal finance: you can get rich just by saving.</p>
<ul>
<li>The effectiveness of reducing spending is limited. For low-income people, spending is already at its lowest level, making it difficult to reduce further. The author uses data from the U.S. Bureau of Labor Statistics Consumer Expenditure Survey to support this point.</li>
<li>Increasing income is more effective than reducing spending because as income increases, spending does not necessarily increase proportionately (diminishing marginal utility). The author calls this the &ldquo;law of the stomach.&rdquo;</li>
<li>Five ways to increase your income:
<ul>
<li>Sell your time/expertise: easy to do, but not scalable.</li>
<li>Sell a skill/service: higher income, but takes time to develop skills.</li>
<li>Teach: easy to scale, but highly competitive.</li>
<li>Sell a product: scalable, but requires a lot of upfront investment and ongoing marketing efforts.</li>
<li>Climb the career ladder: traditional but effective, can gain skills, experience and stable income growth.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>The most reliable way to get rich is: <strong>Increase your income and invest in income-producing assets.</strong></li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chapter 4. How to Spend Money Without Guilt? 
    <div id="chapter-4-how-to-spend-money-without-guilt" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chapter-4-how-to-spend-money-without-guilt" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Most financial advice uses guilt to make you question your spending decisions, causing you to be overly nervous about spending money.</li>
<li>Two tips to help you make financial decisions without worry and spend money without guilt:
<ul>
<li>The 2x rule: When you splurge, invest the same amount of money in income-producing assets or donate it to charity. For example, if you want to buy a pair of $400 shoes, buy $400 worth of stock at the same time.</li>
<li>Focus on maximizing satisfaction: Think about whether your purchase can bring autonomy, mastery, and purpose, thereby increasing your long-term satisfaction. For example, a daily latte might allow you to do your job better.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>The only right way to spend money is: <strong>the way that works for you</strong>. Think about what you want to get out of life, and make spending decisions accordingly. Research from the University of Cambridge shows that the more your spending patterns match your psychological state, the higher your life satisfaction, and this effect is greater than the happiness brought by your total income.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chapter 5. How Much Lifestyle Inflation Is Harmless? 
    <div id="chapter-5-how-much-lifestyle-inflation-is-harmless" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chapter-5-how-much-lifestyle-inflation-is-harmless" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>Lifestyle inflation refers to the increase in spending that follows an increase in one&rsquo;s income.</li>
<li>Some lifestyle inflation is enjoyable, but too much lifestyle inflation will lead to having to delay retirement.</li>
<li>The author simulates the retirement plans of two investors with different savings rates after salary increases to arrive at these conclusions:
<ul>
<li>The lower your current savings rate, the higher your lifestyle inflation can be without affecting your original retirement plan.</li>
<li>The author recommends saving at least 50% of your future raises, a rule that is simple, practical, and suitable for most people.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chapter 6. Should You Go Into Debt? 
    <div id="chapter-6-should-you-go-into-debt" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chapter-6-should-you-go-into-debt" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>Debt is not necessarily good or bad, it depends on how you use it.</p>
<ul>
<li>Debt as a form of risk mitigation: Some people, even with savings, keep credit card debt as a strategy to reduce the risk of future funding shortages.</li>
<li>Debt as a behavioral pillar of forced savings: Some people use debt as a behavioral pillar to force themselves to save.</li>
<li>The two most useful types of debt:
<ul>
<li>To reduce risk: for example, keeping cash on hand for emergencies or fixing housing costs.</li>
<li>To earn a return higher than the cost of borrowing: for example, by taking out education loans, business loans, or mortgages to generate higher returns. The author uses data to demonstrate that getting a college degree is often worthwhile.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Debt can also have non-financial costs, such as psychological stress and health problems, so non-mortgage financial debt should be avoided as much as possible.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chapter 7. Should You Rent or Buy? 
    <div id="chapter-7-should-you-rent-or-buy" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chapter-7-should-you-rent-or-buy" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>The point of buying a home is not whether to buy it, but when to buy it.</p>
<ul>
<li>In addition to the mortgage, there are a number of one-time and ongoing costs associated with buying a home, such as down payment, closing costs, taxes, maintenance, and insurance. The author details these costs, concluding that buying a home is only cost-effective if the buyer intends to live in it for the long term.</li>
<li>In the short term, buying a home is riskier than renting, but in the long term, renters face greater long-term risks such as rent fluctuations, housing instability, and moving costs.</li>
<li>In the United States, the long-term return on  homeownership as an investment is not ideal, far lower than the stock market. The author uses the example of his grandparents buying a home to illustrate this point.</li>
<li>The right time to buy a home is when you:
<ul>
<li>plan to stay in that location for at least ten years;</li>
<li>have a stable personal and professional life;</li>
<li>can afford a 20% down payment and keep your debt-to-income ratio below 43%. The author recommends, if possible, to make a 20% down payment and buy a larger home in one step, because the transaction costs are lower in the long run.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chapter 8. How to Save For a Down Payment (and Other Big Purchases)? 
    <div id="chapter-8-how-to-save-for-a-down-payment-and-other-big-purchases" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chapter-8-how-to-save-for-a-down-payment-and-other-big-purchases" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>Why the length of time you save matters?</p>
<ul>
<li>Short-term saving for less than two years: Holding <strong>cash</strong> is the best option, as it has the lowest risk.</li>
<li>Long-term saving for more than two years: Investing in <strong>bonds</strong> is preferable to holding cash because bond returns can offset the effects of inflation. The author compares cash and bonds using two examples: &ldquo;Save $1,000 per month with a goal of $24,000&rdquo; and &ldquo;Save $1,000 per month with a goal of $60,000&rdquo;.</li>
<li>Longer-term saving for more than three years: You can choose to invest in <strong>stocks</strong>, but the risk is higher and you need to choose an appropriate portfolio based on your own risk tolerance. The author uses data to show that stocks have much higher long-term returns than bonds, but also greater volatility.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chapter 9. When Can You Retire? 
    <div id="chapter-9-when-can-you-retire" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chapter-9-when-can-you-retire" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>There&rsquo;s more to consider than just money when it comes to retirement.</p>
<ul>
<li>The 4% rule: When your retirement savings reach 25 times your expected annual expenses, you can retire.
<ul>
<li>You can withdraw 4% of your investment assets (half bonds and half stocks) in the first year of retirement, and increase the amount withdrawn by 3% each year to keep up with inflation.</li>
<li>If you have a pension or other guaranteed income, you only need to save 25 times your &ldquo;annual excess spending&rdquo; (expected annual expenses less future guaranteed income).</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>The crossover point rule: The point at which your monthly investment income is greater than your monthly expenses, you have reached the &ldquo;crossover point&rdquo; and achieved financial freedom.
<ul>
<li>&ldquo;Crossover Assets&rdquo; = Monthly Expenses / Monthly Investment Return.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Retirement is much more than just a financial decision, it&rsquo;s a lifestyle decision. You need to think about what you want to do and how you want to live after retirement. The author uses the examples of several celebrities to illustrate the confusion and emptiness that can exist after early retirement.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chapter 10. Why You Should Invest? 
    <div id="chapter-10-why-you-should-invest" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chapter-10-why-you-should-invest" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>Three reasons to make your money grow.</p>
<ul>
<li>Save for your future self: Investing allows you to have a pool of resources to draw from as you age. Human lifespans are increasing, and the concept of &ldquo;retirement&rdquo; has emerged accordingly. To ensure quality of life after retirement, it is necessary to invest in advance.</li>
<li>Fight inflation and maintain the purchasing power of your wealth: Investing can offset the impact of inflation and maintain or increase your purchasing power. The author uses data to show that investing can effectively combat the effects of inflation.</li>
<li>Replace your human capital with financial capital: Investing can turn your diminishing human capital into financial capital that can continue to generate returns. The author illustrates this with the example of professional athletes.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chapter 11. What Should You Invest In? 
    <div id="chapter-11-what-should-you-invest-in" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chapter-11-what-should-you-invest-in" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>There is no single right way to get rich.</p>
<ul>
<li>The author lists a variety of income-producing assets, including:
<ul>
<li>Stocks: One of the most reliable ways to build wealth over the long term, easy to own and trade, with low maintenance costs, but highly volatile and valuations easily influenced by market sentiment.</li>
<li>Bonds: Low volatility, safe principal, and helpful in rebalancing portfolios, but returns are generally lower than stocks, especially in a low interest rate environment.</li>
<li>Investment real estate: Returns are higher than stocks or bonds, especially when using leverage, but require more effort to manage and are difficult to diversify.</li>
<li>Real Estate Investment Trusts (REITs): Provide access to real estate investment income without needing to manage it yourself, but are more volatile and highly correlated with stocks and other risky assets during stock market crashes.</li>
<li>Farmland: Low correlation with stocks and bonds, low volatility, inflation-resistant, but low liquidity, higher fees, and requires &ldquo;accredited investor&rdquo; status to participate.</li>
<li>Small businesses/franchises/angel investing: Potential for high returns and the more effort you put in, the greater the return, but requires a significant time commitment and has a high failure rate.</li>
<li>Royalties: Can generate stable income that is uncorrelated with traditional financial assets, but sellers incur high fees and public taste changes are unpredictable.</li>
<li>Your own products: 100% ownership, personal satisfaction and achievement, can create a valuable brand, but very labor-intensive and no guarantee of return.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>The author also contrasts the characteristics of income-producing and non-income-producing assets (e.g., gold, cryptocurrency, art, etc.) and their respective advantages and disadvantages.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chapter 12. Why You Shouldn&rsquo;t Buy Individual Stocks? 
    <div id="chapter-12-why-you-shouldnt-buy-individual-stocks" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chapter-12-why-you-shouldnt-buy-individual-stocks" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>Why underperforming the market is the least of your worries?</p>
<ul>
<li>Most people (even professionals) can&rsquo;t beat the market. Data from the SPIVA report shows that active funds tend to underperform index funds over the long term.</li>
<li>Only a very small percentage of individual stocks outperform in the long run. Bessembinder&rsquo;s research indicates that since 1926, only 4% of stocks have generated returns that exceed U.S. Treasury bonds.</li>
<li>Even stocks that outperform are not always winners. West&rsquo;s statistical analysis suggests that many companies will disappear within a decade.</li>
<li>Choosing individual stocks is emotionally draining and stressful. The author uses the example of his friend Darren investing in GameStop stock to detail the emotional rollercoaster of stock trading.</li>
<li>It&rsquo;s hard to tell if you&rsquo;re really good at picking stocks. The link between stock picking decisions and outcomes is not significant, making it difficult to assess your stock picking skills. Even if you have performed well in the past, there is no guarantee that you will continue to do so in the future.</li>
<li>The risk of holding a concentrated position in a single stock is that the return is lower than the market. The author uses data on U.S. stock performance since 1963 to show that the median return of individual stocks is lower than that of index funds.</li>
<li>The author suggests buying index funds or ETFs to earn market average returns, which can lead to higher returns and less stress during the investment process.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chapter 13. How Early Should You Start Investing? 
    <div id="chapter-13-how-early-should-you-start-investing" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chapter-13-how-early-should-you-start-investing" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>Why buying early is better than buying late?</p>
<ul>
<li>Most markets tend to go up most of the time, so investing early allows for a longer period of compounding growth.</li>
<li>The author compares two investment strategies:
<ul>
<li>Buy now: Put all the money you can invest in immediately.</li>
<li>Average in: Invest the money you can invest in batches.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Conclusion: The <strong>buy now</strong> strategy is generally better than the average-in strategy. The author uses U.S. stock market data from 1997 to 2020, as well as U.S. stock market data from 1920 to 2020, to respectively prove this conclusion. The same results hold when testing other types of assets.</li>
<li>For risk-averse investors, you can choose to invest in a lower risk portfolio. For example, change an 80% stock / 20% bond portfolio to a 60% stock / 40% bond portfolio.</li>
<li>Even if market valuations are high, the buy now strategy is still better than the average in strategy. The author compares the two strategies using CAPE percentile categories, and the results show that the buy now strategy is still superior even during periods of high valuations.</li>
<li>For investors concerned about the risk of a lump sum investment, you can take a longer time to gradually adjust to your target asset allocation.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chapter 14. Why You Shouldn&rsquo;t Wait to Buy the Dip? 
    <div id="chapter-14-why-you-shouldnt-wait-to-buy-the-dip" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chapter-14-why-you-shouldnt-wait-to-buy-the-dip" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>Even God can&rsquo;t beat dollar-cost averaging.</p>
<ul>
<li>The buy the dip strategy only works if the market is about to have a big drop and you can accurately predict when it will happen.</li>
<li>Big market drops don&rsquo;t happen that often, so the buy the dip strategy has a small chance of beating dollar-cost averaging. The author simulates the two strategies using U.S. stock market data from between 1920 and 1980. The results show that in all forty-year investment periods, the buy-the-dip strategy underperformed dollar-cost averaging more than 70% of the time.</li>
<li>Even with perfect information, the buy the dip strategy often loses to dollar-cost averaging because the market may continue to rise while you miss out on compounding growth. The author simulates the two strategies using U.S. stock market data from 1975 onward, again proving this conclusion.</li>
<li>Even if the predicted time of the market bottom is off by only two months, the long-term investment performance of the buy-the-dip strategy still loses to dollar-cost averaging.</li>
<li>Conclusion: <strong>you should invest as early as possible and as often as possible</strong>.</li>
<li>Investment returns are heavily influenced by time, and the power of strategy is far less than the power of market change.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chapter 15. Why Does Investing Involve Luck? 
    <div id="chapter-15-why-does-investing-involve-luck" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chapter-15-why-does-investing-involve-luck" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>And why you shouldn&rsquo;t care.</p>
<ul>
<li>The year you were born influences your investment returns because markets fluctuate unpredictably. The author illustrates this with data on 10-, 20-, and 30-year investment returns in the U.S. stock market since 1910.</li>
<li>The sequence of investment returns also affects your final return because you invest more money in the later stages of your investment, so later returns are more important. The author illustrates the impact of return sequence with two cases of 20-year investment horizons with the same annualized return but in reverse order.</li>
<li>How to mitigate bad luck:
<ul>
<li>Hold low-risk assets (such as bonds) for the long term to diversify risk.</li>
<li>Withdraw less money during market downturns.</li>
<li>Consider getting a part-time job to supplement your income.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chapter 16. Why You Shouldn&rsquo;t Fear Market Volatility? 
    <div id="chapter-16-why-you-shouldnt-fear-market-volatility" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chapter-16-why-you-shouldnt-fear-market-volatility" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>The price of admission for successful investing.</p>
<ul>
<li>Avoiding too many market declines can limit your upside.</li>
<li>Using the analogy of a &ldquo;market genie&rdquo; that tells you the maximum intra-year drawdown for the coming year, the author simulates different risk aversion strategies. The conclusion is that if you want to maximize long-term wealth, you should accept some degree of intra-year market decline (0% to 15%) and avoid large intra-year market declines (greater than 15%).</li>
<li>Buying a diversified portfolio of income-producing assets over the long term is one of the best ways to combat market volatility as it rears its ugly head.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chapter 17. How to Buy During a Crisis? 
    <div id="chapter-17-how-to-buy-during-a-crisis" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chapter-17-how-to-buy-during-a-crisis" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>Why you should keep your cool when the market panics?</p>
<ul>
<li>Market crashes are opportunities to buy because every dollar you invest at this point will earn a higher return after the market recovers. The author uses the 1929 U.S. stock market crash as an example to illustrate the excess returns of investing at the bottom of the market.</li>
<li>The more the market falls, the higher the return you need to make up for the loss. The author illustrates this with a simple mathematical formula and chart.</li>
<li>Even if the market takes a long time to recover, buying during a crisis is still a good decision because you can earn a decent annualized return while you wait. The author proves this conclusion using examples of the U.S. stock market falling 30% and 50% between 1920 and 2020.</li>
<li>Most stock markets trend upwards most of the time, and even if a prolonged downturn occurs, the likelihood of losing money is significantly reduced if you make regular investments as most investors do, rather than a single lump sum investment. The author illustrates this with the example of the Japanese stock market.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chapter 18. When Should You Sell? 
    <div id="chapter-18-when-should-you-sell" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chapter-18-when-should-you-sell" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>About rebalancing, concentrated positions, and the purpose of investing.</p>
<ul>
<li>Three situations where you should consider selling an investment asset:
<ul>
<li>Rebalancing your portfolio.</li>
<li>Getting rid of a concentrated (or consistently losing) investment position.</li>
<li>Meeting your financial needs.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>You should have a plan in place before you consider selling investment assets to avoid emotional decisions.</li>
<li>Selling gradually (or selling later) is generally better than selling immediately, because in the long run, the market tends to go up.</li>
<li>Regularly rebalancing your portfolio can reduce risk, but it generally reduces returns. The author simulates two strategies, annual rebalancing and never rebalancing, using a portfolio of 60% stocks/40% bonds, and compares the returns and maximum drawdowns after 30 years.</li>
<li>Accumulative rebalancing is a better way to rebalance by buying asset classes that are underweight over time to avoid incurring tax liabilities. The author uses the same portfolio to simulate a strategy of adding investments each month, demonstrating that this strategy can effectively reduce the maximum drawdown.</li>
<li>For investors holding large concentrated positions, it is advisable to sell some of the assets to reduce risk and meet their own living needs. Selling strategies can range from selling a portion on a regular basis to selling based on price levels, as long as it is decided in advance.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chapter 19. Where Should Your Investments Be Held? 
    <div id="chapter-19-where-should-your-investments-be-held" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chapter-19-where-should-your-investments-be-held" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>On taxes, traditional 401(k) vs. Roth 401(k), and why you might not want to maximize your 401(k).</p>
<ul>
<li>Tax policy in the United States is constantly changing, and financial management should also be adjusted according to tax policy. The author reviews the history of income tax in the United States to illustrate this point.</li>
<li>When choosing between a traditional 401(k) and a Roth 401(k), the most important factor is whether your effective income tax rate is higher now (during your working years) or later (in retirement).</li>
<li>The author favors traditional 401(k)s because they offer more flexibility and allow you to convert funds to a Roth IRA when tax rates are lower, such as when you are in business school or on maternity leave.</li>
<li>Roth 401(k)s may be a better option for high savers because they can enjoy greater total tax deferral benefits. The author illustrates this with the example of Sally and Sam.</li>
<li>Using a retirement savings account to invest can avoid capital gains taxes, which can lead to significant long-term gains. The author uses simulated data to compare the returns of three approaches: tax-free accounts, accounts taxed once on capital gains, and accounts taxed annually on capital gains. The author also explains the impact of compounding on investment returns.</li>
<li>Maximizing your 401(k) may not be the best option because 401(k) plan fees may offset the tax benefits. The author suggests that you should at least increase your personal contributions to the point where you can receive the maximum employer match. For any contributions beyond that, you need to take into account the 401(k)&rsquo;s expense ratio and your own need for liquidity.</li>
<li>When allocating assets, it is advisable to place high-growth assets (e.g. stocks) in tax-advantaged accounts and low-growth assets (e.g. bonds) in taxable accounts.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chapter 20. Why Will You Never Feel Rich? 
    <div id="chapter-20-why-will-you-never-feel-rich" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chapter-20-why-will-you-never-feel-rich" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>You might already be rich, so why not?</p>
<ul>
<li>People can always find someone richer than themselves, so it&rsquo;s hard to feel content. The author illustrates people&rsquo;s sense of relative wealth by telling the story of Powerball lottery winner Jack Whittaker, and the story of his friend John.</li>
<li>If you compare yourself to people around the world, you may find that you are much richer than you think. For example, if your net worth is over $4,210, you are wealthier than half the world; if your net worth is over $93,170, you are in the top 10% of the world&rsquo;s wealth.</li>
<li>Don&rsquo;t let feelings of relative wealth affect your happiness and appreciate the wealth you have.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Chapter 21. The Most Important Asset 
    <div id="chapter-21-the-most-important-asset" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#chapter-21-the-most-important-asset" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>Why you can never get more of this asset.</p>
<ul>
<li>Time is your most important asset, and how you use your time will have a huge impact on your future life. The author tells the story of Dashrath Manjhi, an Indian villager who carved a road through a mountain, to illustrate the power of time.</li>
<li>In your younger years, you should prioritize career development because that&rsquo;s when your income grows the fastest. The author uses his own experience to illustrate the importance of making the right career choices early on.</li>
<li>Don&rsquo;t sacrifice your time in pursuit of money, because you can never buy more time with money.</li>
<li>People&rsquo;s happiness tends to follow a U-shaped curve as they age, overestimating their future happiness in their youth, being more pessimistic in middle age, and feeling pleasantly surprised in old age.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Conclusion. The Just Keep Buying Rules 
    <div id="conclusion-the-just-keep-buying-rules" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#conclusion-the-just-keep-buying-rules" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<p>How to win the time traveler&rsquo;s game?</p>
<ul>
<li>The author summarizes 21 financial guidelines to help you succeed on your financial journey, these guidelines are called the &ldquo;Just Keep Buying Rules&rdquo;:
<ol>
<li>The poor should focus on saving, and the rich should focus on investing.</li>
<li>Save what you can save.</li>
<li>Focus on income, not expenses.</li>
<li>Use the &ldquo;2x rule&rdquo; to eliminate spending guilt.</li>
<li>Save at least 50% of your future raises and bonuses.</li>
<li>Debt is not necessarily a good thing or a bad thing, it depends on how you use it.</li>
<li>Only buy a house when the timing is right.</li>
<li>Use cash when saving for large purchases.</li>
<li>There&rsquo;s more to retirement than just money.</li>
<li>Invest to accumulate financial capital to replace your diminishing human capital.</li>
<li>Think like an owner and buy income-producing assets.</li>
<li>Don&rsquo;t buy individual stocks.</li>
<li>Buy fast, sell slow.</li>
<li>Invest as early and as often as possible.</li>
<li>Investing is not just about the cards you have, it&rsquo;s also about how you play them.</li>
<li>Don&rsquo;t be afraid when volatility inevitably comes.</li>
<li>Market crashes are usually opportunities to buy.</li>
<li>Use your money for the life you need before risking it for the life you want.</li>
<li>Think twice before maximizing your 401(k).</li>
<li>You&rsquo;ll never feel rich, and that&rsquo;s okay.</li>
<li>Time is your most important asset.</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">III. Quotes 
    <div id="iii-quotes" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii-quotes" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>The surest way to get rich is to increase your income and invest in income-producing assets.</p></blockquote>
<p>Analysis: Instead of blindly pursuing saving, it is better to focus your energy on increasing your income and investing in assets that can generate income; this is a more reliable path to financial freedom.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The only right way to spend money is the way that works for you.</p></blockquote>
<p>Analysis: Everyone&rsquo;s values, life goals, and preferences are different, so their financial management style should also be personalized. Don&rsquo;t blindly follow the crowd; find a spending pattern that suits you in order to achieve true happiness.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Time is your most important asset.</p></blockquote>
<p>Analysis: Time is a non-renewable resource. We should cherish time and spend it on the most valuable things. Investing early is not only about accumulating wealth, but also about buying back more time and freedom.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">IV. Guiding Significance 
    <div id="iv-guiding-significance" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv-guiding-significance" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<ul>
<li><strong>Establishing the right financial mindset:</strong> This book helps us understand the essence of personal finance and how to develop a sound savings and investment plan, avoiding common financial pitfalls.</li>
<li><strong>Enhancing personal competitiveness:</strong> The book emphasizes the importance of increasing income and encourages us to continuously learn and improve our personal skills to gain greater career development space.</li>
<li><strong>Balancing life and wealth:</strong> The author reminds us that wealth is not the only goal in life. We should focus on the quality of life and the realization of personal values while pursuing wealth.</li>
<li><strong>Viewing investment rationally:</strong> This book emphasizes the importance of long-term investing and warns investors not to blindly chase short-term gains or be intimidated by market volatility. Only rationality and patience can ultimately lead to success.</li>
</ul>

  



<div
  
    class="flex px-4 py-3 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900"
  >

  <span
    
      class="text-primary-400 ltr:pr-3 rtl:pl-3 flex items-center"
    >

    

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 640 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M172.5 131.1C228.1 75.51 320.5 75.51 376.1 131.1C426.1 181.1 433.5 260.8 392.4 318.3L391.3 319.9C381 334.2 361 337.6 346.7 327.3C332.3 317 328.9 297 339.2 282.7L340.3 281.1C363.2 249 359.6 205.1 331.7 177.2C300.3 145.8 249.2 145.8 217.7 177.2L105.5 289.5C73.99 320.1 73.99 372 105.5 403.5C133.3 431.4 177.3 435 209.3 412.1L210.9 410.1C225.3 400.7 245.3 404 255.5 418.4C265.8 432.8 262.5 452.8 248.1 463.1L246.5 464.2C188.1 505.3 110.2 498.7 60.21 448.8C3.741 392.3 3.741 300.7 60.21 244.3L172.5 131.1zM467.5 380C411 436.5 319.5 436.5 263 380C213 330 206.5 251.2 247.6 193.7L248.7 192.1C258.1 177.8 278.1 174.4 293.3 184.7C307.7 194.1 311.1 214.1 300.8 229.3L299.7 230.9C276.8 262.1 280.4 306.9 308.3 334.8C339.7 366.2 390.8 366.2 422.3 334.8L534.5 222.5C566 191 566 139.1 534.5 108.5C506.7 80.63 462.7 76.99 430.7 99.9L429.1 101C414.7 111.3 394.7 107.1 384.5 93.58C374.2 79.2 377.5 59.21 391.9 48.94L393.5 47.82C451 6.731 529.8 13.25 579.8 63.24C636.3 119.7 636.3 211.3 579.8 267.7L467.5 380z"/></svg>

  </span>


  </span>

  <span
    
      class="dark:text-neutral-300"
    ><strong>Further Reading</strong>: Check out the author, <strong>Nick Maggiulli</strong>&rsquo;s blog: <a href="https://ofdollarsanddata.com/" target="_blank"><strong>Of Dollars And Data</strong></a></span>
</div>

<hr>

<section class="space-y-10 w-full">
    
    
        
            






















  <a class="flex flex-wrap article " href="/en/posts/1728295490690-book-list/">
    
        
        <div class="w-full md:w-auto h-full thumbnail nozoom thumbnailshadow md:mr-7" style="background-image:url(/posts/1728295490690-book-list/featured_hu_a14921d8ab66af4e.jpg);"></div>
        
      <div class=" mt-3 md:mt-0">
      <div class="items-center text-left text-xl font-semibold">
        
        <div class="font-bold text-xl text-neutral-800 decoration-primary-500 hover:underline hover:underline-offset-2 dark:text-neutral"
          href="/en/posts/1728295490690-book-list/">Recommended Reading List</div>
        
        
        
      </div>
      <div class="text-sm text-neutral-500 dark:text-neutral-400">
        











  



















<div class="flex flex-row flex-wrap items-center">
  
  
  <time datetime="2024-10-01T00:00:00&#43;00:00">1 October 2024</time>
  

  
  
</div>





<div class="flex flex-row flex-wrap items-center">
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  <span style="margin-top:0.5rem" class="mr-2" onclick="window.open(&#34;/en/tags/recommended/&#34;,'_self');">
    <span class="flex" style="cursor: pointer;">
  <span class="rounded-md border border-primary-400 px-1 py-[1px] text-xs font-normal text-primary-700 dark:border-primary-600 dark:text-primary-400">
    Recommended
  </span>
</span>
  </span>
  
  <span style="margin-top:0.5rem" class="mr-2" onclick="window.open(&#34;/en/tags/book/&#34;,'_self');">
    <span class="flex" style="cursor: pointer;">
  <span class="rounded-md border border-primary-400 px-1 py-[1px] text-xs font-normal text-primary-700 dark:border-primary-600 dark:text-primary-400">
    Book
  </span>
</span>
  </span>
  
  
  
  
</div>




      </div>
      
    </div>
  </a>

        
    
</section>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Invest in NASDAQ 100</title>
      <link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1728723295012-invest-qqq/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1728723295012-invest-qqq/</guid>
      <description>a description</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="qqq-tradingview">
    <script>
        const container = document.getElementById('qqq-tradingview');
        const script = document.createElement('script');
        script.type = 'text/javascript';
        script.src = 'https://s3.tradingview.com/external-embedding/embed-widget-mini-symbol-overview.js';  // TradingView
        script.async = true; //  
        script.textContent = `{"symbol": "NASDAQ:NDX",
                                "width": "100%",
                                "height": "220",
                                "locale": "EN",
                                "dateRange": "ALL",
                                "colorTheme": "dark",
                                "isTransparent": true,
                                "autosize": true}`;
        container.appendChild(script);  //   <script> 
    </script>
</div>


<h2 class="relative group">North America 
    <div id="north-america" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#north-america" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">United States 
    <div id="united-states" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#united-states" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<table>
  <thead>
      <tr>
          <th>Ticker</th>
          <th>Product Name</th>
          <th>Remarks</th>
      </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
      <tr>
          <td><strong>QQQ</strong></td>
          <td>Invesco QQQ Trust</td>
          <td></td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td><strong>QQQM</strong></td>
          <td>Invesco NASDAQ 100 ETF</td>
          <td></td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>QLD</td>
          <td>ProShares Ultra QQQ</td>
          <td>2x</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>TQQQ</td>
          <td>ProShares UltraPro QQQ</td>
          <td>3x</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>PSQ</td>
          <td>ProShares Short QQQ</td>
          <td>-1x</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>QID</td>
          <td>ProShares UltraShort QQQ</td>
          <td>-2x</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>SQQQ</td>
          <td>ProShares UltraPro Short QQQ</td>
          <td>-3x</td>
      </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>


<h3 class="relative group">Canada 
    <div id="canada" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#canada" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<table>
  <thead>
      <tr>
          <th>Ticker</th>
          <th>Product Name</th>
          <th>Remarks</th>
      </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
      <tr>
          <td>XQQ</td>
          <td>iShares NASDAQ 100 (CAD Hedged)</td>
          <td></td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>QQC</td>
          <td>Invesco NASDAQ 100 Index Fund</td>
          <td></td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>HQU</td>
          <td>BetaPro NASDAQ-100 2x Daily Bull</td>
          <td>2x</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>HQD</td>
          <td>BetaPro NASDAQ-100 2x Daily Bear</td>
          <td>-2x</td>
      </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>


<h2 class="relative group">Asia 
    <div id="asia" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#asia" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">China 
    <div id="china" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#china" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<table>
  <thead>
      <tr>
          <th>Ticker</th>
          <th>Product Name</th>
          <th>Remarks</th>
      </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
      <tr>
          <td>159941</td>
          <td>GF Fund NASDAQ-100 ETF</td>
          <td></td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>513100</td>
          <td>Cathay NASDAQ-100 ETF</td>
          <td></td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>513300</td>
          <td>ChinaAMC NASDAQ-100 ETF</td>
          <td></td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>159513</td>
          <td>Dacheng NASDAQ-100 ETF</td>
          <td></td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>159632</td>
          <td>HuaAn NASDAQ-100 ETF</td>
          <td></td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>159501</td>
          <td>Harvest NASDAQ-100 ETF</td>
          <td></td>
      </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>


<h3 class="relative group">Hong Kong, China 
    <div id="hong-kong-china" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#hong-kong-china" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<table>
  <thead>
      <tr>
          <th>Ticker</th>
          <th>Product Name</th>
          <th>Remarks</th>
      </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
      <tr>
          <td>02834</td>
          <td>iShares NASDAQ 100</td>
          <td></td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>03034</td>
          <td>CSOP NASDAQ 100</td>
          <td></td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>07266</td>
          <td>FL 2X CSOP NASDAQ 100</td>
          <td>2x</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>07261</td>
          <td>FL 2X ChinaAMC NASDAQ 100</td>
          <td>2x</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>07568</td>
          <td>FI 2X Inverse CSOP NASDAQ 100</td>
          <td>-2x</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>07522</td>
          <td>FI 2X Inverse ChinaAMC NASDAQ 100</td>
          <td>-2x</td>
      </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>


<h3 class="relative group">Taiwan, China 
    <div id="taiwan-china" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#taiwan-china" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<table>
  <thead>
      <tr>
          <th>Ticker</th>
          <th>Product Name</th>
          <th>Remarks</th>
      </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
      <tr>
          <td>00662</td>
          <td>Fubon NASDAQ 100</td>
          <td></td>
      </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>


<h3 class="relative group">India 
    <div id="india" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#india" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<table>
  <thead>
      <tr>
          <th>Ticker</th>
          <th>Product Name</th>
          <th>Remarks</th>
      </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
      <tr>
          <td>N100</td>
          <td>Motilal Oswal MOSt Shares NASDAQ 100</td>
          <td></td>
      </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>


<h3 class="relative group">Japan 
    <div id="japan" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#japan" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<table>
  <thead>
      <tr>
          <th>Ticker</th>
          <th>Product Name</th>
          <th>Remarks</th>
      </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
      <tr>
          <td>2569</td>
          <td>Listed Index Fund US Equity (NASDAQ100) Currency Hedged</td>
          <td></td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>1545</td>
          <td>NEXT FUNDS NASDAQ-100</td>
          <td></td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>2568</td>
          <td>Listed Index Fund US Equity (NASDAQ100) No Currency Hedging</td>
          <td></td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>2631</td>
          <td>MUKAM MAXIS NASDAQ100 ETF</td>
          <td></td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>2842</td>
          <td>iFreeETF NASDAQ100 Inverse</td>
          <td>-1x</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>2869</td>
          <td>iFreeETF NASDAQ100 Leveraged (2x)</td>
          <td>2x</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>2870</td>
          <td>iFreeETF NASDAQ100 Double Inverse (-2x)</td>
          <td>-2x</td>
      </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>


<h3 class="relative group">South Korea 
    <div id="south-korea" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#south-korea" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<table>
  <thead>
      <tr>
          <th>Ticker</th>
          <th>Product Name</th>
          <th>Remarks</th>
      </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
      <tr>
          <td>379810</td>
          <td>Samsung KODEX US NASDAQ100 Total Return</td>
          <td></td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>409820</td>
          <td>SAMSUNG KODEX US NASDAQ100 Leverage (SYNTH H)</td>
          <td></td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>367380</td>
          <td>KIM KINDEX NASDAQ100</td>
          <td></td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>368590</td>
          <td>KB KBSTAR US NASDAQ100</td>
          <td></td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>133690</td>
          <td>Mirae Asset TIGER NASDAQ 100 ETF</td>
          <td></td>
      </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>


<h2 class="relative group">Europe 
    <div id="europe" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#europe" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Germany 
    <div id="germany" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#germany" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<table>
  <thead>
      <tr>
          <th>Ticker</th>
          <th>Product Name</th>
          <th>Remarks</th>
      </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
      <tr>
          <td>NDXEX</td>
          <td>iShares NASDAQ-100 UCITS ETF</td>
          <td></td>
      </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>


<h3 class="relative group">United Kingdom 
    <div id="united-kingdom" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#united-kingdom" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<table>
  <thead>
      <tr>
          <th>Ticker</th>
          <th>Product Name</th>
          <th>Remarks</th>
      </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
      <tr>
          <td>CNDX</td>
          <td>iShares NASDAQ 100 UCITS ETF</td>
          <td></td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>EQQQ</td>
          <td>INVESCO MARKETS III PLC INVESCO EQQQ NASDAQ 100 UCITS ETF</td>
          <td></td>
      </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>


<h3 class="relative group">France 
    <div id="france" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#france" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<table>
  <thead>
      <tr>
          <th>Ticker</th>
          <th>Product Name</th>
          <th>Remarks</th>
      </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
      <tr>
          <td>USTE</td>
          <td>Lyxor UCITS Nasdaq-100 D-EUR</td>
          <td></td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>PUST</td>
          <td>Lyxor PEA Nasdaq 100 C</td>
          <td></td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>PANX</td>
          <td>Amundi ETF PEA Nasdaq-100 UCITS</td>
          <td></td>
      </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>


<h3 class="relative group">Austria 
    <div id="austria" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#austria" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<table>
  <thead>
      <tr>
          <th>Ticker</th>
          <th>Product Name</th>
          <th>Remarks</th>
      </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
      <tr>
          <td>EXXT</td>
          <td>iShares NASDAQ-100 UCITS</td>
          <td></td>
      </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>


<h3 class="relative group">Hungary 
    <div id="hungary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#hungary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<table>
  <thead>
      <tr>
          <th>Ticker</th>
          <th>Product Name</th>
          <th>Remarks</th>
      </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
      <tr>
          <td>DE0A0F.</td>
          <td>iShares NASDAQ-100 UCITS</td>
          <td></td>
      </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>


<h3 class="relative group">Switzerland 
    <div id="switzerland" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#switzerland" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<table>
  <thead>
      <tr>
          <th>Ticker</th>
          <th>Product Name</th>
          <th>Remarks</th>
      </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
      <tr>
          <td>CSNDX</td>
          <td>iShares Nasdaq 100 UCITS</td>
          <td></td>
      </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>


<h2 class="relative group">South America 
    <div id="south-america" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#south-america" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Brazil 
    <div id="brazil" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#brazil" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<table>
  <thead>
      <tr>
          <th>Ticker</th>
          <th>Product Name</th>
          <th>Remarks</th>
      </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
      <tr>
          <td>NASD11</td>
          <td>Trend ETF Nasdaq 100 Fundo de ndice</td>
          <td></td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>QQQI11</td>
          <td>Buena Vista Nasdaq-100 High Income</td>
          <td></td>
      </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>


<h2 class="relative group">Africa 
    <div id="africa" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#africa" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">South Africa 
    <div id="south-africa" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#south-africa" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<table>
  <thead>
      <tr>
          <th>Ticker</th>
          <th>Product Name</th>
          <th>Remarks</th>
      </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
      <tr>
          <td>STXNDQJ</td>
          <td>Satrix Nasdaq 100 Feeder Portfolio</td>
          <td></td>
      </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>


<h2 class="relative group">Oceania 
    <div id="oceania" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#oceania" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Australia 
    <div id="australia" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#australia" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<table>
  <thead>
      <tr>
          <th>Ticker</th>
          <th>Product Name</th>
          <th>Remarks</th>
      </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
      <tr>
          <td>NDQ</td>
          <td>Betashares Nasdaq 100</td>
          <td></td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>HNDQ</td>
          <td>BetaShares NASDAQ 100 ETF - Currency Hedged</td>
          <td></td>
      </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>


<h2 class="relative group">Middle East 
    <div id="middle-east" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#middle-east" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Israel 
    <div id="israel" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#israel" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<table>
  <thead>
      <tr>
          <th>Ticker</th>
          <th>Product Name</th>
          <th>Remarks</th>
      </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
      <tr>
          <td>MTFF96</td>
          <td>MTF Sal (4A) Nasdaq 100 Currency Hedged</td>
          <td></td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>MTFF95</td>
          <td>MTF Sal (4D) Nasdaq 100</td>
          <td></td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>KSMF83</td>
          <td>KSM 4A NASDAQ 100 Currency Hedged</td>
          <td></td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>HRLF49</td>
          <td>Harel Sal 4A NASDAQ 100 Currency Hedged</td>
          <td></td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>HRLF217</td>
          <td>Harel Sal (E) 3 Time Lvrg Nasdaq 100 Mnth CH (6A)</td>
          <td>3x</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>KSMF115</td>
          <td>KSM 6D Short Leveraged NASDAQ 100 x3 Monthly</td>
          <td>-3x</td>
      </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>
<hr>
<img src="https://www.uscreditcardguide.com/wp-content/uploads/ibkr-300x203.png" alt="ibkr" style="display: block; margin: 0 auto; border-radius: 6px;">


<h2 class="relative group">Interactive Brokers (IBKR) 
    <div id="interactive-brokers-ibkr" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#interactive-brokers-ibkr" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p><a href="https://www.interactivebrokers.com/en/general/about/ibkr-fact-sheet.php" target="_blank">Interactive Brokers LLC (IBKR)</a>, a US-based online brokerage firm, is the largest online broker in the United States. Founded in 1977 by Thomas Peterffy in the US, Interactive Brokers Group has its headquarters in Greenwich, Connecticut. The company went public in 2007 and is listed on the Nasdaq Stock Market under the ticker symbol <a href="https://www.nasdaq.com/market-activity/stocks/ibkr" target="_blank"><strong>IBKR</strong></a>.</p>
<p>Interactive Brokers Group affiliates provide automated trade execution and custody of securities, commodities and foreign exchange around the clock on over 150 markets in 27 currencies, from a single integrated platform, to clients from over 200 countries and territories. We service individual investors, hedge funds, proprietary trading groups, financial advisors and introducing brokers. Our four decades of focus on technology and automation have enabled us to equip our clients with a uniquely sophisticated platform to manage their investment portfolios. We strive to provide our clients with advantageous execution prices and trading, risk and portfolio management tools, research facilities and investment products, all at low or no cost, positioning them to achieve superior returns on investments. For the sixth consecutive year, Barron&rsquo;s ranked Interactive Brokers #1 with 5 out of 5 stars in its June 9, 2023, Best Online Brokers Review.</p>
<ul>
<li>IBG LLC was founded by its Chairman, Thomas Peterffy. Over the last 47 years, it has grown internally to become a major securities firm with equity capital of 15.2 billion .</li>
<li>Interactive Brokers&rsquo; headquarters is in Greenwich Connecticut, and it has 2,950+ employees in its offices in the United States, Switzerland, Canada, Hong Kong, United Kingdom, Australia, Japan, Hungary, Russia, India, China, Luxembourg, Ireland, Singapore and Estonia. IBKR is regulated by the SEC, FINRA, SFA and other regulatory agencies around the world.</li>
<li>IBKR is among the largest electronic brokers based on daily average revenue trades (DARTs) executing 2,634,000 trades per day.</li>
<li>Interactive Brokers Group has consistently been at the <a href="https://www.interactivebrokers.com/en/general/about/about.php" target="_blank">forefront of trading innovation</a>, starting with the invention of the first floor-based handheld computer in 1983.</li>
<li>Standard &amp; Poor&rsquo;s issues investment grade ratings to both <a href="https://www.interactivebrokers.com/download/IBG_SandP-Rating-06-2022.pdf" target="_blank">IBG LLC</a> and <a href="https://www.interactivebrokers.com/download/IBG_SandP-Rating-06-2022.pdf" target="_blank">IB LLC (IBKR)</a>.</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Referral Link for Account Opening 
    <div id="referral-link-for-account-opening" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#referral-link-for-account-opening" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://ibkr.com/referral/zumou900" target="_blank">Interactive Brokers (IBKR)</a></li>
</ul>

  



<div
  
    class="flex px-4 py-3 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900"
  >

  <span
    
      class="text-primary-400 ltr:pr-3 rtl:pl-3 flex items-center"
    >

    

  <span class="relative block icon">
    <svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 512 512"><path fill="currentColor" d="M256 0C114.6 0 0 114.6 0 256s114.6 256 256 256s256-114.6 256-256S397.4 0 256 0zM256 128c17.67 0 32 14.33 32 32c0 17.67-14.33 32-32 32S224 177.7 224 160C224 142.3 238.3 128 256 128zM296 384h-80C202.8 384 192 373.3 192 360s10.75-24 24-24h16v-64H224c-13.25 0-24-10.75-24-24S210.8 224 224 224h32c13.25 0 24 10.75 24 24v88h16c13.25 0 24 10.75 24 24S309.3 384 296 384z"/></svg>

  </span>


  </span>

  <span
    
      class="dark:text-neutral-300"
    >For every $100 in assets (cash or other assets) you deposit in your account after opening an account using <strong>the link above</strong>, you&rsquo;ll receive $1 worth of IBKR stock, up to a maximum value of $1,000. The average balance must be maintained for at least one year for the stock to vest.  <a href="https://www.ibtws.com/en/trading/referral-member-to-member.php" target="_blank">(Official Instructions)</a></span>
</div>

]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Property of Money: Book Notes</title>
      <link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1728564107112/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1728564107112/</guid>
      <description>Korean entrepreneur Kim Seung-ho shares his personal journey from poverty to wealth, providing practical guidance on wealth accumulation, management, and the pursuit of financial freedom.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[

<h2 class="relative group">I. Summary 
    <div id="i-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>&ldquo;Property of Money&rdquo; is Korean entrepreneur Kim Seung-ho&rsquo;s insightful account of his path to financial success. Starting from humble beginnings, he climbed the economic ladder, gaining profound insights into the multifaceted nature of money.  Driven by a desire to share his valuable experiences, the book explores five key attributes of money and outlines four essential skills necessary for achieving wealth. Through compelling stories and real-life examples, Kim Seung-ho demystifies complex economic concepts and investment principles, offering readers a practical guide towards financial freedom.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">II.  Chapter Summary 
    <div id="ii--chapter-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii--chapter-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>


<h3 class="relative group">Part 1: The Essence of Money 
    <div id="part-1-the-essence-of-money" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#part-1-the-essence-of-money" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>
<p><strong>Money is Personified:</strong> Kim personifies money, suggesting it possesses emotions and will. Your attitude towards money influences how it behaves towards you. Respect and treat it like a friend to earn its favor.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Investing in Superior Entrepreneurs:</strong>  Investing in companies and entrepreneurs more competent than oneself is a wise move, akin to partnering with them and reaping the rewards of their success. The author shares how he invested in successful companies like Microsoft, Amazon, and Nike, effectively becoming their &ldquo;partner.&rdquo;</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>The Secret of Compound Interest:</strong>  Compound interest is a fundamental principle in investment, capable of multiplying wealth. However, one must also be wary of its power when applied to debt. The author uses Warren Buffett&rsquo;s &ldquo;Mona Lisa&rdquo; analogy to illustrate the impact of compound interest.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>The Strength of Fixed Income:</strong> Stable cash flow surpasses inconsistent income, attracting and accumulating wealth. Kim compares fixed income to a well-trained army, capable of efficiently managing a large-scale organization despite smaller numbers.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Money&rsquo;s Gravitational Force:</strong> Substantial wealth attracts more wealth. Starting with small accumulations, compound interest propels wealth multiplication, much like the Earth formed from the gradual attraction of minuscule particles. The author illustrates this concept with the Han River and the Amazon River, demonstrating how small streams can converge to form vast rivers.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Highest Risk, Lowest Risk:</strong> The stock market is riskiest when everyone is bullish and chasing the latest hot stock; conversely, it&rsquo;s least risky when fear grips the market and everyone is selling.  Maintain a balanced perspective on fear and greed, embracing opportunity during widespread fear and exercising caution when greed prevails. Warren Buffet&rsquo;s famous quote, &ldquo;Be fearful when others are greedy, and greedy when others are fearful,&rdquo; encapsulates this wisdom.  The author uses the example of increased airline safety a week after an accident to illustrate this point.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Treat Others&rsquo; Money as You Treat Your Own:</strong> Treating others&rsquo; money with respect safeguards your own from similar disrespect.  Respect for others&rsquo; money is reciprocated. The author uses his attitude towards shopping carts at supermarkets to emphasize the importance of respecting others&rsquo; money.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Inheriting Millions with a &ldquo;No Loss&rdquo; Clause:</strong>  Through a hypothetical scenario, Kim highlights that preserving wealth is not straightforward. It requires learning, accumulating experience, and recognizing the significance of consistent income. The protagonist in the story inherits a substantial sum with the stipulation of no loss, ultimately realizing that maintaining wealth&rsquo;s value is no easy feat.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Rejecting Quick Riches:</strong>  The pursuit of quick wealth often leads to speculative traps and the perils of greed, ultimately ending in failure.  Building wealth demands a steady and gradual approach.  The author uses the analogy of constructing a house to demonstrate the importance of gradual wealth accumulation.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Can Economists Predict the Future?:</strong>  No one can accurately predict the macroeconomic future, especially in the long term, due to inherent uncertainties. Resist blindly following expert predictions; cultivate independent thinking and continuous learning.  Kim quotes economist John Kenneth Galbraith: &ldquo;There are two kinds of people in the world: those who don&rsquo;t know and those who don&rsquo;t know they don&rsquo;t know.&rdquo;</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Buying Samsung Stock at Samsung Securities:</strong> This anecdote illustrates the need for knowledge before venturing into investments. Avoid assumptions; understand market rules and investment tools. Kim compares the stock market to a ruthless jungle, where knowledge is essential for survival.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Changing Your Destiny Through Respectful Address:</strong> A personal experience highlights the importance of respecting others and showing genuine interest in their affairs, leading to trust, goodwill, and ultimately, good fortune.  The entrepreneur in the story habitually addresses everyone as &ldquo;that person,&rdquo; ultimately losing friends and connections.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Repeated Luck is Skill, Repeated Failure is Habit:</strong> Lucky individuals often possess greater astuteness and intelligence. They excel at observation, learning, and accumulating experience.  Conversely, repeated failure calls for introspection and addressing personal shortcomings.  The author uses examples like lottery tickets, rock-paper-scissors, and parking spots to illustrate the interplay of luck and skill.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Discerning Fact from Investment Hype in News:</strong> Using the COVID-19 pandemic as an example, Kim underlines the importance of focusing on facts and data, rather than blindly trusting media reports and expert predictions. He reached a more accurate assessment by comparing the total number of infections with the infection rate.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Each Dollar Experiences Time Differently:</strong> Borrowing Einstein&rsquo;s theory of relativity, the author suggests that money is also subject to the influence of time. Different sources of money experience time differently; always invest with money that has ample time.  Kim compares &ldquo;time-rich&rdquo; money to individuals who have more time to build relationships, fall in love, and raise children.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Diversification Isn&rsquo;t Enough:</strong> Kim critiques the misinterpretation of the saying &ldquo;Don&rsquo;t put all your eggs in one basket.&rdquo; Diversifying within a single market is merely using multiple baskets on the same shelf, still exposed to risk. He recommends spreading investments across diverse markets such as stocks, bonds, and real estate.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Three Paths to Wealth:</strong>  The author outlines three ways to become wealthy: inheritance, winning the lottery, and business success. He encourages young people to pursue entrepreneurship or engage in long-term investment. Kim elaborates on two paths to business success: starting a business or investing in successful companies.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Why Savings Don&rsquo;t Grow:</strong>  The root causes of stagnant savings lie in spending future income, neglecting asset management, undervaluing small amounts of money, and lacking investment knowledge. The author advises readers to ditch credit cards, use debit cards, and appreciate the power of accumulating small amounts of money.</p>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Part 2: The Wisdom of Investment 
    <div id="part-2-the-wisdom-of-investment" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#part-2-the-wisdom-of-investment" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li>
<p><strong>Identifying Financial Illiteracy:</strong>  Kim presents a list of 90+ economic and financial terms, encouraging readers to study and master this foundational knowledge, enhancing their financial literacy. He believes financial literacy is a vital survival skill for modern individuals.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Traits of Successful Stock Market Investors:</strong> These individuals perceive themselves as business owners, hold high-quality money, and excel at buying at low prices. The author emphasizes selecting quality company stocks for long-term holding, engaging with the company&rsquo;s progress as if they were owners.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Defining True Wealth:</strong>  Genuine wealth encompasses owning a mortgage-free home, a steady stream of passive income, and the mentality of &ldquo;not needing to work.&rdquo; Kim recognizes that the standard of wealth is relative, and true wealth lies in inner freedom.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Daily Habits for Wealth Protection:</strong>  The author shares his routine of diligently reading news, scanning economic websites, and collecting information. He believes continuous learning and market awareness are crucial for maintaining investment sensitivity and making informed decisions.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>The Harsh Realities of Poverty:</strong> Drawing from personal experience, Kim paints a grim picture of poverty, encouraging readers to believe in their potential for wealth. He underscores poverty&rsquo;s power to strip dignity and even dismantle family relationships.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Three Responses to Financial Panic:</strong>  The author categorizes people&rsquo;s responses to financial panics: those who suffer losses, those unaffected, and those who capitalize and profit. He analyzes the characteristics of each group, noting that individuals with no debt and stable income weather the storm while those who seize opportunities emerge wealthier.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Rewinding Time for Wealth:</strong>  Reflecting on his experience, Kim encourages young people to start investing early and highlights the limitations of relying solely on bank savings. He suggests young people focus on long-term investments in quality company stocks instead of traditional bank savings.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>The Foundation of Wisdom:</strong> Learning fundamental knowledge is a prerequisite for gaining wisdom.  The author encourages young people to study languages and mathematics, cultivating logical thinking abilities.  He believes learning new languages broadens horizons while studying mathematics sharpens logical reasoning.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Immediate Action for Wealth:</strong>  Drawing inspiration from Marie Kondo&rsquo;s organizational methods, Kim recommends readers declutter their homes, fostering respect for possessions, and reflecting on their spending habits. He suggests that the way we treat possessions reflects our attitude towards money; respecting belongings leads to cherishing wealth.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Will the Stock Market Rise?:</strong>  Don&rsquo;t obsess over short-term market fluctuations. Focus on long-term investment, select quality companies, and patiently wait for value to return. He advises readers to identify quality companies that warrant long-term investment and maintain unwavering confidence.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Unlocking the Value of Rent Payments:</strong>  Entrepreneurs consistently paying rent possess the capacity to purchase property. The author encourages them to become property owners and capitalize on the potential for greater returns.  He emphasizes that rental income can translate into property appreciation, while property ownership offers greater security and returns.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Real Estate vs. Stock Market:</strong>  Instead of fixating on which market is superior, choose an investment approach aligned with your style and risk tolerance. Kim provides a comparative analysis of real estate and stock market investments, highlighting their unique features and potential risks.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>My Independence Day:</strong>   Using the concept of a personal &ldquo;independence day&rdquo; marked by financial independence, the author emphasizes the significance of economic self-reliance. He encourages readers to develop financial strategies and strive for early financial freedom, recognizing its role as a foundation for personal liberty.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Four Skills of Money Management:</strong>  Kim outlines four essential skills for managing money: earning, saving, preserving, and spending. He provides insights into the characteristics of each skill and recommends learning methods. He emphasizes that these are interconnected skills that need to be mastered for effective wealth management.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Investing with Values:</strong> The author shares his investment principles, avoiding industries that profit from misfortunes. He believes such money carries negative consequences and clashes with his values. He exemplifies this with businesses centered around firearms, cigarettes, and drugs.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Insurance is not Savings:</strong>  Kim criticizes the practice of insurance companies selling high-commission, low-return products disguised as savings. He advises readers to choose insurance primarily for its protection function, not as investment vehicles, and to select suitable products based on their individual needs.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Beautiful Junk:</strong>  Drawing from a luxurious travel experience, Kim conveys that experiences and memories are more valuable than material possessions.  He urges readers to avoid accumulating &ldquo;beautiful junk,&rdquo; recognizing that many purchases become unused clutter, wasting both money and space.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Separating Economics from Political Bias:</strong>  Readers are urged to approach economic news with a critical eye, avoiding interpretation solely from a political standpoint. Refer to factual data to form judgments.  Kim suggests that many media reports are politically charged, encouraging independent thinking and caution against being swayed by media biases.</p>
</li>
</ul>


<h3 class="relative group">Part 4: The Mindset and Responsibilities of the Wealthy 
    <div id="part-4-the-mindset-and-responsibilities-of-the-wealthy" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#part-4-the-mindset-and-responsibilities-of-the-wealthy" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>The Underdog Advantage:</strong>  Using historical and business examples, the author illustrates that underdogs overcoming giants is a recurring theme. He encourages young people to embrace challenges and strive for success. He believes individuals from humble backgrounds often possess greater drive and innovation, enabling them to seize opportunities and achieve upward mobility.</li>
<li><strong>Your Personal PER:</strong>  Kim introduces the concept of Price-to-Earnings Ratio (PER) and applies it to personal careers and businesses, reminding readers to focus on the stability and sustainability of income sources. He emphasizes that high income doesn&rsquo;t equate to wealth; building systems that generate consistent income is crucial.</li>
<li><strong>Wealth Is Not Predestined:</strong> Great wealth arises from a combination of opportunities, hard work, intelligence, and luck, not from predetermined destiny. The author encourages readers to actively seek opportunities and prepare themselves, believing everyone holds the potential for success, provided they believe in themselves and strive diligently.</li>
<li><strong>Start Small, Dream Big:</strong> Young aspiring entrepreneurs are advised to gain experience and build connections by initially working in small companies.  He believes small companies offer more opportunities for learning and practical experience, facilitating rapid growth.</li>
<li><strong>Perseverance is Power:</strong>  The author emphasizes the importance of consistency and perseverance, advising readers to devote 100 days or three months to mastering a skill or forming a good habit. He believes persistence is key to success, as any skill requires continuous effort to achieve mastery.</li>
<li><strong>Limitless Business Opportunities:</strong>  Kim encourages readers to think outside the box and be receptive to business opportunities. He shares his experience of launching a flower shop, demonstrating that opportunities are present in everyday life; a keen eye can unearth suitable ventures.</li>
<li><strong>Entrepreneurship: The Path to Freedom:</strong> Entrepreneurship is championed as the only profession offering genuine control over one&rsquo;s destiny. The author encourages young people to pursue entrepreneurship, breaking free from the limitations of corporate employment. He highlights that entrepreneurship offers greater freedom, a sense of accomplishment, and the potential for significant wealth creation.</li>
<li><strong>Discerning the Nature of Money:</strong> Earn money of good character, avoiding ill-gotten gains from sources like gambling or fraud. Kim believes that good money brings blessings, while bad money carries misfortune, using examples of money obtained through gambling or fraud to illustrate the harmful effects of ill-gotten gains.</li>
<li><strong>Navigating Family Responsibilities as the Wealthiest Sibling:</strong> Kim shares guidance based on his own experience, recommending different strategies for supporting and caring for family members, depending on the scale of wealth.
<ul>
<li><strong>Under 100 Million Won:</strong> Prioritize women in the family who have contributed significantly but are often overlooked, such as sisters-in-law, along with nieces and nephews. Buy them gifts, cover family meal expenses, and provide regular financial support to parents. Avoid lending money to siblings for business ventures or assisting parents in upgrading their homes or cars.</li>
<li><strong>Under 500 Million Won:</strong> You can purchase a house or car for your parents, cover all their living expenses, and assist nieces and nephews with education costs. At this stage, you can offer measured support to siblings.</li>
<li><strong>Over 1 Billion Won:</strong> Actively help siblings escape poverty, select suitable siblings to participate in the management of family businesses, and lead the entire family to prosperity.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>The Right to Fail:</strong>  Young people are encouraged to embrace challenges without fear of failure, viewing failure as a valuable learning opportunity. He believes failure is a precious life experience, making success more appreciated when achieved.</li>
<li><strong>Can Books Create Wealth?:</strong>  Reading alone cannot make one wealthy; the key is to cultivate independent thinking and draw inspiration from books.  He suggests reading with a discerning mind, applying what you learn to your own experiences.</li>
<li><strong>God&rsquo;s Impartiality:</strong>  God&rsquo;s fairness lies in his non-intervention in earthly affairs. The author encourages readers to rely on their own efforts rather than placing their hope in divine intervention. He believes each individual is responsible for their own destiny and shouldn&rsquo;t place their hopes solely on divine intervention.</li>
<li><strong>The Passionate Entrepreneur and His Furious Wife:</strong>  A fictional story emphasizes the vital role of family harmony in business success, condemning the practice of prioritizing investments at the expense of family well-being.  The story features an entrepreneur, Mr. Song, who runs a successful dessert shop and a barbecue restaurant. He pours all the profits back into developing new menu items and his research lab, leading to financial strain at home and his wife&rsquo;s understandable frustration.</li>
<li><strong>Partnerships: A Delicate Dance:</strong>  Kim outlines the conditions and considerations for successful partnerships, emphasizing the importance of respecting partners&rsquo; money and drafting legally sound agreements.  He believes that trust and respect are paramount in any partnership, and all aspects of the agreement should be clearly defined in writing to prevent future disputes.</li>
<li><strong>Stick to the Main Road:</strong>  When investing in unfamiliar sectors, opt for companies that are industry leaders to mitigate risk. He compares investing in a leading company to navigating a well-defined road, reducing the risk of getting lost and generally offering greater security.</li>
<li><strong>The Quarter Rule:</strong>  The author unveils his personal &ldquo;Quarter Rule,&rdquo; advocating for living expenses to be capped at one-quarter of one&rsquo;s financial capacity.  This strategy allows for enjoying life while maintaining a financial safety net.</li>
<li><strong>Prayers Alone Won&rsquo;t Bring Riches:</strong>  True wealth comes through hard work, wisdom, and seizing opportunities, not reliance on divine intervention or supernatural forces. While prayer might offer spiritual solace, it cannot replace action.</li>
<li><strong>Four Habits of Saving:</strong>  Cultivate good habits early in life, starting with simple daily actions that lay a strong foundation for wealth accumulation. These habits are: stretching upon waking, making your bed, drinking a glass of water on an empty stomach each morning, and maintaining consistent sleep and wake times.</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">III. Notable Quotes 
    <div id="iii-notable-quotes" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii-notable-quotes" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;Money is personified.&rdquo;</p></blockquote>
<p>Money, like people, has emotions and a will; your attitude towards it influences its behavior towards you.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;Compound interest is the greatest invention of mankind, the eighth wonder of the world.&rdquo;</p></blockquote>
<p>The power of compounding is immense, capable of multiplying wealth. It is one of the most important principles in investing.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;Be fearful when others are greedy and greedy when others are fearful.&rdquo;</p></blockquote>
<p>Approach market sentiment rationally, seize opportunities during fear, exercise caution during greed.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;Treat others&rsquo; money as you treat your own.&rdquo;</p></blockquote>
<p>Respect for other people&rsquo;s money earns respect for yours. It reflects a fundamental principle of human interaction.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;The only way to quickly become rich is to not be in a hurry to become rich.&rdquo;</p></blockquote>
<p>Avoid the pitfalls of chasing quick riches, build wealth steadily and gradually.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;Not knowing is the right answer.&rdquo;</p></blockquote>
<p>The future is full of uncertainties. No one can accurately predict it. Maintain humility and a willingness to learn.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;An illiterate person might experience inconvenience, but a financially illiterate person cannot survive.&rdquo;</p></blockquote>
<p>Financial knowledge is essential for survival. Learn and master financial literacy to effectively manage wealth and avoid scams.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;The person paying rent is the landlord.&rdquo;</p></blockquote>
<p>Entrepreneurs capable of consistently paying rent possess the capability to own property. Seize opportunities to become property owners.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;The fastest way to become rich is to slowly become rich.&rdquo;</p></blockquote>
<p>Avoid the rush to wealth. Genuine wealth comes through persistent learning and gradual accumulation.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;Working hard doesn&rsquo;t guarantee wealth, acquiring wealth doesn&rsquo;t guarantee you&rsquo;ll be rich, and being rich doesn&rsquo;t guarantee happiness.&rdquo;</p></blockquote>
<p>Wealth is not an end but a means to an end. A balanced perspective on money is crucial for true happiness.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;Failure is a right.&rdquo;</p></blockquote>
<p>Young people should embrace challenges without fear of failure, viewing failure as a valuable learning experience.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>God will not make you rich.</p></blockquote>
<p>Wealth comes from hard work, intelligence, and opportunity, not divine intervention or supernatural forces.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;Small change is the &ldquo;sprout&rdquo; of big money.&rdquo;</p></blockquote>
<p>Don&rsquo;t underestimate the power of accumulating small amounts of money. Start small and gradually build your wealth system.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Money has different characters.</p></blockquote>
<p>Earn money through ethical means and avoid ill-gotten gains like those from gambling or fraud.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">IV. Guiding Principles 
    <div id="iv-guiding-principles" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv-guiding-principles" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>&ldquo;The Attributes of Money&rdquo; provides practical guidance for finance and life, offering these key takeaways:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Perspective on Money:</strong> Respect money, utilize it wisely, and treat it as a tool to achieve your goals, not as an end in itself.</li>
<li><strong>Financial Management:</strong>  Cultivate strong financial habits, value savings, learn to invest, and protect yourself from scams.</li>
<li><strong>Investment Philosophy:</strong>  Interpret market emotions rationally, pursue long-term investments, choose quality companies, and implement a well-defined asset allocation strategy.</li>
<li><strong>Life Philosophy:</strong>  Embrace challenges, learn from failures, and continuously learn and grow. Strive for financial and spiritual freedom.</li>
<li><strong>Family Values:</strong>  Prioritize family harmony, cherish your loved ones, and fulfill your responsibilities towards them.</li>
<li><strong>Ethics in Action:</strong>  Show respect for others, be willing to help, and cultivate kindness in your interactions.</li>
</ul>
<hr>

<section class="space-y-10 w-full">
    
    
        
            






















  <a class="flex flex-wrap article " href="/en/posts/1728295490690-book-list/">
    
        
        <div class="w-full md:w-auto h-full thumbnail nozoom thumbnailshadow md:mr-7" style="background-image:url(/posts/1728295490690-book-list/featured_hu_a14921d8ab66af4e.jpg);"></div>
        
      <div class=" mt-3 md:mt-0">
      <div class="items-center text-left text-xl font-semibold">
        
        <div class="font-bold text-xl text-neutral-800 decoration-primary-500 hover:underline hover:underline-offset-2 dark:text-neutral"
          href="/en/posts/1728295490690-book-list/">Recommended Reading List</div>
        
        
        
      </div>
      <div class="text-sm text-neutral-500 dark:text-neutral-400">
        











  



















<div class="flex flex-row flex-wrap items-center">
  
  
  <time datetime="2024-10-01T00:00:00&#43;00:00">1 October 2024</time>
  

  
  
</div>





<div class="flex flex-row flex-wrap items-center">
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  <span style="margin-top:0.5rem" class="mr-2" onclick="window.open(&#34;/en/tags/recommended/&#34;,'_self');">
    <span class="flex" style="cursor: pointer;">
  <span class="rounded-md border border-primary-400 px-1 py-[1px] text-xs font-normal text-primary-700 dark:border-primary-600 dark:text-primary-400">
    Recommended
  </span>
</span>
  </span>
  
  <span style="margin-top:0.5rem" class="mr-2" onclick="window.open(&#34;/en/tags/book/&#34;,'_self');">
    <span class="flex" style="cursor: pointer;">
  <span class="rounded-md border border-primary-400 px-1 py-[1px] text-xs font-normal text-primary-700 dark:border-primary-600 dark:text-primary-400">
    Book
  </span>
</span>
  </span>
  
  
  
  
</div>




      </div>
      
    </div>
  </a>

        
    
</section>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Psychology of Money: Book Notes</title>
      <link>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1728478918602/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jomonylw.github.io/en/posts/1728478918602/</guid>
      <description>This book, focusing on the psychology of money, states that the key to financial success is not intellect but behavior. Through numerous real-life examples and stories, it reveals the psychological weaknesses, biases, and behavioral patterns that influence human financial decisions, proposing strategies for making smarter choices in personal finance. </description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[

<h2 class="relative group">I. Summary 
    <div id="i-summary" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#i-summary" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p>The central argument of the book is that financial success is less about IQ and more about how you behave. Author Morgan Housel argues that by understanding the common psychological pitfalls associated with money, we can make better decisions. He illustrates this through a series of compelling stories and case studies, shedding light on our financial decision-making process.</p>


<h2 class="relative group">II. Chapter Summaries 
    <div id="ii-chapter-summaries" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#ii-chapter-summaries" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<p><strong>1. No One&rsquo;s Crazy</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Peoples unique experiences shape their financial perspectives and actions, leading to seemingly irrational yet logically justifiable behaviors.</li>
<li>For example, low-income individuals might be drawn to lotteries as their perceived only shot at a life-altering fortune.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>2. Luck &amp; Risk</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Nothing is as good or as bad as it seems, as luck and risk play crucial roles in personal outcomes.</li>
<li>Bill Gates getting into a high school with a computer was luck. His friend Kent Evans dying in a mountain climbing accident was risk.</li>
<li>Recognizing the influence of luck and risk helps avoid over-attributing success or failure solely to personal effort or poor decisions.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>3. Never Enough</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Contentment is key in finance. The pursuit of &ldquo;never enough&rdquo; leads to a dangerous cycle of insatiable desire that can ultimately lead to ruin.</li>
<li>Former McKinsey CEO Rajat Gupta and Ponzi schemer Bernie Madoff are cited as examples of individuals who lost everything due to greed.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>4. Confounding Compounding</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Compoundings power lies in long-term accumulation, allowing even small gains to snowball into extraordinary results.</li>
<li>Warren Buffett&rsquo;s immense wealth is attributed not just to skilled investment but to 70 years of consistent investing, highlighting the power of time.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>5. Getting Wealthy vs. Staying Wealthy</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Getting wealthy requires taking risks, while staying wealthy requires humility, frugality, and respecting the fleeting nature of good fortune.</li>
<li>Trading legend Jesse Livermore, despite remarkable success, fell victim to overconfidence and excessive risk-taking, ultimately leading to bankruptcy and suicide.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>6. Tails, You Win</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>In business and investing, &ldquo;tail events&rdquo; (rare, high-impact events) often disproportionately drive overall results.</li>
<li>Walt Disney produced hundreds of films, but the success of a single one, Snow White, propelled his entire enterprise to unimaginable heights.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>7. Freedom</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>The greatest dividend of wealth is the ability to control your time, offering the ultimate flexibility to pursue your passions and spend time with loved ones.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>8. The Ferrari Fallacy</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>People care less about your wealth than you think. Their attention is often directed towards their own desires and comparing themselves to you.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>9. Wealth is What You Don&rsquo;t See</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>True wealth lies not in flashy possessions but in the unseen: financial security, flexibility, and the ability to make choices.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>10. Save Money</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Building wealth hinges on your savings rate, which is driven by lifestyle choices and managing desires.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>11. Reasonable &gt; Rational</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>In financial decisions, making reasonable choices that you can stick with is often more effective than striving for absolute rationality.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>12. Surprise!</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>History is full of surprises, so relying solely on historical patterns to predict the future is unreliable. Recognizing the constant possibility of the unexpected is crucial.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>13. Room for Error</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>The most important part of every plan is planning on your plan not going according to plan: Building in a margin of safety is crucial.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>14. You&rsquo;ll Change</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Our goals, thoughts, and aspirations change over time. Acknowledging this is essential when making long-term financial plans. Avoid extreme financial goals, embracing the fluid nature of life.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>15. Nothing&rsquo;s Free</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Everything has a price. Success in investing comes with costs: volatility, fear, and uncertainty. Viewing these as fees for a valuable service rather than penalties to avoid helps navigate the emotional rollercoaster of investing.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>16. No One&rsquo;s Crazy (Reprise)</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Avoid blindly following financial advice from people with different circumstances and timelines than your own.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>17. The Seduction of Pessimism</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Pessimism often seems more intelligent and gains more attention, even though the world has generally improved significantly over time.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>18. When You Believe Anything</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>The power of narratives shapes our beliefs. The more we want something to be true, the more likely we are to embrace narratives that inflate its likelihood, especially in high-risk, high-reward scenarios like investing.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>19. Summary</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>This chapter provides a recap of the key principles and advice from previous chapters to guide sound financial decision-making.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>20. Confessions</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>The author shares his own personal approach to money management, highlighting the importance of seeking financial independence and emphasizing long-term investing.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Appendix: A Brief History of the American Consumer</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Post-WWII, the US deliberately engineered the American consumer through low-interest rates, consumer credit, and programs like the GI Bill, fostering a culture of consumption and economic growth.</li>
<li>From the 1950s to the 1970s, income distribution remained relatively equitable, the debt was manageable, and confidence in a better future was high.</li>
<li>The 1980s onwards witnessed growing income inequality. The aspirational lifestyles of a small group of prosperous individuals diverged drastically from those of the average person, fostering a culture of keeping up appearances, fueled by debt.</li>
<li>The 2008 financial crisis, a culmination of a debt bubble, exposed the cracks in this system.</li>
<li>Recent years have seen a rise in social unrest tied to income inequality, prompting individuals to question the current economic and social model.</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">III. Memorable Quotes 
    <div id="iii-memorable-quotes" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iii-memorable-quotes" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;Nothing is as good or as bad as it seems.&rdquo;</p></blockquote>
<ul>
<li>Lifes outcomes are influenced by chance and factors outside our control. This quote urges us to be mindful of the unpredictable nature of events.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;The hardest financial skill is getting the goalpost to stop moving.&rdquo;</p></blockquote>
<ul>
<li>Contentment is essential for financial well-being. Constantly shifting financial goals in pursuit of &ldquo;more&rdquo; can become a destructive cycle.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;The greatest dividend of wealth is the ability to control your time.&rdquo;</p></blockquote>
<ul>
<li>Wealth allows us to free ourselves from time constraints, enabling us to spend our time as we see fit.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;Wealth is what you don&rsquo;t see.&rdquo;</p></blockquote>
<ul>
<li>True wealth resides in our ability to make choices and have options, not in material possessions.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>Save Money. Just save.</p></blockquote>
<ul>
<li>Saving should be a default behavior, a fundamental habit for financial stability and future flexibility.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote>
<p>No Ones Crazy (Reprise).</p></blockquote>
<ul>
<li>Recognize that financial advice must be individualized. Avoid mimicking strategies without considering personal circumstances and goals.</li>
</ul>


<h2 class="relative group">IV. Practical Takeaways 
    <div id="iv-practical-takeaways" class="anchor"></div>
    
    <span
        class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100">
        <a class="group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700"
            style="text-decoration-line: none !important;" href="#iv-practical-takeaways" aria-label="Anchor">#</a>
    </span>        
    
</h2>
<ul>
<li><strong>Acknowledge your psychological biases</strong>  Understand your weaknesses related to managing money and avoid impulsive decisions.</li>
<li><strong>View money as a tool, not an end goal</strong>  Strive to use wealth as a means to achieve freedom and happiness, not to pursue material possessions.</li>
<li><strong>Create a financial plan that makes sense to you</strong>  Develop a plan, tailored to your needs and risk tolerance, that fosters financial stability. Incorporate a margin of safety for unforeseen events and market fluctuations.</li>
<li><strong>Invest for the long-term and stay the course</strong>  Compounding works best over long periods. Choose an investment strategy that resonates with your goals and  commit to it, riding out the inevitable market ups and downs.</li>
<li><strong>Pursue time freedom and happiness</strong>   Remember that the ultimate goal of acquiring wealth is to create a life of greater freedom and happiness.</li>
</ul>
<hr>

<section class="space-y-10 w-full">
    
    
        
            






















  <a class="flex flex-wrap article " href="/en/posts/1728295490690-book-list/">
    
        
        <div class="w-full md:w-auto h-full thumbnail nozoom thumbnailshadow md:mr-7" style="background-image:url(/posts/1728295490690-book-list/featured_hu_a14921d8ab66af4e.jpg);"></div>
        
      <div class=" mt-3 md:mt-0">
      <div class="items-center text-left text-xl font-semibold">
        
        <div class="font-bold text-xl text-neutral-800 decoration-primary-500 hover:underline hover:underline-offset-2 dark:text-neutral"
          href="/en/posts/1728295490690-book-list/">Recommended Reading List</div>
        
        
        
      </div>
      <div class="text-sm text-neutral-500 dark:text-neutral-400">
        











  



















<div class="flex flex-row flex-wrap items-center">
  
  
  <time datetime="2024-10-01T00:00:00&#43;00:00">1 October 2024</time>
  

  
  
</div>





<div class="flex flex-row flex-wrap items-center">
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  
  <span style="margin-top:0.5rem" class="mr-2" onclick="window.open(&#34;/en/tags/recommended/&#34;,'_self');">
    <span class="flex" style="cursor: pointer;">
  <span class="rounded-md border border-primary-400 px-1 py-[1px] text-xs font-normal text-primary-700 dark:border-primary-600 dark:text-primary-400">
    Recommended
  </span>
</span>
  </span>
  
  <span style="margin-top:0.5rem" class="mr-2" onclick="window.open(&#34;/en/tags/book/&#34;,'_self');">
    <span class="flex" style="cursor: pointer;">
  <span class="rounded-md border border-primary-400 px-1 py-[1px] text-xs font-normal text-primary-700 dark:border-primary-600 dark:text-primary-400">
    Book
  </span>
</span>
  </span>
  
  
  
  
</div>




      </div>
      
    </div>
  </a>

        
    
</section>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
